<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2024-03-24T00:50:51.677Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2024-03-24T00:50:51.677Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dark Matter Induced Power in Quantum Devices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.121801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.121801"/>
        <updated>2024-03-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anirban Das, Noah Kurinsky, and Rebecca K. Leane
Sub-GeV dark matter particles can be probed via power measurements in quantum devices.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 121801] Published Fri Mar 22, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anirban Das, Noah Kurinsky, and Rebecca K. Leane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of the Earth Tides with a Diamagnetic-Levitated Micro-Oscillator at Room Temperature]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.123601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.123601"/>
        <updated>2024-03-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yingchun Leng, Yiming Chen, Rui Li, Lihua Wang, Hao Wang, Lei Wang, Han Xie, Chang-Kui Duan, Pu Huang, and Jiangfeng Du
A new gravimeter is compact and stable and can detect the daily solar and lunar gravitational oscillations that are responsible for the tides.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 123601] Published Fri Mar 22, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yingchun Leng, Yiming Chen, Rui Li, Lihua Wang, Hao Wang, Lei Wang, Han Xie, Chang-Kui Duan, Pu Huang, and Jiangfeng Du</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Model for the dynamics of the large-scale circulations in two-layer turbulent convection]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.033501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.033501"/>
        <updated>2024-03-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yu Sun, Yi-Chao Xie, Jin-Xiao Xie, Jin-Qiang Zhong, Jianwei Zhang, and Ke-Qing Xia
A physically motivated low-dimensional model describes properly the interaction of two vertically-aligned large-scale circulations (LSC) in two-layer turbulent convection, and predicts their preferred flow states of thermal and viscous coupling. The model reveals that flow reversals can be achieved when turbulent fluctuations drive the LSC azimuthal diffusion into a flow state such that the two LSC planes are orthogonal to each other, the strength of the LSC in the high Rayleigh number fluid layer then reduces to zero deterministically. The model provides satisfactory interpretation for the high occurrence frequency of flow reversals observed in two-layer turbulent convection.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 033501] Published Fri Mar 22, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yu Sun, Yi-Chao Xie, Jin-Xiao Xie, Jin-Qiang Zhong, Jianwei Zhang, and Ke-Qing Xia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optical coherence and spin population dynamics in $^{171}\mathrm{Yb}^{3+}$:${\mathrm{Y}}_{2}{\mathrm{SiO}}_{5}$ single crystals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.094114</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.094114"/>
        <updated>2024-03-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Federico Chiossi, Eloïse Lafitte-Houssat, Alban Ferrier, Sacha Welinski, Loïc Morvan, Perrine Berger, Diana Serrano, Mikael Afzelius, and Philippe Goldner
Rare earth doped crystals are a promising platform for long-distance quantum communications, where they can perform quantum light storage. Among different systems, 171Yb3+-doped Y2SiO5 (YSO) crystals stand out because of long optical and spin coherence times, and large hyperfine splitting, enabling long-time storage over large bandwidths. Here, the authors study the mechanisms affecting the optical decoherence in a broad range of temperatures (40 mK to 18 K) using high-resolution spectroscopic techniques, and identify ways to further improve the crystal’s properties.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 094114] Published Fri Mar 22, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Federico Chiossi, Eloïse Lafitte-Houssat, Alban Ferrier, Sacha Welinski, Loïc Morvan, Perrine Berger, Diana Serrano, Mikael Afzelius, and Philippe Goldner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ultrafast hybrid fermion-to-qubit mapping]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.115149</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.115149"/>
        <updated>2024-03-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Oliver O'Brien and Sergii Strelchuk
Simulating the behavior of fermionic systems is a major application of quantum computers. The key challenge for quantum algorithms that simulate such systems is how to efficiently map fermionic interactions to qubits. By meticulous combination of the most efficient mappings in one dimension – the Jordan-Wigner as well as Bravyi-Kitaev with two-dimensional Verstraete-Cirac methods – the authors derive new high-performance mappings that use fewer ancillary resources and produce shorter quantum circuits than existing techniques. Low-resource requirements make these mappings suitable for emerging quantum hardware.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 115149] Published Fri Mar 22, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver O'Brien and Sergii Strelchuk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sympathetic cooling of trapped ${\mathrm{Th}}^{3+}$ alpha-recoil ions for laser spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.033116</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.033116"/>
        <updated>2024-03-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): G. Zitzer, J. Tiedau, M. V. Okhapkin, K. Zhang, C. Mokry, J. Runke, Ch. E. Düllmann, and E. Peik
The authors experimentally demonstrate the sympathetic cooling of Th3+ ions, captured from uranium alpha-recoil sources, in a linear Paul trap using laser-cooled 88Sr+ ions. They show the efficacy of their method via high-resolution laser spectroscopy. This demonstration is an important step in enabling the use of these ions as the reference of a highly accurate nuclear optical clock.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 033116] Published Fri Mar 22, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>G. Zitzer, J. Tiedau, M. V. Okhapkin, K. Zhang, C. Mokry, J. Runke, Ch. E. Düllmann, and E. Peik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of the $^{140}\mathrm{Ce}(\mathrm{n},γ)$ Cross Section at n_TOF and Its Astrophysical Implications for the Chemical Evolution of the Universe]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.122701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.122701"/>
        <updated>2024-03-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Amaducci et al. (n_TOF Collaboration)
A widening gap between the cerium-140 abundance predicted by theories and that measured in observations of certain stars indicates a potential need for updated models of element formation.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 122701] Published Thu Mar 21, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Amaducci &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (n_TOF Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Efficient Full-Frequency GW Calculations Using a Lanczos Method]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.126402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.126402"/>
        <updated>2024-03-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Weiwei Gao, Zhao Tang, Jijun Zhao, and James R. Chelikowsky
The spectroscopic data of hundreds of atoms can now be computed on a single workstation using the new Lanczos method in full-frequency GW calculations.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 126402] Published Thu Mar 21, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weiwei Gao, Zhao Tang, Jijun Zhao, and James R. Chelikowsky</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phase Transition to Chaos in Complex Ecosystems with Nonreciprocal Species-Resource Interactions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.127401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.127401"/>
        <updated>2024-03-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Emmy Blumenthal, Jason W. Rocks, and Pankaj Mehta
Nonreciprocal interactions in large ecosystems can give rise to a transition to chaos controlled by the ratio of surviving species to surviving resources.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 127401] Published Thu Mar 21, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emmy Blumenthal, Jason W. Rocks, and Pankaj Mehta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hybrid approach to long-term binary neutron-star simulations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.064061</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.064061"/>
        <updated>2024-03-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Harry Ho-Yin Ng, Jin-Liang Jiang, Carlo Musolino, Christian Ecker, Samuel D. Tootle, and Luciano Rezzolla
The numerical simulations of binary neutron star mergers is an important, but computationally expensive endeavor. The authors demonstrate that significant computational savings can be realized by adopting a hybrid approach to these simulations by using a fully dynamical spacetime solver initially, but switching to a conformally-flat spacetime solver as the system evolves.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 064061] Published Thu Mar 21, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Harry Ho-Yin Ng, Jin-Liang Jiang, Carlo Musolino, Christian Ecker, Samuel D. Tootle, and Luciano Rezzolla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thermal equation of state of rhodium to 191 GPa and 2700 K using double-sided flash laser heating in a diamond anvil cell]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.094113</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.094113"/>
        <updated>2024-03-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. D. McHardy, C. V. Storm, M. J. Duff, C. M. Lonsdale, G. A. Woolman, M. I. McMahon, N. Giordano, and S. G. MacLeod
Elemental rhodium (Rh) is one of eight noble metals in the periodic table exhibiting high resistance to corrosion and oxidation, even at elevated temperatures, and finds wide-ranging industrial applications. This paper presents a thermal equation of state describing the structural and volumetric behaviour of Rh under static compression to 191 GPa and flash laser heating to 2700 K as determined by \textit{in situ} synchrotron x-ray diffraction (XRD) in a diamond anvil cell. Fast scanning, combined with a small x-ray spot size, enables micron-scale XRD mapping of the local stress conditions within the sample assembly.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 094113] Published Thu Mar 21, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. D. McHardy, C. V. Storm, M. J. Duff, C. M. Lonsdale, G. A. Woolman, M. I. McMahon, N. Giordano, and S. G. MacLeod</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symmetric improved estimators for multipoint vertex functions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.125138</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.125138"/>
        <updated>2024-03-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jae-Mo Lihm, Johannes Halbinger, Jeongmin Shim, Jan von Delft, Fabian B. Kugler, and Seung-Sup B. Lee
The authors develop here a new representation of two-particle vertices, the effective interaction between quantum particles in a many-body environment. This yields numerical results with much higher accuracy and robustness than previously possible. By avoiding error-prone inversion, their “symmetric improved estimators” successfully pass stringent precision tests in both the real- and imaginary-frequency frameworks of quantum field theory. This scheme allows field-theoretic methods for strongly correlated electrons to expand into the real-frequency direction.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 125138] Published Thu Mar 21, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jae-Mo Lihm, Johannes Halbinger, Jeongmin Shim, Jan von Delft, Fabian B. Kugler, and Seung-Sup B. Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strong-coupling topological states and phase transitions in helical trilayer graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.125141</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.125141"/>
        <updated>2024-03-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yves H. Kwan, Patrick J. Ledwith, Chiu Fan Bowen Lo, and Trithep Devakul
Helical trilayer graphene is a new experimentally accessible magic-angle graphene heterostructure with nontrivial physics at both the moiré and supermoiré scale. The authors’ theoretical analysis reveals a plethora of topological strong-coupling Chern insulators at all integer moiré fillings. Crucially, the band renormalization that plagues previous moiré graphene systems is significantly suppressed, ensuring the validity of the strong-coupling perspective and opening the path to fractionalized phases. At experimentally accessible displacement fields, the authors find continuous topological transitions to more complex orders. Their results establish helical trilayer graphene as a promising platform for tunable strongly interacting topological phases.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 125141] Published Thu Mar 21, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yves H. Kwan, Patrick J. Ledwith, Chiu Fan Bowen Lo, and Trithep Devakul</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multigap nodeless superconductivity in the Dirac intermetallic alloy ${\mathrm{V}}_{2}{\mathrm{Ga}}_{5}$ with one-dimensional vanadium chains]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L100506</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L100506"/>
        <updated>2024-03-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. Q. Xu, C. C. Zhao, Y. Shen, D. Ratkovski, X. Ma, W. Zhou, Xunqing Yin, B. Li, A. F. Bangura, Chao Cao, Baomin Wang, Ziming Zhu, X. Ke, Dong Qian, Shiyan Li, and Xiaofeng Xu
A vast landscape of topological phases of matter with emergent quasiparticles has been explored in the past two decades, but the majority of them are 2D or 3D in essence and far fewer 1D counterparts are known to exist. Here, first-principles calculations reveal a multitude of topological fermions near the Fermi level in the quasi-one-dimensional alloy V2Ga5, which becomes a multigap nodeless superconductor below 3.6 K, raising the possibility of realizing topological superconductivity in this quasi-1D system.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, L100506] Published Thu Mar 21, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. Q. Xu, C. C. Zhao, Y. Shen, D. Ratkovski, X. Ma, W. Zhou, Xunqing Yin, B. Li, A. F. Bangura, Chao Cao, Baomin Wang, Ziming Zhu, X. Ke, Dong Qian, Shiyan Li, and Xiaofeng Xu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Demonstrating a Long-Coherence Dual-Rail Erasure Qubit Using Tunable Transmons]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011051</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011051"/>
        <updated>2024-03-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): H. Levine et al.
Researchers have realized a recently proposed qubit in which the errors mostly involve erasure of the qubit state, an advance that could help simplify the architecture of fault-tolerant quantum computers.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011051] Published Wed Mar 20, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>H. Levine &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disorder and diffuse scattering in single-chirality (${\mathrm{TaSe}}_{4}{)}_{2}\text{I}$ crystals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.034202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.034202"/>
        <updated>2024-03-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jacob A. Christensen, Simon Bettler, Kejian Qu, Jeffrey Huang, Soyeun Kim, Yinchuan Lu, Chengxi Zhao, Jin Chen, Matthew J. Krogstad, Toby J. Woods, Fahad Mahmood, Pinshane Y. Huang, Peter Abbamonte, and Daniel P. Shoemaker
The chiral charge density wave material (TaSe4)2I contains a half-filled Ta d-orbital, which creates Weyl points in a metallic band structure. However, historical measurements show insulating electrical transport. The authors use single-crystal diffraction and transmission electron microscopy to show that large single crystals have pristine chirality: they can exhibit a single enantiomer over millimeters. They resolve the contradiction in transport by showing a consistent iodine deficiency of more than 10%. These vacancies produce structural modulations visible in diffuse scattering and represent a new competing interaction in a class of materials with fragile electronic states.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 034202] Published Wed Mar 20, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jacob A. Christensen, Simon Bettler, Kejian Qu, Jeffrey Huang, Soyeun Kim, Yinchuan Lu, Chengxi Zhao, Jin Chen, Matthew J. Krogstad, Toby J. Woods, Fahad Mahmood, Pinshane Y. Huang, Peter Abbamonte, and Daniel P. Shoemaker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On granular flows: From kinetic theory to inertial rheology and nonlocal constitutive models]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.034304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.034304"/>
        <updated>2024-03-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Diego Berzi
The case is made that the kinetic theory of granular gases provides the long-sought universal framework to predict the flow of realistic particles from dilute to very dense conditions. In so doing, the popular inertial rheology and its nonlocal extension to deal with heterogeneities based on the granular fluidity concept are derived as special limits of the kinetic theory.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 034304] Published Wed Mar 20, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Diego Berzi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Identifying hubs in directed networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.034310</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.034310"/>
        <updated>2024-03-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alec Kirkley
Nodes with high connectivity, also called hubs, play a critical role in determining the structural and functional properties of networked systems. The author develops classification methods for directed networks that provide a definition of network hubs, and demonstrates them in a range of example applications.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 034310] Published Wed Mar 20, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alec Kirkley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological dualities via tensor networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.6.013302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.6.013302"/>
        <updated>2024-03-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. Wille, J. Eisert, and A. Altland
Dualities between three paradigmatic models in condensed-matter physics (the two-dimensional classical Ising model, the toric code, and a class D topological superconductor) are explored from a tensor network perspective. Being exact and explicit in nature, the approach allows for the translation of properties of the three different systems on a microscopic level and for the linking of nontrivial phenomena such as topological excitations, edge modes, and disorder operators.

[Phys. Rev. Research 6, 013302] Published Tue Mar 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. Wille, J. Eisert, and A. Altland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of $WWγ$ Production and Search for $Hγ$ Production in Proton-Proton Collisions at $\sqrt{s}=13\text{ }\text{ }\mathrm{TeV}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.121901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.121901"/>
        <updated>2024-03-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Hayrapetyan et al. (CMS Collaboration)
The production of two W bosons and a photon—a standard-model process—is observed for the first time.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 121901] Published Tue Mar 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Hayrapetyan &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (CMS Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Current-Induced Creation of Topological Vortex Rings in a Magnetic Nanocylinder]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.126701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.126701"/>
        <updated>2024-03-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yizhou Liu and Naoto Nagaosa
Scientists have devised a promising method for generating and manipulating exotic spin patterns called magnetic vortex rings, which could have applications in energy-efficient data storage and processing.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 126701] Published Tue Mar 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yizhou Liu and Naoto Nagaosa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin current leakage and Onsager reciprocity in interfacial spin-charge interconversion]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.094424</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.094424"/>
        <updated>2024-03-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aurélien Manchon, Shuyuan Shi, and Hyunsoo Yang
Spintronics involves converting spin currents to charge currents and vice versa, a process that has wide-ranging applications. However, in magnetic heterostructures, the efficiency of converting spins into charges is not always equivalent to converting charges into spins. This study intends to explain this discrepancy by accounting for both interfacial and bulk spin-orbit coupling. It shows that the charge-to-spin conversion is highly sensitive to spin current leakage, whereas spin-to-charge conversion is less affected by it. As a result, spin pumping appears as a more robust process than spin-orbit torque to quantify spin-charge interconversion efficiencies.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 094424] Published Tue Mar 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aurélien Manchon, Shuyuan Shi, and Hyunsoo Yang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amperean superconductivity cannot be induced by deep subwavelength cavities in a two-dimensional material]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.104513</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.104513"/>
        <updated>2024-03-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gian Marcello Andolina, Antonella De Pasquale, Francesco Maria Dimitri Pellegrino, Iacopo Torre, Frank H. L. Koppens, and Marco Polini
Amperean superconductivity is stemming from attractive effective electron-electron interactions mediated by a transverse gauge field. Amperean superconductivity has been recently proposed to occur at temperatures on the order of 1 K in two-dimensional electron gases embedded inside deep subwavelength optical cavities. Here, the authors generalize the microscopic theory of cavity-induced Amperean superconductivity to the case of graphene and then argue that this superconducting state cannot be achieved in the deep subwavelength regime.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 104513] Published Tue Mar 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gian Marcello Andolina, Antonella De Pasquale, Francesco Maria Dimitri Pellegrino, Iacopo Torre, Frank H. L. Koppens, and Marco Polini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interactions and Migration Rescuing Ecological Diversity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.2.013014</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.2.013014"/>
        <updated>2024-03-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Giulia Garcia Lorenzana, Ada Altieri, and Giulio Biroli
In this study, the authors describe the phase diagram of an ecological system with demographic noise, heterogeneous interactions, and migration, showing how mutualism can spontaneously emerge.

[PRX Life 2, 013014] Published Mon Mar 18, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giulia Garcia Lorenzana, Ada Altieri, and Giulio Biroli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological Flat Bands in Graphene Super-Moiré Lattices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.126401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.126401"/>
        <updated>2024-03-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mohammed M. Al Ezzi, Junxiong Hu, Ariando Ariando, Francisco Guinea, and Shaffique Adam
A super-moiré lattice in monolayer graphene generates flat bands, providing a viable platform to engineer its correlated states.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 126401] Published Mon Mar 18, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mohammed M. Al Ezzi, Junxiong Hu, Ariando Ariando, Francisco Guinea, and Shaffique Adam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Structures in the $J/ψJ/ψ$ Mass Spectrum in Proton-Proton Collisions at $\sqrt{s}=13\text{ }\text{ }\mathrm{TeV}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.111901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.111901"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Hayrapetyan et al. (CMS Collaboration)
Three structures, X(6900) and two new ones around 6.64 and 7.13 GeV, are seen in the J/ψJ/ψ mass spectrum that are consistent with being part of a family of radial excitations.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 111901] Published Fri Mar 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Hayrapetyan &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (CMS Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Direct Observation of Sub-Poissonian Temporal Statistics in a Continuous Free-Electron Beam with Subpicosecond Resolution]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.115001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.115001"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Borrelli, T. C. H. de Raadt, S. B. van der Geer, P. H. A. Mutsaers, K. A. H. van Leeuwen, and O. J. Luiten
A new method to measure the arrival times of electrons could aid in the design of future electron microscopes.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 115001] Published Fri Mar 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Borrelli, T. C. H. de Raadt, S. B. van der Geer, P. H. A. Mutsaers, K. A. H. van Leeuwen, and O. J. Luiten</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shortcuts of Freely Relaxing Systems Using Equilibrium Physical Observables]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.117102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.117102"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Isidoro González-Adalid Pemartín, Emanuel Mompó, Antonio Lasanta, Víctor Martín-Mayor, and Jesús Salas
Equilibrium observables can control nonequilibrium dynamics such as anomalous heating and cooling effects.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 117102] Published Fri Mar 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isidoro González-Adalid Pemartín, Emanuel Mompó, Antonio Lasanta, Víctor Martín-Mayor, and Jesús Salas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tensor Network Message Passing]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.117401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.117401"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yijia Wang, Yuwen Ebony Zhang, Feng Pan, and Pan Zhang
The tensor network message passing method reduces the error in the calculation of local observables by several orders of magnitude compared with state-of-the-art techniques.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 117401] Published Fri Mar 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yijia Wang, Yuwen Ebony Zhang, Feng Pan, and Pan Zhang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stresslet in a dilute suspension of rigid spheres in an Oldroyd-B fluid]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.033301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.033301"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Boon Siong Neo and Eric S. G. Shaqfeh
The stresslet in a dilute suspension of rigid spheres in a viscoelastic (Oldroyd-B) fluid is studied under imposed shear and uniaxial extensional flow. We observe that, due to its hyperbolic nature, the polymer constitutive equation can be directly evaluated along streamlines of the flow. Specifically, evaluating along streamlines on the particle surface, in the limit of the Newtonian flow fields, produces an analytical scaling which we evaluate and test against numerical results. This approach also provides physical insight into the mechanism driving the observed trends.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 033301] Published Fri Mar 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Boon Siong Neo and Eric S. G. Shaqfeh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interaction of soliton gases in deep-water surface gravity waves]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.034207</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.034207"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Loic Fache, Félicien Bonnefoy, Guillaume Ducrozet, François Copie, Filip Novkoski, Guillaume Ricard, Giacomo Roberti, Eric Falcon, Pierre Suret, Gennady El, and Stéphane Randoux
A soliton gas, a large random ensemble of solitons, does not reach thermodynamic equilibrium because there are infinitely many conserved quantities. The authors report water wave experiments with two interacting jets of soliton gases, and find good quantitative agreement with the predictions of spectral kinetic theory.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 034207] Published Fri Mar 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Loic Fache, Félicien Bonnefoy, Guillaume Ducrozet, François Copie, Filip Novkoski, Guillaume Ricard, Giacomo Roberti, Eric Falcon, Pierre Suret, Gennady El, and Stéphane Randoux</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microscopic optical potentials for medium-mass isotopes derived at the first order of Watson multiple-scattering theory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.034613</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.034613"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Vorabbi, C. Barbieri, V. Somà, P. Finelli, and C. Giusti
Optical potentials, either phenomenological or microscopic, are used in nuclear reactions to reduce the complexity of the quantum many-body scattering to a tractable one-body problem. In this work the authors extend to heavier nuclei a highly predictive microscopic approach based on ab-initio self-consistent Green’s function (SCGF) calculations that use NN and 3N chiral interactions as the only input. The computed elastic proton scattering off Ca and Ni isotope chains demonstrate the stability of the SCGF input, a method that requires only polynomial scaling of computational resources and reaches masses up to 140 nucleons or more. The predictive power of their optical potential promises interesting implications for studying nuclei away from stability, a frontier in nuclear science including nuclear astrophysics in the coming years.

[Phys. Rev. C 109, 034613] Published Fri Mar 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Vorabbi, C. Barbieri, V. Somà, P. Finelli, and C. Giusti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kitaev-Heisenberg model on the star lattice: From chiral Majorana fermions to chiral triplons]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.094421</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.094421"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): P. d'Ornellas and J. Knolle
Recently, the Kitaev Heisenberg model has attracted considerable interest as a description of Kitaev materials. On the honeycomb lattice, it has a phase diagram containing two spin-liquid and four magnetically ordered phases. Here, the authors consider this model on a lattice that breaks bipartite symmetry, frustrating the formation of antiferromagnetic order. Using mean field theory and DMRG, they find that this leads to the formation of two novel valence bond solid phases with a rich topological phase diagram and protected edge modes.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 094421] Published Fri Mar 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>P. d'Ornellas and J. Knolle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feasibility and potential of a thorium-doped barium-lithium-fluoride single crystal as a candidate for solid-state nuclear optical clock material]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.033109</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.033109"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Qiaorui Gong, SiLiang Tao, Shanming Li, Guoliang Deng, Chengchun Zhao, and Yin Hang
The authors study the feasibility of using Th:BaLiF3 single crystal as a solid-state nuclear clock material through density-functional-theory calculations. The authors then grow and characterize the crystal in the lab, demonstrating its potential for creating a solid-state nuclear clock in the future.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 033109] Published Fri Mar 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qiaorui Gong, SiLiang Tao, Shanming Li, Guoliang Deng, Chengchun Zhao, and Yin Hang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electron-correlation-induced nonclassicality of light from high-order harmonic generation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.033110</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.033110"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christian Saugbjerg Lange, Thomas Hansen, and Lars Bojer Madsen
In this paper, the authors use a fully quantum-mechanical description to study the effect of electron-electron correlations on the quantum state of light emitted via high-harmonic generation. The work represents a crucial step toward a fully quantized description of the interaction between intense laser fields and complex systems, with potential applications in quantum light engineering.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 033110] Published Fri Mar 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christian Saugbjerg Lange, Thomas Hansen, and Lars Bojer Madsen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pure quartic three-dimensional spatiotemporal Kerr solitons in graded-index media]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.033516</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.033516"/>
        <updated>2024-03-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pedro Parra-Rivas, Yifan Sun, Fabio Mangini, Mario Ferraro, Mario Zitelli, and Stefan Wabnitz
The authors study the formation of three-dimensional spatiotemporal solitons in waveguides with a parabolic refractive index profile and pure quartic chromatic dispersion using variational and numerical methods. They find that pure quartic spatiotemporal solitons remain stable within a significantly larger energy range with respect to their second-order dispersion counterparts.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 033516] Published Fri Mar 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pedro Parra-Rivas, Yifan Sun, Fabio Mangini, Mario Ferraro, Mario Zitelli, and Stefan Wabnitz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optical tuning of the diamond Fermi level measured by correlated scanning probe microscopy and quantum defect spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.036201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.036201"/>
        <updated>2024-03-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christian Pederson, Rajiv Giridharagopal, Fang Zhao, Scott T. Dunham, Yevgeny Raitses, David S. Ginger, and Kai-Mei C. Fu
Precise control of diamond’s surface termination is crucial for electronic devices and the charge stability of shallow, implanted color centers for quantum devices, such as the nitrogen-vacancy (NV) and silicon-vacancy (SiV) center. Previously, such surface control relied on aggressive treatments, such as annealing, plasma exposure, or strong acids, but here the authors demonstrate a novel technique utilizing a laser under ambient conditions. This technique is demonstrated on NV and SiV centers, with optical spatial resolution and continuous optical feedback. They are able to image the change in the diamond’s work function through Kelvin probe force microscopy, and determine the mechanism as laser-assisted oxidation.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 036201] Published Thu Mar 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christian Pederson, Rajiv Giridharagopal, Fang Zhao, Scott T. Dunham, Yevgeny Raitses, David S. Ginger, and Kai-Mei C. Fu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multispecies Ion Acceleration in 3D Magnetic Reconnection with Hybrid-Kinetic Simulations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.115201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.115201"/>
        <updated>2024-03-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Qile Zhang, Fan Guo, William Daughton, Hui Li, Ari Le, Tai Phan, and Mihir Desai
Computationally challenging 3D hybrid simulations of magnetic reconnection for multiple ion species give insights into the acceleration process for heavy ions and energy spectra compatible with in-situ spacecraft observations.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 115201] Published Thu Mar 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qile Zhang, Fan Guo, William Daughton, Hui Li, Ari Le, Tai Phan, and Mihir Desai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin-Orbit Excitons in a Correlated Metal: Raman Scattering Study of ${\mathrm{Sr}}_{2}{\mathrm{RhO}}_{4}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.116502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.116502"/>
        <updated>2024-03-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lichen Wang, Huimei Liu, Valentin Zimmermann, Arvind Kumar Yogi, Masahiko Isobe, Matteo Minola, Matthias Hepting, Giniyat Khaliullin, and Bernhard Keimer
A combined Raman scattering and theoretical study of spin-orbit excitations in Sr2RhO4 reveals unusual but well-defined excitations around 230 meV that are excitonic transitions between the spin-orbit multiplets of the Rh ions, excitations analogous to those recently observed in the Mott insulators Sr2IrO4 and RuCl3.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 116502] Published Thu Mar 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lichen Wang, Huimei Liu, Valentin Zimmermann, Arvind Kumar Yogi, Masahiko Isobe, Matteo Minola, Matthias Hepting, Giniyat Khaliullin, and Bernhard Keimer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Signatures of Majorana bound states in the diffraction patterns of extended superconductor–topological insulator–superconductor Josephson junctions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.094511</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.094511"/>
        <updated>2024-03-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Guang Yue, Can Zhang, Erik D. Huemiller, Jessica H. Montone, Gilbert R. Arias, Drew G. Wild, Jered Y. Zhang, David R. Hamilton, Xiaoyu Yuan, Xiong Yao, Deepti Jain, Jisoo Moon, Maryam Salehi, Nikesh Koirala, Seongshik Oh, and Dale J. Van Harlingen
Lateral Josephson junctions with topological insulator barriers (S-TI-S junctions) have been proposed as a platform to support Majorana bound states that can be used for topologically protected quantum processing. Here, the authors present a compilation of measurements of the critical current versus magnetic field diffraction patterns of such junctions and compare them to a model incorporating Majorana states, taking into account the effects of junction disorder and Majorana parity fluctuations. They observe entry features and lifting of odd nodes consistent with this picture.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 094511] Published Thu Mar 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guang Yue, Can Zhang, Erik D. Huemiller, Jessica H. Montone, Gilbert R. Arias, Drew G. Wild, Jered Y. Zhang, David R. Hamilton, Xiaoyu Yuan, Xiong Yao, Deepti Jain, Jisoo Moon, Maryam Salehi, Nikesh Koirala, Seongshik Oh, and Dale J. Van Harlingen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Temperature-induced structural and electronic phase transitions in <i>λ</i>-phase $\mathrm{T}{\mathrm{i}}_{3}{\mathrm{O}}_{5}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.035002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.035002"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): K. Yoshimatsu, H. Nakao, and H. Kumigashira
Metastable λ-Ti3O5, which undergoes phase transition to other polymorphs by external stimuli such as light, pressure, and temperature, is a candidate material for optolectronic and heat-storage devices. Here, the authors investigate the changes in the electrical and structural properties of λ-Ti3O5 with a single-crystalline thin film form across the temperature-induced phase transition. Resistivity and synchrotron X-ray diffraction measurements unveils a complex phase diagram divided into three temperature regions, which is composed of metal-insulator transition and second-order structural phase transition.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 035002] Published Wed Mar 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>K. Yoshimatsu, H. Nakao, and H. Kumigashira</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hydrodynamic Mechanism for Clumping along the Equatorial Rings of SN1987A and Other Stars]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.111201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.111201"/>
        <updated>2024-03-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Michael J. Wadas, William J. White, Heath J. LeFevre, Carolyn C. Kuranz, Aaron Towne, and Eric Johnsen
The clumpy structure of a ring of gas ejected by the progenitor star of the supernova 1987A could have formed when vortices in the gas interacted.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 111201] Published Wed Mar 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael J. Wadas, William J. White, Heath J. LeFevre, Carolyn C. Kuranz, Aaron Towne, and Eric Johnsen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RNA-induced Allosteric Coupling Drives Viral Capsid Assembly]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.2.013012</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.2.013012"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sean Hamilton, Tushar Modi, Petr Šulc, and S. Banu Ozkan
In this study, RNA-mediated allosteric protein regulation is proposed as a key mechanism driving viral capsid formation, revealing how single mutations can disrupt viral assembly and identifying new targets for antiviral treatments.

[PRX Life 2, 013012] Published Tue Mar 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Hamilton, Tushar Modi, Petr Šulc, and S. Banu Ozkan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monolithic Selenium/Silicon Tandem Solar Cells]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXEnergy.3.013013</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXEnergy.3.013013"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rasmus Nielsen, Andrea Crovetto, Alireza Assar, Ole Hansen, Ib Chorkendorff, and Peter C.K. Vesborg
Experiment and device simulation are combined to explore a monolithically integrated selenium/silicon tandem solar cell, offering insights toward positioning tandem solar cells as strong contenders for photovoltaic technologies.

[PRX Energy 3, 013013] Published Tue Mar 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rasmus Nielsen, Andrea Crovetto, Alireza Assar, Ole Hansen, Ib Chorkendorff, and Peter C.K. Vesborg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chemomechanics in alloy phase stability]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.033801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.033801"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sesha Sai Behara, John C. Thomas, Brian Puchala, and Anton Van der Ven
This work introduces a first-principles statistical mechanics method to calculate the free energies of crystalline alloys, including dependence on temperature, composition, and strain. The approach extends the alloy cluster expansion to include an explicit dependence on homogeneous strain in addition to site occupation variables that track chemical ordering. The method is applied to the Si-Ge binary alloy and is used to analyze phase stability under arbitrary epitaxial constraints. As a surrogate model, the new cluster expansion is a convenient compromise between the more restrictive configuration-only cluster expansions and machine-learned interatomic potentials, which require a substantially larger effort to train.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 033801] Published Tue Mar 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sesha Sai Behara, John C. Thomas, Brian Puchala, and Anton Van der Ven</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Selective observation of enantiomeric chiral phonons in $α$-quartz]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.104306</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.104306"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Eiichi Oishi, Yasuhiro Fujii, and Akitoshi Koreeda
Phonons that have angular momentum and propagate in crystals are known as chiral phonons. The authors demonstrate the selective observation of chiral phonons in α-quartz, the most typical chiral crystal, by circularly polarized Raman spectroscopy. They clarify the Raman tensors of the chiral phonons verifying the angular momentum conservation law in the Raman process, involving photons and the chiral phonon. This study suggests the possibility of controlling the angular momentum and propagation direction of chiral phonons via the Raman process.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 104306] Published Tue Mar 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eiichi Oishi, Yasuhiro Fujii, and Akitoshi Koreeda</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Precision-Spectroscopic Determination of the Binding Energy of a Two-Body Quantum System: The Hydrogen Atom and the Proton-Size Puzzle]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.113001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.113001"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Simon Scheidegger and Frédéric Merkt
Researchers have measured the transition energy of several highly excited states, which could help resolve a discrepancy about the size of the proton.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 113001] Published Mon Mar 11, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Scheidegger and Frédéric Merkt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonequilibrium symmetry-protected topological order: Emergence of semilocal Gibbs ensembles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.115117</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.115117"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maurizio Fagotti, Vanja Marić, and Lenart Zadnik
A generic nonequilibrium quantum system relaxes locally into a state resembling a thermal one even when isolated from the environment. In one-dimensional systems at finite temperature, ordered phases are generally excluded. Consequently, although symmetry-protected topological order may be present at zero temperature, its emergence at late times is not expected. This paper uncovers a mechanism that allows symmetry-protected topological order to emerge away from equilibrium for arbitrarily long times. It is based on the existence of hidden (semilocal) symmetries associated with operators that represent local observables only in a symmetry-restricted Hilbert space.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 115117] Published Mon Mar 11, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maurizio Fagotti, Vanja Marić, and Lenart Zadnik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evolutionary Conservation of Mechanical Strain Distributions in Functional Transitions of Protein Structures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011042</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011042"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pablo Sartori and Stanislas Leibler
The motions within the molecule provide a new way to compare the structures and functions of similar proteins.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011042] Published Fri Mar 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pablo Sartori and Stanislas Leibler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interaction between swarming active matter and flow: The impact on Lagrangian coherent structures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.033101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.033101"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xinyu Si and Lei Fang
We find that the impact of active matter on Lagrangian coherent structures (LCSs) was much more significant compared to localized random noise with similar energy. This is because the perturbation generated by active matter could couple with the background flow and further deform the LCSs. In addition, rotational elliptical regions of the flow were much more susceptible to active matter perturbation than the hyperbolic regions. Lastly, we revealed that the LCSs could be decently altered even at a small number density of active matter.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 033101] Published Fri Mar 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xinyu Si and Lei Fang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phonon thermal Hall effect in charge-compensated topological insulators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.104304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.104304"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rohit Sharma, Mahasweta Bagchi, Yongjian Wang, Yoichi Ando, and Thomas Lorenz
The observation of surprisingly large thermal Hall ratios in a growing number of mainly oxide-based insulators is a major puzzle and raises the question about potential mechanisms that can induce a thermal Hall effect in materials with dominant charge-neutral heat carriers. Here, the authors report the finding of comparable thermal Hall ratios in a series of charge-compensated topological insulators and discuss this observation in the context of a recent proposal that a thermal Hall effect can result from skew scattering of phonons on charged defects.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 104304] Published Fri Mar 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rohit Sharma, Mahasweta Bagchi, Yongjian Wang, Yoichi Ando, and Thomas Lorenz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manipulating topological properties in ${\text{Bi}}_{2}{\text{Se}}_{3}/\text{BiSe}$/transition metal dichalcogenide heterostructures with interface charge transfer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.115112</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.115112"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xuance Jiang, Turgut Yilmaz, Elio Vescovo, and Deyu Lu
The 3D topological insulator Bi2Se3 transitions to a trivial insulator under the 2D limit. Through first-principles studies, the authors show here that significant charge transfer occurs at the Bi2Se3/BiSe/transition metal dichalcogenide heterostructure interfaces that stabilizes the BiSe layer as an electron donor and the resulting dipole field breaks the inversion symmetry of the Bi2Se3 layer. This results in giant Rashba band splitting and the reemergence of the Dirac states in thin Bi2Se3 layers.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 115112] Published Fri Mar 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xuance Jiang, Turgut Yilmaz, Elio Vescovo, and Deyu Lu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlinear dynamics in neuromorphic photonic networks: Physical simulation in Verilog-A]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.034013</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.034013"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hugh Morison, Jagmeet Singh, Nayem Al Kayed, A. Aadhi, Maryam Moridsadat, Marcus Tamura, Alexander N. Tait, and Bhavin J. Shastri
Recurrent neural networks based on silicon photonics can take on a wide range of dynamical features at high bandwidth, but experimental demonstrations are being held back by of the lack of a physical-level simulation platform that accounts for parasitic effects. This study uses photonic Verilog-A models to demonstrate characteristic neural dynamics. Simulation reveals that these dynamics exhibit a topological equivalence to the continuous-time recurrent-neural-network model.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 034013] Published Fri Mar 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hugh Morison, Jagmeet Singh, Nayem Al Kayed, A. Aadhi, Maryam Moridsadat, Marcus Tamura, Alexander N. Tait, and Bhavin J. Shastri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pressure-Induced Superconductivity In Polycrystalline ${\mathrm{La}}_{3}{\mathrm{Ni}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{7−δ}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011040</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011040"/>
        <updated>2024-03-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): G. Wang, N. N. Wang, X. L. Shen, J. Hou, L. Ma, L. F. Shi, Z. A. Ren, Y. D. Gu, H. M. Ma, P. T. Yang, Z. Y. Liu, H. Z. Guo, J. P. Sun, G. M. Zhang, S. Calder, J.-Q. Yan, B. S. Wang, Y. Uwatoko, and J.-G. Cheng
Researchers have measured a zero-resistance state for the nickelate La3Ni2O7, which measurements suggest may superconduct at temperatures above the boiling point of liquid nitrogen.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011040] Published Thu Mar 07, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>G. Wang, N. N. Wang, X. L. Shen, J. Hou, L. Ma, L. F. Shi, Z. A. Ren, Y. D. Gu, H. M. Ma, P. T. Yang, Z. Y. Liu, H. Z. Guo, J. P. Sun, G. M. Zhang, S. Calder, J.-Q. Yan, B. S. Wang, Y. Uwatoko, and J.-G. Cheng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Method to assess the trustworthiness of machine coding at scale]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.20.010113</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.20.010113"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rebeckah K. Fussell, Emily M. Stump, and N. G. Holmes
A four part method will help draw trustworthy claims from machine coding of qualitative data.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 20, 010113] Published Wed Mar 06, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebeckah K. Fussell, Emily M. Stump, and N. G. Holmes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nanoscale electronic inhomogeneities in $1T{\text{-TaS}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.034002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.034002"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): B. Campbell, J. V. Riffle, A. de la Torre, Q. Wang, K. W. Plumb, and S. M. Hollen
In 1T-TaS2, native defects create electronic inhomogeneities spanning 5-10 nanometers that coexist with a well-formed commensurate charge density wave with a 1.3 nm period. Over these inhomogeneities, the band center shifts by up to 60meV and the gap varies by more than 100 meV. Surprisingly, the charge density wave order is unperturbed. These results reopen questions of how disorder affects charge density wave phases in correlated systems and emphasize the importance of real-space measurements in resolving the structural and electronic properties of quantum materials.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 034002] Published Wed Mar 06, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>B. Campbell, J. V. Riffle, A. de la Torre, Q. Wang, K. W. Plumb, and S. M. Hollen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orbital Magneto-Nonlinear Anomalous Hall Effect in Kagome Magnet ${\mathrm{Fe}}_{3}{\mathrm{Sn}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.106601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.106601"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lujunyu Wang, Jiaojiao Zhu, Haiyun Chen, Hui Wang, Jinjin Liu, Yue-Xin Huang, Bingyan Jiang, Jiaji Zhao, Hengjie Shi, Guang Tian, Haoyu Wang, Yugui Yao, Dapeng Yu, Zhiwei Wang, Cong Xiao, Shengyuan A. Yang, and Xiaosong Wu
Researchers have observed a new class of nonlinear Hall effect that can be understood through a geometric description of the electronic wave function.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 106601] Published Wed Mar 06, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lujunyu Wang, Jiaojiao Zhu, Haiyun Chen, Hui Wang, Jinjin Liu, Yue-Xin Huang, Bingyan Jiang, Jiaji Zhao, Hengjie Shi, Guang Tian, Haoyu Wang, Yugui Yao, Dapeng Yu, Zhiwei Wang, Cong Xiao, Shengyuan A. Yang, and Xiaosong Wu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Near- and mid-infrared excitation of ultrafast demagnetization in a cobalt multilayer system]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.094407</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.094407"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Katherine Légaré, Guillaume Barrette, Laurent Giroux, Jean-Michel Parent, Elissa Haddad, Heide Ibrahim, Philippe Lassonde, Emmanuelle Jal, Boris Vodungbo, Jan Lüning, Fabio Boschini, Nicolas Jaouen, and François Légaré
Ultrafast demagnetization occurs when magnetic materials are excited by a sudden burst of energy, such as from an ultrashort laser pulse. After generating pulses from the ultraviolet to the mid-infrared spectral regions, the authors retrieve here the ultrafast magnetic dynamics of a multilayered cobalt ferromagnet excited by femtosecond pulses with wavelengths ranging from 0.8 to 8.7 µm. A weak relationship between the excitation wavelength and the magnetic dynamics is uncovered as well as a significant effect of the pulse’s shape and duration.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 094407] Published Wed Mar 06, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine Légaré, Guillaume Barrette, Laurent Giroux, Jean-Michel Parent, Elissa Haddad, Heide Ibrahim, Philippe Lassonde, Emmanuelle Jal, Boris Vodungbo, Jan Lüning, Fabio Boschini, Nicolas Jaouen, and François Légaré</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microbunch rotation in an x-ray free-electron laser using a first-order achromatic bend]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.27.030702</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.27.030702"/>
        <updated>2024-03-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rachel A. Margraf, James P. MacArthur, Gabriel Marcus, Heinz-Dieter Nuhn, Alberto Lutman, Aliaksei Halavanau, Zhen Zhang, and Zhirong Huang
Microbunch rotation through an achromatic bend enables hard x-ray multiplexing and could be used to out-couple microbunches from a cavity based XFEL.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 27, 030702] Published Tue Mar 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel A. Margraf, James P. MacArthur, Gabriel Marcus, Heinz-Dieter Nuhn, Alberto Lutman, Aliaksei Halavanau, Zhen Zhang, and Zhirong Huang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three-dimensional imaging of single atoms in an optical lattice via helical point-spread-function engineering]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.033304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.033304"/>
        <updated>2024-03-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tangi Legrand, Falk-Richard Winkelmann, Wolfgang Alt, Dieter Meschede, Andrea Alberti, and Carrie A. Weidner
The authors develop a method for determining the three-dimensional location of single atoms in a quantum gas microscopy system using point-spread-function engineering of the atoms’ fluorescence signal. The technique extends quantum simulation with microscopy systems into the regime of three dimensions.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 033304] Published Tue Mar 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tangi Legrand, Falk-Richard Winkelmann, Wolfgang Alt, Dieter Meschede, Andrea Alberti, and Carrie A. Weidner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shape effects in the fluctuations of random isochrones on a square lattice]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.034104</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.034104"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Iván Álvarez Domenech, Javier Rodríguez-Laguna, Rodolfo Cuerno, Pedro Córdoba-Torres, and Silvia N. Santalla
In first-passage percolation one is interested in the region that can be reached from an origin within a given time. The authors show that on a square lattice with disorder, the boundary of this region behaves as a fluctuating interface in the Kardar-Parisi-Zhang universality class.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 034104] Published Mon Mar 04, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iván Álvarez Domenech, Javier Rodríguez-Laguna, Rodolfo Cuerno, Pedro Córdoba-Torres, and Silvia N. Santalla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of ferrotoroidic domains in a metal]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L100401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L100401"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Takeshi Hayashida, Ryusuke Misawa, Manfred Fiebig, and Tsuyoshi Kimura
Ferrotoroidic order refers to a spontaneous vortex arrangement of magnetic dipoles, which has recently been established as the fourth primary ferroic state of matter. Thus far, ferrotoroidic order has been studied extensively in insulators, but much less investigated in metallic materials. Here, the authors demonstrate the visualization of ferrotoroidic domains in metallic NdB4 by spatial distribution measurements of optical second harmonic generation (SHG). This study will stimulate research on unique functionalities of ferrotoroidic order in metals, such as an electric current induced domain switching.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, L100401] Published Mon Mar 04, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Takeshi Hayashida, Ryusuke Misawa, Manfred Fiebig, and Tsuyoshi Kimura</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Opposite Effects of the Rotational and Translational Energy on the Rates of Ion-Molecule Reactions near 0 K: The ${\mathrm{D}}_{2}^{+}+{\mathrm{NH}}_{3}$ and ${\mathrm{D}}_{2}^{+}+{\mathrm{ND}}_{3}$ Reactions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011034</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011034"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Raphaël Hahn, David Schlander, Valentina Zhelyazkova, and Frédéric Merkt
Experiments demonstrate some of the unusual features of molecular reactions that occur in the deep cold of interstellar space.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011034] Published Fri Mar 01, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Raphaël Hahn, David Schlander, Valentina Zhelyazkova, and Frédéric Merkt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ultrahigh Critical Current Density across Sliding Electrical Contacts in Structural Superlubric State]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.096201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.096201"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tielin Wu, Weipeng Chen, Lingyi Wangye, Yiran Wang, Zhanghui Wu, Ming Ma, and Quanshui Zheng
An experimental study of sliding electrical graphite contacts demonstrates simultaneous superlubricity and extremely high electrical conductivity.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 096201] Published Fri Mar 01, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tielin Wu, Weipeng Chen, Lingyi Wangye, Yiran Wang, Zhanghui Wu, Ming Ma, and Quanshui Zheng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exploration-Exploitation Paradigm for Networked Biological Systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.098402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.098402"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vito Dichio and Fabrizio De Vico Fallani
In the context of the brain wiring problem, development of the nematode, C. elegans, follows an exploration-exploitation paradigm.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 098402] Published Fri Mar 01, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vito Dichio and Fabrizio De Vico Fallani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of a giant band splitting in altermagnetic MnTe]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.115102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.115102"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Osumi, S. Souma, T. Aoyama, K. Yamauchi, A. Honma, K. Nakayama, T. Takahashi, K. Ohgushi, and T. Sato
This paper reports angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy and first-principles band calculations for MnTe, a candidate for an altermagnet that is now emerging as a new type of magnet, distinct from conventional ferromagnets and antiferromagnets. The authors provide direct experimental evidence for an exchange band splitting that reaches 0.8 eV. This band splitting was found to show strong anisotropy and multiple nodal lines in momentum space associated with the PT symmetry breaking characteristic of altermagnets.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 115102] Published Fri Mar 01, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Osumi, S. Souma, T. Aoyama, K. Yamauchi, A. Honma, K. Nakayama, T. Takahashi, K. Ohgushi, and T. Sato</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moiré fractals in twisted graphene layers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.125302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.125302"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Deepanshu Aggarwal, Rohit Narula, and Sankalpa Ghosh
Fractals are ubiquitous in nature. When two-dimensional crystals such as graphene or h-BN are multiply stacked and then twisted by a specific angle, the resulting super-moiré pattern exhibits electronic fractality. The authors call these novel structures “moiré fractals”. They derive a formula that relates their fractal dimension to the number of electronic bands in a given energy window. Such a number of bands fundamentally constrains charge and heat transport, thus providing a powerful tool for engineering designer quantum materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 125302] Published Fri Mar 01, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Deepanshu Aggarwal, Rohit Narula, and Sankalpa Ghosh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental demonstration of a two-dimensional hole gas in a GaN/AlGaN/GaN based heterostructure by optical spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.125401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.125401"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Loïc Méchin, François Médard, Joël Leymarie, Sophie Bouchoule, Jean-Yves Duboz, Blandine Alloing, Jesús Zuñiga-Pérez, and Pierre Disseix
Optical spectroscopy techniques, including time-resolved and intensity-dependent photoluminescence, are employed here to optically demonstrate, for the first time, the presence of a buried two-dimensional hole gas (2DHG) in a nitride-based heterostructure. The characteristic spectral and temporal features of this recombination highlight the asymmetric electric field distribution on either side of the 2DHG. The effects of this electric field are discussed, particularly regarding their implications for optical recombination mechanisms within the heterostructure.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 125401] Published Fri Mar 01, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Loïc Méchin, François Médard, Joël Leymarie, Sophie Bouchoule, Jean-Yves Duboz, Blandine Alloing, Jesús Zuñiga-Pérez, and Pierre Disseix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diverging nonlocal fields: Operationalizing critical disability physics identity with neurodivergent physicists outside academia]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.20.010111</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.20.010111"/>
        <updated>2024-02-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Liam G. McDermott, Nazeer A. Mosley, and Geraldine L. Cochran
Neurodivergent students experience unnecessary barriers to success in physics from assessment that is not constructed for how neurodivergent physicists perform physics-related tasks.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 20, 010111] Published Thu Feb 29, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liam G. McDermott, Nazeer A. Mosley, and Geraldine L. Cochran</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lateral solid phase epitaxy of yttrium iron garnet]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.L020402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.L020402"/>
        <updated>2024-02-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sebastian Sailler, Darius Pohl, Heike Schlörb, Bernd Rellinghaus, Andy Thomas, Sebastian T. B. Goennenwein, and Michaela Lammel
Yttrium iron garnet (YIG) is a prototypical material in the fields of spintronics and magnonics due to its exceptional magnetic properties. However, up to now, the focus has been on planar YIG thin films owing to the challenges associated with manufacturing non-planar structures. Here, the authors demonstrate the fabrication of single crystalline YIG via lateral solid phase epitaxy on top of an artificially defined SiOx mesa over micrometer length scales. The reported results lay the foundation for the development of non-planar, epitaxial YIG thin films as well as free standing YIG structures, while still maintaining complete control over the crystal orientation.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, L020402] Published Thu Feb 29, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sebastian Sailler, Darius Pohl, Heike Schlörb, Bernd Rellinghaus, Andy Thomas, Sebastian T. B. Goennenwein, and Michaela Lammel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Polar Self-Organization of Ferroelectric Nematic-Liquid-Crystal Molecules on Atomically Flat Au(111) Surface]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.098101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.098101"/>
        <updated>2024-02-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexandr A. Marchenko, Oleksiy L. Kapitanchuk, Yaroslava Yu. Lopatina, Kostiantyn G. Nazarenko, Anton I. Senenko, Nathalie Katsonis, Vassili G. Nazarenko, and Oleg D. Lavrentovich
Using a scanning tunneling microscope polar molecular ordering in a monolayer of ferroelectric nematic liquid crystal has been directly observed for the first time.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 098101] Published Thu Feb 29, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandr A. Marchenko, Oleksiy L. Kapitanchuk, Yaroslava Yu. Lopatina, Kostiantyn G. Nazarenko, Anton I. Senenko, Nathalie Katsonis, Vassili G. Nazarenko, and Oleg D. Lavrentovich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-fidelity reconstruction of large-area damaged turbulent fields with a physically constrained generative adversarial network]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.024608</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.024608"/>
        <updated>2024-02-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Qinmin Zheng, Tianyi Li, Benteng Ma, Lin Fu, and Xiaomeng Li
In this work, we propose a novel framework for the high-fidelity reconstruction of large-area damaged turbulent fields with high resolution based on a physically constrained generative adversarial network. The network leverages complete/sparse fields of velocity components as physical constraints and adopts a PatchGAN discriminator network. The proposed reconstruction framework has been shown to achieve excellent reconstruction performance. The reconstructed flow fields are consistent with the raw flow fields in terms of magnitude, power spectrum, and two-point correlation function.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 024608] Published Thu Feb 29, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qinmin Zheng, Tianyi Li, Benteng Ma, Lin Fu, and Xiaomeng Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spatiotemporal Torquing of Light]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011031</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011031"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. W. Hancock, S. Zahedpour, A. Goffin, and H. M. Milchberg
Researchers have determined the amount of transverse orbital angular momentum that a type of optical vortex carries per photon, an important step for future applications.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011031] Published Wed Feb 28, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. W. Hancock, S. Zahedpour, A. Goffin, and H. M. Milchberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guiding diamond spin qubit growth with computational methods]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.026204</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.026204"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jonathan C. Marcks, Mykyta Onizhuk, Nazar Delegan, Yu-Xin Wang (王语馨), Masaya Fukami, Maya Watts, Aashish A. Clerk, F. Joseph Heremans, Giulia Galli, and David D. Awschalom
Spin defects in semiconductors play a major role in quantum technologies. Synthesizing high-quality spin qubits relies on controlling the incorporation of noise sources, such as other, unwanted spin defects, into the host crystal. In this work, the authors provide quantitative calculations of the coherence properties of spin qubits in diamond. They incorporate these results into an existing materials synthesis platform to develop predictive models and in situ feedback for more reliable creation of qubits tailored to applications.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 026204] Published Wed Feb 28, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan C. Marcks, Mykyta Onizhuk, Nazar Delegan, Yu-Xin Wang (王语馨), Masaya Fukami, Maya Watts, Aashish A. Clerk, F. Joseph Heremans, Giulia Galli, and David D. Awschalom</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conformal Invariance in Water-Wave Turbulence]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.094001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.094001"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Noseda and P. J. Cobelli
Experiments on gravity-capillary waves and analysis techniques drawn from stochastic partial differential equation theory establish a connection between zero-height isolines and the critical 2D Ising model’s domain walls, revealing a novel link between water-wave turbulence and critical systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 094001] Published Wed Feb 28, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Noseda and P. J. Cobelli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep-Learning Density Functional Perturbation Theory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.096401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.096401"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): He Li, Zechen Tang, Jingheng Fu, Wen-Han Dong, Nianlong Zou, Xiaoxun Gong, Wenhui Duan, and Yong Xu
A framework leveraging deep learning and automatic differentiation circumvents the computational bottleneck associated with density functional perturbation theory calculations.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 096401] Published Wed Feb 28, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>He Li, Zechen Tang, Jingheng Fu, Wen-Han Dong, Nianlong Zou, Xiaoxun Gong, Wenhui Duan, and Yong Xu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recycling of a quantum field and optimal states for single-qubit rotations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.022439</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.022439"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shanon Vuglar and Julio Gea-Banacloche
The authors introduce a protocol to generate the electromagnetic field state that is optimal for controlling a given qubit rotation. The protocol, based on the interaction of the field with ancilla qubits, allows for field “recycling” and could potentially reduce error rates and improve energy efficiency in quantum computing schemes.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 022439] Published Wed Feb 28, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shanon Vuglar and Julio Gea-Banacloche</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement-Free Fault-Tolerant Quantum Error Correction in Near-Term Devices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.5.010333</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.5.010333"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sascha Heußen, David F. Locher, and Markus Müller
A fault-tolerant quantum error-correction scheme is presented that does not require measuring individual qubits and could thus revolutionize platforms that do not support midcircuit measurements.

[PRX Quantum 5, 010333] Published Tue Feb 27, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sascha Heußen, David F. Locher, and Markus Müller</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Large-scale characterization of ${\mathrm{Cu}}_{2}\mathrm{O}$ monocrystals via Rydberg excitons]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.026202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.026202"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kerwan Morin, Delphine Lagarde, Angélique Gillet, Xavier Marie, and Thomas Boulier
This research introduces a novel experimental technique to characterize Rydberg excitons in copper oxide (Cu2O) crystals with sub-micron resolution. By employing spatially resolved resonant absorption spectroscopy and photoluminescence imaging, the study unveils the influence of optically-active charged oxygen vacancies on Rydberg excitons. This approach yields comprehensive spatial maps of exciton properties, including energy, linewidth, and peak absorption without any mobile part, providing valuable insights into crystal quality. The findings highlight the predominant role of charged oxygen vacancies in influencing Rydberg excitons in Cu2O and offer a reliable method for assessing crystal quality in view of solid-state Rydberg physics.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 026202] Published Tue Feb 27, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kerwan Morin, Delphine Lagarde, Angélique Gillet, Xavier Marie, and Thomas Boulier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Viscoplastic rimming flow inside a rotating cylinder]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.023304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.023304"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Thomasina V. Ball and Neil J. Balmforth
When a small fraction of viscoplastic fluid is placed into a rotating cylinder, steady states can be reached with pool at the bottom of the cylinder and a residual coating elsewhere. Lubrication theory used to model the film thickness builds on previous models by bridging between two asymptotic limits, incorporating both the gravitational force along the cylinder and the hydrostatic pressure gradients. The model predicts steady states are reached after a small number of rotations and allows exploration of drainage when the cylinder comes to a halt. Experiments using a Carbopol suspension provide a suitable comparison to test the thin film theory.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 023304] Published Tue Feb 27, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomasina V. Ball and Neil J. Balmforth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spectral and Krylov complexity in billiard systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.046017</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.046017"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hugo A. Camargo, Viktor Jahnke, Hyun-Sik Jeong, Keun-Young Kim, and Mitsuhiro Nishida
The authors study spectral and Krylov complexity in quantum billiard systems at finite temperature. They show that spectral complexity may be used to probe the transition between the chaotic and integrable configurations for the billiard systems. For Krylov complexity, they study the associated Lanczos coefficients showing that their growth rate satisfies the conjectured generalized chaos bound, and that they produce an exponential growth of the Krylov complexity at early times.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 046017] Published Tue Feb 27, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hugo A. Camargo, Viktor Jahnke, Hyun-Sik Jeong, Keun-Young Kim, and Mitsuhiro Nishida</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Producing circular field harmonics inside elliptic magnet apertures with superconducting canted-cosine-theta coils]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.27.022402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.27.022402"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): L. Brouwer
An analytic solution to the electromagnetic design of elliptic-bore superconducting accelerator magnets, and its application to canted-cosine-theta magnets.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 27, 022402] Published Tue Feb 27, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L. Brouwer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonreciprocal Frustration: Time Crystalline Order-by-Disorder Phenomenon and a Spin-Glass-like State]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011029</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011029"/>
        <updated>2024-02-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ryo Hanai
New theoretical work establishes an analogy between systems that are dynamically frustrated, such as glasses, and thermodynamic systems whose members have conflicting goals, such as predator–prey ecosystems.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011029] Published Mon Feb 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ryo Hanai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of van der Waals phonons in the single-layer cuprate ${(\mathrm{Bi},\mathrm{Pb})}_{2}{(\mathrm{Sr},\mathrm{La})}_{2}{\mathrm{CuO}}_{6+δ}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024804</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024804"/>
        <updated>2024-02-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Y. Y. Peng, I. Boukahil, K. Krongchon, Q. Xiao, A. A. Husain, Sangjun Lee, Q. Z. Li, A. Alatas, A. H. Said, H. T. Yan, Y. Ding, L. Zhao, X. J. Zhou, T. P. Devereaux, L. K. Wagner, C. D. Pemmaraju, and P. Abbamonte
Interlayer van der Waals (vdW) coupling is ubiquitous in two-dimensional materials. The authors explore these interactions in the cuprate (Bi, Pb)2(Sr,La)2CuO6+δ, revealing ultra-low energy phonon modes similar to graphene and transition metal dichalcogenides. Using high-resolution inelastic hard x-ray scattering and first-principles simulations, they reveal vdW phonons from the shear motion of adjacent Bi-O layers. These findings deepen our understanding of the vibrational properties of cuprates and suggest opportunities for the design of novel heterostructures. These results highlight the generic nature of vdW modes in layered materials, including doped copper oxides, and provide insights for future materials design and research.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 024804] Published Mon Feb 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Y. Y. Peng, I. Boukahil, K. Krongchon, Q. Xiao, A. A. Husain, Sangjun Lee, Q. Z. Li, A. Alatas, A. H. Said, H. T. Yan, Y. Ding, L. Zhao, X. J. Zhou, T. P. Devereaux, L. K. Wagner, C. D. Pemmaraju, and P. Abbamonte</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum dots as optimized chiral emitters for photonic integrated circuits]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085431</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085431"/>
        <updated>2024-02-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jakub Rosiński, Michał Gawełczyk, Karol Tarnowski, Paweł Karwat, Daniel Wigger, and Paweł Machnikowski
A quantum emitter coupled to a photonic waveguide may emit photons in one particular direction. It is, however, challenging to create a system that matches the requirements of the directional coupling over a broad area of the waveguide. The authors show here that a properly designed quantum dot can be fine tuned in situ with a magnetic field to yield the desired directionality. This finding overcomes the obstacles on the path to efficient chiral coupling in QD-based photonic integrated circuits.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 085431] Published Mon Feb 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jakub Rosiński, Michał Gawełczyk, Karol Tarnowski, Paweł Karwat, Daniel Wigger, and Paweł Machnikowski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum criticality and entanglement for the two-dimensional long-range Heisenberg bilayer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L081114</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L081114"/>
        <updated>2024-02-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Menghan Song, Jiarui Zhao, Yang Qi, Junchen Rong, and Zi Yang Meng
The authors conduct here a pioneering and unbiased investigation into the entanglement properties of (2+1)-dimensional O(3) quantum critical points and two-dimensional Néel states in systems with long-range interactions. This study uncovers exotic properties, such as the vanishing of logarithmic corrections to entanglement entropies at QCPs and an enhancement in Néel states as long-range interactions amplify. Moreover, they determine precise critical exponents of QCPs influenced by long-range interactions, characterized by three distinct renormalization group fixed points.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, L081114] Published Mon Feb 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Menghan Song, Jiarui Zhao, Yang Qi, Junchen Rong, and Zi Yang Meng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>