<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2022-11-20T01:06:45.895Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2022-11-20T01:06:45.895Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frequency Comb from a Single Driven Nonlinear Nanomechanical Mode]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.12.041019</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.12.041019"/>
        <updated>2022-11-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. S. Ochs, D. K. J. Boneß, G. Rastelli, M. Seitner, W. Belzig, M. I. Dykman, and E. M. Weig
Experiments show that a frequency comb can be generated by just one resonantly driven nanomechanical mode, rather than two or more, opening a new route to comb generation and novel technological applications.

[Phys. Rev. X 12, 041019] Published Fri Nov 18, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. S. Ochs, D. K. J. Boneß, G. Rastelli, M. Seitner, W. Belzig, M. I. Dykman, and E. M. Weig</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comparison of Low-Redshift Lyman-$α$ Forest Observations to Hydrodynamical Simulations with Dark Photon Dark Matter]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.211102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.211102"/>
        <updated>2022-11-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): James S. Bolton, Andrea Caputo, Hongwan Liu, and Matteo Viel
Spectra from quasars suggest that intergalactic gas may have been heated by a form of dark matter called dark photons.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 211102] Published Fri Nov 18, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James S. Bolton, Andrea Caputo, Hongwan Liu, and Matteo Viel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First-Principles Fermi Acceleration in Magnetized Turbulence]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.215101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.215101"/>
        <updated>2022-11-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Martin Lemoine
A newly developed first-principles description of particle acceleration in magnetized turbulence connects particle energization with the intermittent nature of the velocity gradients of magnetic field lines.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 215101] Published Fri Nov 18, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Lemoine</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonequilibrium components in the region of very low transverse momentum in high-energy nuclear collisions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.106.054908</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.106.054908"/>
        <updated>2022-11-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuuka Kanakubo, Yasuki Tachibana, and Tetsufumi Hirano
The theoretical interpretation of data produced in relativistic heavy-ion collisions has relied on applying relativistic viscous fluid-dynamical modeling approaches. Recently, the focus of several studies has been on the transition between the very first instants of the collision and the hydrodynamic phase. This paper shows that the addition of a corona component to a fluid-dynamical core increases the agreement between theory and low-momentum data. This supports the importance of non-equilibrium physics in the characterization of the quark-gluon plasma.

[Phys. Rev. C 106, 054908] Published Fri Nov 18, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuuka Kanakubo, Yasuki Tachibana, and Tetsufumi Hirano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theoretical uncertainty quantification for heavy-ion fusion]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.106.L051602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.106.L051602"/>
        <updated>2022-11-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): K. Godbey, A. S. Umar, and C. Simenel
Many aspects of physics that spans from the origin of the elements to nuclear technologies rely on a robust description of nuclear reactions. One therefore needs predictive modelling of nuclear quantum many-body dynamics in which the uncertainties are well-understood. The authors use the time-dependent Hartree-Fock approach, and apply uncertainty quantification to the nuclear dynamics, considering a collection of low-energy heavy-ion fusion reactions. They find that the uncertainty in the theoretical results mainly arises from structure properties, such as the skin of neutron-rich nuclei, which are particularly ill-constrained. This work highlights the importance of including reaction data in the construction and constraint of new theoretical models that can treat dynamics and structure on the same footing.

[Phys. Rev. C 106, L051602] Published Fri Nov 18, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>K. Godbey, A. S. Umar, and C. Simenel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disorder-free localization with Stark gauge protection]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.174305</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.174305"/>
        <updated>2022-11-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Haifeng Lang, Philipp Hauke, Johannes Knolle, Fabian Grusdt, and Jad C. Halimeh
A paradigm of strong ergodicity breaking – disorder-free localization (DFL) – offers a fundamental probe of out-of-equilibrium quantum many-body physics and also promises potential applications in quantum information technology. As such, stabilizing DFL against errors on modern quantum simulators becomes of paramount importance. Here, the authors introduce the concept of Stark gauge protection, which comprises an experimentally friendly sum of local symmetry generators each weighted by its spatial location. This stabilizes DFL up to all investigated evolution times.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 174305] Published Fri Nov 18, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haifeng Lang, Philipp Hauke, Johannes Knolle, Fabian Grusdt, and Jad C. Halimeh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetic dynamics of ${\mathrm{NiPS}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.174422</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.174422"/>
        <updated>2022-11-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. R. Wildes, J. R. Stewart, M. D. Le, R. A. Ewings, K. C. Rule, G. Deng, and K. Anand
NiPS3 is a layered van der Waals compound. Like graphite, it can be delaminated down to a monolayer. Unlike graphite, it is magnetic. Neutron inelastic scattering has been performed on bulk single-crystal samples of NiPS3 to measure the magnetic dynamics, key to understanding the magnetic properties. Clear spin waves are observed, quantifying the magnetic exchange within and between the layers and the predominantly planar anisotropy. The findings have important ramifications for NiPS3 in graphene-based research.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 174422] Published Fri Nov 18, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. R. Wildes, J. R. Stewart, M. D. Le, R. A. Ewings, K. C. Rule, G. Deng, and K. Anand</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accurate localization of Kosterlitz-Thouless-type quantum phase transitions for one-dimensional spinless fermions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.205133</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.205133"/>
        <updated>2022-11-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Florian Gebhard, Kevin Bauerbach, and Örs Legeza
Spinless fermions in one dimension with nearest-neighbor transfer amplitude −t and interaction V display a Kosterlitz-Thouless-type quantum phase transition from a Luttinger liquid metal to a charge density wave insulator at finite interaction strength Vc=2t. The authors use the density matrix renormalization group (DMRG) method on rings with L≤512 sites for an accurate localization of the transition. The maximum of the quasiparticle density in the upper Hartree-Fock band, nβmax(L,V)=maxknk,β(L,V), develops a peak close to the critical interaction whose position extrapolates to the exact result in the thermodynamic limit, limL→∞Vβmax(L,V)=Vc, with an accuracy of better than one percent. Monitoring the Luttinger parameter permits to locate the transition with an accuracy of three percent.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 205133] Published Fri Nov 18, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Florian Gebhard, Kevin Bauerbach, and Örs Legeza</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pattern of inclusions inside rippled icicles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.054211</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.054211"/>
        <updated>2022-11-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): John Ladan and Stephen W. Morris
Some icicles develop surface ripples as they grow. Researchers now explain the growth mechanism, but a full explanation remains elusive.

[Phys. Rev. E 106, 054211] Published Thu Nov 17, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Ladan and Stephen W. Morris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rethinking mirror symmetry as a local duality on fields]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.105014</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.105014"/>
        <updated>2022-11-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chiung Hwang, Sara Pasquetti, and Matteo Sacchi
The authors develop an algorithm for a field theoretical implementation of mirror symmetry. This is based on the so-called quiver representation of certain N=1 supersymmetric theories and is a non-abelian generalization of the piecewise dualization of three-dimensional abelian theories. Extensions of this local field-theoretic operations to non-supersymmetric theories are expected.

[Phys. Rev. D 106, 105014] Published Thu Nov 17, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chiung Hwang, Sara Pasquetti, and Matteo Sacchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Curvature as an external field in mechanical antiferromagnets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.6.115203</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.6.115203"/>
        <updated>2022-11-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Abigail Plummer, Paul Z. Hanakata, and David R. Nelson
The authors construct a mechanical analog of an Ising antiferromagnet by inserting a square array of locally dilated sites into a 2D crystalline membrane. Past a buckling threshold, these dilations become bistable, and buckle either above or below the host lattice. When the host lattice is planar, neighboring dilations prefer to be antialigned, but a cylindrical host lattice can bias the dilations to buckle away from the center of curvature. They show that curvature acts as an effective external field on the mechanical antiferromagnet, and map out the phase behavior of the system at zero and finite temperature. This demonstrates how curvature and temperature can be used to design and operate a responsive and tunable metamaterial at either the macroscale or nanoscale.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 6, 115203] Published Wed Nov 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abigail Plummer, Paul Z. Hanakata, and David R. Nelson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minimizing the Elastic Energy of Growing Leaves by Conformal Mapping]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.218101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.218101"/>
        <updated>2022-11-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anna Dai and Martine Ben Amar
Physicists have shown that a mathematical transformation called a conformal map can be used to predict how leaves grow.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 218101] Published Wed Nov 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Dai and Martine Ben Amar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hele-Shaw flow for parity odd three-dimensional fluids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.7.114201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.7.114201"/>
        <updated>2022-11-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dylan Reynolds, Gustavo M. Monteiro, and Sriram Ganeshan
We derive the governing equation of flow for a three-dimensional fluid with a parity-broken viscosity tensor when confined to a Hele-Shaw cell. When such a fluid is pushed through a channel, a transverse force is exerted on the walls, and when a bubble of air expands into a region of such fluid, a circulation develops in the far field. The Saffman-Taylor stability condition is also modified, with these terms tending to stabilize the two fluid interface. Such experiments can in principle facilitate the measurement of parity odd coefficients in both synthetic and natural active matter systems.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 7, 114201] Published Wed Nov 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dylan Reynolds, Gustavo M. Monteiro, and Sriram Ganeshan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimal Design of Three-Dimensional Voxel Printed Multimaterial Lattice Metamaterials via Machine Learning and Evolutionary Algorithm]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.054050</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.054050"/>
        <updated>2022-11-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Le Dong and Dong Wang
Mechanical metamaterials present tremendous potential through synergistic material distribution and structural design, but current approaches mainly focus on structure while neglecting the material distribution. The authors propose an optimized method for designing lattice metamaterials, considering both control aspects. This framework can be used to match multiple targets, such as reproducing the stress-strain and Poisson’s ratio curves of biological tissues simultaneously, and to enable customized lateral profiles. This work expands the design space of lattice metamaterials and is promising for flexible electronics and soft robotics.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 054050] Published Wed Nov 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Le Dong and Dong Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Systematic Control of the Interlayer Exchange Coupling in Perpendicularly Magnetized Synthetic Antiferromagnets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.054051</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.054051"/>
        <updated>2022-11-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Teng Xu, Jiahao Liu, Xichao Zhang, Qihan Zhang, Heng-An Zhou, Yiqing Dong, Pierluigi Gargiani, Manuel Valvidares, Yan Zhou, and Wanjun Jiang
Controlling the interlayer exchange coupling in synthetic antiferromagnets (SAFs) is crucial for realizing spintronic phenomena and devices. Here researchers investigate such control in Pt/Co/Ru/Fe0.55Tb0.45 by tuning the thicknesses of various layers. Complementary measurements using three techniques show that SAFs with different magnetization-reversal characteristics may be clearly resolved. The results suggest that the interlayer exchange coupling may be tuned effectively in this manner, which could be quite useful for designing SAF-based magnetic memory or sensing devices.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 054051] Published Wed Nov 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Teng Xu, Jiahao Liu, Xichao Zhang, Qihan Zhang, Heng-An Zhou, Yiqing Dong, Pierluigi Gargiani, Manuel Valvidares, Yan Zhou, and Wanjun Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hard-sphere jamming through the lens of linear optimization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.055310</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.055310"/>
        <updated>2022-11-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Claudia Artiaco, Rafael Díaz Hernández Rojas, Giorgio Parisi, and Federico Ricci-Tersenghi
Simulating the jamming of hard spheres is difficult because of the singular interaction potential, which is either zero or infinite. This paper analyzes an algorithm that uses a mapping onto a constrained optimization problem to generate jammed hard-sphere packings that satisfy force balance and are globally stable.

[Phys. Rev. E 106, 055310] Published Tue Nov 15, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claudia Artiaco, Rafael Díaz Hernández Rojas, Giorgio Parisi, and Federico Ricci-Tersenghi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Structure of axion miniclusters]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.103514</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.103514"/>
        <updated>2022-11-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): David Ellis, David J. E. Marsh, Benedikt Eggemeier, Jens Niemeyer, Javier Redondo, and Klaus Dolag
Asteroid-sized clumps of a dark matter candidate known as an axion could be detectable in a gravitational-microlensing survey.

[Phys. Rev. D 106, 103514] Published Tue Nov 15, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Ellis, David J. E. Marsh, Benedikt Eggemeier, Jens Niemeyer, Javier Redondo, and Klaus Dolag</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unidirectional Chiral Magnonics in Cylindrical Synthetic Antiferromagnets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.054044</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.054044"/>
        <updated>2022-11-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R.A. Gallardo, P. Alvarado-Seguel, and P. Landeros
Progress in spintronics continues briskly, with many different approaches and physical phenomena underlying candidate technologies. This study uses modern spin-wave theory to predict the magnonic spectrum of a cylindrical synthetic antiferromagnet consisting of two coaxial nanotubes. The proposed device incorporates two coupled ferromagnetic nanotubes hosting oppositely magnetized vortices. Nonreciprocal features of the proposed architecture are provided by both intra- and interlayer dipolar coupling. Unidirectional spin-wave behavior is found, which may impact the realization of low-power magnonic devices operating at nano- to micrometer scales.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 054044] Published Tue Nov 15, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R.A. Gallardo, P. Alvarado-Seguel, and P. Landeros</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flow of quantum correlations in noisy two-mode squeezed microwave states]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.052415</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.052415"/>
        <updated>2022-11-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Renger, S. Pogorzalek, F. Fesquet, K. Honasoge, F. Kronowetter, Q. Chen, Y. Nojiri, K. Inomata, Y. Nakamura, A. Marx, F. Deppe, R. Gross, and K. G. Fedorov
The authors experimentally investigate the behavior of quantum discord and entanglement in two-mode squeezed states generated by superconducting Josephson parametric amplifiers. They show how correlations flow between the two modes and the noisy environment, and relate their findings to the security of entanglement-based quantum key distribution.

[Phys. Rev. A 106, 052415] Published Tue Nov 15, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Renger, S. Pogorzalek, F. Fesquet, K. Honasoge, F. Kronowetter, Q. Chen, Y. Nojiri, K. Inomata, Y. Nakamura, A. Marx, F. Deppe, R. Gross, and K. G. Fedorov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simulating Models of Challenging Correlated Molecules and Materials on the Sycamore Quantum Processor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.3.040318</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.3.040318"/>
        <updated>2022-11-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ruslan N. Tazhigulov, Shi-Ning Sun, Reza Haghshenas, Huanchen Zhai, Adrian T.K. Tan, Nicholas C. Rubin, Ryan Babbush, Austin J. Minnich, and Garnet Kin-Lic Chan
Two problems of interest in chemistry and materials science are tested on a quantum processor used for quantum advantage experiments.

[PRX Quantum 3, 040318] Published Mon Nov 14, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ruslan N. Tazhigulov, Shi-Ning Sun, Reza Haghshenas, Huanchen Zhai, Adrian T.K. Tan, Nicholas C. Rubin, Ryan Babbush, Austin J. Minnich, and Garnet Kin-Lic Chan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crossing $N=28$ Toward the Neutron Drip Line: First Measurement of Half-Lives at FRIB]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.212501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.212501"/>
        <updated>2022-11-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): H. L. Crawford et al.
Researchers have discovered the heaviest-known bound isotope of sodium and characterized other neutron-rich isotopes, offering important benchmarks for refining nuclear models.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 212501] Published Mon Nov 14, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>H. L. Crawford &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discovery of $^{39}\mathrm{Na}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.212502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.212502"/>
        <updated>2022-11-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. S. Ahn et al.
Researchers have discovered the heaviest-known bound isotope of sodium and characterized other neutron-rich isotopes, offering important benchmarks for refining nuclear models.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 212502] Published Mon Nov 14, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. S. Ahn &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meandering features of wall-attached structures in turbulent boundary layer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.7.114603</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.7.114603"/>
        <updated>2022-11-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jinyul Hwang and Jae Hwa Lee
In wall turbulence, meandering behaviors of large-scale structures observed in the logarithmic layer is a crucial spatial feature for understanding the spatial organization of these structures and improving the structure-based turbulence model. These structures extend from the near-wall region to the edge of boundary layers. Their meandering motions leave an imprint on the two-point turbulence statistics across the flow, especially in the logarithmic region. Here, we demonstrate the influence of the meandering motions of wall-attached structures on the two-point correlation and premultiplied two-dimensional spectra by analyzing direct numerical simulation data of the turbulent boundary layer.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 7, 114603] Published Mon Nov 14, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jinyul Hwang and Jae Hwa Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Surrogate model for gravitational wave signals from nonspinning, comparable-to large-mass-ratio black hole binaries built on black hole perturbation theory waveforms calibrated to numerical relativity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.104025</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.104025"/>
        <updated>2022-11-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tousif Islam, Scott E. Field, Scott A. Hughes, Gaurav Khanna, Vijay Varma, Matthew Giesler, Mark A. Scheel, Lawrence E. Kidder, and Harald P. Pfeiffer
Gravitational waveforms obtained using numerical relativity (NR) are computationally expensive and slow. Surrogate models provide an alternative to full NR by extrapolating from the point-particle regime of high-mass ratio binary waveforms calibrated to NR to much smaller mass ratios. The authors show that their methods work over a remarkable range of mass ratios of 2.5 to 10000 showing good agreement with NR simulations.

[Phys. Rev. D 106, 104025] Published Mon Nov 14, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tousif Islam, Scott E. Field, Scott A. Hughes, Gaurav Khanna, Vijay Varma, Matthew Giesler, Mark A. Scheel, Lawrence E. Kidder, and Harald P. Pfeiffer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stable and High-Quality Electron Beams from Staged Laser and Plasma Wakefield Accelerators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.12.041016</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.12.041016"/>
        <updated>2022-11-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): F. M. Foerster et al.
A new type of plasma accelerator combines two previous methods of producing an electron beam into one compact design.

[Phys. Rev. X 12, 041016] Published Thu Nov 10, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>F. M. Foerster &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Demonstration of a Quantum Gate Using Electromagnetically Induced Transparency]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.200501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.200501"/>
        <updated>2022-11-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): K. McDonnell, L. F. Keary, and J. D. Pritchard
A neutral-atom CNOT gate based on electromagnetically induced transparency in a Rydberg system is experimentally realized.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 200501] Published Thu Nov 10, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>K. McDonnell, L. F. Keary, and J. D. Pritchard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synthetic Images of Magnetospheric Reconnection-Powered Radiation around Supermassive Black Holes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.205101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.205101"/>
        <updated>2022-11-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Benjamin Crinquand, Benoît Cerutti, Guillaume Dubus, Kyle Parfrey, and Alexander Philippov
Simulations of the plasma around a black hole indicate that “magnetic reconnection” could induce radio-wave hot spots that orbit the black hole, a prediction future Event Horizon Telescope measurements could test.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 205101] Published Thu Nov 10, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin Crinquand, Benoît Cerutti, Guillaume Dubus, Kyle Parfrey, and Alexander Philippov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interlayer Electron-Hole Friction in Tunable Twisted Bilayer Graphene Semimetal]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.206802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.206802"/>
        <updated>2022-11-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. A. Bandurin, A. Principi, I. Y. Phinney, T. Taniguchi, K. Watanabe, and P. Jarillo-Herrero
In a perpendicular electric field, a small-angle twisted bilayer graphene system is tuned to a Fermi liquid with strong friction between electrons and holes, providing insight into heat and charge transport mechanisms in semimetals.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 206802] Published Thu Nov 10, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. A. Bandurin, A. Principi, I. Y. Phinney, T. Taniguchi, K. Watanabe, and P. Jarillo-Herrero</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discrimination of Chiral and Helical Contributions to Raman Scattering of Liquid Crystals Using Vortex Beams]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.207801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.207801"/>
        <updated>2022-11-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Silvia Müllner, Florian Büscher, Angela Möller, and Peter Lemmens
By transferring angular momentum from structured light to chiral liquid crystals it is possible to discriminate chiral and helical contributions of Raman scattering.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 207801] Published Thu Nov 10, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Silvia Müllner, Florian Büscher, Angela Möller, and Peter Lemmens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Polarized image of equatorial emission in horizonless spacetimes: Traversable wormholes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.104024</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.104024"/>
        <updated>2022-11-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Valentin Deliyski, Galin Gyulchev, Petya Nedkova, and Stoytcho Yazadjiev
Predictions indicate that wormholes and black holes may have nearly identical polarized light spectra, making these astrophysical objects difficult to distinguish.

[Phys. Rev. D 106, 104024] Published Thu Nov 10, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Valentin Deliyski, Galin Gyulchev, Petya Nedkova, and Stoytcho Yazadjiev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multiple Rabi rotations of trions in InGaAs quantum dots observed by photon echo spectroscopy with spatially shaped laser pulses]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.205408</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.205408"/>
        <updated>2022-11-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Grisard, H. Rose, A. V. Trifonov, R. Reichhardt, D. E. Reiter, M. Reichelt, C. Schneider, M. Kamp, S. Höfling, M. Bayer, T. Meier, and I. A. Akimov
The authors investigate Rabi rotations, arising in photon echoes from an ensemble of InGaAs quantum dots. To overcome the dephasing of the Rabi rotations imposed by the inhomogeneity of laser intensities, a spatially flat intensity profile is introduced. This allows to observe robust Rabi rotations and to identify efficient coupling to acoustic phonons as the dominating channel of decoherence. The insights gained are crucial for the realization of optical quantum memories based on photon echoes from semiconductor quantum dots.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 205408] Published Thu Nov 10, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Grisard, H. Rose, A. V. Trifonov, R. Reichhardt, D. E. Reiter, M. Reichelt, C. Schneider, M. Kamp, S. Höfling, M. Bayer, T. Meier, and I. A. Akimov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-regulating soliton switching waves in microresonators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.053508</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.053508"/>
        <updated>2022-11-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Heming Wang, Boqiang Shen, Yan Yu, Zhiquan Yuan, Chengying Bao, Warren Jin, Lin Chang, Mark A. Leal, Avi Feshali, Mario Paniccia, John E. Bowers, and Kerry Vahala
The authors study theoretically and experimentally how Kerr frequency combs can be controlled using self-injection locking. The authors show how self-stabilized switching waves supported by microresonators with normal dispersion and feedback can be used to generate frequency combs more efficiently by tuning the pulse duty cycle into regimes that are difficult to access using other methods.

[Phys. Rev. A 106, 053508] Published Thu Nov 10, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heming Wang, Boqiang Shen, Yan Yu, Zhiquan Yuan, Chengying Bao, Warren Jin, Lin Chang, Mark A. Leal, Avi Feshali, Mario Paniccia, John E. Bowers, and Kerry Vahala</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proposal for Detection of the ${0}^{′}$ and ${π}^{′}$ Phases in Quantum-Dot Josephson Junctions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.207701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.207701"/>
        <updated>2022-11-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Minchul Lee, Rosa López, H. Q. Xu, and Gloria Platero
Theoretical proof that the conventional magnetotransport in quantum-dot Josephson junctions in the Kondo regime can be used to detect intermediate phases.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 207701] Published Wed Nov 09, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Minchul Lee, Rosa López, H. Q. Xu, and Gloria Platero</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scaling Description of Creep Flow in Amorphous Solids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.208001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.208001"/>
        <updated>2022-11-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marko Popović, Tom W. J. de Geus, Wencheng Ji, Alberto Rosso, and Matthieu Wyart
Researchers have developed a comprehensive theory of creep flow—a type of flow seen in amorphous solids such as coffee foam.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 208001] Published Wed Nov 09, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marko Popović, Tom W. J. de Geus, Wencheng Ji, Alberto Rosso, and Matthieu Wyart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effective-action model for dynamical scalarization beyond the adiabatic approximation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.104016</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.104016"/>
        <updated>2022-11-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mohammed Khalil, Raissa F. P. Mendes, Néstor Ortiz, and Jan Steinhoff
The authors provide a model for dynamical scalarization, beyond the adiabatic approximation, using effective field theory techniques, demonstrating that the inclusion of post-adiabatic corrections is crucial. The model is agnostic, i.e., independent of a specific theory of gravity and can therefore be used even for alternative gravity theories.

[Phys. Rev. D 106, 104016] Published Wed Nov 09, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mohammed Khalil, Raissa F. P. Mendes, Néstor Ortiz, and Jan Steinhoff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time-resolved measurement of spin excitations in ${\mathrm{Cu}}_{2}{\mathrm{OSeO}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.174409</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.174409"/>
        <updated>2022-11-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. M. Burn, S. L. Zhang, G. van der Laan, and T. Hesjedal
Studying the dynamic behavior of topological spin textures can unlock future low-energy and high-speed spintronics devices. Recently, the synchrotron-based technique of diffractive ferromagnetic resonance (DFMR) was developed, allowing for element-selective dynamic studies of selected, ordered magnetic modes. In this work, the authors reveal by using DFMR how time-dependent magnetization dynamics couple to the complex spin texture in the well-known chiral magnetic system Cu2OSeO3, uncovering dynamical phase compressing that remained previously hidden using other experimental techniques.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 174409] Published Wed Nov 09, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. M. Burn, S. L. Zhang, G. van der Laan, and T. Hesjedal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analytic approach to transport in superconducting junctions with arbitrary carrier density]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.4.043087</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.4.043087"/>
        <updated>2022-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): F. Setiawan and Johannes Hofmann
By developing a general framework for transport across superconducting junctions that goes beyond the standard Andreev approximation, two crucial transport signatures are proposed for s-wave Josephson junctions along the BCS-BEC crossover: negative differential conductance as a signature of unitarity and a complete suppression of multiple-Andreev-reflection-induced current as a hallmark of the splitting point.

[Phys. Rev. Research 4, 043087] Published Tue Nov 08, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>F. Setiawan and Johannes Hofmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Encoding a one-dimensional topological gauge theory in a Raman-coupled Bose-Einstein condensate]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.4.043088</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.4.043088"/>
        <updated>2022-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. S. Chisholm, A. Frölian, E. Neri, R. Ramos, L. Tarruell, and A. Celi
A Raman-coupled Bose-Einstein condensate faithfully realizes the chiral BF theory, a one-dimensional reduction of the celebrated Chern-Simons gauge theory of fractional quantum Hall systems.

[Phys. Rev. Research 4, 043088] Published Tue Nov 08, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. S. Chisholm, A. Frölian, E. Neri, R. Ramos, L. Tarruell, and A. Celi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random-Access Quantum Memory Using Chirped Pulse Phase Encoding]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.12.041014</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.12.041014"/>
        <updated>2022-11-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): James O’Sullivan, Oscar W. Kennedy, Kamanasish Debnath, Joseph Alexander, Christoph W. Zollitsch, Mantas Šimėnas, Akel Hashim, Christopher N. Thomas, Stafford Withington, Irfan Siddiqi, Klaus Mølmer, and John J. L. Morton
A new quantum random-access memory device reads and writes information using a chirped electromagnetic pulse and a superconducting resonator, making it significantly more hardware-efficient than previous devices.

[Phys. Rev. X 12, 041014] Published Mon Nov 07, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James O’Sullivan, Oscar W. Kennedy, Kamanasish Debnath, Joseph Alexander, Christoph W. Zollitsch, Mantas Šimėnas, Akel Hashim, Christopher N. Thomas, Stafford Withington, Irfan Siddiqi, Klaus Mølmer, and John J. L. Morton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Controlling the configuration space topology of mechanical structures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.055002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.055002"/>
        <updated>2022-11-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Berry, David Limberg, M. E. Lee-Trimble, Ryan Hayward, and C. D. Santangelo
Linkages are mechanical assemblies of rods connected by rotating joints that are of both practical and theoretical interest. They can be designed to perform certain motions, and this work describes a method to do so more easily by focusing on perturbations around special configurations called branch points.

[Phys. Rev. E 106, 055002] Published Mon Nov 07, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Berry, David Limberg, M. E. Lee-Trimble, Ryan Hayward, and C. D. Santangelo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimized geometries for cooperative photon storage in an impurity coupled to a two-dimensional atomic array]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.053706</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.053706"/>
        <updated>2022-11-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Samuel Buckley-Bonanno, Stefan Ostermann, Oriol Rubies-Bigorda, Taylor L. Patti, and Susanne F. Yelin
Quantum emitter arrays with embedded impurities offer the ability to control interactions between individual photons and quantum matter. Here, the authors investigate the lifetime of optical excitations in such arrays and reveal the importance of placement.

[Phys. Rev. A 106, 053706] Published Mon Nov 07, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Buckley-Bonanno, Stefan Ostermann, Oriol Rubies-Bigorda, Taylor L. Patti, and Susanne F. Yelin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emergence of Isotropy and Dynamic Scaling in 2D Wave Turbulence in a Homogeneous Bose Gas]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.190402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.190402"/>
        <updated>2022-11-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maciej Gałka, Panagiotis Christodoulou, Martin Gazo, Andrey Karailiev, Nishant Dogra, Julian Schmitt, and Zoran Hadzibabic
The observation of the onset of turbulence in a gas of bosons allows researchers to explore how turbulence comes to life.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 190402] Published Fri Nov 04, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maciej Gałka, Panagiotis Christodoulou, Martin Gazo, Andrey Karailiev, Nishant Dogra, Julian Schmitt, and Zoran Hadzibabic</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Increased Ion Temperature and Neutron Yield Observed in Magnetized Indirectly Driven ${\mathrm{D}}_{2}$-Filled Capsule Implosions on the National Ignition Facility]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.195002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.195002"/>
        <updated>2022-11-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. D. Moody et al.
A magnetic field can significantly boost the performance of a large-scale fusion experiment that may lead to a future source of clean power.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 195002] Published Fri Nov 04, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. D. Moody &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evolution of the cyclotron mass with doping in ${\mathrm{La}}_{2−x}{\mathrm{Sr}}_{x}{\mathrm{CuO}}_{4}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.195110</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.195110"/>
        <updated>2022-11-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Legros, K. W. Post, Prashant Chauhan, D. G. Rickel, Xi He, Xiaotao Xu, Xiaoyan Shi, Ivan Božović, S. A. Crooker, and N. P. Armitage
The recent observation of cyclotron resonance in optimally doped La2−xSrxCuO4 using terahertz spectroscopy in a high magnetic field has opened new possibilities for the study of cuprate superconductors. Here, the authors measured cyclotron resonance from slightly underdoped to highly overdoped samples. The cyclotron mass is monotonically increasing and positive for all dopings and with a magnitude systematically below the heat capacity mass for under and optimally doped samples, while exceeding it for overdoped samples. These results are surprising as photoemission reveals a Lifshitz transition in the middle of the doping range. The sign of the cyclotron mass determined from a finite frequency resonance is, in conventional theories, a topological quantity only sensitive to whether or not the Fermi surface is closed around holes or electrons. These results should provide motivation to investigate the cyclotron resonance in non-Fermi liquids and systems with strong anisotropic scattering.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 195110] Published Fri Nov 04, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Legros, K. W. Post, Prashant Chauhan, D. G. Rickel, Xi He, Xiaotao Xu, Xiaoyan Shi, Ivan Božović, S. A. Crooker, and N. P. Armitage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elastic properties of moiré lattices in epitaxial two-dimensional materials]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L201402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L201402"/>
        <updated>2022-11-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexandre Artaud, Nicolas Rougemaille, Sergio Vlaic, Vincent T. Renard, Nicolae Atodiresei, and Johann Coraux
Two-dimensional (2D) superlattices in conventional semiconductors are rigid. In 2D materials, where they are called moiré patterns, they are flexible so the physical properties depend not only on the super-periodicity but also on the 2D membrane’s topography. A mixed continuous+atomistic theory, treating 2D materials as crystalline elastic membranes, reveals the role of out-of-plane deformations on the ground-state topography. The model’s predictions agree with experimental structural characterizations on model systems (epitaxial graphene and MoS2 on metals) and explain moiré wavelength selection and wrinkling phenomena.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L201402] Published Fri Nov 04, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandre Artaud, Nicolas Rougemaille, Sergio Vlaic, Vincent T. Renard, Nicolae Atodiresei, and Johann Coraux</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adiabatic quantum Zeno dynamics of bosonic atom pairs with large inelastic losses]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.053304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.053304"/>
        <updated>2022-11-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Manel Bosch Aguilera, Alexis Ghermaoui, Rémy Vatré, Raphaël Bouganne, Jérôme Beugnon, and Fabrice Gerbier
The authors study experimentally the non-Hermitian dynamics and dissipative properties of pairs of two-level atoms tightly confined in an optical lattice and driven by a near-resonant laser towards a lossy state. They demonstrate the control of the quantum state of the pairs in the strong dissipation regime by adiabatically preparing them in a loss-protected state, where the dynamics is governed by the quantum Zeno effect.

[Phys. Rev. A 106, 053304] Published Fri Nov 04, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Manel Bosch Aguilera, Alexis Ghermaoui, Rémy Vatré, Raphaël Bouganne, Jérôme Beugnon, and Fabrice Gerbier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sequence of phase transitions in a model of interacting rods]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.L052101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.L052101"/>
        <updated>2022-11-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Juliane U. Klamser, Tridib Sadhu, and Deepak Dhar
This article studies a system of rods pinned on a lattice with only rotational degrees of freedom, using Monte Carlo simulations. The system shows an infinite number of phase transitions as a function of the inverse temperature and the relative size of the rod with respect to the lattice, that can be broadly characterized as either Ising-like or of geometrical origin.

[Phys. Rev. E 106, L052101] Published Thu Nov 03, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Juliane U. Klamser, Tridib Sadhu, and Deepak Dhar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast flavor instability in hypermassive neutron star disk outflows]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.103003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.103003"/>
        <updated>2022-11-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rodrigo Fernández, Sherwood Richers, Nicole Mulyk, and Steven Fahlman
Neutron star mergers are of tremendous astrophysical interest for a variety of reasons that include their role in initiating r-process nucleosynthesis in their ejecta. In this article, the authors tackle the complex influence of extremely rapid neutrino flavor conversion (fast flavor instability - FFI) on ejecta from accretion disks around hypermassive neutron stars (HMNSs) formed in mergers. By studying a wide variety of scenarios, the authors detail the influence of FFI and show that it depends strongly on the lifetime of the HMNS.

[Phys. Rev. D 106, 103003] Published Thu Nov 03, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rodrigo Fernández, Sherwood Richers, Nicole Mulyk, and Steven Fahlman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bubble dynamics in fluids with $N$-body simulations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.103501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.103501"/>
        <updated>2022-11-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marek Lewicki, Ville Vaskonen, and Hardi Veermäe
The authors set up a new method (proof of concept) for studying bubble wall dynamics in first-order cosmological phase transitions based on N-body simulations. The technique goes beyond commonly used perfect fluid descriptions and equilibrium assumptions. This allows e.g. the computation of the terminal bubble wall velocity, a key ingredient for determining the gravitational wave signal created in the cosmological phase transition, based on particle physics properties rather than on phenomenological fluid parameters.

[Phys. Rev. D 106, 103501] Published Thu Nov 03, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marek Lewicki, Ville Vaskonen, and Hardi Veermäe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Many-body theory of phonon-induced spin relaxation and decoherence]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.174404</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.174404"/>
        <updated>2022-11-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jinsoo Park, Yao Luo, Jin-Jian Zhou, and Marco Bernardi
Electron spin decoherence from atomic vibrations (phonons) limits the performance of spin-based devices but is difficult to model quantitatively. Here, the authors present a new theory for addressing this challenge. Their approach unifies the theoretical treatment of two mechanisms – spin scattering off phonons and spin precession altered by phonons – and provides unprecedented microscopic insight into spin motion in materials. This work enables precise predictions for spin relaxation and decoherence in materials, advancing the quest for spin-based quantum technologies.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 174404] Published Thu Nov 03, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jinsoo Park, Yao Luo, Jin-Jian Zhou, and Marco Bernardi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why mercury is a superconductor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L180501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L180501"/>
        <updated>2022-11-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Cesare Tresca, Gianni Profeta, Giovanni Marini, Giovanni B. Bachelet, Antonio Sanna, Matteo Calandra, and Lilia Boeri
In 1911, Kamerlingh Onnes discovered superconductivity, measuring the low-temperature resistivity in mercury. Nowadays, more than 100 years later, many new superconductors have been discovered with higher and higher critical temperatures. Ironically, the exact origin of the superconducting phase in mercury has remained hidden so far. The authors decided to revisit the description of this fascinating material with ab initio techniques, revealing all its intricate physical properties. Despite its apparent simplicity, mercury hides effects that are anything but trivial. Their proper description is a challenging problem and requires advanced computational and theoretical techniques, which have become available only recently.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L180501] Published Thu Nov 03, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cesare Tresca, Gianni Profeta, Giovanni Marini, Giovanni B. Bachelet, Antonio Sanna, Matteo Calandra, and Lilia Boeri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enhanced amplitude for superconductivity due to spectrum-wide wave function criticality in quasiperiodic and power-law random hopping models]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L180503</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L180503"/>
        <updated>2022-11-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xinghai Zhang and Matthew S. Foster
The shape of electron wave functions determines key properties of quantum materials. Very recently, it was found that disorder can turn all wave functions into fractals (“spectrum-wide quantum criticality,” SWQC) in models of topological and strongly correlated superconductors. The implications of SWQC for superconductivity itself remain largely unexplored. Here, the authors show that superconductivity can be strongly enhanced near the SWQC Anderson transition in two one-dimensional models. The study highlights a new potential mechanism for achieving higher transition temperatures via random or structured inhomogeneity.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L180503] Published Thu Nov 03, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xinghai Zhang and Matthew S. Foster</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Single-exciton trapping in an electrostatically defined two-dimensional semiconductor quantum dot]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L201401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L201401"/>
        <updated>2022-11-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Daniel N. Shanks, Fateme Mahdikhanysarvejahany, Michael R. Koehler, David G. Mandrus, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Brian J. LeRoy, and John R. Schaibley
The ability to deterministically trap and control single interlayer excitons in 2D transition metal dichalcogenide heterostructures opens new opportunities to utilize their spin and valley degrees of freedom for quantum information applications. In this work, the authors fabricate a lithographically defined electrostatic exciton trap using a nanopatterned graphene gate. Photoluminescence measurements show discrete excitation power-dependent emission energies, corresponding to different number states of excitons occupying the trap, with the lowest-energy state corresponding a single-exciton population.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L201401] Published Thu Nov 03, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel N. Shanks, Fateme Mahdikhanysarvejahany, Michael R. Koehler, David G. Mandrus, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Brian J. LeRoy, and John R. Schaibley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scalable Quantum Logic Spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.193603</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.193603"/>
        <updated>2022-11-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kaifeng Cui, Jose Valencia, Kevin T. Boyce, Ethan R. Clements, David R. Leibrandt, and David B. Hume
A new precision spectroscopy of forbidden ionic transitions can be scaled to numerous trapped ions without the need to observe their scattered photons directly.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 193603] Published Wed Nov 02, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kaifeng Cui, Jose Valencia, Kevin T. Boyce, Ethan R. Clements, David R. Leibrandt, and David B. Hume</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Machine Learning of Implicit Combinatorial Rules in Mechanical Metamaterials]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.198003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.198003"/>
        <updated>2022-11-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ryan van Mastrigt, Marjolein Dijkstra, Martin van Hecke, and Corentin Coulais
A new tool can determine whether a collection of building blocks will assemble into a mechanically sound structure.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 198003] Published Wed Nov 02, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ryan van Mastrigt, Marjolein Dijkstra, Martin van Hecke, and Corentin Coulais</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Many-body correction to the intrinsic anomalous and spin Hall conductivities]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L201102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L201102"/>
        <updated>2022-11-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Moslem Mir and Saeed H. Abedinpour
Spin-orbit coupling breaks the Galilean invariance in materials, leading to observable many-body corrections to different transport coefficients. Here, the authors study the intrinsic contribution to anomalous Hall and spin Hall conductivities of a magnetic two-dimensional electron liquid with Rashba spin-orbit coupling. They show that both of these responses are strongly affected by electron-electron interaction. The anomalous Hall conductivity is enhanced at low carrier concentrations, while in the same regime, the sign of spin Hall conductivity is reversed.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L201102] Published Wed Nov 02, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Moslem Mir and Saeed H. Abedinpour</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giant Dampinglike-Torque Efficiency in Naturally Oxidized Polycrystalline $\mathrm{Ta}\mathrm{As}$ Thin Films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.054004</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.054004"/>
        <updated>2022-11-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wilson Yanez, Yongxi Ou, Run Xiao, Supriya Ghosh, Jyotirmay Dwivedi, Emma Steinebronn, Anthony Richardella, K. Andre Mkhoyan, and Nitin Samarth
Efficient interconversion between charge and spin is expected in topological quantum materials, and theory predicts high spin Hall conductivity for the Weyl semimetal TaAs, making it an attractive material for spintronics. The authors measure charge-spin conversion in thin films of TaAs and find a large spin Hall conductivity, consistent with calculations—even though the films are polycrystalline, whereas the calculations are for single-crystal material. More surprisingly, oxidation of the films results in very large conversion efficiency, hinting at hidden physics that could be exploited to develop topological spintronic devices with large figures of merit.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 054004] Published Wed Nov 02, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wilson Yanez, Yongxi Ou, Run Xiao, Supriya Ghosh, Jyotirmay Dwivedi, Emma Steinebronn, Anthony Richardella, K. Andre Mkhoyan, and Nitin Samarth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interplay between disorder and collective coherent response: Superradiance and spectral motional narrowing in the time domain]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.053703</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.053703"/>
        <updated>2022-11-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hsing-Ta Chen, Zeyu Zhou, Maxim Sukharev, Joseph E. Subotnik, and Abraham Nitzan
Typically, in molecular ensembles, the fast random modulation of transition frequencies is merely considered to result in molecular dephasing. In contrast, the authors here show that such modulation may actually recover collective superradiant emission.

[Phys. Rev. A 106, 053703] Published Wed Nov 02, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hsing-Ta Chen, Zeyu Zhou, Maxim Sukharev, Joseph E. Subotnik, and Abraham Nitzan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kinematic Signatures of Impulsive Supernova Feedback in Dwarf Galaxies]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.191103</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.191103"/>
        <updated>2022-11-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jan D. Burger, Jesús Zavala, Laura V. Sales, Mark Vogelsberger, Federico Marinacci, and Paul Torrey
A proposed study of dwarf galaxies could give insight into whether dark matter particles interact with each other.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 191103] Published Tue Nov 01, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jan D. Burger, Jesús Zavala, Laura V. Sales, Mark Vogelsberger, Federico Marinacci, and Paul Torrey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetic structure and spin fluctuations in the colossal magnetoresistance ferrimagnet ${\mathrm{Mn}}_{3}{\mathrm{Si}}_{2}{\mathrm{Te}}_{6}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L180402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L180402"/>
        <updated>2022-11-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Feng Ye, Masaaki Matsuda, Zachary Morgan, Todd Sherline, Yifei Ni, Hengdi Zhao, and G. Cao
Characterizing the magnetic structure is crucial to understand the extraordinary colossal magnetoresistance of ferrimagnetic Mn3Si2Te6. This material exhibits orders of magnitude reduction in resistivity when a magnetic polarization is avoided. Using single-crystal neutron diffraction, the authors reveal here the field evolution of the spin configuration. Prominent magnetic diffuse scattering is present and decays slowly well above the transition. The spin correlation lengths agree well with the electrical resistivity, underscoring the role of magnetic fluctuations contributing to the magnetoresistivity near the transition.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L180402] Published Tue Nov 01, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Feng Ye, Masaaki Matsuda, Zachary Morgan, Todd Sherline, Yifei Ni, Hengdi Zhao, and G. Cao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Integer quantum Hall effect and enhanced $g$ factor in quantum-confined ${\mathrm{Cd}}_{3}{\mathrm{As}}_{2}$ films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L201101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L201101"/>
        <updated>2022-11-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Run Xiao, Junyi Zhang, Juan Chamorro, Jinwoong Kim, Tyrel M. McQueen, David Vanderbilt, Morteza Kayyalha, Yi Li, and Nitin Samarth
A concerted experimental and theoretical investigation of Shubnikov–de Haas oscillations and the integer quantum Hall effect in thin films of Cd3As2 leads to a new understanding of the Landau level spectrum in this archetypal Dirac semimetal under strong quantum confinement conditions. Experiments reveal an emerging ν=3 quantum Hall state as the film thickness is reduced, indicating an enhanced spin splitting. This is consistent with tight-binding calculations that show nonmonotonic enhancement of the g factor with increasing quantum confinement.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L201101] Published Tue Nov 01, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Run Xiao, Junyi Zhang, Juan Chamorro, Jinwoong Kim, Tyrel M. McQueen, David Vanderbilt, Morteza Kayyalha, Yi Li, and Nitin Samarth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mass-energy equivalence in gravitationally bound quantum states of the neutron]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.052801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.052801"/>
        <updated>2022-11-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Germain Tobar, Simon Haine, Fabio Costa, and Magdalena Zych
The authors study quantum effects resulting from mass-energy equivalence using ultracold neutrons that are confined gravitationally by considering a quantum correction to the neutron’s mass due to the neutron spin in the presence of an external magnetic field. The authors show that the neutron’s additional weight due to the quantum treatment of mass-energy equivalence will cause a small shift in the neutron’s eigenenergies and eigenstates, which could provide signatures in an interferometric experiment.

[Phys. Rev. A 106, 052801] Published Tue Nov 01, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Germain Tobar, Simon Haine, Fabio Costa, and Magdalena Zych</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dense and Hot QCD at Strong Coupling]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.12.041012</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.12.041012"/>
        <updated>2022-10-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tuna Demircik, Christian Ecker, and Matti Järvinen
Thermodynamic phases governed by the strong nuclear force have been linked together using multiple theoretical tools.

[Phys. Rev. X 12, 041012] Published Mon Oct 31, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tuna Demircik, Christian Ecker, and Matti Järvinen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Constrained Dynamics and Directed Percolation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.190601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.190601"/>
        <updated>2022-10-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aydin Deger, Achilleas Lazarides, and Sthitadhi Roy
Constraining the dynamics in a chaotic system gives rise to a phase transition that belongs to the directed percolation universality class.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 190601] Published Mon Oct 31, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aydin Deger, Achilleas Lazarides, and Sthitadhi Roy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black Hole Solutions as Topological Thermodynamic Defects]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.191101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.191101"/>
        <updated>2022-10-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shao-Wen Wei, Yu-Xiao Liu, and Robert B. Mann
The thermodynamic stability of a black hole is governed by a local topological number.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 191101] Published Mon Oct 31, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shao-Wen Wei, Yu-Xiao Liu, and Robert B. Mann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Expressive power of complex-valued restricted Boltzmann machines for solving nonstoquastic Hamiltonians]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.134437</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.134437"/>
        <updated>2022-10-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chae-Yeun Park and Michael J. Kastoryano
Variational Monte Carlo with neural quantum states is one of the most powerful tools for solving the ground state of quantum many-body Hamiltonians. However, the performance of the method on frustrated Hamiltonians remains significantly worse than that of sign-free Hamiltonians, even though the method itself is free from sum-over alternating signs. Here, the authors systematically study numerical subtleties in restricted Boltzmann machine based variational Monte Carlo for solving Hamiltonians with the sign problem and unveil how quantum phases are related to the numerics.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 134437] Published Mon Oct 31, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chae-Yeun Park and Michael J. Kastoryano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Full configuration interaction quantum Monte Carlo for coupled electron-boson systems and infinite spaces]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.155158</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.155158"/>
        <updated>2022-10-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Robert J. Anderson, Charles J. C. Scott, and George H. Booth
When electrons interact not only with themselves, but also with bosons (phonons or other bosonic quasiparticles), what was previously a “curse of dimensionality” for its computational solution now becomes one of infinite size. To deal with this, the authors adapt here a recent method for its stochastic solution, without requiring truncation of the bosonic occupations, and which allows systematic improvability to exact solutions. They apply this to the paradigmatic Hubbard-Holstein model of local phonons, finding a state-of-the-art solution in the thermodynamic limit, as well as to a novel approach in which long-range collective electronic fluctuations are mapped to bosonic quasiparticles to tackle even long-range interacting problems of purely electronic form.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 155158] Published Mon Oct 31, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert J. Anderson, Charles J. C. Scott, and George H. Booth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-Efficiency Selective Wireless Power Transfer with a Bistable Parity-Time-Symmetric Circuit]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.044076</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.044076"/>
        <updated>2022-10-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hongjian Cui, Zhenya Dong, Han-Joon Kim, Chenhui Li, Weijin Chen, Guoqiang Xu, Cheng-Wei Qiu, and John S. Ho
Wireless power transfer has broad applications in e.g. consumer electronics and electric vehicles. Unfortunately, available methods to transfer power to one specific receiver out of many are inefficient, or rely on complicated tuning schemes. This study uses a bistable parity-time-symmetric circuit to achieve wireless power transfer that is efficient, robust, and selective. The authors show that the bistability provides access to system modes with highly asymmetrical energy distributions, enabling improved efficiency and selectivity. This work could lead to more versatile and energy-efficient wireless charging systems.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 044076] Published Mon Oct 31, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hongjian Cui, Zhenya Dong, Han-Joon Kim, Chenhui Li, Weijin Chen, Guoqiang Xu, Cheng-Wei Qiu, and John S. Ho</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electron-Phonon Interaction and Longitudinal-Transverse Phonon Splitting in Doped Semiconductors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.185902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.185902"/>
        <updated>2022-10-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Francesco Macheda, Paolo Barone, and Francesco Mauri
A first-principles method based on maximally localized Wannier functions predicts the doping dependence of the electron-phonon interaction in semiconductors much more accurately than other state-of-the-art methods.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 185902] Published Fri Oct 28, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Francesco Macheda, Paolo Barone, and Francesco Mauri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fractional Optical Angular Momentum and Multi-Defect-Mediated Mode Renormalization and Orientation Control in Photonic Crystal Microring Resonators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.186101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.186101"/>
        <updated>2022-10-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mingkang Wang, Feng Zhou, Xiyuan Lu, Andrew McClung, Marcelo Davanco, Vladimir A. Aksyuk, and Kartik Srinivasan
A ring-shaped waveguide with a particular pattern of notches can force a light wave to make two round trips before completing an integer number of wave cycles.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 186101] Published Fri Oct 28, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mingkang Wang, Feng Zhou, Xiyuan Lu, Andrew McClung, Marcelo Davanco, Vladimir A. Aksyuk, and Kartik Srinivasan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Complexity emerges in measures of the marking dynamics in football games]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.044308</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.044308"/>
        <updated>2022-10-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Chacoma, O. V. Billoni, and M. N. Kuperman
Network theory can show how successfully a soccer team performs when it’s on the defense.

[Phys. Rev. E 106, 044308] Published Fri Oct 28, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Chacoma, O. V. Billoni, and M. N. Kuperman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Large extrinsic phonon thermal Hall effect from resonant scattering]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.144111</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.144111"/>
        <updated>2022-10-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xiao-Qi Sun, Jing-Yuan Chen, and Steven A. Kivelson
From a symmetry perspective, a magnetic field makes a material chiral and thus leads to a nonzero thermal Hall effect. However, recent experiments on a variety of interesting insulators – including a number of cuprates – have uncovered an unexpectedly large field-induced thermal Hall effect, despite the fact that there are no low-energy charge-carrying excitations, i.e., itinerant electrons. The authors propose here a mechanism of coupling a magnetic field to phonons and producing a thermal Hall response of the requisite magnitude through resonant skew scattering of phonons from a certain class of three-level systems.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 144111] Published Fri Oct 28, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiao-Qi Sun, Jing-Yuan Chen, and Steven A. Kivelson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unconventional Floquet Topological Phases from Quantum Engineering of Band-Inversion Surfaces]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.3.040312</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.3.040312"/>
        <updated>2022-10-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Long Zhang and Xiong-Jun Liu
Using a new approach to access band structures, a systematic and high-precision scheme to realize, manipulate, and detect unconventional Floquet topological phases on quantum simulators is developed.

[PRX Quantum 3, 040312] Published Thu Oct 27, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Long Zhang and Xiong-Jun Liu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Packed Swarms on Dirt: Two-Dimensional Incompressible Flocks with Quenched and Annealed Disorder]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.188004</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.188004"/>
        <updated>2022-10-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Leiming Chen, Chiu Fan Lee, Ananyo Maitra, and John Toner
Predictions indicate that disorder induced by immobile imperfections does not prevent organisms from moving collectively as a group.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 188004] Published Thu Oct 27, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leiming Chen, Chiu Fan Lee, Ananyo Maitra, and John Toner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phase separation and critical size in molecular sorting]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.044412</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.044412"/>
        <updated>2022-10-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Elisa Floris, Andrea Piras, Francesco Saverio Pezzicoli, Marco Zamparo, Luca Dall'Asta, and Andrea Gamba
Cells can produce small vesicles containing specific proteins by concentrating the proteins in a domain, which then detaches from the cell membrane. This work proposes a link between the size of domains that successfully form such vesicles and the critical size for domain growth in the theory of phase separation.

[Phys. Rev. E 106, 044412] Published Thu Oct 27, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elisa Floris, Andrea Piras, Francesco Saverio Pezzicoli, Marco Zamparo, Luca Dall'Asta, and Andrea Gamba</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hydrodynamic theory of two-dimensional incompressible polar active fluids with quenched and annealed disorder]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.044608</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.044608"/>
        <updated>2022-10-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Leiming Chen, Chiu Fan Lee, Ananyo Maitra, and John Toner
Predictions indicate that disorder induced by immobile imperfections does not prevent organisms from moving collectively as a group.

[Phys. Rev. E 106, 044608] Published Thu Oct 27, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leiming Chen, Chiu Fan Lee, Ananyo Maitra, and John Toner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Planckian properties of two-dimensional semiconductor systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.155427</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.155427"/>
        <updated>2022-10-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Seongjin Ahn and Sankar Das Sarma
The low-temperature resistivity and the temperature-dependent inelastic scattering rate of several different doped 2D semiconductor systems are described and discussed from the perspective of the Planckian hypothesis of the scattering rate having an intrinsic fundamental bound of kBT. The Planckian holds for all the systems with the scattering rate never exceeding kBT by more than an order of magnitude either in the experiment or in the theory. In addition, the authors calculate the temperature-dependent electron-electron inelastic scattering rate by obtaining the temperature-dependent self-energy arising from the Coulomb interaction, also finding it to obey the Planckian bound within an order of magnitude at all densities and temperatures. A theory is provided for why such a generalized Planckian bound applies generically.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 155427] Published Thu Oct 27, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Seongjin Ahn and Sankar Das Sarma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hybrid Photonic-Plasmonic Cavity Design for Very Large Purcell Factors at Telecommunication Wavelengths]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.044066</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.044066"/>
        <updated>2022-10-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Angela Barreda, Laura Mercadé, Mario Zapata-Herrera, Javier Aizpurua, and Alejandro Martínez
Hybrid photonic-plasmonic cavities based on nanoparticle-on-a-mirror structures simultaneously provide ultralow mode volume and high Q-factor, and so a very large Purcell factor, which is a key measure of light-matter interaction. Operation of such cavities has been constrained to wavelengths below 1 μm, with the technologically relevant telecom regime remaining elusive. This study describes a hybrid cavity operating at telecom wavelengths. The proposed design leads to extremely large Purcell factors (~107–108), and could impact many different applications, such as molecular optomechanics, bio- and chemosensing, efficient quantum emitters, and enhanced Raman spectroscopy.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 044066] Published Thu Oct 27, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Angela Barreda, Laura Mercadé, Mario Zapata-Herrera, Javier Aizpurua, and Alejandro Martínez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thermodynamics of quantum measurement and Maxwell's demon's arrow of time]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.042221</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.042221"/>
        <updated>2022-10-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kagan Yanik, Bibek Bhandari, Sreenath K. Manikandan, and Andrew N. Jordan
In a single-qubit weak-measurement-based device, one may imagine feedback control as conducted by a quantum Maxwell’s demon. Here, the authors investigate both discrete and continuous measurements in such a device in order to connect work and entropy statistics to the demon’s perceived arrow of time.

[Phys. Rev. A 106, 042221] Published Thu Oct 27, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kagan Yanik, Bibek Bhandari, Sreenath K. Manikandan, and Andrew N. Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Merger and Postmerger of Binary Neutron Stars with a Quark-Hadron Crossover Equation of State]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.181101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.181101"/>
        <updated>2022-10-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yong-Jia Huang, Luca Baiotti, Toru Kojo, Kentaro Takami, Hajime Sotani, Hajime Togashi, Tetsuo Hatsuda, Shigehiro Nagataki, and Yi-Zhong Fan
Simulations indicate that postmerger gravitational waves from coalescing neutron stars could allow researchers to hear the phase transitions between exotic states of matter.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 181101] Published Wed Oct 26, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yong-Jia Huang, Luca Baiotti, Toru Kojo, Kentaro Takami, Hajime Sotani, Hajime Togashi, Tetsuo Hatsuda, Shigehiro Nagataki, and Yi-Zhong Fan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multifractal Conductance Fluctuations in High-Mobility Graphene in the Integer Quantum Hall Regime]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.186802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.186802"/>
        <updated>2022-10-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kazi Rafsanjani Amin, Ramya Nagarajan, Rahul Pandit, and Aveek Bid
Researchers find that a phenomenon called multifractality manifests in the conductance fluctuations of a 2D electron gas as the gas undergoes a topological phase transition.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 186802] Published Wed Oct 26, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kazi Rafsanjani Amin, Ramya Nagarajan, Rahul Pandit, and Aveek Bid</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Freezing phase transition in hard-core lattice gases on the triangular lattice with exclusion up to seventh next-nearest neighbor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.044136</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.044136"/>
        <updated>2022-10-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Asweel Ahmed A. Jaleel, Dipanjan Mandal, Jetin E. Thomas, and R. Rajesh
Hard-core lattice gases are simple models that exhibit a phase transition, and that have applications in various areas of research. This paper uses a Monte Carlo algorithm to study these models with up to seventh neighbor exclusion on a triangular lattice, finding improvements over previous results.

[Phys. Rev. E 106, 044136] Published Wed Oct 26, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Asweel Ahmed A. Jaleel, Dipanjan Mandal, Jetin E. Thomas, and R. Rajesh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetic interactions in AB-stacked kagome lattices: Magnetic structure, symmetry, and duality]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.144433</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.144433"/>
        <updated>2022-10-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Zelenskiy, T. L. Monchesky, M. L. Plumer, and B. W. Southern
Magnetic compounds that combine the effects of geometric frustration and strong spin-orbit coupling (SOC) often host exotic magnetic phases. In many cases, anisotropic lattice-dependent interactions that originate from the SOC significantly reduce the symmetry of the system and constrain the magnetic moments to specific orientations. Using numerical simulations and symmetry analysis, this study demonstrates that, in compounds with the AB-stacked kagome layer structure, the anisotropy gives rise to a large number of duality transformations that provide exact mappings between the properties of distinct magnetic phases.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 144433] Published Wed Oct 26, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Zelenskiy, T. L. Monchesky, M. L. Plumer, and B. W. Southern</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Narrow Optical Transitions in Erbium-Implanted Silicon Waveguides]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.12.041009</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.12.041009"/>
        <updated>2022-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Andreas Gritsch, Lorenz Weiss, Johannes Früh, Stephan Rinner, and Andreas Reiserer
Improved fabrication methods for qubits made from erbium-doped silicon waveguides give these qubits the key prerequisites for becoming a contender for future quantum computers.

[Phys. Rev. X 12, 041009] Published Tue Oct 25, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andreas Gritsch, Lorenz Weiss, Johannes Früh, Stephan Rinner, and Andreas Reiserer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First-Principles Phonon Quasiparticle Theory Applied to a Strongly Anharmonic Halide Perovskite]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.185901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.185901"/>
        <updated>2022-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Terumasa Tadano and Wissam A. Saidi
First principles lattice dynamics theory predicts the thermal conductivity and the lattice structure phase transition of strongly anharmonic crystals much more accurately than conventional theories.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 185901] Published Tue Oct 25, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Terumasa Tadano and Wissam A. Saidi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Field-Deployable Quantum Memory for Quantum Networking]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.044058</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.044058"/>
        <updated>2022-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yang Wang, Alexander N. Craddock, Rourke Sekelsky, Mael Flament, and Mehdi Namazi
The quantum Internet will support paradigm shifts in cybersecurity, distributed quantum computing, and sensing. Its realization, however, has been held back by the lack of practical technologies to enable deployment and scalability. To date, most demonstrations have been limited to laboratories with expensive resources such as cryogenic and vacuum systems. The authors overcome this challenge by designing a field-deployable quantum memory, based on warm atomic vapor, that demonstrates high-fidelity performance and robustness to environmental noise. This represents a key technology for distributing quantum entanglement across large-scale quantum networks.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 044058] Published Tue Oct 25, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yang Wang, Alexander N. Craddock, Rourke Sekelsky, Mael Flament, and Mehdi Namazi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Gd-based magnetic compound ${\mathrm{GdPt}}_{2}\mathrm{B}$ with a chiral crystal structure]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.6.104412</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.6.104412"/>
        <updated>2022-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yoshiki J. Sato, Hikari Manako, Yoshiya Homma, Dexin Li, Ryuji Okazaki, and Dai Aoki
Chirality, a fundamental property of symmetry, can produce unique magnetic and electronic properties in materials. The discovery of new magnetic compounds with “chirality” leads to the exploration of exotic physical phenomena in chiral crystals. Here, the authors report the discovery and single-crystal growth of a novel Gd-based magnetic compound GdPt2B with a chiral crystal structure. GdPt2B exhibits a magnetic transition at 87 K and shows magnetic properties arising from the competition between ferromagnetic and Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya interactions. These results pave the way for demonstrating novel spin textures, topological electronic states, and exotic transport phenomena in the novel rare-earth-based chiral crystal.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 6, 104412] Published Mon Oct 24, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yoshiki J. Sato, Hikari Manako, Yoshiya Homma, Dexin Li, Ryuji Okazaki, and Dai Aoki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atom Interferometry with Floquet Atom Optics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.183202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.183202"/>
        <updated>2022-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Thomas Wilkason, Megan Nantel, Jan Rudolph, Yijun Jiang (姜一君), Benjamin E. Garber, Hunter Swan, Samuel P. Carman, Mahiro Abe, and Jason M. Hogan
The engineering of so-called Floquet states leads to almost-perfect atom-optics elements for matter-wave interferometers—which could boost these devices’ ability to probe new physics.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 183202] Published Mon Oct 24, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Wilkason, Megan Nantel, Jan Rudolph, Yijun Jiang (姜一君), Benjamin E. Garber, Hunter Swan, Samuel P. Carman, Mahiro Abe, and Jason M. Hogan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First constraints on axionlike particles from Galactic sub-PeV gamma rays]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.083020</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.083020"/>
        <updated>2022-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. Eckner and F. Calore
The authors model the latest sub-PeV Galactic diffuse emission from gamma-ray data to assess a hitherto unexplored region of parameter space for Axion-like Particles (ALPs). They constrain the photon-ALP coupling constant for ALP masses ≤2×10−7 eV, further closing the mass gap to limits from the Axion Dark Matter Experiment (ADMX).

[Phys. Rev. D 106, 083020] Published Mon Oct 24, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. Eckner and F. Calore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chiral magnetic structure of spin-ladder multiferroic ${\mathrm{BaFe}}_{2}{\mathrm{Se}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.134429</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.134429"/>
        <updated>2022-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): W. G. Zheng, V. Balédent, E. Ressouche, V. Petricek, D. Bounoua, P. Bourges, Y. Sidis, A. Forget, D. Colson, and P. Foury-Leylekian
A complex magnetic structure with specific symmetry properties is a relevant ingredient for magnetoelectric multiferroicity. In BaFe2Se3, a member of the Fe spin-ladder family of pressure-induced superconductors, the authors reveal this complexity. Using polarized and unpolarized single-crystal neutron diffraction, they evidence a chiral, umbrella-like magnetic order made of blocks of quasiferromagnetic spins, antiferromagnetically ordered along the ladder. Such accurate information on the magnetism will help to understand the magnetoelectric coupling in this family and its puzzling phase diagram.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 134429] Published Mon Oct 24, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>W. G. Zheng, V. Balédent, E. Ressouche, V. Petricek, D. Bounoua, P. Bourges, Y. Sidis, A. Forget, D. Colson, and P. Foury-Leylekian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Laser-induced terahertz spin transport in magnetic nanostructures arises from the same force as ultrafast demagnetization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.144427</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.144427"/>
        <updated>2022-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Reza Rouzegar, Liane Brandt, Lukáš Nádvorník, David A. Reiss, Alexander L. Chekhov, Oliver Gueckstock, Chihun In, Martin Wolf, Tom S. Seifert, Piet W. Brouwer, Georg Woltersdorf, and Tobias Kampfrath
The authors observe here that (a) laser-induced ultrafast demagnetization (UDM) of a metallic ferromagnet F has the same time evolution as (b) terahertz spin transport (TST) from F into an adjacent normal metal N. They conclude that UDM in F and TST in F|N samples are driven by the same force: (c) a generalized spin voltage, i.e., an excess magnetization of F. One can now apply the vast knowledge of UDM to TST to significantly increase spin-current amplitudes for ultrafast spintronic applications.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 144427] Published Mon Oct 24, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reza Rouzegar, Liane Brandt, Lukáš Nádvorník, David A. Reiss, Alexander L. Chekhov, Oliver Gueckstock, Chihun In, Martin Wolf, Tom S. Seifert, Piet W. Brouwer, Georg Woltersdorf, and Tobias Kampfrath</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flat bands and band-touching from real-space topology in hyperbolic lattices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.155146</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.155146"/>
        <updated>2022-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tomáš Bzdušek and Joseph Maciejko
Hopping models on geometrically frustrated lattices, such as the kagome and dice lattices, exhibit perfectly flat energy bands that result from eigenstates localized along contractible and/or noncontractible real-space loops. The degeneracy of such flat bands has been understood from an interplay of real-space topology and momentum-space band theory. Here, the authors generalize this paradigm to frustrated hyperbolic lattices, including those realized in recent circuit quantum electrodynamics experiments. They show that hyperbolic flat-band characteristics can similarly be understood by combining real-space topology arguments with the recently developed hyperbolic band theory.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 155146] Published Mon Oct 24, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tomáš Bzdušek and Joseph Maciejko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accelerated three-dimensional quasistatic particle-in-cell code]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.25.104603</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.25.104603"/>
        <updated>2022-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tianhong Wang, Vladimir Khudik, Jihoon Kim, and Gennady Shvets
A new three-dimensional quasistatic particle-in-cell code for laser wakefield and plasma wakefield accelerators.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 25, 104603] Published Mon Oct 24, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tianhong Wang, Vladimir Khudik, Jihoon Kim, and Gennady Shvets</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>