<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-10-03T00:44:28.962Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-10-03T00:44:28.962Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unsteady Inherent Convective Mixing in Thermal-Energy-Storage Systems during Standby Periods]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXEnergy.2.043001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXEnergy.2.043001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Henning Otto, Clemens Naumann, Christian Odenthal, and Christian Cierpka
Experimental studies of the fluid dynamics of small- and large-scale stratified-thermal-storage tanks demonstrate that inherent flow near the tank sidewalls increases mixing of the hot and cold fluid layers and decreases the energy storage efficiency.

[PRX Energy 2, 043001] Published Mon Oct 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Henning Otto, Clemens Naumann, Christian Odenthal, and Christian Cierpka</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Energy dissipation of a carbon monoxide molecule manipulated using a metallic tip on copper surfaces]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165401"/>
        <updated>2023-10-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Norio Okabayashi, Thomas Frederiksen, Alexander Liebig, and Franz J. Giessibl
The manipulation process of a single CO molecule on a copper single crystal by a metallic tip is studied here using noncontact atomic force microscopy, with dissipation energy detection, vibrational spectroscopy, and density functional theory calculations. The manipulation of the CO molecule between the two adjacent top sites is found to occur via an intermediate state of CO on the bridging site. Furthermore, this finding allows for the interpretation of static and dynamic friction at the atomic scale.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 165401] Published Mon Oct 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Norio Okabayashi, Thomas Frederiksen, Alexander Liebig, and Franz J. Giessibl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Efficient and quantum-adaptive machine learning with fermion neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044002"/>
        <updated>2023-10-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pei-Lin Zheng, Jia-Bao Wang, and Yi Zhang
Application of machine learning to quantum data and models has been held back by the lack of adaptability and efficiency in present-day neural networks. This study proposes fermion neural networks for quantum-adaptive machine learning with direct applications to complex quantum systems, and offers in situ analysis without preprocessing or presumption. An efficient optimization comparable to back propagation is established, enabling competitive performance in challenging machine-learning benchmarks. Fermion neural networks’ quantum properties, such as entanglement and correlation, also bring various advantages and insights.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 044002] Published Mon Oct 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pei-Lin Zheng, Jia-Bao Wang, and Yi Zhang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long-Lived Squeezed Ground States in a Quantum Spin Ensemble]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.133402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.133402"/>
        <updated>2023-09-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lin Xin, Maryrose Barrios, Julia T. Cohen, and Michael S. Chapman
Spin squeezed ground states of a Bose-Einstein condensate are achieved by a shortcut to adiabaticity involving Hamiltonian tuning.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 133402] Published Fri Sep 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lin Xin, Maryrose Barrios, Julia T. Cohen, and Michael S. Chapman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamical Franz-Keldysh Effect in Diamond in the Deep Ultraviolet Probed by Transient Absorption and Dispersion Spectroscopy Using a Miniature Beamline]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.136902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.136902"/>
        <updated>2023-09-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jan Reislöhner, Xiao Chen, Doyeong Kim, Silvana Botti, and Adrian N. Pfeiffer
By using a pair of offset beams, researchers are able to generate femtosecond UV pulses that can be aimed directly into a target as a spectroscopic probe.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 136902] Published Fri Sep 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jan Reislöhner, Xiao Chen, Doyeong Kim, Silvana Botti, and Adrian N. Pfeiffer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thermoelectric signatures of order-parameter symmetries in iron-based superconducting tunnel junctions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L100511</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L100511"/>
        <updated>2023-09-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Claudio Guarcello, Alessandro Braggio, Francesco Giazotto, and Roberta Citro
The authors suggest here how to unveil the symmetry of the order parameter in iron-based superconductors (FeSCs) via thermoelectricity: in the quest to unveil their specific symmetry, a groundbreaking avenue emerges. Harnessing the power of linear thermoelectric effects in low-temperature tunnel junctions with FeSCs, a novel window into the world of superconducting order parameters is opened. Dive into the realm of unconventional coupling states and discover how thermoelectric measurements can unlock the hidden complexities of Fe-based systems, with implications spanning from quantum technologies to energy harvesting. Explore the untapped potential of thermoelectricity in deciphering the puzzles of quantum materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L100511] Published Fri Sep 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claudio Guarcello, Alessandro Braggio, Francesco Giazotto, and Roberta Citro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Design and demonstration of low current density dc septum magnet]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.092401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.092401"/>
        <updated>2023-09-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hiroshi Yamaguchi, Tsutomu Taniuchi, Kenji Fukami, Yasuhiro Takemura, Tsuyoshi Aoki, Shiro Takano, and Takahiro Watanabe
A novel topology decreases the current density and power consumption of dc septum magnets.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 26, 092401] Published Fri Sep 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hiroshi Yamaguchi, Tsutomu Taniuchi, Kenji Fukami, Yasuhiro Takemura, Tsuyoshi Aoki, Shiro Takano, and Takahiro Watanabe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optical stimulated-Raman sideband spectroscopy of a single $^{9}\mathrm{Be}^{+}$ ion in a Penning trap]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033226</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033226"/>
        <updated>2023-09-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Juan M. Cornejo, Johannes Brombacher, Julia A. Coenders, Moritz von Boehn, Teresa Meiners, Malte Niemann, Stefan Ulmer, and Christian Ospelkaus
A sideband spectroscopy of a single beryllium ion in a Penning trap is demonstrated, finding a temperature of (3.1 ± 0.4) mK. This is a key step for ground-state cooling, so that motional degrees of freedom in Penning traps can be manipulated at the single-quantum level for quantum logic applications and precision measurements.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 033226] Published Thu Sep 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Juan M. Cornejo, Johannes Brombacher, Julia A. Coenders, Moritz von Boehn, Teresa Meiners, Malte Niemann, Stefan Ulmer, and Christian Ospelkaus</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hamiltonian Ratchet for Matter-Wave Transport]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.133401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.133401"/>
        <updated>2023-09-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. Dupont, L. Gabardos, F. Arrouas, N. Ombredane, J. Billy, B. Peaudecerf, and D. Guéry-Odelin
Researchers have turned an optical lattice into a ratchet that moves atoms from one site to the next.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 133401] Published Thu Sep 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Dupont, L. Gabardos, F. Arrouas, N. Ombredane, J. Billy, B. Peaudecerf, and D. Guéry-Odelin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental and numerical investigations on rotor noise in axial descending flight]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.094803</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.094803"/>
        <updated>2023-09-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuhong Li, Xiangtian Li, Han Wu, Peng Zhou, Xin Zhang, and Siyang Zhong
We investigate the aerodynamic and aeroacoustic characteristics of a small-scale drone rotor operating in axial descending flight. The integrated aerodynamic forces and the far-field noise are measured by wind tunnel experiments. Then, near-field flow structures and corresponding noise source analysis are presented based on computational aeroacoustics (CAA) simulations. We found the unique acoustic feature of descending flight is the haystacking-like spectral humps, possibly caused by the interaction between the blade leading edge and the rotor wake.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 094803] Published Thu Sep 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuhong Li, Xiangtian Li, Han Wu, Peng Zhou, Xin Zhang, and Siyang Zhong</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How well do we know the primordial black hole abundance: The crucial role of nonlinearities when approaching the horizon]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.063531</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.063531"/>
        <updated>2023-09-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Valerio De Luca, Alex Kehagias, and Antonio Riotto
Recent pulsar timing array data suggest the presence of stochastic gravitational waves, implying a significant amplitude in curvature perturbations and thus a large abundance of primordial black holes (PBH). The latter is at odds with the observed constraints on the PBH abundance. The authors scrutinize in detail the standard calculation and approximations in determining the PBH abundance and point out several uncertainties, concluding that the PBH abundance is likely much smaller than what is the current consensus.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 063531] Published Thu Sep 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Valerio De Luca, Alex Kehagias, and Antonio Riotto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tuning Arrays with Rays: Physics-Informed Tuning of Quantum Dot Charge States]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034067</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034067"/>
        <updated>2023-09-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Joshua Ziegler, Florian Luthi, Mick Ramsey, Felix Borjans, Guoji Zheng, and Justyna P. Zwolak
Many methods to automatically tune silicon spin qubits are limited by reliability and data efficiency, which makes them less likely to be scalable. The authors demonstrate a reliable, efficient, physics-informed tuning algorithm (PIT) for navigating to a target charge configuration⏤a prerequisite to forming qubits. This tuning method combines machine learning and physical intuition with an algorithm that leverages one-dimensional scans (rays) and conventional peak-finding to navigate from a coarse, unknown device state to a desired charge occupation efficiently and effectively. PIT enables the transformation of an uncalibrated circuit to a functioning quantum processor.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 034067] Published Thu Sep 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joshua Ziegler, Florian Luthi, Mick Ramsey, Felix Borjans, Guoji Zheng, and Justyna P. Zwolak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of Integer and Fractional Quantum Anomalous Hall Effects in Twisted Bilayer ${\mathrm{MoTe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031037</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031037"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fan Xu, Zheng Sun, Tongtong Jia, Chang Liu, Cheng Xu, Chushan Li, Yu Gu, Kenji Watanabe, Takashi Taniguchi, Bingbing Tong, Jinfeng Jia, Zhiwen Shi, Shengwei Jiang, Yang Zhang, Xiaoxue Liu, and Tingxin Li
Direct evidence of the integer and fractional quantum anomalous Hall effects in twisted bilayer MoTe2 paves the way for studies of fractionally charged excitations at zero magnetic field in semiconductor moiré materials.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 031037] Published Wed Sep 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fan Xu, Zheng Sun, Tongtong Jia, Chang Liu, Cheng Xu, Chushan Li, Yu Gu, Kenji Watanabe, Takashi Taniguchi, Bingbing Tong, Jinfeng Jia, Zhiwen Shi, Shengwei Jiang, Yang Zhang, Xiaoxue Liu, and Tingxin Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing complex stacking in a layered material via electron-nuclear quadrupolar coupling]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.L091001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.L091001"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Li Cheng, Linpeng Nie, Xuanyu Long, Li Liang, Dan Zhao, Jian Li, Zheng Liu, Tao Wu, Xianhui Chen, Wenhui Duan, and Xiaolong Zou
The combination of nuclear magnetic resonance with first-principles calculations uncovers the stacking patterns of layers of a quantum material—information that could enable a deeper understanding of the material’s behavior.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, L091001] Published Wed Sep 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Li Cheng, Linpeng Nie, Xuanyu Long, Li Liang, Dan Zhao, Jian Li, Zheng Liu, Tao Wu, Xianhui Chen, Wenhui Duan, and Xiaolong Zou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zero-Field Composite Fermi Liquid in Twisted Semiconductor Bilayers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.136501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.136501"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hart Goldman, Aidan P. Reddy, Nisarga Paul, and Liang Fu
Certain twisted semiconductor bilayers are predicted to host a Fermi liquid of composite fermions—remarkably, without an applied magnetic field.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 136501] Published Wed Sep 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hart Goldman, Aidan P. Reddy, Nisarga Paul, and Liang Fu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Composite Fermi Liquid at Zero Magnetic Field in Twisted ${\mathrm{MoTe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.136502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.136502"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Junkai Dong, Jie Wang, Patrick J. Ledwith, Ashvin Vishwanath, and Daniel E. Parker
Certain twisted semiconductor bilayers are predicted to host a Fermi liquid of composite fermions—remarkably, without an applied magnetic field.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 136502] Published Wed Sep 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Junkai Dong, Jie Wang, Patrick J. Ledwith, Ashvin Vishwanath, and Daniel E. Parker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drafting of two passive swimmer scale models for open-water races]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.094802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.094802"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): B. Bolon, C. Pretot, C. Clanet, F. Larrarte, and R. Carmigniani
We examined interactions in water channels between swimmer-shaped objects moving at different speeds. Results showed that the ideal place for drafting is at the hip of a neighboring swimmer or just behind a lead swimmer. The former reduces drag by 30% and the latter reduces drag by 40%. Results were confirmed by CFD simulations.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 094802] Published Wed Sep 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>B. Bolon, C. Pretot, C. Clanet, F. Larrarte, and R. Carmigniani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gravitational lensing effect on cosmic birefringence]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.063525</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.063525"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fumihiro Naokawa and Toshiya Namikawa
This paper takes into account the effect of Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) gravitational lensing on the Cosmic Birefringence linear polarization rotation angle. It thus paves the way to more accurate interpretation of future-mission data that will seek signatures of Axion-like Particles.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 063525] Published Wed Sep 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fumihiro Naokawa and Toshiya Namikawa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Semiconductor-Quantum-Dot Modulator for Cryogenic Operation of Quantum Circuitry]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034066</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034066"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. R. Hogg, M.G. House, P. Pakkiam, and M.Y. Simmons
Quantum computing devices have the potential to solve problems that are beyond even the most powerful modern supercomputers. Most quantum hardware operates at temperatures near absolute zero, but controlling a quantum computer at cryogenic temperatures using signals propagating from room temperature becomes infeasible for large-scale processors. The authors explore a device that allows control signals to be generated on-chip at cryogenic temperatures, potentially mitigating this cryogenic bottleneck. Their device is fabricated in silicon using established technologies for quantum processors, providing a pathway towards a hybrid quantum-classical integrated circuit.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 034066] Published Wed Sep 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. R. Hogg, M.G. House, P. Pakkiam, and M.Y. Simmons</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bose Polaron Interactions in a Cavity-Coupled Monolayer Semiconductor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031036</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031036"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Li Bing Tan, Oriana K. Diessel, Alexander Popert, Richard Schmidt, Atac Imamoglu, and Martin Kroner
Resonant excitation of a thin-film semiconductor leads to impurities that attract rather than repel each other, providing a possible tool for manipulating superconductivity.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 031036] Published Tue Sep 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Li Bing Tan, Oriana K. Diessel, Alexander Popert, Richard Schmidt, Atac Imamoglu, and Martin Kroner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of New ${\mathrm{Ω}}_{c}^{0}$ States Decaying to the ${\mathrm{Ξ}}_{c}^{+}{K}^{−}$ Final State]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.131902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.131902"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Aaij et al. (LHCb Collaboration)
A precise measurement finds two new Ωc0 baryons, in addition to confirming the existence of five previously observed Ωc0 baryons.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 131902] Published Tue Sep 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Aaij &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHCb Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Constraints on the superconducting state of ${\text{Sr}}_{2}{\text{RuO}}_{4}$ from elastocaloric measurements]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.094516</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.094516"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Grgur Palle, Clifford Hicks, Roser Valentí, Zhenhai Hu, You-Sheng Li, Andreas Rost, Michael Nicklas, Andrew P. Mackenzie, and Jörg Schmalian
In the longstanding quest to determine the symmetry of the superconducting state of Sr2RuO4, this paper exploits recent elastocaloric experiments to narrow down the possibilities down to a handful of options. By analyzing the elastocaloric data, the authors show that a normal-state maximum in the entropy becomes a minimum in the superconducting state. Through modeling of the associated Lifshitz transition, they extract information about the momentum-space structure of the pairing gap function, yielding constraints on the viable pairing states.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 094516] Published Tue Sep 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grgur Palle, Clifford Hicks, Roser Valentí, Zhenhai Hu, You-Sheng Li, Andreas Rost, Michael Nicklas, Andrew P. Mackenzie, and Jörg Schmalian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep thermalization in constrained quantum systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.104317</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.104317"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tanmay Bhore, Jean-Yves Desaules, and Zlatko Papić
Generic quantum systems thermalize as entanglement builds up between a subsystem and its complement. Performing measurements on a complementary subsystem, however, can reveal finer nuances in the system’s ability to thermalize. The authors show here that systems that look ‘thermal’ under the lens of the Eigenstate Thermalization Hypothesis (ETH) can be highly ‘nonthermal’ when probed deeper. They illustrate this finding on several constrained models that describe slow relaxation in quantum glasses and quantum many-body scars in Rydberg atom arrays.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 104317] Published Tue Sep 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tanmay Bhore, Jean-Yves Desaules, and Zlatko Papić</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interface-enhanced room-temperature Curie temperature in $\mathrm{CrP}{\mathrm{S}}_{4}\text{/}\text{graphene}$ van der Waals heterostructure]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L100406</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L100406"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wenxuan Zhu, Cheng Song, Lei Han, Hua Bai, Chong Chen, and Feng Pan
The authors experimentally show here that the Curie temperature of van der Waals CrPS4 is elevated from 40 K up to room temperature by the interfacial effect from graphene. The compatible Fermi level between CrPS4 and graphene enables sufficient interfacial charge transfer across their atomically fine interface, leading to promoted exchange coupling and higher Curie temperature of CrPS4 without the participation of strong spin-orbit coupling. The enhanced magnetism of CrPS4 further induces room-temperature exchange splitting in graphene by the magnetic proximity effect.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L100406] Published Tue Sep 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wenxuan Zhu, Cheng Song, Lei Han, Hua Bai, Chong Chen, and Feng Pan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum Wigner molecules in moiré materials]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L121411</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L121411"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Constantine Yannouleas and Uzi Landman
Quantum Wigner molecules (WMs) in strongly interacting few-body fermionic moiré quantum dots in twisted bilayers of transition metal dichalcogenide (TMD) materials are uncovered via full configuration interaction calculations, going beyond the Aufbau principle of natural atoms and Hubbard modeling. Nested polygonal sliding rings of localized fermions, hidden in the exact particle densities, are revealed through wavefunction correlation analysis [see (3,9) and (1,6,10) electron WMs in 2D semiconductors], broadening the WM portfolio to include the TMD trilobal symmetry as an added resource in twistronics, and providing benchmarks for AI-based many-body computations.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L121411] Published Tue Sep 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Constantine Yannouleas and Uzi Landman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Static Black Binaries in de Sitter Space]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.131401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.131401"/>
        <updated>2023-09-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Óscar J. C. Dias, Gary W. Gibbons, Jorge E. Santos, and Benson Way
Black holes may be less unique than previously thought, as the expansion due to a cosmological constant can hold apart a pair of holes and allow them to mimic a single black hole.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 131401] Published Mon Sep 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Óscar J. C. Dias, Gary W. Gibbons, Jorge E. Santos, and Benson Way</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gallium neutrino absorption cross section and its uncertainty]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.035502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.035502"/>
        <updated>2023-09-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. R. Elliott, V. N. Gavrin, W. C. Haxton, T. V. Ibragimova, and E. J. Rule
The 71Ga radiochemical experiments provided the first constraint on the flux of low-energy electron neutrinos coming from the Sun. Crucial neutrino calibration experiments, however, using intense β-decay sources, yielded rates below that predicted by theory. A recent effort to check the “gallium anomaly” using a more intense source exacerbated the discrepancy. This paper carefully reexamines the nuclear physics of neutrino absorption on 71Ga, slightly reducing but not eliminating the puzzling anomaly.

[Phys. Rev. C 108, 035502] Published Mon Sep 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. R. Elliott, V. N. Gavrin, W. C. Haxton, T. V. Ibragimova, and E. J. Rule</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phase diagram of the $\mathrm{SU}\text{(}N\text{)}$ antiferromagnet of spin $S$ on a square lattice]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115151</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115151"/>
        <updated>2023-09-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jonas Schwab, Francesco Parisen Toldin, and Fakher F. Assaad
Spin systems are a fundamental concept in condensed matter and statistical physics. Here, the authors provide the very first computation of the spin-S SU(N) antiferromagnet in a representation amenable to negative sign free fermion Monte Carlo simulations. They offer a numerical proof of the seminal works of Read and Sachdev. It highlights the close connection between topology and the melting of the quantum antiferromagnet, with the Berry phase explaining the various states observed in the vicinity of the quantum antiferromagnet.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 115151] Published Mon Sep 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonas Schwab, Francesco Parisen Toldin, and Fakher F. Assaad</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raman Probing the Local Ultrastrong Coupling of Vibrational Plasmon Polaritons on Metallic Gratings]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.126902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.126902"/>
        <updated>2023-09-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rakesh Arul, Kishan Menghrajani, Marie S. Rider, Rohit Chikkaraddy, William L. Barnes, and Jeremy J. Baumberg
Using a metallic grating and infrared light, researchers have uncovered a light–matter coupling regime where the local coupling strength can be 3.5 times higher than the global average for the material.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 126902] Published Fri Sep 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rakesh Arul, Kishan Menghrajani, Marie S. Rider, Rohit Chikkaraddy, William L. Barnes, and Jeremy J. Baumberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological Metadefects: Tangles of Dislocations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.128101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.128101"/>
        <updated>2023-09-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pawel Pieranski, Mehdi Zeghal, Maria Helena Godinho, Patrick Judeinstein, Rémi Bouffet-Klein, Bastien Liagre, and Nicodème Rouger
Two or more linear defects can twist around one another to form an entity that may affect the properties of a material.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 128101] Published Fri Sep 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pawel Pieranski, Mehdi Zeghal, Maria Helena Godinho, Patrick Judeinstein, Rémi Bouffet-Klein, Bastien Liagre, and Nicodème Rouger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hexadecapole axial collectivity in the rare earth region: A beyond-mean-field study]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.034312</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.034312"/>
        <updated>2023-09-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. V. Nithish Kumar and L. M. Robledo
Understanding the interplay between the intrinsic shape of nuclei and the dynamics of their low-lying collective states is one of the most pressing challenges in contemporary nuclear structure physics. Within the framework of the generator coordinate method with a Gogny interaction, this paper highlights the important role of hexadecapole deformation in several isotopes of the rare earth region. These features could also have an impact on the evaluation of neutrinoless double-β decay nuclear matrix elements and on heavy ion collision dynamics. The study highlights that the physics touched by considering the hexadecapole degree of freedom is not trivial, and its study is worth further consideration.

[Phys. Rev. C 108, 034312] Published Fri Sep 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. V. Nithish Kumar and L. M. Robledo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electromagnetically-induced-transparency spectra of Rydberg atoms dressed with dual-tone radio-frequency fields]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.033712</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.033712"/>
        <updated>2023-09-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maitreyi Jayaseelan, Andrew P. Rotunno, Nikunjkumar Prajapati, Samuel Berweger, Alexandra B. Artusio-Glimpse, Matthew T. Simons, and Christopher L. Holloway
Rydberg atoms driven by radio-frequency (rf) fields can be used as very sensitive electric-field detectors. Here, the authors extend this concept to dual-frequency rf fields, and show that their theoretical modeling and experimental results match.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 033712] Published Fri Sep 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maitreyi Jayaseelan, Andrew P. Rotunno, Nikunjkumar Prajapati, Samuel Berweger, Alexandra B. Artusio-Glimpse, Matthew T. Simons, and Christopher L. Holloway</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Spinning Black Holes Balanced by Their Synchronized Scalar Hair]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.121401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.121401"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Carlos A. R. Herdeiro and Eugen Radu
When general relativity is coupled to bosonic matter, two spinning black holes can in principle form a stable molecule with quantum effects balancing gravitational effects.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 121401] Published Thu Sep 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carlos A. R. Herdeiro and Eugen Radu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gravitational-Wave Phasing of Quasicircular Compact Binary Systems to the Fourth-and-a-Half Post-Newtonian Order]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.121402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.121402"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Luc Blanchet, Guillaume Faye, Quentin Henry, François Larrouturou, and David Trestini
A collective effort involving various theoretical frameworks results in the successful gravitational wave phasing of nonspinning compact binary systems on quasicircular orbits up to the 4.5 post-Newtonian order.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 121402] Published Thu Sep 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luc Blanchet, Guillaume Faye, Quentin Henry, François Larrouturou, and David Trestini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Isotopic Control of the Boron-Vacancy Spin Defect in Hexagonal Boron Nitride]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.126901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.126901"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Clua-Provost, A. Durand, Z. Mu, T. Rastoin, J. Fraunié, E. Janzen, H. Schutte, J. H. Edgar, G. Seine, A. Claverie, X. Marie, C. Robert, B. Gil, G. Cassabois, and V. Jacques
Engineered purification of certain hBN crystals may provide an optimal host material for boron-vacancy spin defects in quantum technology.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 126901] Published Thu Sep 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Clua-Provost, A. Durand, Z. Mu, T. Rastoin, J. Fraunié, E. Janzen, H. Schutte, J. H. Edgar, G. Seine, A. Claverie, X. Marie, C. Robert, B. Gil, G. Cassabois, and V. Jacques</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Packing spheres in high dimensions with moderate computational effort]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.034117</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.034117"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Veit Elser
An algorithm originally developed for imaging generates useful data for a problem in pure mathematics.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 034117] Published Thu Sep 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Veit Elser</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesoscopic critical fluctuations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.034212</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.034212"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Saikat Banerjee and Nikolai A. Sinitsyn
A system can be made to show critical behavior in a mesoscopic region by introducing a smooth spatial variation of a control parameter around its critical value. The authors investigate this situation using a minimal model based on the Ginzburg-Landau effective free-energy approach.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 034212] Published Thu Sep 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Saikat Banerjee and Nikolai A. Sinitsyn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gravitational-wave flux and quadrupole modes from quasicircular nonspinning compact binaries to the fourth post-Newtonian order]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.064041</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.064041"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Luc Blanchet, Guillaume Faye, Quentin Henry, François Larrouturou, and David Trestini
A collective effort involving various theoretical frameworks results in the successful gravitational wave phasing of nonspinning compact binary systems on quasicircular orbits up to the 4.5 post-Newtonian order.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 064041] Published Thu Sep 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luc Blanchet, Guillaume Faye, Quentin Henry, François Larrouturou, and David Trestini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis of a Skyrme energy density functional with deep learning]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.034311</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.034311"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. Hizawa, K. Hagino, and K. Yoshida
Adapting a technique recently developed in atomic electron systems to nuclear physics, the authors employ a deep-learning method to analyze a Skyrme energy density functional (Skyrme-EDF) with the goal to construct an orbital-free functional that depends only on the particle density distribution. In a first step they compute the energy and particle densities of a nucleus using the Skyrme Kohn-Sham + Bardeen-Cooper-Schrieffer method. With those sets of data and a deep-learning approach they then train an orbital-free functional. When applied to the 24Mg nucleus, the newly constructed functional successfully reproduces the binding energy of the original Skyrme-EDF, with an accuracy of about 40 keV. The significant computational advantage compared to traditional EDF approaches promises useful alternatives for future applications such as for calculating more complex nuclear shapes in heavy and superheavy nuclei.

[Phys. Rev. C 108, 034311] Published Thu Sep 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Hizawa, K. Hagino, and K. Yoshida</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robust intralayer antiferromagnetism and tricriticality in the van der Waals compound $\mathrm{V}{\mathrm{Br}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.104416</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.104416"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dávid Hovančík, Marie Kratochvílová, Tetiana Haidamak, Petr Doležal, Karel Carva, Anežka Bendová, Jan Prokleška, Petr Proschek, Martin Míšek, Denis I. Gorbunov, Jan Kotek, Vladimír Sechovský, and Jiří Pospíšil
Here, the authors report strongly anisotropic uniaxial antiferromagnetism in the van der Waals trihalide VBr3, with a tricritical point in the H-T phase diagram in out-of-plane field. The robustness of the antiferromagnetic state manifested by a high critical metamagnetic field is explained by ab initio calculations that predict a zigzag antiferromagnetic order of V moments described within the J1-J2-J3 model. The observed saturated moment of 1.2 μB/f.u. indicates a significant vanadium orbital moment that is the main ingredient of the strong anisotropy.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 104416] Published Thu Sep 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dávid Hovančík, Marie Kratochvílová, Tetiana Haidamak, Petr Doležal, Karel Carva, Anežka Bendová, Jan Prokleška, Petr Proschek, Martin Míšek, Denis I. Gorbunov, Jan Kotek, Vladimír Sechovský, and Jiří Pospíšil</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamical Information Synergy in Biochemical Signaling Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.128401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.128401"/>
        <updated>2023-09-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lauritz Hahn, Aleksandra M. Walczak, and Thierry Mora
The concurrent analysis of two measurements of a biochemical signaling network can provide more information than two separate probes of the datasets.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 128401] Published Wed Sep 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauritz Hahn, Aleksandra M. Walczak, and Thierry Mora</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jackiw-Teitelboim gravity with matter, generalized eigenstate thermalization hypothesis, and random matrices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.066015</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.066015"/>
        <updated>2023-09-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Daniel Louis Jafferis, David K. Kolchmeyer, Baur Mukhametzhanov, and Julian Sonner
It was conjectured that a particular two-dimensional gravity, Jackiw–Teitelboim (JT) gravity, is dual to a single-trace one-matrix Random Matrix Model (RMM). The authors extend this duality to JT gravity minimally coupled to a free massive scalar field and a single-trace two-matrix model. They study in detail the matching of genus zero one- and two-boundary expectation values in the matrix model to the gravitational disk correlators.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 066015] Published Wed Sep 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Louis Jafferis, David K. Kolchmeyer, Baur Mukhametzhanov, and Julian Sonner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variational Monte Carlo study of symmetric mass generation in a bilayer honeycomb lattice model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125130</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125130"/>
        <updated>2023-09-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wanda Hou and Yi-Zhuang You
This paper investigates the symmetric mass generation transition in a bilayer honeycomb lattice model using variational Monte Carlo simulations. By measuring the fermion scaling dimension at the critical point, the authors provide evidence for fermion fractionalization into deconfined emergent particles, supporting the hypothesis that the transition is a fermionic deconfined quantum critical point. The numerical results, including the critical exponent and fermion dimension, agree with theoretical predictions.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 125130] Published Wed Sep 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wanda Hou and Yi-Zhuang You</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Network Effects Lead to Self-Organization in Metabolic Cycles of Self-Repelling Catalysts]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.128301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.128301"/>
        <updated>2023-09-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vincent Ouazan-Reboul, Ramin Golestanian, and Jaime Agudo-Canalejo
Catalytically active particles form clusters when they respond not only to their own chemical targets but to those of other catalysts, too.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 128301] Published Tue Sep 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vincent Ouazan-Reboul, Ramin Golestanian, and Jaime Agudo-Canalejo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ac Josephson effect in a gate-tunable ${\mathrm{Cd}}_{3}{\mathrm{As}}_{2}$ nanowire superconducting weak link]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.094514</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.094514"/>
        <updated>2023-09-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Haller, M. Osterwalder, G. Fülöp, J. Ridderbos, M. Jung, and C. Schönenberger
Experimental signatures of topological superconductivity have been notoriously difficult to verify, even though they are actively being researched. Here, the authors use nanowires of Cd3As2 – a Dirac semimetal – to hunt for these signatures by simultaneously looking at Josephson radiation and Shapiro patterns at different doping levels. By cross-checking the experimental results with an extensive (RCSJ) model that includes thermal noise, it is concluded that trivial supercurrent dominates and that topological supercurrent, if existent, falls below the detection limit of the setup.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 094514] Published Tue Sep 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Haller, M. Osterwalder, G. Fülöp, J. Ridderbos, M. Jung, and C. Schönenberger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental demonstration of splitting rules for exceptional points and their topological characterization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115427</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115427"/>
        <updated>2023-09-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yi-Xin Xiao, Jing Hu, Zhao-Qing Zhang, and C. T. Chan
This work establishes clear relationships between how exceptional points of varying orders split and which parts of the system are perturbed. Additionally, two topological invariants are identified to fully characterize the various splitting behavior. These findings provide a comprehensive understanding of how exceptional points split in various non-Hermitian systems, and can help optimize the performance of sensors that rely on exceptional points.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 115427] Published Tue Sep 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yi-Xin Xiao, Jing Hu, Zhao-Qing Zhang, and C. T. Chan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Laser-Induced Cavitation for Controlling Crystallization from Solution]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.124001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.124001"/>
        <updated>2023-09-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nagaraj Nagalingam, Aswin Raghunathan, Vikram Korede, Christian Poelma, Carlas S. Smith, Remco Hartkamp, Johan T. Padding, and Hüseyin Burak Eral
High-speed microscope measurements show the nucleation and growth of single KCl crystals at the inner container wall of a supersaturated solution where submillimeter cavitation bubbles are generated by incident laser pulses.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 124001] Published Mon Sep 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nagaraj Nagalingam, Aswin Raghunathan, Vikram Korede, Christian Poelma, Carlas S. Smith, Remco Hartkamp, Johan T. Padding, and Hüseyin Burak Eral</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two-body problem in theories with kinetic screening]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.064033</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.064033"/>
        <updated>2023-09-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mateja Bošković and Enrico Barausse
Due to non-linearities, the two body problem in tensor-scalar theory with kinetic screening is notoriously difficult to solve. In this work, the authors present an analytical solution to this problem and validate it with numerical simulations. They demonstrate that the efficiency of the screening depends on the mass ratio of the two bodies.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 064033] Published Mon Sep 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mateja Bošković and Enrico Barausse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Small Fermi Pockets Intertwined with Charge Stripes and Pair Density Wave Order in a Kagome Superconductor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031030</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031030"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hong Li, Dongjin Oh, Mingu Kang, He Zhao, Brenden R. Ortiz, Yuzki Oey, Shiang Fang, Zheng Ren, Chris Jozwiak, Aaron Bostwick, Eli Rotenberg, Joseph G. Checkelsky, Ziqiang Wang, Stephen D. Wilson, Riccardo Comin, and Ilija Zeljkovic
The observation of Fermi “pockets” in the Fermi surface of exotic superconductors provides a major step toward explaining some mysterious electronic states.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 031030] Published Fri Sep 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hong Li, Dongjin Oh, Mingu Kang, He Zhao, Brenden R. Ortiz, Yuzki Oey, Shiang Fang, Zheng Ren, Chris Jozwiak, Aaron Bostwick, Eli Rotenberg, Joseph G. Checkelsky, Ziqiang Wang, Stephen D. Wilson, Riccardo Comin, and Ilija Zeljkovic</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tunable Crossed Andreev Reflection and Elastic Cotunneling in Hybrid Nanowires]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031031</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031031"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alberto Bordin, Guanzhong Wang, Chun-Xiao Liu, Sebastiaan L. D. ten Haaf, Nick van Loo, Grzegorz P. Mazur, Di Xu, David van Driel, Francesco Zatelli, Sasa Gazibegovic, Ghada Badawy, Erik P. A. M. Bakkers, Michael Wimmer, Leo P. Kouwenhoven, and Tom Dvir
A demonstration that certain electron-transport processes can be tuned in a hybrid semiconductor-superconductor system could be useful for developing quantum computers

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 031031] Published Fri Sep 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alberto Bordin, Guanzhong Wang, Chun-Xiao Liu, Sebastiaan L. D. ten Haaf, Nick van Loo, Grzegorz P. Mazur, Di Xu, David van Driel, Francesco Zatelli, Sasa Gazibegovic, Ghada Badawy, Erik P. A. M. Bakkers, Michael Wimmer, Leo P. Kouwenhoven, and Tom Dvir</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Determination of the Thermomigration Force on Adatoms]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116202"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): F. Leroy, A. El Barraj, F. Cheynis, P. Müller, and S. Curiotto
The slow drift of microscale features on a surface reveals the force driving atoms from the hot to the cold side of the material.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116202] Published Fri Sep 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>F. Leroy, A. El Barraj, F. Cheynis, P. Müller, and S. Curiotto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topology, criticality, and dynamically generated qubits in a stochastic measurement-only Kitaev model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.094304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.094304"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Adithya Sriram, Tibor Rakovszky, Vedika Khemani, and Matteo Ippoliti
Even in the absence of unitary evolution, measurements alone can induce a rich variety of dynamical phases and phenomena in many-body quantum systems. Inspired by the Kitaev honeycomb Hamiltonian, a paradigmatic model of topological physics, the authors construct here a stochastic measurement-only dynamics on a honeycomb lattice and show that it hosts distinct entanglement phases, including phases that protect topological qubits for an exponential amount of time and a critical phase with exotic dynamical scaling.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 094304] Published Fri Sep 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adithya Sriram, Tibor Rakovszky, Vedika Khemani, and Matteo Ippoliti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitored quantum dynamics and the Kitaev spin liquid]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115135</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115135"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ali Lavasani, Zhu-Xi Luo, and Sagar Vijay
The authors study the quantum dynamics of a (2+1)D monitored random circuit involving local projective measurements, inspired by the physics of the Kitaev quantum spin liquid. A Majorana parton description of the dynamics reveals a close connection between the entanglement dynamics of quantum trajectories and the 3D classical fully packed loop model. The authors uncover a critical phase where quantum trajectories exhibit long-range entanglement with a logarithmic (L log L) violation of the area law, and a topologically ordered phase reminiscent of the toric code phase.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 115135] Published Fri Sep 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Lavasani, Zhu-Xi Luo, and Sagar Vijay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetohydrodynamic boundary conditions for the two-dimensional fermion gas]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125305</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125305"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): O. E. Raichev
In the hydrodynamic regime of electron transport, the distribution of electrical currents and potentials inside a conductor are determined by the Navier-Stokes equation with boundary conditions. The derivation of the boundary conditions from kinetic theory includes both an approximate approach, expressing them through the electronic viscosity, and a more accurate approach, implying numerical solution of the Boltzmann equation. With magnetic field, the results of the two approaches are considerably different when the mean free path length determined by electron-electron collisions is comparable to the cyclotron radius.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 125305] Published Fri Sep 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>O. E. Raichev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unavoidability of nonclassicality loss in $\mathcal{PT}$-symmetric systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.033512</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.033512"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jan Peřina, Jr., Adam Miranowicz, Joanna K. Kalaga, and Wiesław Leoński
The authors study the dynamics of two nonlinearly coupled oscillator modes in a PT-symmetric system, in which gain and loss are provided by coupling a pair of bosonic modes to separate baths. The authors show that even when the model parameters are fine-tuned to achieve a balance between gain and loss in the semiclassical limit, the fluctuations of the bath lead to a gradual loss of nonclassicality and entanglement between the modes.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 033512] Published Fri Sep 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jan Peřina, Jr., Adam Miranowicz, Joanna K. Kalaga, and Wiesław Leoński</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prevailing Charge Order in Overdoped ${\mathrm{La}}_{2−x}{\mathrm{Sr}}_{x}{\mathrm{CuO}}_{4}$ beyond the Superconducting Dome]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116002"/>
        <updated>2023-09-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Qizhi Li, Hsiao-Yu Huang, Tianshuang Ren, Eugen Weschke, Lele Ju, Changwei Zou, Shilong Zhang, Qingzheng Qiu, Jiarui Liu, Shuhan Ding, Amol Singh, Oleksandr Prokhnenko, Di-Jing Huang, Ilya Esterlis, Yao Wang, Yanwu Xie, and Yingying Peng
Resonant x-ray scattering measurements reveal the existence of charge ordering in the high-temperature cuprate superconductor, La2−xSrxCuO4, well beyond the expected levels of doping concentrations.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116002] Published Thu Sep 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qizhi Li, Hsiao-Yu Huang, Tianshuang Ren, Eugen Weschke, Lele Ju, Changwei Zou, Shilong Zhang, Qingzheng Qiu, Jiarui Liu, Shuhan Ding, Amol Singh, Oleksandr Prokhnenko, Di-Jing Huang, Ilya Esterlis, Yao Wang, Yanwu Xie, and Yingying Peng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Direct Observation of Topological Phonons in Graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116602"/>
        <updated>2023-09-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jiade Li, Jiangxu Li, Jilin Tang, Zhiyu Tao, Siwei Xue, Jiaxi Liu, Hailin Peng, Xing-Qiu Chen, Jiandong Guo, and Xuetao Zhu
New experiments reveal graphene’s exotic phonon spectrum with unprecedented detail and completeness.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116602] Published Thu Sep 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jiade Li, Jiangxu Li, Jilin Tang, Zhiyu Tao, Siwei Xue, Jiaxi Liu, Hailin Peng, Xing-Qiu Chen, Jiandong Guo, and Xuetao Zhu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic excitations in $5{d}^{4}\phantom{\rule{4pt}{0ex}}J=0\phantom{\rule{4pt}{0ex}}{\mathrm{Os}}^{4+}$ halides studied by resonant inelastic x-ray scattering and optical spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125120</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125120"/>
        <updated>2023-09-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): P. Warzanowski, M. Magnaterra, P. Stein, G. Schlicht, Q. Faure, Ch. J. Sahle, T. Lorenz, P. Becker, L. Bohatý, M. Moretti Sala, G. Monaco, P. H. M. van Loosdrecht, and M. Grüninger
The cubic halides K2OsCl6, K2OsBr6, and Rb2OsBr6 are found to be excellent realizations of spin-orbit-entangled nonmagnetic J=0 compounds in the intermediate coupling regime. The two complementary techniques of resonant inelastic x-ray scattering and optical spectroscopy allow the authors to draw a comprehensive picture of the electronic excitations and to assess the electronic structure. The accurate set of electronic parameters such as spin-orbit coupling, Hund’s coupling, crystal-field splitting, Mott gap, and charge-transfer energy will serve as a solid reference for future studies on Os compounds.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 125120] Published Thu Sep 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>P. Warzanowski, M. Magnaterra, P. Stein, G. Schlicht, Q. Faure, Ch. J. Sahle, T. Lorenz, P. Becker, L. Bohatý, M. Moretti Sala, G. Monaco, P. H. M. van Loosdrecht, and M. Grüninger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phonon-mediated dark to bright plasmon conversion]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125417</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125417"/>
        <updated>2023-09-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Benjamin Rousseaux, Yanko Todorov, Angela Vasanelli, and Carlo Sirtori
Unlocking the full potential of nanophotonic devices involves the engineering of their intrinsic optical properties. Here, the authors investigate a quantum theory that treats the interaction between quantum-confined plasmons and optical phonons in semiconductors. This theory allows computation of the optical response beyond the conventional Drude-Lorentz model. In particular, it predicts new effects, such as an oscillator-strength transfer mechanism between phonons and dark plasmon modes.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 125417] Published Thu Sep 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin Rousseaux, Yanko Todorov, Angela Vasanelli, and Carlo Sirtori</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strongly anisotropic spin and orbital Rashba effect at a tellurium – noble metal interface]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L121107</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L121107"/>
        <updated>2023-09-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): B. Geldiyev, M. Ünzelmann, P. Eck, T. Kißlinger, J. Schusser, T. Figgemeier, P. Kagerer, N. Tezak, M. Krivenkov, A. Varykhalov, A. Fedorov, L. Nicolaï, J. Minár, K. Miyamoto, T. Okuda, K. Shimada, D. Di Sante, G. Sangiovanni, L. Hammer, M. A. Schneider, H. Bentmann, and F. Reinert
The orbital Rashba effect describes the formation of chiral orbital angular momentum textures upon inversion symmetry breaking at surfaces or interfaces. Here, the authors unveil a pronounced anisotropic spin-orbit splitting with a Rashba-type spin polarization in the electronic interface states in the model system Te/Au(100). Exploring the momentum-dependent response of inversion symmetry breaking, they particularly demonstrate that the orbital texture leads to a strongly anisotropic spin and orbital Rashba effect. These findings will provide a valuable contribution to the discovery and understanding of future “orbitronic” phenomena.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L121107] Published Thu Sep 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>B. Geldiyev, M. Ünzelmann, P. Eck, T. Kißlinger, J. Schusser, T. Figgemeier, P. Kagerer, N. Tezak, M. Krivenkov, A. Varykhalov, A. Fedorov, L. Nicolaï, J. Minár, K. Miyamoto, T. Okuda, K. Shimada, D. Di Sante, G. Sangiovanni, L. Hammer, M. A. Schneider, H. Bentmann, and F. Reinert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long-Lived Singlet State in an Oriented Phase and its Survival across the Phase Transition Into an Isotropic Phase]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034030</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034030"/>
        <updated>2023-09-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vishal Varma and T.S. Mahesh
Long-lived states (LLSs) in nuclear magnetic resonance have diverse applications, from medical imaging to chemical analysis to quantum information processing, but were hitherto observed primarily in isotropic phases. The authors prepare LLS in an anisotropic environment of a liquid crystal and observe its survival across the phase transition to the isotropic phase. This study could pave the way for trapping LLS in the symmetric spin pair of an isotropic phase after breaking symmetry in an anisotropic phase, and motivate the realization of LLS in the solid phase, which will have implications for solid-state qubits toward achieving longer lifetimes in addition to long-range interactions.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 034030] Published Thu Sep 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vishal Varma and T.S. Mahesh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimality Pressures toward Lateralization of Complex Brain Functions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031028</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031028"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Luís F. Seoane
A mathematical model shows how increased intricacy of cognitive tasks can break the mirror symmetry of the brain’s neural network.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 031028] Published Wed Sep 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luís F. Seoane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Floquet Engineering of Black Phosphorus upon Below-Gap Pumping]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116401"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shaohua Zhou, Changhua Bao, Benshu Fan, Fei Wang, Haoyuan Zhong, Hongyun Zhang, Peizhe Tang, Wenhui Duan, and Shuyun Zhou
Light-induced band engineering in black phosphorus by pumping below the band gap is experimentally demonstrated, which might extend Floquet engineering to more quantum materials.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116401] Published Wed Sep 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shaohua Zhou, Changhua Bao, Benshu Fan, Fei Wang, Haoyuan Zhong, Hongyun Zhang, Peizhe Tang, Wenhui Duan, and Shuyun Zhou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enhancement of Second-Order Non-Hermitian Skin Effect by Magnetic Fields]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116601"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chang-An Li, Björn Trauzettel, Titus Neupert, and Song-Bo Zhang
The second-order non-Hermitian skin effect is robust and can even be enhanced by magnetic fields, which is in contrast to the first-order non-Hermitian skin effect.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116601] Published Wed Sep 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chang-An Li, Björn Trauzettel, Titus Neupert, and Song-Bo Zhang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental Observation of Critical Scaling in Magnetic Dynamic Phase Transitions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116701"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Quintana and A. Berger
Magneto-optical experiments on ultrathin uniaxial cobalt films reveal (for the first time) critical behavior in such systems, and also show indications of dimensional crossover, with the films exhibiting 2D dynamical and 3D thermodynamic behavior.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116701] Published Wed Sep 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Quintana and A. Berger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maximally localized exciton Wannier functions for solids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125118</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125118"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jonah B. Haber, Diana Y. Qiu, Felipe H. da Jornada, and Jeffrey B. Neaton
Over 25 years ago, Marzari and Vanderbilt introduced maximally localized Wannier functions (MLWFs), the most compact real-space representation of electronic wavefunctions in solids. Here, the authors put forward a generalization of this scheme for excitons, correlated electron-hole pairs that dictate the optical properties of materials. Much as MLWFs have transformed our understanding of electrons in solids, from chemical bonding to polarization to topology, these maximally localized exciton Wannier functions should deepen our understanding of photophysical and excited-state phenomena of materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 125118] Published Wed Sep 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonah B. Haber, Diana Y. Qiu, Felipe H. da Jornada, and Jeffrey B. Neaton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimal single-qubit tomography: Realization of locally optimal measurements on a quantum computer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.032605</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.032605"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bacui Li, Lorcán O. Conlon, Ping Koy Lam, and Syed M. Assad
The authors map qubit tomography to a quantum multiparameter estimation problem and find the optimal single-qubit measurements. Using a quantum computing demonstration they show that the optimal separable measurement bound can be saturated.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 032605] Published Wed Sep 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bacui Li, Lorcán O. Conlon, Ping Koy Lam, and Syed M. Assad</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chemotactic Motility-Induced Phase Separation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.118301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.118301"/>
        <updated>2023-09-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hongbo Zhao, Andrej Košmrlj, and Sujit S. Datta
Chemotaxis and motility-induced phase separation compete against each other in systems of active particles.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 118301] Published Tue Sep 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hongbo Zhao, Andrej Košmrlj, and Sujit S. Datta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Renormalization group for measurement and entanglement phase transitions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.104203</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.104203"/>
        <updated>2023-09-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Adam Nahum and Kay Jörg Wiese
Field theoretic renormalization group is applied to measurement and entanglement phase transitions. The renormalization group flows for both random tensor networks and monitored systems show that, in high dimensions, there exist distinct weak- and strong-coupling universality classes for these phase transitions. In addition, one of the field theories exhibits a supersymmetry that leads to dimensional reduction by four.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 104203] Published Tue Sep 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Nahum and Kay Jörg Wiese</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inhomogeneity-induced time-reversal symmetry breaking in cuprate twist junctions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L100505</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L100505"/>
        <updated>2023-09-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Andrew C. Yuan, Yaar Vituri, Erez Berg, Boris Spivak, and Steven A. Kivelson
The lowest-order Josephson coupling between d-wave superconductors vanishes by symmetry when the twist angle is close to 45 degrees. The authors propose here an “order by disorder” mechanism, whereby spatial fluctuations in the local Josephson coupling generate an effective higher-order coupling, leading to a time reversal symmetry breaking superconducting phase at the twisted interface. This mechanism may offer an explanation for recent experiments in twist junctions between high-Tc cuprate superconductors. These findings have broader implications for high-Tc cuprate physics, requiring a local admixture of an s-wave component in the d-wave order parameter.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L100505] Published Tue Sep 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew C. Yuan, Yaar Vituri, Erez Berg, Boris Spivak, and Steven A. Kivelson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In and Out-of-Equilibrium <i>Ab Initio</i> Theory of Electrons and Phonons]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031026</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031026"/>
        <updated>2023-09-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gianluca Stefanucci, Robert van Leeuwen, and Enrico Perfetto
A new set of equations captures the dynamical interplay of electrons and vibrations in crystals and forms a basis for computational studies.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 031026] Published Mon Sep 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gianluca Stefanucci, Robert van Leeuwen, and Enrico Perfetto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evidence for Suppression of Structure Growth in the Concordance Cosmological Model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.111001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.111001"/>
        <updated>2023-09-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nhat-Minh Nguyen, Dragan Huterer, and Yuewei Wen
A joint analysis of data from the CMB, weak lensing, peculiar velocities, and galaxy clustering, shows that an extension of the concordance cosmological model which includes the suppression of the growth of cosmic structure can alleviate two widely discussed cosmological tensions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 111001] Published Mon Sep 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nhat-Minh Nguyen, Dragan Huterer, and Yuewei Wen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paramagnetic Singularities of the Orbital Magnetism in Graphene with a Moiré Potential]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116201"/>
        <updated>2023-09-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Vallejo Bustamante, R. Ribeiro-Palau, C. Fermon, M. Pannetier-Lecoeur, K. Watanabe, T. Tanigushi, R. Deblock, S. Guéron, M. Ferrier, J. N. Fuchs, G. Montambaux, F. Piéchon, and H. Bouchiat
Magnetization measurements on graphene/hBN samples in a wide range of chemical potential reveal paramagnetism at saddle points of the moiré band structure.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116201] Published Mon Sep 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Vallejo Bustamante, R. Ribeiro-Palau, C. Fermon, M. Pannetier-Lecoeur, K. Watanabe, T. Tanigushi, R. Deblock, S. Guéron, M. Ferrier, J. N. Fuchs, G. Montambaux, F. Piéchon, and H. Bouchiat</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frequency-domain approach to self-force in hyperbolic scattering]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.064017</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.064017"/>
        <updated>2023-09-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christopher Whittall and Leor Barack
The self-force problem in gravity is an approach to the two-body problem in which the mass ratio is extreme enough that the smaller-mass body can be usefully treated as a test particle to the lowest order in the mass ratio. In this paper, frequency domain methods, which are particularly suited for bound orbital motion, are developed in an innovative way so that they can be applied to study hyperbolic scattering in the “toy” problem of a scalar charge. Frequency domain methods as developed here may prove to be a promising approach to the full gravitational self-force problem.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 064017] Published Mon Sep 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher Whittall and Leor Barack</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep learning extraction of band structure parameters from density of states: A case study on trilayer graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125411</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125411"/>
        <updated>2023-09-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Paul Henderson, Areg Ghazaryan, Alexander A. Zibrov, Andrea F. Young, and Maksym Serbyn
Harnessing the power of deep learning, researchers have developed a novel method to fit the band structure parameters of complex 2D materials, such as trilayer graphene. By training neural networks on simulated data for the density of states, and then minimizing the effective distance between network-generated images and experimental data, the authors obtain here accurate predictions of tight-binding parameters, validating their results against literature values. This method can be easily extended to other complex two-dimensional materials, as well as to other experimental techniques.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 125411] Published Mon Sep 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Henderson, Areg Ghazaryan, Alexander A. Zibrov, Andrea F. Young, and Maksym Serbyn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Acoustically Induced Spin Resonances of Silicon-Vacancy Centers in $4H$-SiC]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034017</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034017"/>
        <updated>2023-09-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Vasselon, A. Hernández-Mínguez, M. Hollenbach, G.V. Astakhov, and P.V. Santos
Silicon vacancies in 4H-SiC are color centers with promising applications in quantum technologies, but spin control of the centers generated in a hexagonal local crystallographic environment has yet to be demonstrated above cryogenic temperatures. The authors use the dynamic strain of surface acoustic waves to overcome this limitation and efficiently excite spin transitions in the excited states of these color centers up to room temperature. The acoustic spin control of silicon vacancies opens possibilities for the implementation of efficient quantum spin control and sensing protocols using spin optomechanics.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 034017] Published Mon Sep 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Vasselon, A. Hernández-Mínguez, M. Hollenbach, G.V. Astakhov, and P.V. Santos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nanoscale Transport during Liquid Film Thinning Inhibits Bubble Coalescing Behavior in Electrolyte Solutions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.104003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.104003"/>
        <updated>2023-09-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bo Liu, Rogerio Manica, Qingxia Liu, Zhenghe Xu, Evert Klaseboer, and Qiang Yang
Observations of air-bubble mergers in water explain why dissolved salt slows this process and leads to foam.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 104003] Published Fri Sep 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bo Liu, Rogerio Manica, Qingxia Liu, Zhenghe Xu, Evert Klaseboer, and Qiang Yang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two-way photoeffectlike occupancy dynamics in a single (InGa)As quantum dot]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125301"/>
        <updated>2023-09-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pavel Sterin, Kai Hühn, Mikhail M. Glazov, Jens Hübner, and Michael Oestreich
Spin noise spectroscopy on single quantum dots (QDs) has matured to a highly efficient method to study the spin and charge dynamics of semiconductor quantum dots, including the subtle impact of their surroundings. Here, the authors extend the theory and the experimental technique of optical spin noise spectroscopy to high magnetic fields and study the fundamental mechanisms of decharging and recharging of (InGa)As QDs at quasiresonant and nonresonant optical excitation. The resulting photoinduced two-way charge dynamics in single QDs is not only interesting from the fundamental point of view but plays an important role in many quantum dot based photonic devices, such as optically addressable qubits or reliable single-photon emitters.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 125301] Published Fri Sep 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pavel Sterin, Kai Hühn, Mikhail M. Glazov, Jens Hübner, and Michael Oestreich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Error mitigation for quantum approximate optimization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.032408</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.032408"/>
        <updated>2023-09-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anita Weidinger, Glen Bigan Mbeng, and Wolfgang Lechner
Quantum error mitigation involves reducing errors in hybrid quantum-classical algorithms, which is particularly relevant for near-term noisy quantum devices. The authors introduce an error mitigation technique based on redundant parity encoding of logical variables. They demonstrate the use of this technique by applying it to the quantum approximate optimization algorithm.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 032408] Published Fri Sep 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anita Weidinger, Glen Bigan Mbeng, and Wolfgang Lechner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simulations of a frequency-chirped magneto-optical trap of MgF]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.033105</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.033105"/>
        <updated>2023-09-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kayla J. Rodriguez, Nickolas H. Pilgram, Daniel S. Barker, Stephen P. Eckel, and Eric B. Norrgard
The authors present a theoretical analysis of a frequency-chirped molecular magneto-optical trap (MOT) that may open the way for efficient cooling of a class of light molecules. They show that this approach can increase the capture velocity of the MOT which could be used to capture more molecules from typical molecular sources and, in some cases, perhaps remove the need for laser slowing before capture in the MOT.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 033105] Published Fri Sep 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kayla J. Rodriguez, Nickolas H. Pilgram, Daniel S. Barker, Stephen P. Eckel, and Eric B. Norrgard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Active nematics on flat surfaces: From droplet motility and scission to active wetting]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033165</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033165"/>
        <updated>2023-09-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rodrigo C. V. Coelho, Hélio R. J. C. Figueiredo, and Margarida M. Telo da Gama
Active nematic droplets on surfaces are studied at different activities on a wide range of surfaces. The analysis provides a global description of the dynamical regimes reported for active nematic droplets, such as active wetting, propulsion, and chaotic motion, and it reveals the dimensionless parameters that characterize the dynamics of droplets on surfaces.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 033165] Published Thu Sep 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rodrigo C. V. Coelho, Hélio R. J. C. Figueiredo, and Margarida M. Telo da Gama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Failure of Topological Invariants in Strongly Correlated Matter]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.106601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.106601"/>
        <updated>2023-09-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jinchao Zhao, Peizhi Mai, Barry Bradlyn, and Philip Phillips
When zeros appear in the Green’s function, as in strongly correlated systems, the invariant N3 for the two-dimensional quantum anomalous Hall insulator does not necessarily encode a topological invariant of the ground state, in contrast to expectations.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 106601] Published Thu Sep 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jinchao Zhao, Peizhi Mai, Barry Bradlyn, and Philip Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global and Local Connectivities Describe Hydrogen Intercalation in Metal Oxides]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.108001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.108001"/>
        <updated>2023-09-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Evan V. Miu, James R. McKone, and Giannis Mpourmpakis
The reactivity of a material is describable using only the arrangement of its atoms, a finding that could be used to speed up the search for new catalytic materials.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 108001] Published Thu Sep 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Evan V. Miu, James R. McKone, and Giannis Mpourmpakis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How the fine structure of the electric double layer and the flow affect morphological instability in electrodeposition]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.093701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.093701"/>
        <updated>2023-09-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): I. Rubinstein and B. Zaltzman
Dendrite formation due to morphological instability in cathodic electrodeposition of a metal and related fluid flows are investigated. We show that the electric double layer fine structure and the finite electrode reaction rate regularize the electrodeposition front short-wave singularity and select a range of unstable perturbation modes. The critical wavelength corresponds to the fastest growing mode and scales with the electric double layer width and the reaction-diffusion length. The emerging electroconvective (electroosmotic) flow in the nonequilibrium regime selects the cathodic diffusion layer width as the dominant length scale for morphological instability and emerging dendrites.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 093701] Published Thu Sep 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>I. Rubinstein and B. Zaltzman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Attributing equity gaps to course structure in introductory physics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.020126</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.020126"/>
        <updated>2023-09-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): David J. Webb and Cassandra A. Paul
Changes to the structure of introductory physics courses can eliminate some demographic grade gaps.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 19, 020126] Published Wed Sep 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David J. Webb and Cassandra A. Paul</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tritium Beta Spectrum Measurement and Neutrino Mass Limit from Cyclotron Radiation Emission Spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.102502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.102502"/>
        <updated>2023-09-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Ashtari Esfahani et al. (Project 8 Collaboration)
The first frequency-based limit on the neutrino’s mass sets the stage for next-generation experiments.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 102502] Published Wed Sep 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Ashtari Esfahani &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (Project 8 Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universality of Critical Dynamics with Finite Entanglement]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.106501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.106501"/>
        <updated>2023-09-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. E. Sherman, A. Avdoshkin, and J. E. Moore
A study based on matrix product state simulation of spin chains establishes how finite entanglement affects the Kibble-Zurek mechanism, thereby illustrating the role of entanglement in dynamical critical phenomena.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 106501] Published Wed Sep 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. E. Sherman, A. Avdoshkin, and J. E. Moore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Continuity equation for the many-electron spectral function]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115110</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115110"/>
        <updated>2023-09-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): F. Aryasetiawan
A continuity equation determining the total spectral function of a many-electron system is derived within the recently proposed exchange-correlation field framework. A practical scheme is constructed in which only the diagonal part of the exchange-correlation field is needed as input, leading to an explicit formula for the spectral function. This will greatly simplify calculations of spectral functions provided a reliable approximation for the exchange-correlation field is available. The local-density approximation could be a suitable starting point for an accurate approximation.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 115110] Published Wed Sep 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>F. Aryasetiawan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crossover from exciton polarons to trions in doped two-dimensional semiconductors at finite temperature]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125406</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125406"/>
        <updated>2023-09-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Antonio Tiene, Brendan C. Mulkerin, Jesper Levinsen, Meera M. Parish, and Francesca Maria Marchetti
Should the optical response of doped two-dimensional semiconductors be described within a Fermi polaron or a trion model? Using a finite-temperature Fermi polaron theory, the authors demonstrate here a crossover from a quantum degenerate regime with a well-defined polaron quasiparticle to an incoherent regime at high temperature or low doping, where the lowest-energy attractive polaron becomes subsumed into a broad trion-hole continuum. The crossover is accompanied by a characteristic evolution of the emission profile, from a symmetric Lorentzian to an asymmetric peak.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 125406] Published Wed Sep 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Antonio Tiene, Brendan C. Mulkerin, Jesper Levinsen, Meera M. Parish, and Francesca Maria Marchetti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exactly solvable lattice models for interacting electronic insulators in two dimensions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L121104</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L121104"/>
        <updated>2023-09-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Qing-Rui Wang, Yang Qi, Chen Fang, Meng Cheng, and Zheng-Cheng Gu
Topological insulators in two-dimensional systems are well-understood within the context of free-fermion systems. Nevertheless, comprehending their strongly interacting counterparts presents a significant challenge. Here, the authors developed an innovative lattice model based on U(1)f fermionic charge decorations. The model furnishes a rigorous mathematical framework for delving into fermionic symmetry-protected topological phases that conserve U(1)f charge, among other types of symmetries. Notably, this research expands the existing theoretical landscape by presenting an exactly solvable Hamiltonian with a finite local Hilbert space and a sophisticated classification scheme for continuous symmetries.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L121104] Published Wed Sep 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qing-Rui Wang, Yang Qi, Chen Fang, Meng Cheng, and Zheng-Cheng Gu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Damping in Free Layers of Spin-Transfer-Torque Magnetic Memory at Elevated Temperatures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034006</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034006"/>
        <updated>2023-09-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Adam Whitney, Chuanpu Liu, Tiffany S. Santos, Rajesh V. Chopdekar, Matthew Carey, Galen Street, Vijaysankar Kalappattil, Keira Leistikow, and Mingzhong Wu
The efficiency of spin-transfer-torque magnetic random-access memory (MRAM) critically depends on the damping of the free layer. As MRAM cells operate above room temperature, it is crucial to determine the damping parameter of the free layer at elevated temperatures. This study uses ferromagnetic resonance techniques to measure the damping of MRAM free layers up to 520 K. The data show significant differences in temperature dependence between conventional and low-damping free-layer designs, paving the way for MRAM cells with lower switching current. These insights could impact the development of more efficient and thermally stable MRAM technologies.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 034006] Published Wed Sep 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Whitney, Chuanpu Liu, Tiffany S. Santos, Rajesh V. Chopdekar, Matthew Carey, Galen Street, Vijaysankar Kalappattil, Keira Leistikow, and Mingzhong Wu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing the Connection between Entangled Particles and Wormholes in General Relativity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.101001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.101001"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ben Kain
A numerical study tests how entangled particles may have a dual description involving connection via nontraversable wormholes.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 101001] Published Tue Sep 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ben Kain</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of the Lifetime and $\mathrm{Λ}$ Separation Energy of $_{\mathrm{Λ}}^{3}\mathrm{H}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.102302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.102302"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Acharya et al. (ALICE Collaboration)
Researchers have pinned down the binding energy and lifetime of the so-called hypertriton, a particle that could help explain the structure of neutron stars.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 102302] Published Tue Sep 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Acharya &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (ALICE Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extreme Spontaneous Deformations of Active Crystals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.108301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.108301"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xia-qing Shi, Fu Cheng, and Hugues Chaté
Active particles can form two-dimensional solids different from those formed by nonmotile particles, showing long-range crystalline order accompanied by giant spontaneous deformations.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 108301] Published Tue Sep 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xia-qing Shi, Fu Cheng, and Hugues Chaté</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evolutionary dynamics in non-Markovian models of microbial populations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.034402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.034402"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Farshid Jafarpour, Ethan Levien, and Ariel Amir
The evolution of a population of microbes is influenced by features of single-cell growth and division processes. The authors observe that fluctuations in the cells’ division rate affect the long-term evolution of the population.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 034402] Published Tue Sep 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Farshid Jafarpour, Ethan Levien, and Ariel Amir</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-precision measurement of the Ferrell-Glover-Tinkham sum rule in a cuprate high-temperature superconductor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.104501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.104501"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. D. Dawson, X. Shi, K. S. Rabinovich, D. Putzky, Y.-L. Mathis, G. Christiani, G. Logvenov, B. Keimer, and A. V. Boris
The authors have combined several complementary spectroscopic methods to achieve high-precision control over the superconductivity-induced spectral weight transfer in a DyBa2Cu3O7 film with a superconducting Tc of 90 K, spanning an energy range over three orders of magnitude from ~1 meV to 1 eV. They find that the Ferrell-Glover-Tinkham sum rule is satisfied within an unprecedented accuracy of 2% by integrating the optical conductivity up to 0.6 eV, consistent with the spectral range of antiferromagnetic spin fluctuations.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 104501] Published Tue Sep 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. D. Dawson, X. Shi, K. S. Rabinovich, D. Putzky, Y.-L. Mathis, G. Christiani, G. Logvenov, B. Keimer, and A. V. Boris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Functional renormalization group without functional integrals: Implementing Hilbert space projections for strongly correlated electrons via Hubbard X-operators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115104</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115104"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Andreas Rückriegel, Jonas Arnold, Rüdiger Krämer, and Peter Kopietz
The authors show here that exact functional renormalization group flow (FRG) equations for quantum systems can be derived directly within an operator formalism without using functional integrals. This simple insight opens new possibilities for applying FRG methods to models for strongly correlated electrons with projected Hilbert spaces, such as quantum spin models, the t-J model, or the Hubbard model at infinite on-site repulsion. By representing these models in terms of Hubbard X-operators, various applications of this approach are explored.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 115104] Published Tue Sep 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andreas Rückriegel, Jonas Arnold, Rüdiger Krämer, and Peter Kopietz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photocurrents induced by structured light]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115402"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. A. Gunyaga, M. V. Durnev, and S. A. Tarasenko
Structured light, ranging from intensity or polarization gratings to beams with fully controlled spatiotemporal structure, has great potential for use in optics and optoelectronics. This paper explores the photoresponse of a two-dimensional electron system to structured terahertz radiation and uncovers photocurrents related to the gradients of radiation intensity, polarization, and phase. The theory is applied to study the radial and azimuthal currents induced by twisted light beams carrying orbital angular momentum.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 115402] Published Tue Sep 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. A. Gunyaga, M. V. Durnev, and S. A. Tarasenko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exciton-phonon scattering: Competition between the bosonic and fermionic nature of bound electron-hole pairs]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L121102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L121102"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Manuel Katzer, Malte Selig, Lukas Sigl, Mirco Troue, Johannes Figueiredo, Jonas Kiemle, Florian Sigger, Ursula Wurstbauer, Alexander W. Holleitner, and Andreas Knorr
Semiconductor excitons are composite particles consisting of fermionic carriers. Nevertheless they are considered as paradigmatic candidates for bosonic condensation and the formation of macroscopic coherence in solids. To address both effects, the kinetics of exciton thermalization is studied, including their composite fermionic character. This way, exciton condensation based on the primary assumption of a bosonic thermalization is questioned. In this light, also discussed is whether a recently observed decrease of linewidths at increasing exciton density can be related to a signature for emerging excitonic coherence.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L121102] Published Tue Sep 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Manuel Katzer, Malte Selig, Lukas Sigl, Mirco Troue, Johannes Figueiredo, Jonas Kiemle, Florian Sigger, Ursula Wurstbauer, Alexander W. Holleitner, and Andreas Knorr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ultrashort Electron Wave Packets via Frequency-Comb Synthesis]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034005</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034005"/>
        <updated>2023-09-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Matteo Aluffi, Thomas Vasselon, Seddik Ouacel, Hermann Edlbauer, Clément Geffroy, Preden Roulleau, D. Christian Glattli, Giorgos Georgiou, and Christopher Bäuerle
Single-electron sources are vital for modern nanoelectronics, enabling advances in the emerging field of electron quantum optics. However, their performance is limited by the current method for generating single electrons by applying Lorentzian voltage pulses on the Fermi sea of a quantum conductor. The authors introduce a Fourier synthesis-based voltage pulse generator, allowing the generation and in-situ characterization of a 27-ps electron wave packet in an electronic Mach-Zehnder interferometer. This advancement can potentially enable the study of ultrafast dynamics in quantum nanoelectronic systems and the generation of high-frequency flying-electron qubits.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 034005] Published Tue Sep 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matteo Aluffi, Thomas Vasselon, Seddik Ouacel, Hermann Edlbauer, Clément Geffroy, Preden Roulleau, D. Christian Glattli, Giorgos Georgiou, and Christopher Bäuerle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>