<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-10-12T00:42:00.937Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-10-12T00:42:00.937Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimal Generators for Quantum Sensing]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.150802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.150802"/>
        <updated>2023-10-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jarrod T. Reilly, John Drew Wilson, Simon B. Jäger, Christopher Wilson, and Murray J. Holland
A new method identifies the most sensitive measurement that can be performed using a given quantum state, knowledge key for designing improved quantum sensors.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 150802] Published Wed Oct 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jarrod T. Reilly, John Drew Wilson, Simon B. Jäger, Christopher Wilson, and Murray J. Holland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magneto-Optical Detection of the Orbital Hall Effect in Chromium]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.156702</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.156702"/>
        <updated>2023-10-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Igor Lyalin, Sanaz Alikhah, Marco Berritta, Peter M. Oppeneer, and Roland K. Kawakami
Two different experiments on two different transition metals reveal that a current of electron orbital angular momentum flows in response to an electric field.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 156702] Published Wed Oct 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Igor Lyalin, Sanaz Alikhah, Marco Berritta, Peter M. Oppeneer, and Roland K. Kawakami</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orbital Hanle Magnetoresistance in a $3d$ Transition Metal]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.156703</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.156703"/>
        <updated>2023-10-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Giacomo Sala, Hanchen Wang, William Legrand, and Pietro Gambardella
Two different experiments on two different transition metals reveal that a current of electron orbital angular momentum flows in response to an electric field.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 156703] Published Wed Oct 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giacomo Sala, Hanchen Wang, William Legrand, and Pietro Gambardella</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum Optics Measurement Scheme for Quantum Geometry and Topological Invariants]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.156901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.156901"/>
        <updated>2023-10-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Markus Lysne, Michael Schüler, and Philipp Werner
A proposed optical setup combines a Fabry-Perot-type optical cavity with heterodyne photon detection for extracting the topological properties of two-dimensional semiconductor materials.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 156901] Published Wed Oct 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Markus Lysne, Michael Schüler, and Philipp Werner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Green's-function treatment of Rydberg molecules with spins]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042805</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042805"/>
        <updated>2023-10-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chris H. Greene and Matthew T. Eiles
The authors present a method based on the Coulomb Green’s function to derive the electronic structure of ultra-long-range Rydberg molecules including spins, providing a promising alternative to the standard method based on basis-set expansion, which was shown to have serious convergence problems. Use of this approach should enable more accurate studies of Rydberg-molecule spectra and the electron-atom scattering phase shifts upon which they depend.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 042805] Published Wed Oct 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris H. Greene and Matthew T. Eiles</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Testing the topological insulator behavior of half-Heusler PdYBi and PtYBi (111) epitaxial thin films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.104203</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.104203"/>
        <updated>2023-10-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): V. Palin, A. Anadón, S. Andrieu, Y. Fagot-Revurat, C. de Melo, J. Ghanbaja, O. Kurnosikov, S. Petit-Watelot, F. Bertran, and J.-C. Rojas-Sánchez
Materials with high spin-to-charge interconversion efficiency are of high interest for advanced spintronic applications. Previous work has suggested that topological insulators may exhibit higher efficiency than traditionally-used heavy metals. Here, the authors explore the half-Heusler compounds PdYBi and PtYBi and their potential use for spin-to-charge interconversion. Epitaxial thin films of PdYBi and PtYBi are successfully prepared and demonstrated to exhibit nontrivial topology. Characterization of the magnetotransport in a model device shows that these half-Heusler films can outperform platinum in spin-to-charge interconversion.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 104203] Published Tue Oct 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>V. Palin, A. Anadón, S. Andrieu, Y. Fagot-Revurat, C. de Melo, J. Ghanbaja, O. Kurnosikov, S. Petit-Watelot, F. Bertran, and J.-C. Rojas-Sánchez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Realization of a $\mathbb{Z}$-Classified Chiral-Symmetric Higher-Order Topological Insulator in a Coupling-Inverted Acoustic Crystal]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.157201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.157201"/>
        <updated>2023-10-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dongyi Wang, Yuanchen Deng, Jun Ji, Mourad Oudich, Wladimir A. Benalcazar, Guancong Ma, and Yun Jing
An experiment shows the existence of Z-classified multiple chiral topological phase, which requires both chiral symmetry and a unique condition where the long-range hopping is stronger than the nearest-neighboring one.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 157201] Published Tue Oct 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dongyi Wang, Yuanchen Deng, Jun Ji, Mourad Oudich, Wladimir A. Benalcazar, Guancong Ma, and Yun Jing</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hydrodynamics-Induced Long-Range Attraction between Plates in Bacterial Suspensions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.158301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.158301"/>
        <updated>2023-10-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Luhui Ning, Xin Lou, Qili Ma, Yaochen Yang, Nan Luo, Ke Chen, Fanlong Meng, Xin Zhou, Mingcheng Yang, and Yi Peng
The flow field generated by swimming bacteria drives a long-range attractive force felt by passive objects much larger than the swimmers themselves.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 158301] Published Tue Oct 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luhui Ning, Xin Lou, Qili Ma, Yaochen Yang, Nan Luo, Ke Chen, Fanlong Meng, Xin Zhou, Mingcheng Yang, and Yi Peng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coexistence of extended and localized states in finite-sized mosaic Wannier-Stark lattices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L140202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L140202"/>
        <updated>2023-10-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jun Gao, Ivan M. Khaymovich, Adrian Iovan, Xiao-Wei Wang, Govind Krishna, Ze-Sheng Xu, Emrah Tortumlu, Alexander V. Balatsky, Val Zwiller, and Ali W. Elshaari
The transport of quantum particles and their possible localization are fundamental concepts in physics. Such particles are known to get stuck in strong electric fields due to the Wannier-Stark effect. But what will happen with this particle localization if the electric potential is present only on every second site? To answer this question, the authors mimic here the behavior of quantum particles with light in optical waveguides (shown in the image) and demonstrate that in finite systems there are both extended states, carrying the transport, and localized ones that are stuck. This first step opens the possibility to use this system as an encoder of quantum information in a compact way.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L140202] Published Tue Oct 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jun Gao, Ivan M. Khaymovich, Adrian Iovan, Xiao-Wei Wang, Govind Krishna, Ze-Sheng Xu, Emrah Tortumlu, Alexander V. Balatsky, Val Zwiller, and Ali W. Elshaari</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scattering-matrix approach for a quantitative evaluation of the topological protection in valley photonic crystals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.043505</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.043505"/>
        <updated>2023-10-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gaëtan Lévêque, Yan Pennec, Pascal Szriftgiser, Alberto Amo, and Alejandro Martínez
The authors explore limitations to topological protection in valley Hall waveguides by developing a phenomenological semi-analytical model for analyzing different sources of backscattering. The model can be used to predict the performance of larger-scale structures that are intractable using direct finite-element simulations.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 043505] Published Tue Oct 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gaëtan Lévêque, Yan Pennec, Pascal Szriftgiser, Alberto Amo, and Alejandro Martínez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Particle acceleration by magnetic Rayleigh-Taylor instability: Mechanism for flares in black hole accretion flows]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043023</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043023"/>
        <updated>2023-10-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vladimir Zhdankin, Bart Ripperda, and Alexander A. Philippov
This article uses magnetic Rayleigh-Taylor instability in relativistic collisionless plasma as an example of an astrophysical process for nonthermal particle acceleration, and uncover the onset of large-scale plumes formed by accumulation of small ones via particle-in-cell simulations. This is posed as a potential mechanism for flares.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 043023] Published Mon Oct 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vladimir Zhdankin, Bart Ripperda, and Alexander A. Philippov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of Ultra-High-Energy Diffuse Gamma-Ray Emission of the Galactic Plane from 10 TeV to 1 PeV with LHAASO-KM2A]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.151001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.151001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zhen Cao et al. (LHAASO Collaboration)
Interstellar magnetic fields perturb the trajectories of cosmic rays, making it difficult to identify their sources. A new survey of gamma radiation produced when cosmic rays interact with the interstellar medium should help in this identification.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 151001] Published Mon Oct 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhen Cao &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHAASO Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mechanistic Insights into Water Autoionization through Metadynamics Simulation Enhanced by Machine Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.158001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.158001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ling Liu, Yingqi Tian, Xuanye Yang, and Chungen Liu
Machine learning-assisted metadynamics is used to study water autoionization, one of the most important properties of water for all biological and chemical process including electrolysis (related to batteries).

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 158001] Published Mon Oct 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ling Liu, Yingqi Tian, Xuanye Yang, and Chungen Liu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental study of the penetrative convection in gases]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.103501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.103501"/>
        <updated>2023-10-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Valentin Dorel, Patrice Le Gal, and Michael Le Bars
Penetrative convection is the interaction between a lower turbulent convective layer of fluid and an upper stably-stratified one. It plays a key role in the atmosphere’s dynamics and in stellar interiors. In this study, we built an experiment of penetrative convection in gases which is closer to the geophysical applications. The internal gravity waves field is studied, as well as the growth of the convective layer. In our setup, the convective layer grows quadratically in time which is strikingly different from the 1/2 exponent obtained with classical models and salted water experiments.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 103501] Published Mon Oct 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Valentin Dorel, Patrice Le Gal, and Michael Le Bars</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statistical properties of shear and nonshear velocity components in isotropic turbulence and turbulent jets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.104602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.104602"/>
        <updated>2023-10-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ryo Enoki, Tomoaki Watanabe, and Koji Nagata
Velocity fields induced by small-scale shear layers and vortex tubes in turbulence are investigated with the triple decomposition of a velocity gradient tensor. The velocity fields are reconstructed with the Biot-Savart law applied to the vorticity vectors of shear and rigid-body rotation. The key image shows a mean flow pattern of small-scale shear layers in isotropic turbulence. The velocity associated with the shear layers dominates the turbulent kinetic energy budget, scalar transport, and energy cascade in isotropic turbulence and planar jets.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 104602] Published Mon Oct 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ryo Enoki, Tomoaki Watanabe, and Koji Nagata</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fractal nature of high-order time crystal phases]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L140102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L140102"/>
        <updated>2023-10-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Guido Giachetti, Andrea Solfanelli, Lorenzo Correale, and Nicolò Defenu
In Floquet time crystals, characterized by the spontaneous breaking of time-translational invariance, observables exhibit oscillations with a period multiple p>2 of the driving. Here, a new, experimentally accessible, order parameter is introduced, able to detect time-crystalline phases regardless of the value of p. This unveils a rich landscape with self-similar fractal boundaries in the phase diagram of the long-range kicked Ising model. These features are explained within the theoretical framework, along with the emergence of the Zp symmetry in Bloch eigenstates.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L140102] Published Mon Oct 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guido Giachetti, Andrea Solfanelli, Lorenzo Correale, and Nicolò Defenu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep macroscopic pure-optical potential for laser cooling and trapping of neutral atoms]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.043107</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.043107"/>
        <updated>2023-10-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): O. N. Prudnikov, R. Ya. Ilenkov, A. V. Taichenachev, V. I. Yudin, and S. N. Bagaev
It is possible to trap neutral atoms in optical lattices without using magnetic fields, but it is currently difficult to achieve deep trapping potentials in such systems. Here, the authors propose using bichromatic light to induce an optical rectification effect that results in a strong spatial force variance and therefore deep dissipative potentials, demonstrating that such lattices could replace magneto-optical traps in neutral atom cooling and trapping applications.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 043107] Published Mon Oct 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>O. N. Prudnikov, R. Ya. Ilenkov, A. V. Taichenachev, V. I. Yudin, and S. N. Bagaev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topologically constrained fluctuations and thermodynamics regulate nonequilibrium response]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.044113</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.044113"/>
        <updated>2023-10-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gabriela Fernandes Martins and Jordan M. Horowitz
Near equilibrium, the fluctuation-dissipation theorem is an important tool in understanding how a system responds to external perturbations. Here the authors derive expressions that describe the response of physical observables outside of equilibrium, in terms of both the topology of the microscopic state space and the strength of thermodynamic driving.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 044113] Published Fri Oct 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gabriela Fernandes Martins and Jordan M. Horowitz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Near-infrared hybrid quantum photonic interface for ${}^{171}{\mathrm{Yb}}^{3+}$ solid-state qubits]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044018</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044018"/>
        <updated>2023-10-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chun-Ju Wu, Daniel Riedel, Andrei Ruskuc, Ding Zhong, Hyounghan Kwon, and Andrei Faraon
171Yb3+ ions in yttrium orthovanadate are promising candidates for building quantum networks, based on their excellent optical and spin properties and access to a secondary nuclear-spin quantum register. In this study the authors transfer GaAs photonic crystal nanobeam resonators to the surface of the host YVO4 to enhance the optical transitions of the Yb3+ ions and efficiently collect the emitted photons. This hybrid quantum photonic interface facilitates addressing of single Yb3+ ions and paves the way for the implementation of a scalable photonic architecture in the near infrared.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 044018] Published Fri Oct 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chun-Ju Wu, Daniel Riedel, Andrei Ruskuc, Ding Zhong, Hyounghan Kwon, and Andrei Faraon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Connecting cooperative transport by ants with the physics of self-propelled particles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.1.023001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.1.023001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tabea Heckenthaler, Tobias Holder, Ariel Amir, Ofer Feinerman, and Ehud Fonio
Drawing from the physics of self-propelled particles, the authors introduce a macroscopic model to describe their experiments on ants’ cooperative transport. They connected this to previous coupled-carrier models, bridging the gap from micro to macro scales.

[PRX Life 1, 023001] Published Thu Oct 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tabea Heckenthaler, Tobias Holder, Ariel Amir, Ofer Feinerman, and Ehud Fonio</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dark Matter Constraints from Isomeric $^{178m}\mathrm{Hf}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.141801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.141801"/>
        <updated>2023-10-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. S. M. Alves, S. R. Elliott, R. Massarczyk, S. J. Meijer, and H. Ramani
A search for the collisional deexcitation of metastable 178mHf puts new constraints on the parameter space of inelastic dark matter.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 141801] Published Thu Oct 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. S. M. Alves, S. R. Elliott, R. Massarczyk, S. J. Meijer, and H. Ramani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gate-Defined Topological Josephson Junctions in Bernal Bilayer Graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.146601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.146601"/>
        <updated>2023-10-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ying-Ming Xie, Étienne Lantagne-Hurtubise, Andrea F. Young, Stevan Nadj-Perge, and Jason Alicea
Gapped superconductivity emerging via intervalley coherence in bilayer graphene or monolayer WSe2 can lead to formation of Majorana zero modes.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 146601] Published Thu Oct 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ying-Ming Xie, Étienne Lantagne-Hurtubise, Andrea F. Young, Stevan Nadj-Perge, and Jason Alicea</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spatially dispersive helicity-dependent photocurrent in Dirac semimetal ${\mathrm{Cd}}_{3}{\mathrm{As}}_{2}$ nanobelts]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165405</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165405"/>
        <updated>2023-10-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bob Minyu Wang, Yuqing Zhu, Henry Clark Travaglini, Renzhi Sun, Sergey Y. Savrasov, William Hahn, Klaus van Benthem, and Dong Yu
Dirac semimetals (DSMs) have demonstrated many exotic properties, such as high carrier mobility, 3D quantum spin Hall effect, and topologically protected spin transport. However, their spin degeneracy has inhibited widespread applications in spintronics and quantum devices. Using a helicity-dependent photocurrent (HDPC), the authors demonstrate here spin generation in strain-free DSM Cd3As2 nanobelt field effect transistors at room temperature. The observed HDPC is attributed to spin-polarized Fermi arcs at the surface. This work provides key insights on light-controlled spin manipulation in Dirac materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 165405] Published Thu Oct 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bob Minyu Wang, Yuqing Zhu, Henry Clark Travaglini, Renzhi Sun, Sergey Y. Savrasov, William Hahn, Klaus van Benthem, and Dong Yu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lossless Monochromator in an Ultrafast Electron Microscope Using Near-Field THz Radiation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.145002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.145002"/>
        <updated>2023-10-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Michael Yannai, Yuval Adiv, Raphael Dahan, Kangpeng Wang, Alexey Gorlach, Nicholas Rivera, Tal Fishman, Michael Krüger, and Ido Kaminer
Researchers demonstrate a method to reduce the energy spread of electrons used in electron microscopes, opening the door to time- and energy-resolved studies of quasiparticles such as phonons and plasmons.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 145002] Published Wed Oct 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Yannai, Yuval Adiv, Raphael Dahan, Kangpeng Wang, Alexey Gorlach, Nicholas Rivera, Tal Fishman, Michael Krüger, and Ido Kaminer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Four-electron negative-$U$ vacancy defects in antimony selenide]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134102"/>
        <updated>2023-10-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xinwei Wang, Seán R. Kavanagh, David O. Scanlon, and Aron Walsh
Negative-U defects in solids break the assumption that like charges repel. The standard negative-U model describes the favorable attraction of a second electron to a defect centre. Here, the authors demonstrate an extension of negative-U behavior up to a change of four electrons. This occurs for the emerging photovoltaic compound Sb2Se3. The phenomenon is explained as a special case of valence alternation arising from the large change in structure and bonding that accompanies electron capture.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 134102] Published Wed Oct 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xinwei Wang, Seán R. Kavanagh, David O. Scanlon, and Aron Walsh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Constraints on a split superconducting transition under uniaxial strain in ${\mathrm{Sr}}_{2}{\mathrm{RuO}}_{4}$ from scanning SQUID microscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144501"/>
        <updated>2023-10-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Eli Mueller, Yusuke Iguchi, Christopher Watson, Clifford W. Hicks, Yoshiteru Maeno, and Kathryn A. Moler
Strontium ruthenate continues to draw considerable scientific interest as an unconventional superconductor. One open question is whether the superconducting order parameter has a single component or two degenerate components. Here, the authors use scanning SQUID microscopy to test for a second superconducting transition in the superfluid density under application of symmetry breaking strain, a key prediction for a system with a two-component order parameter. The reported non-observation of a second superconducting transition constrains future models of unconventional superconductivity in this fascinating material.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 144501] Published Wed Oct 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eli Mueller, Yusuke Iguchi, Christopher Watson, Clifford W. Hicks, Yoshiteru Maeno, and Kathryn A. Moler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnon-polaron driven thermal Hall effect in a Heisenberg-Kitaev antiferromagnet]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L140402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L140402"/>
        <updated>2023-10-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. Li, R. R. Neumann, S. K. Guang, Q. Huang, J. Liu, K. Xia, X. Y. Yue, Y. Sun, Y. Y. Wang, Q. J. Li, Y. Jiang, J. Fang, Z. Jiang, X. Zhao, A. Mook, J. Henk, I. Mertig, H. D. Zhou, and X. F. Sun
The thermal Hall effect, where a transverse heat current is generated in response to a longitudinal temperature gradient, probes charge-neutral excitations in insulating quantum matter. By studying thermal transport in the Heisenberg-Kitaev antiferromagnet and spin liquid candidate Na2Co2TeO6, the authors find here that magnon polarons, i.e., hybridized phonons and magnons produced by spin-lattice coupling, govern the sign and magnitude of the observed signal. This is in contrast to a pure magnon transport theory, which fails to capture important features of the experiment.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L140402] Published Wed Oct 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Li, R. R. Neumann, S. K. Guang, Q. Huang, J. Liu, K. Xia, X. Y. Yue, Y. Sun, Y. Y. Wang, Q. J. Li, Y. Jiang, J. Fang, Z. Jiang, X. Zhao, A. Mook, J. Henk, I. Mertig, H. D. Zhou, and X. F. Sun</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impact of mode regularization for quasinormal-mode perturbation theories]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.043502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.043502"/>
        <updated>2023-10-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sebastian Franke, Juanjuan Ren, and Stephen Hughes
The authors develop a regularized quasinormal-mode perturbation theory for quasinormal modes of leaky resonators, which can be used to predict the impact of weak perturbations placed outside the resonators of interest. The general method is then applied to two illustrative examples, a one-dimensional double-barrier system and a three-dimensional plasmonic dimer structure.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 043502] Published Wed Oct 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sebastian Franke, Juanjuan Ren, and Stephen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Excess Noise and Photoinduced Effects in Highly Reflective Crystalline Mirror Coatings]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041002"/>
        <updated>2023-10-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jialiang Yu, Sebastian Häfner, Thomas Legero, Sofia Herbers, Daniele Nicolodi, Chun Yu Ma, Fritz Riehle, Uwe Sterr, Dhruv Kedar, John M. Robinson, Eric Oelker, and Jun Ye
A crystalline reflective coating being considered for future gravitational-wave detectors exhibits peculiar noise features at cryogenic temperatures.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 041002] Published Tue Oct 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jialiang Yu, Sebastian Häfner, Thomas Legero, Sofia Herbers, Daniele Nicolodi, Chun Yu Ma, Fritz Riehle, Uwe Sterr, Dhruv Kedar, John M. Robinson, Eric Oelker, and Jun Ye</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Results of GERDA on the Two-Neutrino Double-$β$ Decay Half-Life of $^{76}\mathrm{Ge}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.142501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.142501"/>
        <updated>2023-10-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Agostini et al. (GERDA Collaboration)
The GERDA collaboration has made the most precise determination of the two-neutrino double-β decay half-life of 76Ge.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 142501] Published Tue Oct 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Agostini &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (GERDA Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental Demonstration to Control the Pulse Length of Coherent Undulator Radiation by Chirped Microbunching]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.145001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.145001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Takashi Tanaka, Yuichiro Kida, Satoshi Hashimoto, Shuji Miyamoto, Tadashi Togashi, Hiromitsu Tomizawa, Aoi Gocho, Keisuke Kaneshima, and Yoshihito Tanaka
A new free-electron laser (FEL) scheme that uses chirped microbunching to compress pulse length has been demonstrated, opening the path to the realization of single-cycle FELs.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 145001] Published Tue Oct 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Takashi Tanaka, Yuichiro Kida, Satoshi Hashimoto, Shuji Miyamoto, Tadashi Togashi, Hiromitsu Tomizawa, Aoi Gocho, Keisuke Kaneshima, and Yoshihito Tanaka</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fluids in Random Media and Dimensional Augmentation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.147102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.147102"/>
        <updated>2023-10-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): John Cardy
A nonrandom fluid in d dimensions with finite-range two-body potentials is precisely equivalent to one in a quenched random medium in d+2 dimensions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 147102] Published Tue Oct 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Cardy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lifting, Loading, and Buckling in Conical Shells]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.148202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.148202"/>
        <updated>2023-10-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Daniel Duffy, Joselle M. McCracken, Tayler S. Hebner, Timothy J. White, and John S. Biggins
The early failure of thin-walled cones under compression was thought to arise mainly from the presence of imperfections. A new model suggests otherwise.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 148202] Published Tue Oct 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Duffy, Joselle M. McCracken, Tayler S. Hebner, Timothy J. White, and John S. Biggins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamical Pattern Formation without Self-Attraction in Quorum-Sensing Active Matter: The Interplay between Nonreciprocity and Motility]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.148301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.148301"/>
        <updated>2023-10-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yu Duan, Jaime Agudo-Canalejo, Ramin Golestanian, and Benoît Mahault
Nonreciprocal interactions and self-propulsion lead to the formation of dynamical patterns that do not rely on self-attraction in binary mixtures of quorum-sensing active particles.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 148301] Published Tue Oct 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yu Duan, Jaime Agudo-Canalejo, Ramin Golestanian, and Benoît Mahault</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[$\mathrm{QS}G\stackrel{̂}{W}$: Quasiparticle self-consistent $GW$ with ladder diagrams in $W$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165104</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165104"/>
        <updated>2023-10-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Brian Cunningham, Myrta Grüning, Dimitar Pashov, and Mark van Schilfgaarde
The QSGŴ approximation is presented here. It is an extension to the QSGW formulation [PRB 76, 165106 (2007)] with ladder diagrams in the screening W via the Bethe-Salpeter Equation. Implemented in Questaal (https://www.questaal.org), additional short-ranged correlations in QSGŴ ameliorate much of the discrepancies with experiment for the one-body self-energy and two-body dielectric response in both simple semiconductors and correlated systems such as NiO and CoO, with a stronger effect observed for flat bands.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 165104] Published Tue Oct 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Cunningham, Myrta Grüning, Dimitar Pashov, and Mark van Schilfgaarde</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unsteady Inherent Convective Mixing in Thermal-Energy-Storage Systems during Standby Periods]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXEnergy.2.043001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXEnergy.2.043001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Henning Otto, Clemens Naumann, Christian Odenthal, and Christian Cierpka
Experimental studies of the fluid dynamics of small- and large-scale stratified-thermal-storage tanks demonstrate that inherent flow near the tank sidewalls increases mixing of the hot and cold fluid layers and decreases the energy storage efficiency.

[PRX Energy 2, 043001] Published Mon Oct 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Henning Otto, Clemens Naumann, Christian Odenthal, and Christian Cierpka</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Energy dissipation of a carbon monoxide molecule manipulated using a metallic tip on copper surfaces]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165401"/>
        <updated>2023-10-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Norio Okabayashi, Thomas Frederiksen, Alexander Liebig, and Franz J. Giessibl
The manipulation process of a single CO molecule on a copper single crystal by a metallic tip is studied here using noncontact atomic force microscopy, with dissipation energy detection, vibrational spectroscopy, and density functional theory calculations. The manipulation of the CO molecule between the two adjacent top sites is found to occur via an intermediate state of CO on the bridging site. Furthermore, this finding allows for the interpretation of static and dynamic friction at the atomic scale.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 165401] Published Mon Oct 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Norio Okabayashi, Thomas Frederiksen, Alexander Liebig, and Franz J. Giessibl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Efficient and quantum-adaptive machine learning with fermion neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044002"/>
        <updated>2023-10-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pei-Lin Zheng, Jia-Bao Wang, and Yi Zhang
Application of machine learning to quantum data and models has been held back by the lack of adaptability and efficiency in present-day neural networks. This study proposes fermion neural networks for quantum-adaptive machine learning with direct applications to complex quantum systems, and offers in situ analysis without preprocessing or presumption. An efficient optimization comparable to back propagation is established, enabling competitive performance in challenging machine-learning benchmarks. Fermion neural networks’ quantum properties, such as entanglement and correlation, also bring various advantages and insights.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 044002] Published Mon Oct 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pei-Lin Zheng, Jia-Bao Wang, and Yi Zhang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long-Lived Squeezed Ground States in a Quantum Spin Ensemble]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.133402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.133402"/>
        <updated>2023-09-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lin Xin, Maryrose Barrios, Julia T. Cohen, and Michael S. Chapman
Spin squeezed ground states of a Bose-Einstein condensate are achieved by a shortcut to adiabaticity involving Hamiltonian tuning.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 133402] Published Fri Sep 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lin Xin, Maryrose Barrios, Julia T. Cohen, and Michael S. Chapman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamical Franz-Keldysh Effect in Diamond in the Deep Ultraviolet Probed by Transient Absorption and Dispersion Spectroscopy Using a Miniature Beamline]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.136902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.136902"/>
        <updated>2023-09-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jan Reislöhner, Xiao Chen, Doyeong Kim, Silvana Botti, and Adrian N. Pfeiffer
By using a pair of offset beams, researchers are able to generate femtosecond UV pulses that can be aimed directly into a target as a spectroscopic probe.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 136902] Published Fri Sep 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jan Reislöhner, Xiao Chen, Doyeong Kim, Silvana Botti, and Adrian N. Pfeiffer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thermoelectric signatures of order-parameter symmetries in iron-based superconducting tunnel junctions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L100511</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L100511"/>
        <updated>2023-09-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Claudio Guarcello, Alessandro Braggio, Francesco Giazotto, and Roberta Citro
The authors suggest here how to unveil the symmetry of the order parameter in iron-based superconductors (FeSCs) via thermoelectricity: in the quest to unveil their specific symmetry, a groundbreaking avenue emerges. Harnessing the power of linear thermoelectric effects in low-temperature tunnel junctions with FeSCs, a novel window into the world of superconducting order parameters is opened. Dive into the realm of unconventional coupling states and discover how thermoelectric measurements can unlock the hidden complexities of Fe-based systems, with implications spanning from quantum technologies to energy harvesting. Explore the untapped potential of thermoelectricity in deciphering the puzzles of quantum materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L100511] Published Fri Sep 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claudio Guarcello, Alessandro Braggio, Francesco Giazotto, and Roberta Citro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Design and demonstration of low current density dc septum magnet]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.092401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.092401"/>
        <updated>2023-09-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hiroshi Yamaguchi, Tsutomu Taniuchi, Kenji Fukami, Yasuhiro Takemura, Tsuyoshi Aoki, Shiro Takano, and Takahiro Watanabe
A novel topology decreases the current density and power consumption of dc septum magnets.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 26, 092401] Published Fri Sep 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hiroshi Yamaguchi, Tsutomu Taniuchi, Kenji Fukami, Yasuhiro Takemura, Tsuyoshi Aoki, Shiro Takano, and Takahiro Watanabe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optical stimulated-Raman sideband spectroscopy of a single $^{9}\mathrm{Be}^{+}$ ion in a Penning trap]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033226</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033226"/>
        <updated>2023-09-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Juan M. Cornejo, Johannes Brombacher, Julia A. Coenders, Moritz von Boehn, Teresa Meiners, Malte Niemann, Stefan Ulmer, and Christian Ospelkaus
A sideband spectroscopy of a single beryllium ion in a Penning trap is demonstrated, finding a temperature of (3.1 ± 0.4) mK. This is a key step for ground-state cooling, so that motional degrees of freedom in Penning traps can be manipulated at the single-quantum level for quantum logic applications and precision measurements.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 033226] Published Thu Sep 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Juan M. Cornejo, Johannes Brombacher, Julia A. Coenders, Moritz von Boehn, Teresa Meiners, Malte Niemann, Stefan Ulmer, and Christian Ospelkaus</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hamiltonian Ratchet for Matter-Wave Transport]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.133401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.133401"/>
        <updated>2023-09-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. Dupont, L. Gabardos, F. Arrouas, N. Ombredane, J. Billy, B. Peaudecerf, and D. Guéry-Odelin
Researchers have turned an optical lattice into a ratchet that moves atoms from one site to the next.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 133401] Published Thu Sep 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Dupont, L. Gabardos, F. Arrouas, N. Ombredane, J. Billy, B. Peaudecerf, and D. Guéry-Odelin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental and numerical investigations on rotor noise in axial descending flight]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.094803</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.094803"/>
        <updated>2023-09-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuhong Li, Xiangtian Li, Han Wu, Peng Zhou, Xin Zhang, and Siyang Zhong
We investigate the aerodynamic and aeroacoustic characteristics of a small-scale drone rotor operating in axial descending flight. The integrated aerodynamic forces and the far-field noise are measured by wind tunnel experiments. Then, near-field flow structures and corresponding noise source analysis are presented based on computational aeroacoustics (CAA) simulations. We found the unique acoustic feature of descending flight is the haystacking-like spectral humps, possibly caused by the interaction between the blade leading edge and the rotor wake.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 094803] Published Thu Sep 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuhong Li, Xiangtian Li, Han Wu, Peng Zhou, Xin Zhang, and Siyang Zhong</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How well do we know the primordial black hole abundance: The crucial role of nonlinearities when approaching the horizon]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.063531</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.063531"/>
        <updated>2023-09-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Valerio De Luca, Alex Kehagias, and Antonio Riotto
Recent pulsar timing array data suggest the presence of stochastic gravitational waves, implying a significant amplitude in curvature perturbations and thus a large abundance of primordial black holes (PBH). The latter is at odds with the observed constraints on the PBH abundance. The authors scrutinize in detail the standard calculation and approximations in determining the PBH abundance and point out several uncertainties, concluding that the PBH abundance is likely much smaller than what is the current consensus.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 063531] Published Thu Sep 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Valerio De Luca, Alex Kehagias, and Antonio Riotto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tuning Arrays with Rays: Physics-Informed Tuning of Quantum Dot Charge States]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034067</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034067"/>
        <updated>2023-09-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Joshua Ziegler, Florian Luthi, Mick Ramsey, Felix Borjans, Guoji Zheng, and Justyna P. Zwolak
Many methods to automatically tune silicon spin qubits are limited by reliability and data efficiency, which makes them less likely to be scalable. The authors demonstrate a reliable, efficient, physics-informed tuning algorithm (PIT) for navigating to a target charge configuration⏤a prerequisite to forming qubits. This tuning method combines machine learning and physical intuition with an algorithm that leverages one-dimensional scans (rays) and conventional peak-finding to navigate from a coarse, unknown device state to a desired charge occupation efficiently and effectively. PIT enables the transformation of an uncalibrated circuit to a functioning quantum processor.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 034067] Published Thu Sep 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joshua Ziegler, Florian Luthi, Mick Ramsey, Felix Borjans, Guoji Zheng, and Justyna P. Zwolak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of Integer and Fractional Quantum Anomalous Hall Effects in Twisted Bilayer ${\mathrm{MoTe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031037</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031037"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fan Xu, Zheng Sun, Tongtong Jia, Chang Liu, Cheng Xu, Chushan Li, Yu Gu, Kenji Watanabe, Takashi Taniguchi, Bingbing Tong, Jinfeng Jia, Zhiwen Shi, Shengwei Jiang, Yang Zhang, Xiaoxue Liu, and Tingxin Li
Direct evidence of the integer and fractional quantum anomalous Hall effects in twisted bilayer MoTe2 paves the way for studies of fractionally charged excitations at zero magnetic field in semiconductor moiré materials.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 031037] Published Wed Sep 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fan Xu, Zheng Sun, Tongtong Jia, Chang Liu, Cheng Xu, Chushan Li, Yu Gu, Kenji Watanabe, Takashi Taniguchi, Bingbing Tong, Jinfeng Jia, Zhiwen Shi, Shengwei Jiang, Yang Zhang, Xiaoxue Liu, and Tingxin Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing complex stacking in a layered material via electron-nuclear quadrupolar coupling]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.L091001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.L091001"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Li Cheng, Linpeng Nie, Xuanyu Long, Li Liang, Dan Zhao, Jian Li, Zheng Liu, Tao Wu, Xianhui Chen, Wenhui Duan, and Xiaolong Zou
The combination of nuclear magnetic resonance with first-principles calculations uncovers the stacking patterns of layers of a quantum material—information that could enable a deeper understanding of the material’s behavior.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, L091001] Published Wed Sep 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Li Cheng, Linpeng Nie, Xuanyu Long, Li Liang, Dan Zhao, Jian Li, Zheng Liu, Tao Wu, Xianhui Chen, Wenhui Duan, and Xiaolong Zou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zero-Field Composite Fermi Liquid in Twisted Semiconductor Bilayers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.136501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.136501"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hart Goldman, Aidan P. Reddy, Nisarga Paul, and Liang Fu
Certain twisted semiconductor bilayers are predicted to host a Fermi liquid of composite fermions—remarkably, without an applied magnetic field.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 136501] Published Wed Sep 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hart Goldman, Aidan P. Reddy, Nisarga Paul, and Liang Fu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Composite Fermi Liquid at Zero Magnetic Field in Twisted ${\mathrm{MoTe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.136502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.136502"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Junkai Dong, Jie Wang, Patrick J. Ledwith, Ashvin Vishwanath, and Daniel E. Parker
Certain twisted semiconductor bilayers are predicted to host a Fermi liquid of composite fermions—remarkably, without an applied magnetic field.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 136502] Published Wed Sep 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Junkai Dong, Jie Wang, Patrick J. Ledwith, Ashvin Vishwanath, and Daniel E. Parker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drafting of two passive swimmer scale models for open-water races]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.094802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.094802"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): B. Bolon, C. Pretot, C. Clanet, F. Larrarte, and R. Carmigniani
We examined interactions in water channels between swimmer-shaped objects moving at different speeds. Results showed that the ideal place for drafting is at the hip of a neighboring swimmer or just behind a lead swimmer. The former reduces drag by 30% and the latter reduces drag by 40%. Results were confirmed by CFD simulations.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 094802] Published Wed Sep 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>B. Bolon, C. Pretot, C. Clanet, F. Larrarte, and R. Carmigniani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gravitational lensing effect on cosmic birefringence]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.063525</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.063525"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fumihiro Naokawa and Toshiya Namikawa
This paper takes into account the effect of Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) gravitational lensing on the Cosmic Birefringence linear polarization rotation angle. It thus paves the way to more accurate interpretation of future-mission data that will seek signatures of Axion-like Particles.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 063525] Published Wed Sep 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fumihiro Naokawa and Toshiya Namikawa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Semiconductor-Quantum-Dot Modulator for Cryogenic Operation of Quantum Circuitry]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034066</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034066"/>
        <updated>2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. R. Hogg, M.G. House, P. Pakkiam, and M.Y. Simmons
Quantum computing devices have the potential to solve problems that are beyond even the most powerful modern supercomputers. Most quantum hardware operates at temperatures near absolute zero, but controlling a quantum computer at cryogenic temperatures using signals propagating from room temperature becomes infeasible for large-scale processors. The authors explore a device that allows control signals to be generated on-chip at cryogenic temperatures, potentially mitigating this cryogenic bottleneck. Their device is fabricated in silicon using established technologies for quantum processors, providing a pathway towards a hybrid quantum-classical integrated circuit.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 034066] Published Wed Sep 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. R. Hogg, M.G. House, P. Pakkiam, and M.Y. Simmons</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bose Polaron Interactions in a Cavity-Coupled Monolayer Semiconductor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031036</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031036"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Li Bing Tan, Oriana K. Diessel, Alexander Popert, Richard Schmidt, Atac Imamoglu, and Martin Kroner
Resonant excitation of a thin-film semiconductor leads to impurities that attract rather than repel each other, providing a possible tool for manipulating superconductivity.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 031036] Published Tue Sep 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Li Bing Tan, Oriana K. Diessel, Alexander Popert, Richard Schmidt, Atac Imamoglu, and Martin Kroner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of New ${\mathrm{Ω}}_{c}^{0}$ States Decaying to the ${\mathrm{Ξ}}_{c}^{+}{K}^{−}$ Final State]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.131902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.131902"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Aaij et al. (LHCb Collaboration)
A precise measurement finds two new Ωc0 baryons, in addition to confirming the existence of five previously observed Ωc0 baryons.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 131902] Published Tue Sep 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Aaij &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHCb Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Constraints on the superconducting state of ${\text{Sr}}_{2}{\text{RuO}}_{4}$ from elastocaloric measurements]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.094516</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.094516"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Grgur Palle, Clifford Hicks, Roser Valentí, Zhenhai Hu, You-Sheng Li, Andreas Rost, Michael Nicklas, Andrew P. Mackenzie, and Jörg Schmalian
In the longstanding quest to determine the symmetry of the superconducting state of Sr2RuO4, this paper exploits recent elastocaloric experiments to narrow down the possibilities down to a handful of options. By analyzing the elastocaloric data, the authors show that a normal-state maximum in the entropy becomes a minimum in the superconducting state. Through modeling of the associated Lifshitz transition, they extract information about the momentum-space structure of the pairing gap function, yielding constraints on the viable pairing states.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 094516] Published Tue Sep 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grgur Palle, Clifford Hicks, Roser Valentí, Zhenhai Hu, You-Sheng Li, Andreas Rost, Michael Nicklas, Andrew P. Mackenzie, and Jörg Schmalian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep thermalization in constrained quantum systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.104317</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.104317"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tanmay Bhore, Jean-Yves Desaules, and Zlatko Papić
Generic quantum systems thermalize as entanglement builds up between a subsystem and its complement. Performing measurements on a complementary subsystem, however, can reveal finer nuances in the system’s ability to thermalize. The authors show here that systems that look ‘thermal’ under the lens of the Eigenstate Thermalization Hypothesis (ETH) can be highly ‘nonthermal’ when probed deeper. They illustrate this finding on several constrained models that describe slow relaxation in quantum glasses and quantum many-body scars in Rydberg atom arrays.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 104317] Published Tue Sep 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tanmay Bhore, Jean-Yves Desaules, and Zlatko Papić</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interface-enhanced room-temperature Curie temperature in $\mathrm{CrP}{\mathrm{S}}_{4}\text{/}\text{graphene}$ van der Waals heterostructure]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L100406</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L100406"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wenxuan Zhu, Cheng Song, Lei Han, Hua Bai, Chong Chen, and Feng Pan
The authors experimentally show here that the Curie temperature of van der Waals CrPS4 is elevated from 40 K up to room temperature by the interfacial effect from graphene. The compatible Fermi level between CrPS4 and graphene enables sufficient interfacial charge transfer across their atomically fine interface, leading to promoted exchange coupling and higher Curie temperature of CrPS4 without the participation of strong spin-orbit coupling. The enhanced magnetism of CrPS4 further induces room-temperature exchange splitting in graphene by the magnetic proximity effect.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L100406] Published Tue Sep 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wenxuan Zhu, Cheng Song, Lei Han, Hua Bai, Chong Chen, and Feng Pan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum Wigner molecules in moiré materials]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L121411</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L121411"/>
        <updated>2023-09-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Constantine Yannouleas and Uzi Landman
Quantum Wigner molecules (WMs) in strongly interacting few-body fermionic moiré quantum dots in twisted bilayers of transition metal dichalcogenide (TMD) materials are uncovered via full configuration interaction calculations, going beyond the Aufbau principle of natural atoms and Hubbard modeling. Nested polygonal sliding rings of localized fermions, hidden in the exact particle densities, are revealed through wavefunction correlation analysis [see (3,9) and (1,6,10) electron WMs in 2D semiconductors], broadening the WM portfolio to include the TMD trilobal symmetry as an added resource in twistronics, and providing benchmarks for AI-based many-body computations.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L121411] Published Tue Sep 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Constantine Yannouleas and Uzi Landman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Static Black Binaries in de Sitter Space]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.131401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.131401"/>
        <updated>2023-09-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Óscar J. C. Dias, Gary W. Gibbons, Jorge E. Santos, and Benson Way
Black holes may be less unique than previously thought, as the expansion due to a cosmological constant can hold apart a pair of holes and allow them to mimic a single black hole.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 131401] Published Mon Sep 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Óscar J. C. Dias, Gary W. Gibbons, Jorge E. Santos, and Benson Way</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gallium neutrino absorption cross section and its uncertainty]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.035502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.035502"/>
        <updated>2023-09-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. R. Elliott, V. N. Gavrin, W. C. Haxton, T. V. Ibragimova, and E. J. Rule
The 71Ga radiochemical experiments provided the first constraint on the flux of low-energy electron neutrinos coming from the Sun. Crucial neutrino calibration experiments, however, using intense β-decay sources, yielded rates below that predicted by theory. A recent effort to check the “gallium anomaly” using a more intense source exacerbated the discrepancy. This paper carefully reexamines the nuclear physics of neutrino absorption on 71Ga, slightly reducing but not eliminating the puzzling anomaly.

[Phys. Rev. C 108, 035502] Published Mon Sep 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. R. Elliott, V. N. Gavrin, W. C. Haxton, T. V. Ibragimova, and E. J. Rule</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phase diagram of the $\mathrm{SU}\text{(}N\text{)}$ antiferromagnet of spin $S$ on a square lattice]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115151</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115151"/>
        <updated>2023-09-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jonas Schwab, Francesco Parisen Toldin, and Fakher F. Assaad
Spin systems are a fundamental concept in condensed matter and statistical physics. Here, the authors provide the very first computation of the spin-S SU(N) antiferromagnet in a representation amenable to negative sign free fermion Monte Carlo simulations. They offer a numerical proof of the seminal works of Read and Sachdev. It highlights the close connection between topology and the melting of the quantum antiferromagnet, with the Berry phase explaining the various states observed in the vicinity of the quantum antiferromagnet.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 115151] Published Mon Sep 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonas Schwab, Francesco Parisen Toldin, and Fakher F. Assaad</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raman Probing the Local Ultrastrong Coupling of Vibrational Plasmon Polaritons on Metallic Gratings]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.126902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.126902"/>
        <updated>2023-09-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rakesh Arul, Kishan Menghrajani, Marie S. Rider, Rohit Chikkaraddy, William L. Barnes, and Jeremy J. Baumberg
Using a metallic grating and infrared light, researchers have uncovered a light–matter coupling regime where the local coupling strength can be 3.5 times higher than the global average for the material.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 126902] Published Fri Sep 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rakesh Arul, Kishan Menghrajani, Marie S. Rider, Rohit Chikkaraddy, William L. Barnes, and Jeremy J. Baumberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological Metadefects: Tangles of Dislocations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.128101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.128101"/>
        <updated>2023-09-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pawel Pieranski, Mehdi Zeghal, Maria Helena Godinho, Patrick Judeinstein, Rémi Bouffet-Klein, Bastien Liagre, and Nicodème Rouger
Two or more linear defects can twist around one another to form an entity that may affect the properties of a material.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 128101] Published Fri Sep 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pawel Pieranski, Mehdi Zeghal, Maria Helena Godinho, Patrick Judeinstein, Rémi Bouffet-Klein, Bastien Liagre, and Nicodème Rouger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hexadecapole axial collectivity in the rare earth region: A beyond-mean-field study]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.034312</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.034312"/>
        <updated>2023-09-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. V. Nithish Kumar and L. M. Robledo
Understanding the interplay between the intrinsic shape of nuclei and the dynamics of their low-lying collective states is one of the most pressing challenges in contemporary nuclear structure physics. Within the framework of the generator coordinate method with a Gogny interaction, this paper highlights the important role of hexadecapole deformation in several isotopes of the rare earth region. These features could also have an impact on the evaluation of neutrinoless double-β decay nuclear matrix elements and on heavy ion collision dynamics. The study highlights that the physics touched by considering the hexadecapole degree of freedom is not trivial, and its study is worth further consideration.

[Phys. Rev. C 108, 034312] Published Fri Sep 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. V. Nithish Kumar and L. M. Robledo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electromagnetically-induced-transparency spectra of Rydberg atoms dressed with dual-tone radio-frequency fields]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.033712</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.033712"/>
        <updated>2023-09-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maitreyi Jayaseelan, Andrew P. Rotunno, Nikunjkumar Prajapati, Samuel Berweger, Alexandra B. Artusio-Glimpse, Matthew T. Simons, and Christopher L. Holloway
Rydberg atoms driven by radio-frequency (rf) fields can be used as very sensitive electric-field detectors. Here, the authors extend this concept to dual-frequency rf fields, and show that their theoretical modeling and experimental results match.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 033712] Published Fri Sep 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maitreyi Jayaseelan, Andrew P. Rotunno, Nikunjkumar Prajapati, Samuel Berweger, Alexandra B. Artusio-Glimpse, Matthew T. Simons, and Christopher L. Holloway</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Spinning Black Holes Balanced by Their Synchronized Scalar Hair]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.121401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.121401"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Carlos A. R. Herdeiro and Eugen Radu
When general relativity is coupled to bosonic matter, two spinning black holes can in principle form a stable molecule with quantum effects balancing gravitational effects.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 121401] Published Thu Sep 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carlos A. R. Herdeiro and Eugen Radu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gravitational-Wave Phasing of Quasicircular Compact Binary Systems to the Fourth-and-a-Half Post-Newtonian Order]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.121402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.121402"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Luc Blanchet, Guillaume Faye, Quentin Henry, François Larrouturou, and David Trestini
A collective effort involving various theoretical frameworks results in the successful gravitational wave phasing of nonspinning compact binary systems on quasicircular orbits up to the 4.5 post-Newtonian order.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 121402] Published Thu Sep 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luc Blanchet, Guillaume Faye, Quentin Henry, François Larrouturou, and David Trestini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Isotopic Control of the Boron-Vacancy Spin Defect in Hexagonal Boron Nitride]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.126901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.126901"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Clua-Provost, A. Durand, Z. Mu, T. Rastoin, J. Fraunié, E. Janzen, H. Schutte, J. H. Edgar, G. Seine, A. Claverie, X. Marie, C. Robert, B. Gil, G. Cassabois, and V. Jacques
Engineered purification of certain hBN crystals may provide an optimal host material for boron-vacancy spin defects in quantum technology.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 126901] Published Thu Sep 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Clua-Provost, A. Durand, Z. Mu, T. Rastoin, J. Fraunié, E. Janzen, H. Schutte, J. H. Edgar, G. Seine, A. Claverie, X. Marie, C. Robert, B. Gil, G. Cassabois, and V. Jacques</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Packing spheres in high dimensions with moderate computational effort]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.034117</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.034117"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Veit Elser
An algorithm originally developed for imaging generates useful data for a problem in pure mathematics.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 034117] Published Thu Sep 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Veit Elser</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mesoscopic critical fluctuations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.034212</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.034212"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Saikat Banerjee and Nikolai A. Sinitsyn
A system can be made to show critical behavior in a mesoscopic region by introducing a smooth spatial variation of a control parameter around its critical value. The authors investigate this situation using a minimal model based on the Ginzburg-Landau effective free-energy approach.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 034212] Published Thu Sep 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Saikat Banerjee and Nikolai A. Sinitsyn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gravitational-wave flux and quadrupole modes from quasicircular nonspinning compact binaries to the fourth post-Newtonian order]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.064041</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.064041"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Luc Blanchet, Guillaume Faye, Quentin Henry, François Larrouturou, and David Trestini
A collective effort involving various theoretical frameworks results in the successful gravitational wave phasing of nonspinning compact binary systems on quasicircular orbits up to the 4.5 post-Newtonian order.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 064041] Published Thu Sep 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luc Blanchet, Guillaume Faye, Quentin Henry, François Larrouturou, and David Trestini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis of a Skyrme energy density functional with deep learning]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.034311</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.034311"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. Hizawa, K. Hagino, and K. Yoshida
Adapting a technique recently developed in atomic electron systems to nuclear physics, the authors employ a deep-learning method to analyze a Skyrme energy density functional (Skyrme-EDF) with the goal to construct an orbital-free functional that depends only on the particle density distribution. In a first step they compute the energy and particle densities of a nucleus using the Skyrme Kohn-Sham + Bardeen-Cooper-Schrieffer method. With those sets of data and a deep-learning approach they then train an orbital-free functional. When applied to the 24Mg nucleus, the newly constructed functional successfully reproduces the binding energy of the original Skyrme-EDF, with an accuracy of about 40 keV. The significant computational advantage compared to traditional EDF approaches promises useful alternatives for future applications such as for calculating more complex nuclear shapes in heavy and superheavy nuclei.

[Phys. Rev. C 108, 034311] Published Thu Sep 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Hizawa, K. Hagino, and K. Yoshida</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robust intralayer antiferromagnetism and tricriticality in the van der Waals compound $\mathrm{V}{\mathrm{Br}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.104416</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.104416"/>
        <updated>2023-09-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dávid Hovančík, Marie Kratochvílová, Tetiana Haidamak, Petr Doležal, Karel Carva, Anežka Bendová, Jan Prokleška, Petr Proschek, Martin Míšek, Denis I. Gorbunov, Jan Kotek, Vladimír Sechovský, and Jiří Pospíšil
Here, the authors report strongly anisotropic uniaxial antiferromagnetism in the van der Waals trihalide VBr3, with a tricritical point in the H-T phase diagram in out-of-plane field. The robustness of the antiferromagnetic state manifested by a high critical metamagnetic field is explained by ab initio calculations that predict a zigzag antiferromagnetic order of V moments described within the J1-J2-J3 model. The observed saturated moment of 1.2 μB/f.u. indicates a significant vanadium orbital moment that is the main ingredient of the strong anisotropy.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 104416] Published Thu Sep 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dávid Hovančík, Marie Kratochvílová, Tetiana Haidamak, Petr Doležal, Karel Carva, Anežka Bendová, Jan Prokleška, Petr Proschek, Martin Míšek, Denis I. Gorbunov, Jan Kotek, Vladimír Sechovský, and Jiří Pospíšil</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamical Information Synergy in Biochemical Signaling Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.128401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.128401"/>
        <updated>2023-09-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lauritz Hahn, Aleksandra M. Walczak, and Thierry Mora
The concurrent analysis of two measurements of a biochemical signaling network can provide more information than two separate probes of the datasets.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 128401] Published Wed Sep 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauritz Hahn, Aleksandra M. Walczak, and Thierry Mora</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jackiw-Teitelboim gravity with matter, generalized eigenstate thermalization hypothesis, and random matrices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.066015</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.066015"/>
        <updated>2023-09-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Daniel Louis Jafferis, David K. Kolchmeyer, Baur Mukhametzhanov, and Julian Sonner
It was conjectured that a particular two-dimensional gravity, Jackiw–Teitelboim (JT) gravity, is dual to a single-trace one-matrix Random Matrix Model (RMM). The authors extend this duality to JT gravity minimally coupled to a free massive scalar field and a single-trace two-matrix model. They study in detail the matching of genus zero one- and two-boundary expectation values in the matrix model to the gravitational disk correlators.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 066015] Published Wed Sep 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Louis Jafferis, David K. Kolchmeyer, Baur Mukhametzhanov, and Julian Sonner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variational Monte Carlo study of symmetric mass generation in a bilayer honeycomb lattice model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125130</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125130"/>
        <updated>2023-09-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wanda Hou and Yi-Zhuang You
This paper investigates the symmetric mass generation transition in a bilayer honeycomb lattice model using variational Monte Carlo simulations. By measuring the fermion scaling dimension at the critical point, the authors provide evidence for fermion fractionalization into deconfined emergent particles, supporting the hypothesis that the transition is a fermionic deconfined quantum critical point. The numerical results, including the critical exponent and fermion dimension, agree with theoretical predictions.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 125130] Published Wed Sep 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wanda Hou and Yi-Zhuang You</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Network Effects Lead to Self-Organization in Metabolic Cycles of Self-Repelling Catalysts]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.128301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.128301"/>
        <updated>2023-09-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vincent Ouazan-Reboul, Ramin Golestanian, and Jaime Agudo-Canalejo
Catalytically active particles form clusters when they respond not only to their own chemical targets but to those of other catalysts, too.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 128301] Published Tue Sep 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vincent Ouazan-Reboul, Ramin Golestanian, and Jaime Agudo-Canalejo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ac Josephson effect in a gate-tunable ${\mathrm{Cd}}_{3}{\mathrm{As}}_{2}$ nanowire superconducting weak link]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.094514</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.094514"/>
        <updated>2023-09-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Haller, M. Osterwalder, G. Fülöp, J. Ridderbos, M. Jung, and C. Schönenberger
Experimental signatures of topological superconductivity have been notoriously difficult to verify, even though they are actively being researched. Here, the authors use nanowires of Cd3As2 – a Dirac semimetal – to hunt for these signatures by simultaneously looking at Josephson radiation and Shapiro patterns at different doping levels. By cross-checking the experimental results with an extensive (RCSJ) model that includes thermal noise, it is concluded that trivial supercurrent dominates and that topological supercurrent, if existent, falls below the detection limit of the setup.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 094514] Published Tue Sep 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Haller, M. Osterwalder, G. Fülöp, J. Ridderbos, M. Jung, and C. Schönenberger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental demonstration of splitting rules for exceptional points and their topological characterization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115427</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115427"/>
        <updated>2023-09-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yi-Xin Xiao, Jing Hu, Zhao-Qing Zhang, and C. T. Chan
This work establishes clear relationships between how exceptional points of varying orders split and which parts of the system are perturbed. Additionally, two topological invariants are identified to fully characterize the various splitting behavior. These findings provide a comprehensive understanding of how exceptional points split in various non-Hermitian systems, and can help optimize the performance of sensors that rely on exceptional points.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 115427] Published Tue Sep 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yi-Xin Xiao, Jing Hu, Zhao-Qing Zhang, and C. T. Chan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Laser-Induced Cavitation for Controlling Crystallization from Solution]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.124001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.124001"/>
        <updated>2023-09-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nagaraj Nagalingam, Aswin Raghunathan, Vikram Korede, Christian Poelma, Carlas S. Smith, Remco Hartkamp, Johan T. Padding, and Hüseyin Burak Eral
High-speed microscope measurements show the nucleation and growth of single KCl crystals at the inner container wall of a supersaturated solution where submillimeter cavitation bubbles are generated by incident laser pulses.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 124001] Published Mon Sep 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nagaraj Nagalingam, Aswin Raghunathan, Vikram Korede, Christian Poelma, Carlas S. Smith, Remco Hartkamp, Johan T. Padding, and Hüseyin Burak Eral</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two-body problem in theories with kinetic screening]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.064033</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.064033"/>
        <updated>2023-09-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mateja Bošković and Enrico Barausse
Due to non-linearities, the two body problem in tensor-scalar theory with kinetic screening is notoriously difficult to solve. In this work, the authors present an analytical solution to this problem and validate it with numerical simulations. They demonstrate that the efficiency of the screening depends on the mass ratio of the two bodies.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 064033] Published Mon Sep 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mateja Bošković and Enrico Barausse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Small Fermi Pockets Intertwined with Charge Stripes and Pair Density Wave Order in a Kagome Superconductor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031030</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031030"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hong Li, Dongjin Oh, Mingu Kang, He Zhao, Brenden R. Ortiz, Yuzki Oey, Shiang Fang, Zheng Ren, Chris Jozwiak, Aaron Bostwick, Eli Rotenberg, Joseph G. Checkelsky, Ziqiang Wang, Stephen D. Wilson, Riccardo Comin, and Ilija Zeljkovic
The observation of Fermi “pockets” in the Fermi surface of exotic superconductors provides a major step toward explaining some mysterious electronic states.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 031030] Published Fri Sep 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hong Li, Dongjin Oh, Mingu Kang, He Zhao, Brenden R. Ortiz, Yuzki Oey, Shiang Fang, Zheng Ren, Chris Jozwiak, Aaron Bostwick, Eli Rotenberg, Joseph G. Checkelsky, Ziqiang Wang, Stephen D. Wilson, Riccardo Comin, and Ilija Zeljkovic</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tunable Crossed Andreev Reflection and Elastic Cotunneling in Hybrid Nanowires]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031031</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031031"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alberto Bordin, Guanzhong Wang, Chun-Xiao Liu, Sebastiaan L. D. ten Haaf, Nick van Loo, Grzegorz P. Mazur, Di Xu, David van Driel, Francesco Zatelli, Sasa Gazibegovic, Ghada Badawy, Erik P. A. M. Bakkers, Michael Wimmer, Leo P. Kouwenhoven, and Tom Dvir
A demonstration that certain electron-transport processes can be tuned in a hybrid semiconductor-superconductor system could be useful for developing quantum computers

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 031031] Published Fri Sep 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alberto Bordin, Guanzhong Wang, Chun-Xiao Liu, Sebastiaan L. D. ten Haaf, Nick van Loo, Grzegorz P. Mazur, Di Xu, David van Driel, Francesco Zatelli, Sasa Gazibegovic, Ghada Badawy, Erik P. A. M. Bakkers, Michael Wimmer, Leo P. Kouwenhoven, and Tom Dvir</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Determination of the Thermomigration Force on Adatoms]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116202"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): F. Leroy, A. El Barraj, F. Cheynis, P. Müller, and S. Curiotto
The slow drift of microscale features on a surface reveals the force driving atoms from the hot to the cold side of the material.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116202] Published Fri Sep 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>F. Leroy, A. El Barraj, F. Cheynis, P. Müller, and S. Curiotto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topology, criticality, and dynamically generated qubits in a stochastic measurement-only Kitaev model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.094304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.094304"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Adithya Sriram, Tibor Rakovszky, Vedika Khemani, and Matteo Ippoliti
Even in the absence of unitary evolution, measurements alone can induce a rich variety of dynamical phases and phenomena in many-body quantum systems. Inspired by the Kitaev honeycomb Hamiltonian, a paradigmatic model of topological physics, the authors construct here a stochastic measurement-only dynamics on a honeycomb lattice and show that it hosts distinct entanglement phases, including phases that protect topological qubits for an exponential amount of time and a critical phase with exotic dynamical scaling.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 094304] Published Fri Sep 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adithya Sriram, Tibor Rakovszky, Vedika Khemani, and Matteo Ippoliti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monitored quantum dynamics and the Kitaev spin liquid]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115135</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.115135"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ali Lavasani, Zhu-Xi Luo, and Sagar Vijay
The authors study the quantum dynamics of a (2+1)D monitored random circuit involving local projective measurements, inspired by the physics of the Kitaev quantum spin liquid. A Majorana parton description of the dynamics reveals a close connection between the entanglement dynamics of quantum trajectories and the 3D classical fully packed loop model. The authors uncover a critical phase where quantum trajectories exhibit long-range entanglement with a logarithmic (L log L) violation of the area law, and a topologically ordered phase reminiscent of the toric code phase.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 115135] Published Fri Sep 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ali Lavasani, Zhu-Xi Luo, and Sagar Vijay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetohydrodynamic boundary conditions for the two-dimensional fermion gas]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125305</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125305"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): O. E. Raichev
In the hydrodynamic regime of electron transport, the distribution of electrical currents and potentials inside a conductor are determined by the Navier-Stokes equation with boundary conditions. The derivation of the boundary conditions from kinetic theory includes both an approximate approach, expressing them through the electronic viscosity, and a more accurate approach, implying numerical solution of the Boltzmann equation. With magnetic field, the results of the two approaches are considerably different when the mean free path length determined by electron-electron collisions is comparable to the cyclotron radius.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 125305] Published Fri Sep 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>O. E. Raichev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unavoidability of nonclassicality loss in $\mathcal{PT}$-symmetric systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.033512</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.033512"/>
        <updated>2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jan Peřina, Jr., Adam Miranowicz, Joanna K. Kalaga, and Wiesław Leoński
The authors study the dynamics of two nonlinearly coupled oscillator modes in a PT-symmetric system, in which gain and loss are provided by coupling a pair of bosonic modes to separate baths. The authors show that even when the model parameters are fine-tuned to achieve a balance between gain and loss in the semiclassical limit, the fluctuations of the bath lead to a gradual loss of nonclassicality and entanglement between the modes.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 033512] Published Fri Sep 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jan Peřina, Jr., Adam Miranowicz, Joanna K. Kalaga, and Wiesław Leoński</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prevailing Charge Order in Overdoped ${\mathrm{La}}_{2−x}{\mathrm{Sr}}_{x}{\mathrm{CuO}}_{4}$ beyond the Superconducting Dome]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116002"/>
        <updated>2023-09-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Qizhi Li, Hsiao-Yu Huang, Tianshuang Ren, Eugen Weschke, Lele Ju, Changwei Zou, Shilong Zhang, Qingzheng Qiu, Jiarui Liu, Shuhan Ding, Amol Singh, Oleksandr Prokhnenko, Di-Jing Huang, Ilya Esterlis, Yao Wang, Yanwu Xie, and Yingying Peng
Resonant x-ray scattering measurements reveal the existence of charge ordering in the high-temperature cuprate superconductor, La2−xSrxCuO4, well beyond the expected levels of doping concentrations.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116002] Published Thu Sep 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qizhi Li, Hsiao-Yu Huang, Tianshuang Ren, Eugen Weschke, Lele Ju, Changwei Zou, Shilong Zhang, Qingzheng Qiu, Jiarui Liu, Shuhan Ding, Amol Singh, Oleksandr Prokhnenko, Di-Jing Huang, Ilya Esterlis, Yao Wang, Yanwu Xie, and Yingying Peng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Direct Observation of Topological Phonons in Graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116602"/>
        <updated>2023-09-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jiade Li, Jiangxu Li, Jilin Tang, Zhiyu Tao, Siwei Xue, Jiaxi Liu, Hailin Peng, Xing-Qiu Chen, Jiandong Guo, and Xuetao Zhu
New experiments reveal graphene’s exotic phonon spectrum with unprecedented detail and completeness.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116602] Published Thu Sep 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jiade Li, Jiangxu Li, Jilin Tang, Zhiyu Tao, Siwei Xue, Jiaxi Liu, Hailin Peng, Xing-Qiu Chen, Jiandong Guo, and Xuetao Zhu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic excitations in $5{d}^{4}\phantom{\rule{4pt}{0ex}}J=0\phantom{\rule{4pt}{0ex}}{\mathrm{Os}}^{4+}$ halides studied by resonant inelastic x-ray scattering and optical spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125120</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125120"/>
        <updated>2023-09-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): P. Warzanowski, M. Magnaterra, P. Stein, G. Schlicht, Q. Faure, Ch. J. Sahle, T. Lorenz, P. Becker, L. Bohatý, M. Moretti Sala, G. Monaco, P. H. M. van Loosdrecht, and M. Grüninger
The cubic halides K2OsCl6, K2OsBr6, and Rb2OsBr6 are found to be excellent realizations of spin-orbit-entangled nonmagnetic J=0 compounds in the intermediate coupling regime. The two complementary techniques of resonant inelastic x-ray scattering and optical spectroscopy allow the authors to draw a comprehensive picture of the electronic excitations and to assess the electronic structure. The accurate set of electronic parameters such as spin-orbit coupling, Hund’s coupling, crystal-field splitting, Mott gap, and charge-transfer energy will serve as a solid reference for future studies on Os compounds.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 125120] Published Thu Sep 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>P. Warzanowski, M. Magnaterra, P. Stein, G. Schlicht, Q. Faure, Ch. J. Sahle, T. Lorenz, P. Becker, L. Bohatý, M. Moretti Sala, G. Monaco, P. H. M. van Loosdrecht, and M. Grüninger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phonon-mediated dark to bright plasmon conversion]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125417</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125417"/>
        <updated>2023-09-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Benjamin Rousseaux, Yanko Todorov, Angela Vasanelli, and Carlo Sirtori
Unlocking the full potential of nanophotonic devices involves the engineering of their intrinsic optical properties. Here, the authors investigate a quantum theory that treats the interaction between quantum-confined plasmons and optical phonons in semiconductors. This theory allows computation of the optical response beyond the conventional Drude-Lorentz model. In particular, it predicts new effects, such as an oscillator-strength transfer mechanism between phonons and dark plasmon modes.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 125417] Published Thu Sep 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin Rousseaux, Yanko Todorov, Angela Vasanelli, and Carlo Sirtori</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strongly anisotropic spin and orbital Rashba effect at a tellurium – noble metal interface]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L121107</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L121107"/>
        <updated>2023-09-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): B. Geldiyev, M. Ünzelmann, P. Eck, T. Kißlinger, J. Schusser, T. Figgemeier, P. Kagerer, N. Tezak, M. Krivenkov, A. Varykhalov, A. Fedorov, L. Nicolaï, J. Minár, K. Miyamoto, T. Okuda, K. Shimada, D. Di Sante, G. Sangiovanni, L. Hammer, M. A. Schneider, H. Bentmann, and F. Reinert
The orbital Rashba effect describes the formation of chiral orbital angular momentum textures upon inversion symmetry breaking at surfaces or interfaces. Here, the authors unveil a pronounced anisotropic spin-orbit splitting with a Rashba-type spin polarization in the electronic interface states in the model system Te/Au(100). Exploring the momentum-dependent response of inversion symmetry breaking, they particularly demonstrate that the orbital texture leads to a strongly anisotropic spin and orbital Rashba effect. These findings will provide a valuable contribution to the discovery and understanding of future “orbitronic” phenomena.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L121107] Published Thu Sep 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>B. Geldiyev, M. Ünzelmann, P. Eck, T. Kißlinger, J. Schusser, T. Figgemeier, P. Kagerer, N. Tezak, M. Krivenkov, A. Varykhalov, A. Fedorov, L. Nicolaï, J. Minár, K. Miyamoto, T. Okuda, K. Shimada, D. Di Sante, G. Sangiovanni, L. Hammer, M. A. Schneider, H. Bentmann, and F. Reinert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long-Lived Singlet State in an Oriented Phase and its Survival across the Phase Transition Into an Isotropic Phase]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034030</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034030"/>
        <updated>2023-09-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vishal Varma and T.S. Mahesh
Long-lived states (LLSs) in nuclear magnetic resonance have diverse applications, from medical imaging to chemical analysis to quantum information processing, but were hitherto observed primarily in isotropic phases. The authors prepare LLS in an anisotropic environment of a liquid crystal and observe its survival across the phase transition to the isotropic phase. This study could pave the way for trapping LLS in the symmetric spin pair of an isotropic phase after breaking symmetry in an anisotropic phase, and motivate the realization of LLS in the solid phase, which will have implications for solid-state qubits toward achieving longer lifetimes in addition to long-range interactions.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 034030] Published Thu Sep 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vishal Varma and T.S. Mahesh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimality Pressures toward Lateralization of Complex Brain Functions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031028</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031028"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Luís F. Seoane
A mathematical model shows how increased intricacy of cognitive tasks can break the mirror symmetry of the brain’s neural network.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 031028] Published Wed Sep 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luís F. Seoane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Floquet Engineering of Black Phosphorus upon Below-Gap Pumping]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116401"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shaohua Zhou, Changhua Bao, Benshu Fan, Fei Wang, Haoyuan Zhong, Hongyun Zhang, Peizhe Tang, Wenhui Duan, and Shuyun Zhou
Light-induced band engineering in black phosphorus by pumping below the band gap is experimentally demonstrated, which might extend Floquet engineering to more quantum materials.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116401] Published Wed Sep 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shaohua Zhou, Changhua Bao, Benshu Fan, Fei Wang, Haoyuan Zhong, Hongyun Zhang, Peizhe Tang, Wenhui Duan, and Shuyun Zhou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enhancement of Second-Order Non-Hermitian Skin Effect by Magnetic Fields]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116601"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chang-An Li, Björn Trauzettel, Titus Neupert, and Song-Bo Zhang
The second-order non-Hermitian skin effect is robust and can even be enhanced by magnetic fields, which is in contrast to the first-order non-Hermitian skin effect.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116601] Published Wed Sep 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chang-An Li, Björn Trauzettel, Titus Neupert, and Song-Bo Zhang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental Observation of Critical Scaling in Magnetic Dynamic Phase Transitions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116701"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Quintana and A. Berger
Magneto-optical experiments on ultrathin uniaxial cobalt films reveal (for the first time) critical behavior in such systems, and also show indications of dimensional crossover, with the films exhibiting 2D dynamical and 3D thermodynamic behavior.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116701] Published Wed Sep 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Quintana and A. Berger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>