<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-03-23T00:52:00.124Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-03-23T00:52:00.124Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coupling between vortex flow and whisker sensor in cylinder wakes with time-varying streamwise gaps]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.034701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.034701"/>
        <updated>2023-03-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pengyao Gong, Dhanush Bhamitipadi Suresh, and Yaqing Jin
The flow-induced vibration of a whisker in the wake of a movable circular cylinder with time-varying streamwise gaps is experimentally investigated to understand how whiskers detect variations in the swimming status of an upstream target. The results show that whisker sensitivity to gap growth rates gradually decreases when such growth rates become sufficiently high, regardless of initial gaps. From the integrated experimental measurements and theoretical model, the reduction of whisker sensitivity under high gap growth rates can be attributed to sufficiently strong vortices initiated by fast movement of the upstream cylinder, which compensate vortex strength decay due to the gap growth.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 034701] Published Wed Mar 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pengyao Gong, Dhanush Bhamitipadi Suresh, and Yaqing Jin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three-dimensional tomographic imaging of the magnetization vector field using Fourier transform holography]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.094425</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.094425"/>
        <updated>2023-03-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marisel Di Pietro Martínez, Alexis Wartelle, Carlos Herrero Martínez, Farid Fettar, Florent Blondelle, Jean-François Motte, Claire Donnelly, Luke Turnbull, Feodor Ogrin, Gerrit van der Laan, Horia Popescu, Nicolas Jaouen, Flora Yakhou-Harris, and Guillaume Beutier
The authors present a new tomographic technique, based on Fourier transform holography. It is a lensless imaging technique to retrieve the object of interest from its diffraction pattern in a single step of computation. A combination of dual-axis tomographic projections provides a 3D vectorial magnetic image of an 800-nm-thick Fe/Gd multilayer in a 5-μm-diameter field of view with a resolution of 80 nm. The reconstruction reveals not only wormlike domains with magnetization pointing mostly out of plane, but also the subtle features of magnetic flux closure around the domain walls.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 094425] Published Wed Mar 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marisel Di Pietro Martínez, Alexis Wartelle, Carlos Herrero Martínez, Farid Fettar, Florent Blondelle, Jean-François Motte, Claire Donnelly, Luke Turnbull, Feodor Ogrin, Gerrit van der Laan, Horia Popescu, Nicolas Jaouen, Flora Yakhou-Harris, and Guillaume Beutier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generalized multifractality in two-dimensional disordered systems of chiral symmetry classes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104202"/>
        <updated>2023-03-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jonas F. Karcher, Ilya A. Gruzberg, and Alexander D. Mirlin
Anderson transitions between metals and insulators exhibit fascinating spatial structure, fluctuations, and correlations of electronic wave functions. This structure has been properly characterized by the authors in terms of multifractals with continuous spectra of scaling exponents. In this paper, the authors focus on Anderson transitions in systems with a sublattice (chiral) symmetry. This particular class of Anderson transitions has not been well-studied in the past, and the authors fill this gap with a thorough analytical and numerical study of multifractal spectra in the metallic phase and at the critical point of the Anderson transition.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 104202] Published Wed Mar 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonas F. Karcher, Ilya A. Gruzberg, and Alexander D. Mirlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin-orbital order and excitons in magnetoresistive HoBi]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104423</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104423"/>
        <updated>2023-03-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Gaudet, H.-Y. Yang, E. M. Smith, T. Halloran, J. P. Clancy, J. A. Rodriguez-Rivera, Guangyong Xu, Y. Zhao, W. C. Chen, G. Sala, A. A. Aczel, B. D. Gaulin, F. Tafti, and C. Broholm
The rare-earth monopnictides RX have been found to exhibit exotic topological three-dimensional states, coupled to unique magnetotransport responses such as extreme magnetoresistance. These findings generated interest to understand the interplay between electronic band topology, transport, and magnetism in RX. While neutron scattering is indispensable to fully characterize magnetism, there is very little modern work on this family of compounds. Since the details of the magnetism have a profound impact on the electronic band topology and transport in materials, the authors present here a thorough characterization of the magnetism in HoBi, based on modern neutron scattering techniques.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 104423] Published Wed Mar 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Gaudet, H.-Y. Yang, E. M. Smith, T. Halloran, J. P. Clancy, J. A. Rodriguez-Rivera, Guangyong Xu, Y. Zhao, W. C. Chen, G. Sala, A. A. Aczel, B. D. Gaulin, F. Tafti, and C. Broholm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accuracy of quantum simulators with ultracold dipolar molecules: A quantitative comparison between continuum and lattice descriptions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.033323</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.033323"/>
        <updated>2023-03-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Michael Hughes, Axel U. J. Lode, Dieter Jaksch, and Paolo Molignini
The authors perform a quantitative comparison between the continuum description of a one-dimensional gas of dipolar bosons in an optical lattice and the single-band Bose-Hubbard lattice model that it simulates. Discrepancies are found in regimes with strong dipole-dipole interactions and high densities in the continuum system.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 033323] Published Wed Mar 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Hughes, Axel U. J. Lode, Dieter Jaksch, and Paolo Molignini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Many-Body Description of STM-Induced Fluorescence of Charged Molecules]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.126202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.126202"/>
        <updated>2023-03-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Song Jiang, Tomáš Neuman, Rémi Bretel, Alex Boeglin, Fabrice Scheurer, Eric Le Moal, and Guillaume Schull
Spatial maps of the light emitted by an excited molecule reveal how the emission depends on the molecule’s charge states.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 126202] Published Tue Mar 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Song Jiang, Tomáš Neuman, Rémi Bretel, Alex Boeglin, Fabrice Scheurer, Eric Le Moal, and Guillaume Schull</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum oscillations in the centrosymmetric skyrmion-hosting magnet ${\mathrm{GdRu}}_{2}{\mathrm{Si}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104421</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104421"/>
        <updated>2023-03-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. Matsuyama, T. Nomura, S. Imajo, T. Nomoto, R. Arita, K. Sudo, M. Kimata, N. D. Khanh, R. Takagi, Y. Tokura, S. Seki, K. Kindo, and Y. Kohama
The skyrmion formation mechanism in centrosymmetric systems remains to be understood, partially because of the lack of fundamental understanding of the electronic structure. The authors observe de Haas–van Alphen and Shubnikov–de Haas oscillations in high magnetic fields up to 58 T on GdRu2Si2, which is one of such centrosymmetric skyrmion-hosting magnets with the shortest skyrmion diameter ever found. Combined with first-principles calculations, the authors now reveal the electronic structure of GdRu2Si2 and its reconstruction at the magnetic phase boundary.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 104421] Published Tue Mar 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Matsuyama, T. Nomura, S. Imajo, T. Nomoto, R. Arita, K. Sudo, M. Kimata, N. D. Khanh, R. Takagi, Y. Tokura, S. Seki, K. Kindo, and Y. Kohama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First-principles theory of the pressure-induced invar effect in FeNi alloys]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104422</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104422"/>
        <updated>2023-03-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Amanda Ehn, Björn Alling, and Igor A. Abrikosov
Beside the classic Fe64Ni36 Invar alloy, which shows an anomalously low thermal expansion at ambient pressure, Fe-Ni alloys with a higher nickel composition can be driven to Invar behavior by pressure. The authors investigate the pressure induced Invar effect theoretically and demonstrate that it can be explained by a magnetic transition from a ferromagnetic state at high volume to a complex noncollinear state upon compression. They relate the Invar effect to the increasing contribution of magnetic entropy with pressure.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 104422] Published Tue Mar 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amanda Ehn, Björn Alling, and Igor A. Abrikosov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valley-Tunable Even-Denominator Fractional Quantum Hall State in the Lowest Landau Level of an Anisotropic System]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.126301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.126301"/>
        <updated>2023-03-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Md. Shafayat Hossain, Meng K. Ma, Y. J. Chung, S. K. Singh, A. Gupta, K. W. West, K. W. Baldwin, L. N. Pfeiffer, R. Winkler, and M. Shayegan
An in-plane magnetic field and valley occupancy can tune phase transitions in an even-denominator quantum Hall regime.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 126301] Published Mon Mar 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Md. Shafayat Hossain, Meng K. Ma, Y. J. Chung, S. K. Singh, A. Gupta, K. W. West, K. W. Baldwin, L. N. Pfeiffer, R. Winkler, and M. Shayegan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enzyme-Enriched Condensates Show Self-Propulsion, Positioning, and Coexistence]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.128401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.128401"/>
        <updated>2023-03-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Leonardo Demarchi, Andriy Goychuk, Ivan Maryshev, and Erwin Frey
Phase separation within cells creates droplets whose chemical activity leads to surprising mobility that serves cellular function and hints at the origin of life.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 128401] Published Mon Mar 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leonardo Demarchi, Andriy Goychuk, Ivan Maryshev, and Erwin Frey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strong lateral exchange coupling and current-induced switching in single-layer ferrimagnetic films with patterned compensation temperature]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L100412</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L100412"/>
        <updated>2023-03-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zhentao Liu, Zhaochu Luo, Ivan Shorubalko, Christof Vockenhuber, Laura J. Heyderman, Pietro Gambardella, and Aleš Hrabec
Interlayer couplings are widely used in spintronic devices based on magnetic multilayers. Here, the authors demonstrate instead a strong tunable coupling between adjacent regions of a single ferrimagnetic layer, based on the exchange interaction. They unveil a large lateral exchange bias by spatially patterning the compensation temperature of the ferrimagnet. Furthermore, they show electrical switching of ferrimagnetic domains utilizing the lateral exchange coupling mechanism in combination with spin-orbit torques.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L100412] Published Mon Mar 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhentao Liu, Zhaochu Luo, Ivan Shorubalko, Christof Vockenhuber, Laura J. Heyderman, Pietro Gambardella, and Aleš Hrabec</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Precision Measurement of the Microwave Dielectric Loss of Sapphire in the Quantum Regime with Parts-per-Billion Sensitivity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034064</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034064"/>
        <updated>2023-03-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexander P. Read, Benjamin J. Chapman, Chan U Lei, Jacob C. Curtis, Suhas Ganjam, Lev Krayzman, Luigi Frunzio, and Robert J. Schoelkopf
To better understand decoherence in superconducting qubits, the authors develop a technique to measure the loss tangent of dielectric substrates and predict the impact of dielectric loss on qubit lifetimes. This is done with no need to fabricate planar devices; the technique is independent of material platform. Measurements of sapphire in a demonstration of the approach suggest that coherence of superconducting qubits on a common form of sapphire is limited significantly by bulk dielectric loss. The same technique also shows that another form of sapphire would substantially mitigate this bulk dielectric loss and prolong qubit coherence.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 034064] Published Mon Mar 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexander P. Read, Benjamin J. Chapman, Chan U Lei, Jacob C. Curtis, Suhas Ganjam, Lev Krayzman, Luigi Frunzio, and Robert J. Schoelkopf</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anisotropic acoustics in dipolar Fermi gases]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.033321</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.033321"/>
        <updated>2023-03-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Reuben R. W. Wang and John L. Bohn
The authors theoretically study the propagation of plane wave modes in ultracold dipolar Fermi gases in the hydrodynamic limit, including collisions and mean-field dipolar interactions. The authors find that longitudinal waves present anisotropies in both the speed of sound and damping. In addition, two types of shear waves are predicted, which could be used as an experimental means to measure the viscosity coefficients.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 033321] Published Mon Mar 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuben R. W. Wang and John L. Bohn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stacking domain morphology in epitaxial graphene on silicon carbide]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.034001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.034001"/>
        <updated>2023-03-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tobias A. de Jong, Luuk Visser, Johannes Jobst, Ruud M. Tromp, and Sense Jan van der Molen
Despite being considered homogeneous and uniform, graphene grown on silicon carbide has been found to contain a vast network of stacking domains and dislocations. These are formed due to the strain field between graphene and the substrate, and their spatial orientations and shapes arise from minute variations therein. In this work, the authors used low-energy electron microscopy and moire pattern analysis to map out local variations in orientation, strain, and dislocation distribution. This creates a better understanding of the growth process of graphene on silicon carbide (and similar two-dimensional materials) to enable their use in practical applications.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 034001] Published Fri Mar 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tobias A. de Jong, Luuk Visser, Johannes Jobst, Ruud M. Tromp, and Sense Jan van der Molen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switchable Explosives: Performance Tuning of Fluid-Activated High Explosive Architectures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.116105</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.116105"/>
        <updated>2023-03-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Cameron B. Brown, Alexander H. Mueller, Seetharaman Sridhar, Joseph P. Lichthardt, Andrew M. Schmalzer, Bryce C. Tappan, Von H. Whitley, Larry G. Hill, Eduardo Lozano, and Tariq D. Aslam
An explosive material fabricated with a highly porous structure is inactive but is easily “switched on” when filled with water.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 116105] Published Fri Mar 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cameron B. Brown, Alexander H. Mueller, Seetharaman Sridhar, Joseph P. Lichthardt, Andrew M. Schmalzer, Bryce C. Tappan, Von H. Whitley, Larry G. Hill, Eduardo Lozano, and Tariq D. Aslam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Single-Molecule Force Spectroscopy Reveals Cation-$π$ Interactions in Aqueous Media Are Highly Affected by Cation Dehydration]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.118101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.118101"/>
        <updated>2023-03-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Weishuai Di, Kai Xue, Jun Cai, Zhenshu Zhu, Zihan Li, Hui Fu, Hai Lei, Wenbing Hu, Chun Tang, Wei Wang, and Yi Cao
Researchers have developed a method for measuring the strength of certain ion–electron interactions in water, with initial tests throwing up unexpected results.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 118101] Published Fri Mar 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weishuai Di, Kai Xue, Jun Cai, Zhenshu Zhu, Zihan Li, Hui Fu, Hai Lei, Wenbing Hu, Chun Tang, Wei Wang, and Yi Cao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Binary geometries, generalized particles and strings, and cluster algebras]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.066015</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.066015"/>
        <updated>2023-03-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nima Arkani-Hamed, Song He, Thomas Lam, and Hugh Thomas
The authors study the fundamental properties of scattering amplitudes of particles in any spacetime dimension. They introduce binary geometries, giving a completely rigid geometric realization of the combinatorics of generalized associahedra attached to any Dynkin diagram. Furthermore, they define open and closed “cluster string integrals”, which provide a generalization of particle and string scattering amplitudes, and enjoy remarkable factorization properties at finite α′.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 066015] Published Fri Mar 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nima Arkani-Hamed, Song He, Thomas Lam, and Hugh Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Higher-order topological superconductivity in twisted bilayer graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.094512</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.094512"/>
        <updated>2023-03-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aaron Chew, Yijie Wang, B. Andrei Bernevig, and Zhi-Da Song
Twisted bilayer graphene, by nature of its symmetries (like the approximate particle-hole symmetry) and anomalous band structure, realizes a higher-order topological superconductor when s-wave pairing is introduced via proximity. Here, the authors demonstrate this exotic phase numerically and analytically, and illustrate a multitude of consequences: zero modes bound to Abrikosov vortices, the fractional Josephson effect, and much more.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 094512] Published Fri Mar 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aaron Chew, Yijie Wang, B. Andrei Bernevig, and Zhi-Da Song</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin and orbital metallic magnetism in rhombohedral trilayer graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L121405</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L121405"/>
        <updated>2023-03-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chunli Huang, Tobias M. R. Wolf, Wei Qin, Nemin Wei, Igor V. Blinov, and Allan H. MacDonald
Lightly doped multilayer graphene surprised researchers with the emergence of superconductivity and magnetism under strong electric displacement fields. The authors interpret the displacement field versus hole-density phase diagram using mean-field theory and experimentally informed band structure. They find that magnetism in these electronic systems is often intertwined with nematic order because of the noncompact Fermi sea topology and fourfold spin-valley degeneracy.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L121405] Published Fri Mar 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chunli Huang, Tobias M. R. Wolf, Wei Qin, Nemin Wei, Igor V. Blinov, and Allan H. MacDonald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robust quantum control with disorder-dressed evolution]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.032609</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.032609"/>
        <updated>2023-03-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tenzan Araki, Franco Nori, and Clemens Gneiting
Quantum control pulses, used to produce desired states in quantum technology applications, can be problematically sensitive to disorder. Here, the authors develop a systematic approach to finding quantum control pulses that are robust in realistic scenarios by translating disorder into a quantum master equation and maximizing the purity of the resulting density matrix.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 032609] Published Fri Mar 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tenzan Araki, Franco Nori, and Clemens Gneiting</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Helical Locomotion in Yield Stress Fluids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.114002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.114002"/>
        <updated>2023-03-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Farshad Nazari, Kourosh Shoele, and Hadi Mohammadigoushki
If a helical bacteria’s tail propulsion is strong enough to deform the yield-stress fluid ahead of the swimmer, locomotion proceeds.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 114002] Published Thu Mar 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Farshad Nazari, Kourosh Shoele, and Hadi Mohammadigoushki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lattice dynamics and in-plane antiferromagnetism in ${\mathrm{Mn}}_{x}{\mathrm{Zn}}_{1−x}{\mathrm{PS}}_{3}$ across the entire composition range]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104415</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104415"/>
        <updated>2023-03-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Robert Oliva, Esther Ritov, Faris Horani, Iñigo Etxebarria, Adam K. Budniak, Yaron Amouyal, Efrat Lifshitz, and Mael Guennou
Antiferromagnetic MnPS3 and diamagnetic ZnPS3 belong to a family of two-dimensional compounds that exhibit a rich variety of magnetic ordering. Low-temperature Raman spectroscopy and SQUID magnetometer measurements are performed on both compounds and their alloy in order to evaluate a possible Jahn-Teller distortion as well as to reveal magnetic and alloy signatures. With the aid of first-principles calculations, a description of the lattice dynamics of the system is presented, together with the magnetic phase diagram across the entire compositional range.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 104415] Published Thu Mar 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Oliva, Esther Ritov, Faris Horani, Iñigo Etxebarria, Adam K. Budniak, Yaron Amouyal, Efrat Lifshitz, and Mael Guennou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interplay of structure and magnetism in ${\mathrm{LuFe}}_{4}{\mathrm{Ge}}_{2}$ tuned by hydrostatic pressure]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125136</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125136"/>
        <updated>2023-03-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. O. Ajeesh, P. Materne, R. D. dos Reis, K. Weber, S. Dengre, R. Sarkar, R. Khasanov, I. Kraft, A. M. León, W. Bi, J. Zhao, E. E. Alp, S. Medvedev, V. Ksenofontov, H. Rosner, H.-H. Klauss, C. Geibel, and M. Nicklas
Competing ground states often lead to the emergence of novel unconventional phases. The presence of magnetic frustration in such materials brings about additional complexity. Here, the authors present a comprehensive study on the ground-state properties of LuFe4Ge2, a ternary intermetallic compound with magnetic frustration and quasi-one-dimensional structure, elucidating the interplay of structure and magnetism. In contrast to the well-studied two-dimensional iron pnictides with competing exchange interactions, LuFe4Ge2 exhibits quasi-one-dimensional chains of geometrically frustrated Fe tetrahedra. It displays a magnetostructural transition at ambient pressure with a change in symmetry from tetragonal to orthorhombic, similar to that in the iron-pnictides, which evolves in an unexpected way under the application of hydrostatic pressure. In that way the intermetallic LuFe4Ge2 material family offers a new perspective on the entanglement of crystal structure and magnetism.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 125136] Published Thu Mar 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. O. Ajeesh, P. Materne, R. D. dos Reis, K. Weber, S. Dengre, R. Sarkar, R. Khasanov, I. Kraft, A. M. León, W. Bi, J. Zhao, E. E. Alp, S. Medvedev, V. Ksenofontov, H. Rosner, H.-H. Klauss, C. Geibel, and M. Nicklas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological nature of dislocation networks in two-dimensional moiré materials]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125413</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125413"/>
        <updated>2023-03-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rebecca Engelke, Hyobin Yoo, Stephen Carr, Kevin Xu, Paul Cazeaux, Richard Allen, Andres Mier Valdivia, Mitchell Luskin, Efthimios Kaxiras, Minhyong Kim, Jung Hoon Han, and Philip Kim
Twisted bilayers of two-dimensional materials contain a moiré superatomic lattice domain that can be bounded by a domain boundary network. The authors show here that the nodes of this network can be considered topological defects. While the nodes in previously studied twisted moiré materials are vortices, the authors discover antivortices formed in strained moiré systems using transmission electron micrographs. This work provides insight into the underlying rules governing moiré structures, inspiring the construction of new types of moiré interfaces.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 125413] Published Thu Mar 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Engelke, Hyobin Yoo, Stephen Carr, Kevin Xu, Paul Cazeaux, Richard Allen, Andres Mier Valdivia, Mitchell Luskin, Efthimios Kaxiras, Minhyong Kim, Jung Hoon Han, and Philip Kim</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parallel Assembly of Arbitrary Defect-Free Atom Arrays with a Multitweezer Algorithm]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034048</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034048"/>
        <updated>2023-03-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Weikun Tian, Wen Jun Wee, An Qu, Billy Jun Ming Lim, Prithvi Raj Datla, Vanessa Pei Wen Koh, and Huanqian Loh
A new algorithm can organize hundreds of atoms into pristine patterns—including a honeycomb lattice, a fractal called a Sierpiński triangle, and a lion’s head.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 034048] Published Wed Mar 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weikun Tian, Wen Jun Wee, An Qu, Billy Jun Ming Lim, Prithvi Raj Datla, Vanessa Pei Wen Koh, and Huanqian Loh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disordered Heterogeneous Universe: Galaxy Distribution and Clustering across Length Scales]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011038</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011038"/>
        <updated>2023-03-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Oliver H. E. Philcox and Salvatore Torquato
A new methodology for analyzing the 3D distribution of galaxies borrows techniques from the study of colloids and other disordered materials.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 011038] Published Tue Mar 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver H. E. Philcox and Salvatore Torquato</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal Quantum Rewinding Protocol with an Arbitrarily High Probability of Success]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.110201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.110201"/>
        <updated>2023-03-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. Trillo, B. Dive, and M. Navascués
A new technique for reversing the evolution of a quantum system could become a key tool in quantum information technology.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 110201] Published Tue Mar 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. Trillo, B. Dive, and M. Navascués</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological band inversion in HgTe(001): Surface and bulk signatures from photoemission]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L121102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L121102"/>
        <updated>2023-03-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Raphael C. Vidal, Giovanni Marini, Lukas Lunczer, Simon Moser, Lena Fürst, Julia Issing, Chris Jozwiak, Aaron Bostwick, Eli Rotenberg, Charles Gould, Hartmut Buhmann, Wouter Beugeling, Giorgio Sangiovanni, Domenico Di Sante, Gianni Profeta, Laurens W. Molenkamp, Hendrik Bentmann, and Friedrich Reinert
HgTe is a prime example of a topological material that exhibits a range of topological phases based on its dimensionality and lattice strain. The key to its topological properties lies in the band inversion between the Hg 6s and Te 5p valence levels, leading to the emergence of surface states. In this study, the authors present an in-depth examination of the electronic structure of strained HgTe films using angle-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy and density functional theory. The results offer a direct visualization of the topological band inversion and surface states present in HgTe.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L121102] Published Tue Mar 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Raphael C. Vidal, Giovanni Marini, Lukas Lunczer, Simon Moser, Lena Fürst, Julia Issing, Chris Jozwiak, Aaron Bostwick, Eli Rotenberg, Charles Gould, Hartmut Buhmann, Wouter Beugeling, Giorgio Sangiovanni, Domenico Di Sante, Gianni Profeta, Laurens W. Molenkamp, Hendrik Bentmann, and Friedrich Reinert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic Excitation Response of DNA to High-Energy Proton Radiation in Water]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.118401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.118401"/>
        <updated>2023-03-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christopher Shepard, Dillon C. Yost, and Yosuke Kanai
A study of the electron excitation response of DNA to proton radiation has elucidated mechanisms of damage incurred during proton radiotherapy.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 118401] Published Mon Mar 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher Shepard, Dillon C. Yost, and Yosuke Kanai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conserved currents for a Kerr black hole and orthogonality of quasinormal modes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.064030</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.064030"/>
        <updated>2023-03-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Stephen R. Green, Stefan Hollands, Laura Sberna, Vahid Toomani, and Peter Zimmerman
Using a symmetry of the Kerr spacetime, the authors determine an original bilinear form for perturbations of the Weyl scalars. They show that upon choosing appropriate integration contours, this form can also be used on quasi-normal mode data. This manuscript provides a formalism for studying ringdown beyond the leading order, with potential application to numerical relativity and gravitational wave observation.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 064030] Published Mon Mar 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen R. Green, Stefan Hollands, Laura Sberna, Vahid Toomani, and Peter Zimmerman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theoretical investigation of charge transfer between two defects in a wide band gap semiconductor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125305</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125305"/>
        <updated>2023-03-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rodrick Kuate Defo, Alejandro W. Rodriguez, Efthimios Kaxiras, and Steven L. Richardson
In calculating the concentrations of the charge states of various defects, the Fermi level is generally assumed to be uniform throughout a semiconductor. The authors establish the timescales involved in thermally driven charge transfer, ultimately refuting the assumption of Fermi-level uniformity on the timescales over which optically detected magnetic resonance (ODMR) spectroscopy experiments are typically performed for NV centers in diamond. Their results reveal the potential for noninvasive determination of defect distances and average defect concentrations through ODMR spectroscopy.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 125305] Published Mon Mar 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rodrick Kuate Defo, Alejandro W. Rodriguez, Efthimios Kaxiras, and Steven L. Richardson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Appropriate Mechanical Confinement Inhibits Multipolar Cell Division via Pole-Cortex Interaction]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011036</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011036"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Longcan Cheng, Jingchen Li, Houbo Sun, and Hongyuan Jiang
Segregation of chromosomes in dividing cells can be disrupted if the cells are constrained by their surroundings.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 011036] Published Fri Mar 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Longcan Cheng, Jingchen Li, Houbo Sun, and Hongyuan Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin, Charge, and $η$-Spin Separation in One-Dimensional Photodoped Mott Insulators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.106501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.106501"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuta Murakami, Shintaro Takayoshi, Tatsuya Kaneko, Andreas M. Läuchli, and Philipp Werner
A derivation of the exact expression for the wave function of photodoped metastable states in one-dimensional Mott insulators shows that these systems host a number of correlations among the active degrees freedom, such as spin, charge and η-spin separation.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 106501] Published Fri Mar 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuta Murakami, Shintaro Takayoshi, Tatsuya Kaneko, Andreas M. Läuchli, and Philipp Werner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statistical analysis of initial-state and final-state response in heavy-ion collisions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.034905</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.034905"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nicolas Borghini, Marc Borrell, Nina Feld, Hendrik Roch, Sören Schlichting, and Clemens Werthmann
High-energy nuclear collisions are analyzed theoretically using multistage models assembled to simulate the different stages of the reaction. This paper presents a new method for systematically characterizing the early-time density of a heavy-ion collision system. It is then used to analyze events from different models as well as the system response to these initial conditions. This method will help distinguish between different approaches to describing the dynamics of relativistic heavy-ion collisions at very early times.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, 034905] Published Fri Mar 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicolas Borghini, Marc Borrell, Nina Feld, Hendrik Roch, Sören Schlichting, and Clemens Werthmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Structure of charge density waves in ${\mathrm{La}}_{1.875}{\mathrm{Ba}}_{0.125}{\mathrm{CuO}}_{4}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115125</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115125"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Sears, Y. Shen, M. J. Krogstad, H. Miao, E. S. Bozin, I. K. Robinson, G. D. Gu, R. Osborn, S. Rosenkranz, J. M. Tranquada, and M. P. M. Dean
The cuprate superconductors exhibit periodic modulations of their charge density and crystal structure. Using x-ray diffraction, the authors identify the subtle structural displacements associated with this ordering. The displacements are not confined to a single copper-oxygen layer but rather propagate over a surprisingly large distance through the crystal. The authors attribute this effect to the weak c-axis charge screening in cuprates and suggest that this effect could help couple the charge-density wave between adjacent planes in the crystal.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 115125] Published Fri Mar 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Sears, Y. Shen, M. J. Krogstad, H. Miao, E. S. Bozin, I. K. Robinson, G. D. Gu, R. Osborn, S. Rosenkranz, J. M. Tranquada, and M. P. M. Dean</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin polarization of exciton-polariton condensate in a photonic synthetic effective magnetic field]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125303</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125303"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Mirek, M. Furman, M. Król, B. Seredyński, K. Łempicka-Mirek, K. Tyszka, W. Pacuski, M. Matuszewski, J. Szczytko, and B. Piętka
The authors investigate here the spin polarization of localized exciton-polariton condensates in CdTe-based microcavities doped with magnetic ions. They demonstrate that an effective magnetic field originating from the photonic potential landscape leads to the formation of elliptically polarized condensate. The degree of spin polarization of the condensate depends on the excitation power and polarization of the laser. Based on the magnetic field behavior of the condensate in the presence of magnetic ions, they estimate the polariton-polariton interaction strength in a CdTe system.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 125303] Published Fri Mar 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Mirek, M. Furman, M. Król, B. Seredyński, K. Łempicka-Mirek, K. Tyszka, W. Pacuski, M. Matuszewski, J. Szczytko, and B. Piętka</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minimal one-dimensional model of bad metal behavior from fast particle-hole scattering]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L100301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L100301"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yan-Qi Wang, Roman Rausch, Christoph Karrasch, and Joel E. Moore
The authors propose here a mechanism and an explicit one-dimensional model to realize the linear-in-temperature resistivity that is the hallmark of bad metals. They then verify the behavior with advanced DMRG-type simulations. These results open a new approach to understanding the limits of relaxation generated by local interactions in extended many-body systems. This work should push forward research into understanding some of the most basic questions about transport for 1D and critical systems, which bridge quantum matter and quantum chaos.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L100301] Published Fri Mar 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yan-Qi Wang, Roman Rausch, Christoph Karrasch, and Joel E. Moore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electron-Beam Source with a Superconducting Niobium Tip]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034036</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034036"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C.W. Johnson, A.K. Schmid, M. Mankos, R. Röpke, N. Kerker, I.S. Hwang, E.K. Wong, D.F. Ogletree, A.M. Minor, and A. Stibor
Electron-beam sources are foundational in high-resolution electron microscopy and spectroscopy, but applications have been limited due to their relatively large energy spread. The authors fabricate a monocrystalline niobium nanotip electron field emitter and characterize it in superconducting and normal-conducting regimes. This bright, stable, coherent electron beam source features an exceptionally narrow energy spread. The authors also study the role of xenon adsorption and two-electron correlations. This work may improve aberration-corrected microscopy and electron energy-loss spectroscopy and enable high-resolution vibrational spectroscopy or quantum electron microscopy.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 034036] Published Fri Mar 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C.W. Johnson, A.K. Schmid, M. Mankos, R. Röpke, N. Kerker, I.S. Hwang, E.K. Wong, D.F. Ogletree, A.M. Minor, and A. Stibor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Macroscopic quantum electrodynamics theory of resonance energy transfer involving chiral molecules]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.032809</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.032809"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Janine Christine Franz, Stefan Yoshi Buhmann, and A. Salam
The authors develop an approach for studying resonant energy transfer between two chiral molecules embedded in a homogeneous medium as a means for chiral discrimination. They find that the degree of discrimination is usually larger for large intermolecular distances, and can be modified by modifying the surrounding medium.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 032809] Published Fri Mar 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Janine Christine Franz, Stefan Yoshi Buhmann, and A. Salam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Role of geometry and adhesion in droplet freezing dynamics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.033601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.033601"/>
        <updated>2023-03-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lila Seguy, Suzie Protiere, and Axel Huerre
We propose a thermal and geometrical analytical model for the freezing front dynamics of a spherical drop. The growth is characterized by an effective diffusion coefficient that increases as the substrate temperature decreases and a spherical front that meets the edges of the drop perpendicularly. We compare our model with experimental data for substrate temperature ranging from -9 to -80 °C. We highlight the importance of heat diffusion in the liquid and the adhesion of drops to the substrate that decreases at low temperature.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 033601] Published Thu Mar 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lila Seguy, Suzie Protiere, and Axel Huerre</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Assignment of excitonic insulators in <i>ab initio</i> theories: The case of ${\mathrm{NiBr}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115121</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115121"/>
        <updated>2023-03-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Stefano Di Sabatino, Alejandro Molina-Sánchez, Pina Romaniello, and Davide Sangalli
The determination of an excitonic insulator phase relies on the relative value of the excitonic binding energy and the fundamental band gap. With the quite unique case of NiBr2, the authors warn about the risk of running into false positives when using the GW+BSE scheme to determine if a system displays negative excitonic energies, which are a signature of an excitonic insulator phase. They show that consistency between approximations used in the ground-state and excited-state calculations as well as independence from the starting point are essential features for a proper description of excitonic insulators.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 115121] Published Thu Mar 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stefano Di Sabatino, Alejandro Molina-Sánchez, Pina Romaniello, and Davide Sangalli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linear Regression and Machine Learning for Nuclear Forensics of Spent Fuel from Six Types of Nuclear Reactors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034028</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034028"/>
        <updated>2023-03-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shengli Chen, Tianxiang Wang, Zhong Zhang, Runfeng Li, Su Yuan, Ruiyi Zhang, Cenxi Yuan, Chunyu Zhang, and Jianyu Zhu
A new set of diagnostic techniques developed from experimental data will improve authorities’ ability to determine the provenance of spent fuel.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 034028] Published Thu Mar 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shengli Chen, Tianxiang Wang, Zhong Zhang, Runfeng Li, Su Yuan, Ruiyi Zhang, Cenxi Yuan, Chunyu Zhang, and Jianyu Zhu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time-Dependent Magnetic Flux in Devices for Circuit Quantum Electrodynamics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034031</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034031"/>
        <updated>2023-03-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jacob Bryon, D.K. Weiss, Xinyuan You, Sara Sussman, Xanthe Croot, Ziwen Huang, Jens Koch, and Andrew A. Houck
Time-dependent external flux is ubiquitous across circuit quantum electrodynamics and calls for accurate modeling. Contrary to long-held belief, it is recently predicted—but not yet verified—that the allocation of time-dependent flux cannot be arbitrary in the Hamiltonian. This study provides an experimental verification of this prediction by applying fast flux pulses to a fluxonium qubit and taking measurements of the quantum state following the pulses. Given the widespread use of time-dependent flux in experiments with superconducting qubits, verification of this theory is critical to our understanding of circuit quantum electrodynamics.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 034031] Published Thu Mar 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jacob Bryon, D.K. Weiss, Xinyuan You, Sara Sussman, Xanthe Croot, Ziwen Huang, Jens Koch, and Andrew A. Houck</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Light-Induced Subnanometric Modulation of a Single-Molecule Electron Source]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.106204</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.106204"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hirofumi Yanagisawa, Markus Bohn, Hirotaka Kitoh-Nishioka, Florian Goschin, and Matthias F. Kling
The molecular orbitals of a single C60 molecule on a tungsten tip can be used to shape the emission pattern of electrons.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 106204] Published Wed Mar 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hirofumi Yanagisawa, Markus Bohn, Hirotaka Kitoh-Nishioka, Florian Goschin, and Matthias F. Kling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic Excited States in Extreme Limits via Ensemble Density Functionals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.106401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.106401"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tim Gould, Derk P. Kooi, Paola Gori-Giorgi, and Stefano Pittalis
A venerable strategy for approximating a system’s ground states has now been extended to accommodate its excited states.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 106401] Published Wed Mar 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Gould, Derk P. Kooi, Paola Gori-Giorgi, and Stefano Pittalis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Performance Boost of a Collective Qutrit Refrigerator]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034023</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034023"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dmytro Kolisnyk and Gernot Schaller
One of the world’s tiniest autonomous refrigerators can be realized by a single qutrit coupled to three thermal reservoirs. The authors analyze the performance of multiple collectively coupled qutrits, and observe a quantum boost in the steady-state cooling current with a quadratic scaling in the working fluid size. With additional interqutrit interactions, the quantum boost can be maintained also for larger systems and not perfectly collective scenarios, enabling efficient quantum cooling.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 034023] Published Wed Mar 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dmytro Kolisnyk and Gernot Schaller</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scalable Quantum Memory Nodes Using Nuclear Spins in Silicon Carbide]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034026</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034026"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shravan Kumar Parthasarathy, Birgit Kallinger, Florian Kaiser, Patrick Berwian, Durga B.R. Dasari, Jochen Friedrich, and Roland Nagy
A distributed quantum network requires versatile and high-fidelity quantum memory nodes, but it remains challenging to make them scalable. This study investigates the use of multiple controllable quantum memories in silicon carbide—an established semiconductor material platform for various quantum technology applications—and provides a viable solution. The authors show that solid-state spins in silicon carbide are ideal quantum memories in a distributed quantum computing network, wherein a controlled generation of highly coherent qubit registers using nuclear spins is possible. This study will impact the future development of quantum networks with solid states spins as quantum memories.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 034026] Published Wed Mar 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shravan Kumar Parthasarathy, Birgit Kallinger, Florian Kaiser, Patrick Berwian, Durga B.R. Dasari, Jochen Friedrich, and Roland Nagy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Position measurement and the Huygens-Fresnel principle: A quantum model of Fraunhofer diffraction for polarized pure states]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.033706</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.033706"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bernard Fabbro
Starting only from the postulates of quantum mechanics, the author presents a model of Fraunhofer diffraction by an aperture by treating the diaphragm as a position-measurement device, and explains how this model leads to experimentally testable consequences for large diffraction angles and polarization of the diffracted light.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 033706] Published Wed Mar 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bernard Fabbro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Corner universality in polygonal hydraulic jumps]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L032001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L032001"/>
        <updated>2023-03-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. I. Tamim, T. Nichols, J. Lundbek Hansen, T. Bohr, and J. B. Bostwick
Experiments show that vertical liquid jet impact on a solid plate creates a hydraulic jump which takes on a stable polygonal shape with sharp corners. The corner shape exhibits a striking universality that is characterized by the radius of curvature and corner angle at the tip, which remains nearly constant over a wide range of flow conditions. Knowledge of the corner angle allows one to determine the global jump shape, as defined by a dimensionless geometry number related to the isoperimetric inequality, thus giving a complete description of the jump shape.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, L032001] Published Tue Mar 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. I. Tamim, T. Nichols, J. Lundbek Hansen, T. Bohr, and J. B. Bostwick</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evolution of road infrastructure in large urban areas]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.034304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.034304"/>
        <updated>2023-03-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Erwan Taillanter and Marc Barthelemy
Researchers have identified the traffic thresholds at which cities build urban freeways and ring roads, which could help city administrators refine infrastructure plans.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, 034304] Published Tue Mar 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erwan Taillanter and Marc Barthelemy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prototype global analysis of LISA data with multiple source types]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.063004</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.063004"/>
        <updated>2023-03-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tyson B. Littenberg and Neil J. Cornish
A space-based observatory will detect gravitational waves from so many different types of sources at once that a global approach will be needed to crunch the data.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 063004] Published Tue Mar 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tyson B. Littenberg and Neil J. Cornish</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brownian motion of flexibly linked colloidal rings]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.034602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.034602"/>
        <updated>2023-03-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ruben W. Verweij, Julio Melio, Indrani Chakraborty, and Daniela J. Kraft
Motivated by the topological constraints imposed on cyclic polymers, the authors studied experimentally and numerically a model system for ring polymers. Their model system was created from micron-sized silica particles surrounded by a lipid bilayer and flexibly linked through DNA strands inserted in the bilayer. They compared the conformation and diffusive behavior of rings of four to eight segments with the behavior of linear polymers.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, 034602] Published Mon Mar 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ruben W. Verweij, Julio Melio, Indrani Chakraborty, and Daniela J. Kraft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symmetry-resolved entanglement of two-dimensional symmetry-protected topological states]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115113</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115113"/>
        <updated>2023-03-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Daniel Azses, David F. Mross, and Eran Sela
Entanglement spectra and their symmetries provide unique fingerprints of symmetry-protected topological states (SPTs). Unfortunately, using such calculations to identify SPTs numerically is notoriously difficult. Here, the authors develop a numerical method mapping this computation to a one-dimensional problem by utilizing the local nature of the quantum circuits that generate any SPT. Its application to models with Ising symmetry fully confirms field-theoretic predictions for their entanglement spectrum. Additionally, nontrivial deformations of the SPT manifest as many-body Aharonov-Bohm fluxes in the entanglement spectrum.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 115113] Published Mon Mar 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Azses, David F. Mross, and Eran Sela</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Broadband Spintronic Terahertz Source with Peak Electric Fields Exceeding 1.5 MV/cm]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034018</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034018"/>
        <updated>2023-03-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Rouzegar, A.L. Chekhov, Y. Behovits, B.R. Serrano, M.A. Syskaki, C.H. Lambert, D. Engel, U. Martens, M. Münzenberg, M. Wolf, G. Jakob, M. Kläui, T.S. Seifert, and T. Kampfrath
Spintronic terahertz emitters (STEs) are desirable broadband terahertz sources, but their limited signal strength has hindered practical application. By optimizing the photonic and thermal environment, the authors present an STE that could overcome this obstacle. Benchmarking against the state-of-the-art terahertz emitters based on optical rectification, this STE delivers strong terahertz pulses with comparable peak electric field and fluence, and offers additional features such as broadband radiation, easy alignment, and rotation of the terahertz polarization plane without power loss. This work will open up a promising pathway to nonlinear terahertz spectroscopy with spintronic sources.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 034018] Published Mon Mar 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Rouzegar, A.L. Chekhov, Y. Behovits, B.R. Serrano, M.A. Syskaki, C.H. Lambert, D. Engel, U. Martens, M. Münzenberg, M. Wolf, G. Jakob, M. Kläui, T.S. Seifert, and T. Kampfrath</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Implementation and goals of quantum optics experiments in undergraduate instructional labs]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.010117</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.010117"/>
        <updated>2023-03-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Victoria Borish and H. J. Lewandowski
Single-photon experiments are used to teach quantum phenomena in a wide variety of ways and with a wide variety of learning goals.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 19, 010117] Published Fri Mar 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victoria Borish and H. J. Lewandowski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hourglass-type bulk Ni $3d$ band and Ce $4f$ Kondo resonance states in the potential topological Kondo semimetal CeNiSn via angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125109</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125109"/>
        <updated>2023-03-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Seungho Seong, J. D. Denlinger, Kyoo Kim, B. I. Min, Y. Ōnuki, and J.-S. Kang
The electronic structure of CeNiSn, a potential topological Kondo insulator and a Dirac nodal-loop semimetal, is investigated here employing temperature-dependent angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy (ARPES). Dispersive states crossing the Fermi level (EF) exhibit general agreement with theoretical predictions of bulk Ni 3d bands and show consistency with a topological hourglass-type crossing of bulk bands below EF. Flat Ce 4f states at EF exhibit a Kondo resonance temperature dependence consistent with bulk transport. This work demonstrates the importance of coherent Kondo states in determining the topological properties of CeNiSn.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 125109] Published Fri Mar 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Seungho Seong, J. D. Denlinger, Kyoo Kim, B. I. Min, Y. Ōnuki, and J.-S. Kang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recrystallization in string-fluid complex plasmas]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.L012030</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.L012030"/>
        <updated>2023-03-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): E. Joshi, M. Y. Pustylnik, M. H. Thoma, H. M. Thomas, and M. Schwabe
The process of string-like cluster formation in complex plasmas is investigated. Excellent qualitative agreement between experiment and simulation showed that the reduced repulsion in the interparticle potential was enough to induce the formation of this structure

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, L012030] Published Thu Mar 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>E. Joshi, M. Y. Pustylnik, M. H. Thoma, H. M. Thomas, and M. Schwabe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multilayer graphenes as a platform for interaction-driven physics and topological superconductivity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104502"/>
        <updated>2023-03-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Areg Ghazaryan, Tobias Holder, Erez Berg, and Maksym Serbyn
Multilayer graphene systems without a moiré superlattice have emerged as an alternative platform to study interaction and superconducting phases. This study systematically compares density of states of multilayer graphene with different stacking. It identifies tetralayer graphene with rhombohedral (ABCA) stacking as the most promising material for realization of broken-symmetry phases. In-depth analysis of the phase diagram of ABCA graphene shows that, for the accessible range of experimental parameters, the material supports corrugated Fermi surface, which can realize a topological p+ip superconducting state with chiral Majorana edge modes.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 104502] Published Thu Mar 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Areg Ghazaryan, Tobias Holder, Erez Berg, and Maksym Serbyn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Superconducting properties and gap structure of the topological superconductor candidate ${\mathrm{Ti}}_{3}\mathrm{Sb}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104504</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104504"/>
        <updated>2023-03-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Chapai, M. P. Smylie, H. Hebbeker, D. Y. Chung, W.-K. Kwok, J. F. Mitchell, and U. Welp
A15 materials have been studied extensively due to the importance of Nb3Sn for the fabrication of high-field superconducting magnets. Recently, their topological properties have generated substantial interest as these materials have potential to exhibit exotic phenomena, such as topological superconductivity and large spin Hall effect. Here, the authors employ various complementary bulk measurement techniques to characterize the superconducting properties of the A15 material Ti3Sb. They report modestly strong superconducting coupling, indications for paramagnetic limiting, and a full superconducting gap.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 104504] Published Thu Mar 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Chapai, M. P. Smylie, H. Hebbeker, D. Y. Chung, W.-K. Kwok, J. F. Mitchell, and U. Welp</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FeRhCrSi: Spin semimetal with spin-valve behavior at room temperature]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L100401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L100401"/>
        <updated>2023-03-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Y. Venkateswara, Jadupati Nag, S. Shanmukharao Samatham, Akhilesh Kumar Patel, P. D. Babu, Manoj Raama Varma, Jayita Nayak, K. G. Suresh, and Aftab Alam
FeRhCrSi shows unconventional magnetic and transport properties. It belongs to one of the rare spintronic material classes, namely, spin semimetals. Transport measurements reveal its semimetallic nature, which is further confirmed by ab initio calculations on the partially disordered L21 structure, experimentally synthesized by the authors. The most striking feature is theasymmetric magnetoresistance variation with field at room temperature, clearly revealing spin-valve behavior. Disorder-induced ferrimagnetic regions within the ferromagnetic host are proposed to be the reason for this behavior. Simultaneous observation of spin semimetallic and spin valve features makes this alloy quite interesting both from fundamental and applied perspectives.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L100401] Published Thu Mar 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Y. Venkateswara, Jadupati Nag, S. Shanmukharao Samatham, Akhilesh Kumar Patel, P. D. Babu, Manoj Raama Varma, Jayita Nayak, K. G. Suresh, and Aftab Alam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evidence of Antineutrinos from Distant Reactors Using Pure Water at $\mathrm{SNO}+$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.091801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.091801"/>
        <updated>2023-03-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Allega et al. (The SNO+ Collaboration)
Researchers have captured the signal of neutrinos from a nuclear reactor using a water-filled neutrino detector, a first for such a device.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 091801] Published Wed Mar 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Allega &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (The &lt;math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline"&gt;&lt;mrow&gt;&lt;mi&gt;SNO&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mo&gt;+&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;/mrow&gt;&lt;/math&gt; Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetic Field-Resilient Quantum-Limited Parametric Amplifier]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.010322</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.010322"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mingrui Xu, Risheng Cheng, Yufeng Wu, Gangqiang Liu, and Hong X. Tang
A low-noise parametric amplifier based on kinetic inductance, suitable for integration with quantum systems in magnetic fields, is experimentally demonstrated

[PRX Quantum 4, 010322] Published Tue Feb 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mingrui Xu, Risheng Cheng, Yufeng Wu, Gangqiang Liu, and Hong X. Tang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proofs of Network Quantum Nonlocality in Continuous Families of Distributions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.090201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.090201"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alejandro Pozas-Kerstjens, Nicolas Gisin, and Marc-Olivier Renou
A conjecture initially formulated by applying machine learning techniques to network nonlocality is rigorously proved.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 090201] Published Tue Feb 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alejandro Pozas-Kerstjens, Nicolas Gisin, and Marc-Olivier Renou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chiral Light Amplifier with Pumped Weyl Semimetals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.096903</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.096903"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yusuke Nishida
While not yet experimentally realizable, a theory shows that a pumped Weyl semimetal could potentially be used as a “chiral light amplifier” with helicity selectivity whose performance could be tuned using electric, chiral magnetic, and anomalous Hall conductivities.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 096903] Published Tue Feb 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yusuke Nishida</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sampling rare event energy landscapes via birth-death augmented dynamics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.024141</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.024141"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Benjamin Pampel, Simon Holbach, Lisa Hartung, and Omar Valsson
A common problem in simulations of complex systems is the separation of metastable states by high barriers that hinder transitions between the states. The authors address this by adapting a sampling algorithm that includes a birth-death process, and show that this scheme can efficiently sample energy landscapes with such barriers.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, 024141] Published Tue Feb 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin Pampel, Simon Holbach, Lisa Hartung, and Omar Valsson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flow-network-controlled shape transformation of a thin membrane through differential fluid storage and surface expansion]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.024419</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.024419"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yongtian Luo, Che-Ling Ho, Brent R. Helliker, and Eleni Katifori
Flows in a fluid network embedded in a thin material can change the shape of that material. Inspired by the unfolding of flower petals, the authors of this paper study this phenomenon using a simple model that couples hydraulic networks to deformation mechanics.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, 024419] Published Tue Feb 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yongtian Luo, Che-Ling Ho, Brent R. Helliker, and Eleni Katifori</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnons, magnon bound pairs, and their hybrid spin-multipolar topology]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.064429</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.064429"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexander Mook, Rhea Hoyer, Jelena Klinovaja, and Daniel Loss
The fully polarized ferromagnetic ground state is arguably the least quantum of all magnetic ground states. Nonetheless, the authors show that it can support topological quantum spin excitations with exotic spin-multipolar properties if spin conservation is broken. These excitations are superpositions of dipolar magnons and quadrupolar two-magnon bound states. As a result of their topology, such quantum ferromagnets exhibit both chiral edge excitations, akin to edge states in Chern insulators but at finite energy, and an intrinsic thermal Hall effect.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 064429] Published Tue Feb 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexander Mook, Rhea Hoyer, Jelena Klinovaja, and Daniel Loss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonresonant coherent amplitude transfer in attosecond four-wave-mixing spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.023526</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.023526"/>
        <updated>2023-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): James D. Gaynor, Ashley P. Fidler, Yuki Kobayashi, Yen-Cheng Lin, Clare L. Keenan, Daniel M. Neumark, and Stephen R. Leone
The authors use attosecond four-wave-mixing spectroscopy to measure coherent superpositions of Rydberg states resulting from extreme ultraviolet excitation of a 3s electron in gas phase atomic argon to a series of autoionizing 3s-1np Rydberg states. The experimental observations are reproduced by electronic-structure and transition-moment calculations.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 023526] Published Tue Feb 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James D. Gaynor, Ashley P. Fidler, Yuki Kobayashi, Yen-Cheng Lin, Clare L. Keenan, Daniel M. Neumark, and Stephen R. Leone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rigorous Criteria for the Collapse of Nonlinear Cooperative Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.097401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.097401"/>
        <updated>2023-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rui-Jie Wu, Yi-Xiu Kong, Zengru Di, Jordi Bascompte, and Gui-Yuan Shi
An analytic approach for obtaining rigorous bounds on tipping points for general nonlinear cooperative networks makes it possible to calculate accurately the criteria for the collapse of such networks.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 097401] Published Mon Feb 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rui-Jie Wu, Yi-Xiu Kong, Zengru Di, Jordi Bascompte, and Gui-Yuan Shi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Single-Collision Statistics Reveal a Global Mechanism Driven by Sample History for Contact Electrification in Granular Media]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.098202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.098202"/>
        <updated>2023-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Galien Grosjean and Scott Waitukaitis
The results of new experiments indicate that surface-adsorbed water molecules are responsible for contact electrification in granular matter, a finding that challenges established models of this phenomenon.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 098202] Published Mon Feb 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Galien Grosjean and Scott Waitukaitis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sub-meter wind detection with pulsed coherent Doppler lidar]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L022701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L022701"/>
        <updated>2023-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yunpeng Zhang, Jinlong Yuan, Yunbin Wu, Jingjing Dong, and Haiyun Xia
High-resolution wind detection plays a crucial role in aviation safety and aerodynamics. In this work, the fine wind field within 700 meters is continuously detected at a resolution of 0.9 meters/0.5 seconds by a coherent Doppler wind LiDAR. A meter-scale perturbation by an electric fan is remotely sensed, and atmospheric turbulence with length scale down to 3 meters can be observed.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, L022701] Published Mon Feb 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yunpeng Zhang, Jinlong Yuan, Yunbin Wu, Jingjing Dong, and Haiyun Xia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-dual quasiperiodic percolation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.024137</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.024137"/>
        <updated>2023-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Grace M. Sommers, Michael J. Gullans, and David A. Huse
In commonly used percolation models, bonds of a lattice are occupied randomly and one asks if a connected cluster is present. In this paper, the authors study models in which bonds are occupied according to a deterministic and quasiperiodic pattern rather than randomly, and they find critical behavior quite different from random percolation.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, 024137] Published Mon Feb 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grace M. Sommers, Michael J. Gullans, and David A. Huse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Searching for Coleman–de Luccia bubbles in AdS compactifications]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.046020</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.046020"/>
        <updated>2023-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Giuseppe Dibitetto and Nicolò Petri
The authors study the spontaneous nucleation of bubbles within metastable (gravitational) vacua, including a true stable vacuum, in the context of consistent lower-dimensional truncations of string and M-theories. They present two fully backreacted examples, without thin-wall approximation, of gravitational instantons obtained from a numerical integration of the first-order Hamilton-Jacobi equations. These solutions are domain walls connecting a supersymmetric and a non-supersymmetric AdS vacuum that show a nonperturbative instability of the non-SUSY AdS vacua.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 046020] Published Mon Feb 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giuseppe Dibitetto and Nicolò Petri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin wave spectra of single crystal ${\mathrm{CoPS}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.054438</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.054438"/>
        <updated>2023-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. R. Wildes, B. Fåk, U. B. Hansen, M. Enderle, J. R. Stewart, L. Testa, H. M. Rønnow, C. Kim, and Je-Geun Park
CoPS3 is a van der Waals antiferromagnet with the Co2+ ions forming decoupled honeycomb layers. It was a candidate to host exotic magnetic properties such as valence-bond states or Kitaev-like physics. Here, the authors show, using neutron inelastic scattering, that CoPS3 does not have these states. Instead, well-defined excitations are observed that are accurately modeled using linear spin wave theory with high-spin S=3/2 and biaxial single-ion anisotropy, giving insight for the reasons behind the absence of exotic states.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 054438] Published Mon Feb 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. R. Wildes, B. Fåk, U. B. Hansen, M. Enderle, J. R. Stewart, L. Testa, H. M. Rønnow, C. Kim, and Je-Geun Park</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dark and bright modes, and their coherent control in dipolar metasurface bilayers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.023521</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.023521"/>
        <updated>2023-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Saumya Choudhary, Robert W. Boyd, and J. E. Sipe
The authors derive a semianalytical model describing the reflection and absorption spectra of dipolar bilayer metasurfaces, showing how radiative coupling between the layers can result in the formation of nonradiative dark modes which can contribute significantly to the optical response of the system. The ability to vary the reflection and absorption spectra of such bilayers by changing the material and geometrical parameters, and to selectively excite the modes by adjusting the phase between two counter-propagating normally incident fields, promises numerous applications.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 023521] Published Mon Feb 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Saumya Choudhary, Robert W. Boyd, and J. E. Sipe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capillary-Stress Controlled Rheometer Reveals the Dual Rheology of Shear-Thickening Suspensions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011024</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011024"/>
        <updated>2023-02-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bruno Etcheverry, Yoël Forterre, and Bloen Metzger
The “capillarytron” lets researchers access mechanical properties of very dense suspensions.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 011024] Published Fri Feb 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bruno Etcheverry, Yoël Forterre, and Bloen Metzger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Salt Polygons and Porous Media Convection]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011025</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011025"/>
        <updated>2023-02-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jana Lasser, Joanna M. Nield, Marcel Ernst, Volker Karius, Giles F. S. Wiggs, Matthew R. Threadgold, Cédric Beaume, and Lucas Goehring
The geometric patterns on dry, salty lake beds are generated by convection of high- and low-salinity water underground, according to simulations and observations.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 011025] Published Fri Feb 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jana Lasser, Joanna M. Nield, Marcel Ernst, Volker Karius, Giles F. S. Wiggs, Matthew R. Threadgold, Cédric Beaume, and Lucas Goehring</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonaffine Deformation of Semiflexible Polymer and Fiber Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.088101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.088101"/>
        <updated>2023-02-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sihan Chen, Tomer Markovich, and Fred C. MacKintosh
The nonaffine properties of semiflexible networks (common in biomaterials) are captured by an analytical model under various conditions in both 2D and 3D.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 088101] Published Fri Feb 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sihan Chen, Tomer Markovich, and Fred C. MacKintosh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Low-${p}_{T}$ direct-photon production in $\mathrm{Au}+\mathrm{Au}$ collisions at $\sqrt{{s}_{NN}}=39$ and 62.4 GeV]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.024914</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.024914"/>
        <updated>2023-02-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. J. Abdulameer et al. (PHENIX Collaboration)
The PHENIX experiment at RHIC presents a measurement of thermal photons emitted from the quark-gluon plasma produced in collisions of Au ions at sNN=39 and 62.4 GeV. The yield of these photons exceeds what is expected from appropriately scaled proton collisions and is qualitatively consistent with a significant thermal contribution. Compared to results from other beam energies, the data suggest that the bulk of thermal photons are emitted under similar conditions near the transition of the quark-gluon plasma to hadronic matter.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, 024914] Published Fri Feb 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. J. Abdulameer &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (PHENIX Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-Fidelity <span class="sc">CNOT</span> Gate for Donor Electron Spin Qubits in Silicon]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.024068</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.024068"/>
        <updated>2023-02-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ludwik Kranz, Stephen Roche, Samuel K. Gorman, Joris. G. Keizer, and Michelle Y. Simmons
Epitaxial atom-based spin qubits in silicon exhibit excellent properties, and benefit from the outstanding scalability of that material platform. As silicon spin-based qubits now start to meet the 99% fault-tolerance threshold, the authors show how the nuclear spins inherent to the local magnetic environment can be engineered as atomic magnets to boost the fidelities of two-qubit logic gates. Modeling indicates that two-qubit CNOT gate fidelities as high as 99.98% are realistic, through silicon purification and careful engineering. This work provides a roadmap for atom qubits in silicon, showing how to optimize two-qubit gates at both the design and measurement stages.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 024068] Published Fri Feb 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ludwik Kranz, Stephen Roche, Samuel K. Gorman, Joris. G. Keizer, and Michelle Y. Simmons</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Single-Shot Readout of Multiple Donor Electron Spins with a Gate-Based Sensor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.010319</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.010319"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M.R. Hogg, P. Pakkiam, S.K. Gorman, A.V. Timofeev, Y. Chung, G.K. Gulati, M.G. House, and M.Y. Simmons
A new atomic-scale sensor capable of reading out multiple qubits is engineered, providing a pathway for increasing on-chip qubit density.

[PRX Quantum 4, 010319] Published Thu Feb 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M.R. Hogg, P. Pakkiam, S.K. Gorman, A.V. Timofeev, Y. Chung, G.K. Gulati, M.G. House, and M.Y. Simmons</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast High-Fidelity Single-Shot Readout of Spins in Silicon Using a Single-Electron Box]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011023</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011023"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): G. A. Oakes, V. N. Ciriano-Tejel, D. F. Wise, M. A. Fogarty, T. Lundberg, C. Lainé, S. Schaal, F. Martins, D. J. Ibberson, L. Hutin, B. Bertrand, N. Stelmashenko, J. W. A. Robinson, L. Ibberson, A. Hashim, I. Siddiqi, A. Lee, M. Vinet, C. G. Smith, J. J. L. Morton, and M. F. Gonzalez-Zalba
A newly developed compact charge sensor quickly reads the state of electron spin qubits with high fidelity, demonstrating a performance suitable for robust, spin-based quantum processors.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 011023] Published Thu Feb 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>G. A. Oakes, V. N. Ciriano-Tejel, D. F. Wise, M. A. Fogarty, T. Lundberg, C. Lainé, S. Schaal, F. Martins, D. J. Ibberson, L. Hutin, B. Bertrand, N. Stelmashenko, J. W. A. Robinson, L. Ibberson, A. Hashim, I. Siddiqi, A. Lee, M. Vinet, C. G. Smith, J. J. L. Morton, and M. F. Gonzalez-Zalba</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Energetics of Microwaves Probed by Double Quantum Dot Absorption]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.087003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.087003"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Subhomoy Haldar, Harald Havir, Waqar Khan, Sebastian Lehmann, Claes Thelander, Kimberly A. Dick, and Ville F. Maisi
Detuning and stopping-potential measurements in a quantum dot photodiode demonstrate a microwave analog of the photoelectric effect.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 087003] Published Thu Feb 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Subhomoy Haldar, Harald Havir, Waqar Khan, Sebastian Lehmann, Claes Thelander, Kimberly A. Dick, and Ville F. Maisi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inflationary Adler conditions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.043534</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.043534"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Daniel Green, Yiwen Huang, and Chia-Hsien Shen
The authors study the Effective Field Theory (EFT) of Inflation in the sub-horizon limit, where space-time becomes flat but Lorentz boosts are still broken. They consider the Goldstone bosons associated with the spontaneous breaking of Lorentz boosts, and derive a soft theorem for scattering amplitudes. As an application, the authors show that the Dirac-Born-Infeld Inflation is the unique theory that has an emergent Lorentz invariance when the boosts are spontaneously broken.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 043534] Published Thu Feb 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Green, Yiwen Huang, and Chia-Hsien Shen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ferroelectric switching pathways and domain structure of ${\mathrm{SrBi}}_{2}{(\mathrm{Ta,Nb})}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{9}$ from first principles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.054108</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.054108"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nabaraj Pokhrel and Elizabeth A. Nowadnick
The energy barrier for polarization reversal is a key property that impacts the performance of ferroelectric materials. Here, the authors combine symmetry analysis and first-principles calculations to understand the origin of low-energy polarization switching in the Aurivillius-phase ferroelectrics SrBi2Ta2O9 and SrBi2Nb2O9. They show that polarization reverses via a low-energy two-step process facilitated by nonpolar structural order parameter rotations. Analysis of the ferroelectric domain structure shows that the formation of domain wall vortices is energetically favorable.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 054108] Published Thu Feb 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nabaraj Pokhrel and Elizabeth A. Nowadnick</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heat conduction in herbertsmithite: Field dependence at the onset of the quantum spin liquid regime]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.054434</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.054434"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Quentin Barthélemy, Étienne Lefrançois, Jordan Baglo, Patrick Bourgeois-Hope, Dipranjan Chatterjee, Pierre Lefloïc, Matias Velázquez, Victor Balédent, Bernard Bernu, Nicolas Doiron-Leyraud, Fabrice Bert, Philippe Mendels, and Louis Taillefer
Thermal conductivity and thermal Hall effect measurements in the quantum kagome antiferromagnet herbertsmithite reveal that there is no significant contribution to the heat conduction from mobile spin excitations. A clear field dependence of the thermal conductivity is discovered to onset at a new temperature scale, attributed to the establishment of a quantum spin liquid and the gradual polarization of magnetic defects. Their magnetization profile is extracted and found incompatible with a Brillouin function, indicating that they are not isolated paramagnetic objects.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 054434] Published Thu Feb 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Quentin Barthélemy, Étienne Lefrançois, Jordan Baglo, Patrick Bourgeois-Hope, Dipranjan Chatterjee, Pierre Lefloïc, Matias Velázquez, Victor Balédent, Bernard Bernu, Nicolas Doiron-Leyraud, Fabrice Bert, Philippe Mendels, and Louis Taillefer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Surface exciton formation on $\mathrm{InP}(110)−(1×1)$ studied by time- and angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.075304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.075304"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hiroshi Tanimura, Katsumi Tanimura, and Jun'ichi Kanasaki
Time- and angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy provides the ability to obtain deeper insight into the wave functions of excitons in semiconductors. In this paper, the method reveals that the exciton formed on InP(110)-(1x1) surface has a spheroidal radial probability density; the spread is 44 Å in the planes parallel to the surface, while it is confined within the surface region with 6-Å depth. Both the reduced screening and two-dimensional confinements at the surface govern the quasi–two-dimensional characteristics.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 075304] Published Thu Feb 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hiroshi Tanimura, Katsumi Tanimura, and Jun'ichi Kanasaki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multiple Tin-Vacancy Centers in Diamond with Nearly Identical Photon Frequency and Linewidth]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.024061</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.024061"/>
        <updated>2023-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yasuyuki Narita, Peng Wang, Keita Ikeda, Kazuki Oba, Yoshiyuki Miyamoto, Takashi Taniguchi, Shinobu Onoda, Mutsuko Hatano, and Takayuki Iwasaki
Tin-vacancy (Sn-V) centers in diamond, which possess good optical and spin properties, are a promising system for constructing quantum network nodes. Tin atoms are heavy, though, and generating photons with identical wavelength and linewidth from multiple Sn-V emitters is challenging, due to the strain in the diamond host material. This study shows that multiple Sn-V centers, formed deep within bulk diamond by ion implantation and high-temperature annealing, emit nearly identical photons. This leads to two-photon interference from distant centers, an important step toward building quantum network nodes.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 024061] Published Thu Feb 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yasuyuki Narita, Peng Wang, Keita Ikeda, Kazuki Oba, Yoshiyuki Miyamoto, Takashi Taniguchi, Shinobu Onoda, Mutsuko Hatano, and Takayuki Iwasaki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlinear Effects in Black Hole Ringdown]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.081401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.081401"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mark Ho-Yeuk Cheung, Vishal Baibhav, Emanuele Berti, Vitor Cardoso, Gregorio Carullo, Roberto Cotesta, Walter Del Pozzo, Francisco Duque, Thomas Helfer, Estuti Shukla, and Kaze W. K. Wong
Simulations show that nonlinear spacetime dynamics manifest in the postmerger gravitational-wave signal of binary black hole coalescence.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 081401] Published Wed Feb 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Ho-Yeuk Cheung, Vishal Baibhav, Emanuele Berti, Vitor Cardoso, Gregorio Carullo, Roberto Cotesta, Walter Del Pozzo, Francisco Duque, Thomas Helfer, Estuti Shukla, and Kaze W. K. Wong</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlinearities in Black Hole Ringdowns]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.081402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.081402"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Keefe Mitman, Macarena Lagos, Leo C. Stein, Sizheng Ma, Lam Hui, Yanbei Chen, Nils Deppe, François Hébert, Lawrence E. Kidder, Jordan Moxon, Mark A. Scheel, Saul A. Teukolsky, William Throwe, and Nils L. Vu
Simulations show that nonlinear spacetime dynamics manifest in the postmerger gravitational-wave signal of binary black hole coalescence.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 081402] Published Wed Feb 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keefe Mitman, Macarena Lagos, Leo C. Stein, Sizheng Ma, Lam Hui, Yanbei Chen, Nils Deppe, François Hébert, Lawrence E. Kidder, Jordan Moxon, Mark A. Scheel, Saul A. Teukolsky, William Throwe, and Nils L. Vu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimal Cooling of Multiple Levitated Particles through Far-Field Wavefront Shaping]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.083203</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.083203"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jakob Hüpfl, Nicolas Bachelard, Markus Kaczvinszki, Michael Horodynski, Matthias Kühmayer, and Stefan Rotter
Researchers predict that the “scattering matrix” of a collection of particles could be used to slow the particles down, potentially allowing for the cooling of significantly more particles than is possible with current techniques.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 083203] Published Wed Feb 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jakob Hüpfl, Nicolas Bachelard, Markus Kaczvinszki, Michael Horodynski, Matthias Kühmayer, and Stefan Rotter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantifying Energy Conversion in Higher-Order Phase Space Density Moments in Plasmas]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.085201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.085201"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Paul A. Cassak, M. Hasan Barbhuiya, Haoming Liang, and Matthew R. Argall
From first principles, the energy conversion associated with higher moments is calculated for a plasma that is far from local thermodynamic equilibrium.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 085201] Published Wed Feb 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul A. Cassak, M. Hasan Barbhuiya, Haoming Liang, and Matthew R. Argall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chemical Leslie effect in a chiral $\text{smectic-}{C}^{★}$ film: Nonsingular target patterns]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.024703</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.024703"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Félix Bunel and Patrick Oswald
When particles are made to flow through a chiral liquid crystal phase, they can induce flows in the liquid crystal and as well as a rotation of the director. This paper describes experiments with a flux of ethanol through a chiral smectic-C* film, and gives an interpretation of the results in the context of the Leslie theory.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, 024703] Published Wed Feb 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Félix Bunel and Patrick Oswald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chemical Leslie effect in a chiral $\text{smectic-}C*$ film: Singular target patterns]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.024704</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.024704"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Félix Bunel and Patrick Oswald
Ethanol flowing through a chiral smectic-C* film can produce roughly circular patterns, but under different conditions also spiral patterns. Further experiments show these patterns, and their theoretical explanation is confirmed.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, 024704] Published Wed Feb 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Félix Bunel and Patrick Oswald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scanning tunneling spectroscopy of Majorana zero modes in a Kitaev spin liquid]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.054432</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.054432"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tim Bauer, Lucas R. D. Freitas, Rodrigo G. Pereira, and Reinhold Egger
The experimental detection of Majorana zero modes represents a major open problem. In topological superconductors, scanning tunneling spectroscopy provides evidence through zero-bias conductance peaks, which can however be confused with disorder-induced Andreev states. The theory here suggests that the Majorana zero modes bound to vortices in Kitaev spin liquids offer a more favorable testing ground: the Majorana-induced conductance features found are quite distinct from those of an alternative scenario based on magnons.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 054432] Published Wed Feb 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Bauer, Lucas R. D. Freitas, Rodrigo G. Pereira, and Reinhold Egger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Resolving Hall and dissipative viscosity ambiguities via boundary effects]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.075148</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.075148"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pranav Rao and Barry Bradlyn
In fluids without rotational symmetry, different components of the viscosity tensor can lead to physically indistinguishable effects in the bulk of a system. This “viscous redundancy” plays a role for both dissipative and nondissipative (time reversal odd) viscosities in two dimensions. Here, the authors examine the physical implications of the viscous redundancy for two-dimensional anisotropic fluids, providing microscopic examples of the redundancy and showing it can be resolved by studying wave propagation at the boundary of the fluid.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 075148] Published Wed Feb 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pranav Rao and Barry Bradlyn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multiscale Modeling of Metal-Oxide-Metal Conductive Bridging Random-Access Memory Cells: From <i>Ab Initio</i> to Finite-Element Calculations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.024058</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.024058"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jan Aeschlimann, Fabian Ducry, Christoph Weilenmann, Juerg Leuthold, Alexandros Emboras, and Mathieu Luisier
Continuum modeling is a popular, computationally efficient technique that can shed light on the resistance-switching properties of conductive bridging random-access memory (CBRAM) cells. Traditional models typically rely on many fitting parameters, but this approach uses material parameters extracted either from either ab initio or machine-learned empirical calculations. As proof of concept, the authors apply the computational framework to an SiO2-based CBRAM cell, and reveal the relevance of Joule heating in nanoscale devices. With the proposed multiscale methodology it is possible to explore the potential of not-yet-fabricated memory cells, and to optimize their design reliably.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 024058] Published Wed Feb 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jan Aeschlimann, Fabian Ducry, Christoph Weilenmann, Juerg Leuthold, Alexandros Emboras, and Mathieu Luisier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toward a diffraction limited light source]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.021601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.021601"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pantaleo Raimondi and Simone Maria Liuzzo
The design of a large fourth generation light source may open a new era for synchrotron radiation based x-ray science.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 26, 021601] Published Wed Feb 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pantaleo Raimondi and Simone Maria Liuzzo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beam shaping using an ultrahigh vacuum multileaf collimator and emittance exchange beamline]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.022801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.022801"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. Majernik, G. Andonian, W. Lynn, S. Kim, C. Lorch, R. Roussel, S. Doran, E. Wisniewski, C. Whiteford, P. Piot, J. Power, and J. B. Rosenzweig
A multileaf collimator with an emittance exchange beamline allows generation of highly variable longitudinal bunch profiles.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 26, 022801] Published Wed Feb 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Majernik, G. Andonian, W. Lynn, S. Kim, C. Lorch, R. Roussel, S. Doran, E. Wisniewski, C. Whiteford, P. Piot, J. Power, and J. B. Rosenzweig</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measuring ultrafast time-bin qudits]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.022618</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.022618"/>
        <updated>2023-02-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Frédéric Bouchard, Kent Bonsma-Fisher, Khabat Heshami, Philip J. Bustard, Duncan England, and Benjamin Sussman
Time-bin qudits, which are valued in quantum communication protocols for their efficiency and robustness, are made by encoding information into the relative arrival times of photons. However, their practicality has been limited due to the difficulty of the measurements needed to extract this information. Here, the authors demonstrate an effective experimental technique that uses active and passive optical elements to conduct single-shot measurements of ultrafast four-time-bin qudits.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 022618] Published Wed Feb 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Frédéric Bouchard, Kent Bonsma-Fisher, Khabat Heshami, Philip J. Bustard, Duncan England, and Benjamin Sussman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>