<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2024-01-28T00:48:02.057Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2024-01-28T00:48:02.057Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anisotropic anomalous transport in the kagome-based topological antiferromagnetic ${\mathrm{Mn}}_{3}\text{Ga}$ epitaxial thin films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.014204</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.014204"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Raju, Ralph Romero, III, Daisuke Nishio-Hamane, Ryota Uesugi, Mihiro Asakura, Zhenisbek Tagay, Tomoya Higo, N. P. Armitage, Collin Broholm, and Satoru Nakatsuji
Weyl semimetals based on Mn3X (X=Sn, Ge, Ga) are promising materials for antiferromagnetic (AFM) spintronics. Kagome spin structure formed by the Mn moments coupled to nontrivial band topology produces giant topological effects in these materials. Mn3Ga with the largest Néel temperature among this class of materials, is potentially useful for high-speed device applications. In this work, authors develop AFM epitaxial Mn3Ga films with controlled crystal orientation, accessing different orientation of Kagome planes formed by Mn moments. Detailed investigations through structural, magnetization, magnetoresistance, DC and terahertz electrical transport reveal the anisotropic transport signatures emerging from the nontrivial band topology.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 014204] Published Fri Jan 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Raju, Ralph Romero, III, Daisuke Nishio-Hamane, Ryota Uesugi, Mihiro Asakura, Zhenisbek Tagay, Tomoya Higo, N. P. Armitage, Collin Broholm, and Satoru Nakatsuji</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Centrifugal Flows Drive Reverse Rotation of Feynman’s Sprinkler]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.044003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.044003"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kaizhe Wang, Brennan Sprinkle, Mingxuan Zuo, and Leif Ristroph
Which direction would an S-shaped lawn sprinkler rotate if it were submerged and the flow were reversed? Experiments now provide a definitive answer.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 044003] Published Fri Jan 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kaizhe Wang, Brennan Sprinkle, Mingxuan Zuo, and Leif Ristroph</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Energy Gap of the Even-Denominator Fractional Quantum Hall State in Bilayer Graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.046603</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.046603"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexandre Assouline, Taige Wang, Haoxin Zhou, Liam A. Cohen, Fangyuan Yang, Ruining Zhang, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Roger S. K. Mong, Michael P. Zaletel, and Andrea F. Young
A large energy gap is seen for the even-denominator fractional state in bilayer graphene, making it a promising platform for studying non-Abelian anyons.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 046603] Published Fri Jan 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandre Assouline, Taige Wang, Haoxin Zhou, Liam A. Cohen, Fangyuan Yang, Ruining Zhang, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Roger S. K. Mong, Michael P. Zaletel, and Andrea F. Young</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quasicrystal of Binary Hard Spheres on a Plane Stabilized by Configurational Entropy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.048202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.048202"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Etienne Fayen, Laura Filion, Giuseppe Foffi, and Frank Smallenburg
Free-energy calculations demonstrate that configurational entropy stabilizes a dodecagonal quasicrystal in a binary mixture of hard spheres on a plane.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 048202] Published Fri Jan 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Etienne Fayen, Laura Filion, Giuseppe Foffi, and Frank Smallenburg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multiscale Richtmyer-Meshkov instability experiments to isolate the strain rate dependence of strength]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.015002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.015002"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Michael B. Prime, Saryu J. Fensin, David R. Jones, Joshua W. Dyer, and Daniel T. Martinez
This work describes Richtmyer-Meshkov experiments to measure the strain-rate sensitivity of copper in the high-rate regime. The authors extend the maximum strain rate by more than two orders of magnitude. At higher strain rates, their strength estimates show a steep increase that agrees well with extrapolations from some of the data in the literature. The work contributes to the important effort to understand how impacts can affect the strength of solids.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 015002] Published Fri Jan 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael B. Prime, Saryu J. Fensin, David R. Jones, Joshua W. Dyer, and Daniel T. Martinez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electrically sign-reversible topological Hall effect in a top-gated topological insulator ${(\mathrm{Bi},\mathrm{Sb})}_{2}{\mathrm{Te}}_{3}$ grown on europium iron garnet]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024432</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024432"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J.-F. Wong, K.-H. M. Chen, J.-M. Chia, Z.-P. Huang, S.-X. Wang, P.-T. Chen, L. B. Young, Y.-H. G. Lin, S.-F. Lee, C.-Y. Mou, M. Hong, and J. Kwo
The topological Hall effect (THE) is a Hall response that arises from the deflection of motion of charge carriers flowing through nontrivial spin textures. Here, the authors observe a significant THE and investigate its interplay with the spin-polarized topological surface states in a proximity-magnetized topological insulator/ferrimagnet heterostructure. Specifically, they demonstrate a sign change in THE via a top electrical gate as the Fermi level is tuned from the electron-doped to the hole-doped region of the gapped Dirac cone.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 024432] Published Fri Jan 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J.-F. Wong, K.-H. M. Chen, J.-M. Chia, Z.-P. Huang, S.-X. Wang, P.-T. Chen, L. B. Young, Y.-H. G. Lin, S.-F. Lee, C.-Y. Mou, M. Hong, and J. Kwo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Employing quasidegenerate optical modes for chiral sensing]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L041410</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L041410"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. F. Almousa, T. Weiss, and E. A. Muljarov
The authors demonstrate here a linear splitting of quasidegenerate modes in the presence of chirality in optical systems. Employing the resonant-state expansion and two quasidegenerate modes, they reveal the transformation of the chirality effect on mode splitting from second to first order in the Pasteur parameter (ϰ). This linear effect is demonstrated for individual chiral particles and homogeneous chiral perturbations of metasurfaces. These findings deepen our understanding of chirality-induced mode splitting, opening prospects for innovative sensing schemes.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, L041410] Published Fri Jan 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. F. Almousa, T. Weiss, and E. A. Muljarov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tailoring Magnetism of Graphene Nanoflakes via Tip-Controlled Dehydrogenation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.046201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.046201"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chenxiao Zhao, Qiang Huang, Leoš Valenta, Kristjan Eimre, Lin Yang, Aliaksandr V. Yakutovich, Wangwei Xu, Ji Ma, Xinliang Feng, Michal Juríček, Roman Fasel, Pascal Ruffieux, and Carlo A. Pignedoli
Highly precise atomic scale manipulations correlated with theoretical calculations suggest changes in the spin states of a graphene island on Au(111) depending on which site was hydrogenated.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 046201] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chenxiao Zhao, Qiang Huang, Leoš Valenta, Kristjan Eimre, Lin Yang, Aliaksandr V. Yakutovich, Wangwei Xu, Ji Ma, Xinliang Feng, Michal Juríček, Roman Fasel, Pascal Ruffieux, and Carlo A. Pignedoli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin Polarons and Ferromagnetism in Doped Dilute Moiré-Mott Insulators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.046501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.046501"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Urban F. P. Seifert and Leon Balents
A small density of doped electrons couples to local moments in a moire-Mott insulator, constituting a novel mechanism for magnetic ordering in moire transition-metal dichalcogenides.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 046501] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Urban F. P. Seifert and Leon Balents</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bidirectional Multiphoton Communication between Remote Superconducting Nodes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.047001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.047001"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Joel Grebel, Haoxiong Yan, Ming-Han Chou, Gustav Andersson, Christopher R. Conner, Yash J. Joshi, Jacob M. Miller, Rhys G. Povey, Hong Qiao, Xuntao Wu, and Andrew N. Cleland
A device with qubits coupled to microwave resonators achieves transfer and entanglement of complex quantum states between superconducting nodes.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 047001] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joel Grebel, Haoxiong Yan, Ming-Han Chou, Gustav Andersson, Christopher R. Conner, Yash J. Joshi, Jacob M. Miller, Rhys G. Povey, Hong Qiao, Xuntao Wu, and Andrew N. Cleland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnon interactions in the quantum paramagnetic phase of ${\mathrm{CoNb}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{6}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014424</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014424"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. A. Gallegos and A. L. Chernyshev
The strongly anisotropic quasi-one-dimensional ferromagnet CoNb2O6 in a transverse field has provided a spectacular realization of the magnon decay effect in its paramagnetic phase. A self-consistent theory is proposed to regularize unphysical divergences while preserving the integrity of the singular threshold phenomena of magnon decay, demonstrating quantitative agreement with the neutron scattering results throughout the field regime inaccessible by standard spin-wave theory. Phenomenological constraints on the model, connections of CoNb2O6 to the other anisotropic-exchange materials, and the effects of longitudinal fields are explored.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 014424] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. A. Gallegos and A. L. Chernyshev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlinear magnons and exchange Hamiltonians of the delafossite proximate quantum spin liquid candidates ${\text{KYbSe}}_{2}$ and ${\text{NaYbSe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014425</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014425"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. O. Scheie, Y. Kamiya, Hao Zhang, Sangyun Lee, A. J. Woods, M. O. Ajeesh, M. G. Gonzalez, B. Bernu, J. W. Villanova, J. Xing, Q. Huang, Qingming Zhang, Jie Ma, Eun Sang Choi, D. M. Pajerowski, Haidong Zhou, A. S. Sefat, S. Okamoto, T. Berlijn, L. Messio, R. Movshovich, C. D. Batista, and D. A. Tennant
Quantum spin liquids were proposed over 50 years ago, but identifying experimental signatures is extremely difficult. Here, the authors study the Yb triangular materials KYbSe2 and NaYbSe2, and show that KYbSe2 is well described by the Heisenberg J2-J1 model. Comparing this material to NaYbSe2 and CsYbSe2, a trend emerges where the magnetic exchange interactions are correlated with chemical substitution. This allows these systems to be controllably tuned toward (and possibly into) a theoretically predicted quantum spin liquid phase.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 014425] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. O. Scheie, Y. Kamiya, Hao Zhang, Sangyun Lee, A. J. Woods, M. O. Ajeesh, M. G. Gonzalez, B. Bernu, J. W. Villanova, J. Xing, Q. Huang, Qingming Zhang, Jie Ma, Eun Sang Choi, D. M. Pajerowski, Haidong Zhou, A. S. Sefat, S. Okamoto, T. Berlijn, L. Messio, R. Movshovich, C. D. Batista, and D. A. Tennant</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum magnetism in the frustrated square lattice oxyhalides ${\mathrm{YbBi}}_{2}{\mathrm{IO}}_{4}$ and ${\mathrm{YbBi}}_{2}{\mathrm{ClO}}_{4}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014426</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014426"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pyeongjae Park, G. Sala, Th. Proffen, Matthew B. Stone, Andrew D. Christianson, and Andrew F. May
This work establishes Yb-containing oxyhalides as a new family of materials for studying quantum magnetism on a frustrated square lattice. The titular compounds appear to possess long-range magnetic order below ≈0.21 K (YbBi2lO4), but analysis of their thermodynamic properties via a J1-J2 square lattice model suggests large magnetic frustration. This places the materials near the transition to a quantum spin liquid. Thus, the impact of quantum fluctuations is expected to be strong, motivating detailed studies of these and related phases.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 014426] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pyeongjae Park, G. Sala, Th. Proffen, Matthew B. Stone, Andrew D. Christianson, and Andrew F. May</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental investigation of the premelting process in Sn]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024109</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024109"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Stephen G. Lipson and Emil Polturak
Researchers have experimentally captured the melting of defects in a crystal, a process previously only understood through simulations.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 024109] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen G. Lipson and Emil Polturak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin-orbit interaction enabled electronic Raman scattering from charge collective modes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.035160</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.035160"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Surajit Sarkar, Alexander Lee, Girsh Blumberg, and Saurabh Maiti
The inelastic photon scattering process by bulk plasmon collective modes in conventional metals is restricted by conservation laws. Here, the authors demonstrate that for materials with broken SU(2) spin symmetry that is present in inversion broken systems, the restriction on the light scattering process can be removed by spin-correlation mediated coupling of light to plasmons. The theory is supported by resonant Raman scattering experiment on BiTeI, a material with a giant Rashba effect, in which the authors explicitly demonstrate this light scattering process by plasmons.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 035160] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Surajit Sarkar, Alexander Lee, Girsh Blumberg, and Saurabh Maiti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental determination of the spin Hamiltonian of the cubic chiral magnet MnSi]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L020408</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L020408"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): P. Dalmas de Réotier, A. Yaouanc, G. Lapertot, C. Wang, A. Amato, and D. Andreica
The authors determine here the minimal spin Hamiltonian of manganese silicide from analysis of muon spin rotation experimental data measured in its helical and conical phases. The model includes Heisenberg and Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya interactions between the Mn nearest neighbors. In particular, information is derived on the orientation of the Moriya vector that cannot be inferred from the symmetry of the Mn-Mn bond. This result enforces constraints for future theoretical works, e.g., on the origin of the stability of the magnetic skyrmions phase.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, L020408] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>P. Dalmas de Réotier, A. Yaouanc, G. Lapertot, C. Wang, A. Amato, and D. Andreica</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin-mediated direct photon scattering by plasmons in BiTeI]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L041111</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L041111"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. C. Lee, S. Sarkar, K. Du, H.-H. Kung, C. J. Won, K. Wang, S.-W. Cheong, S. Maiti, and G. Blumberg
It has been long established that collective charge oscillations of electron density relative to nuclei lattice – the bulk plasmons in metals – are typically unobservable by light scattering spectroscopy. Here, the authors report the unexpected observation of a distinct long-lived plasmon mode in the Raman spectrum of BiTeI, a material with a giant Rashba spin-orbit coupling. In contrast to conventional expectations, the findings reveal strong and direct light scattering by bulk plasmons even in the long-wavelength limit. The authors also establish the basic criteria enabling the discovered observation.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, L041111] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. C. Lee, S. Sarkar, K. Du, H.-H. Kung, C. J. Won, K. Wang, S.-W. Cheong, S. Maiti, and G. Blumberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dilution-induced current-density increase in disordered organic semiconductor devices: A kinetic Monte Carlo study]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014050</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014050"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Feiling Yang, Harm van Eersel, Jiawei Wang, Quan Niu, Peter A. Bobbert, Reinder Coehoorn, Feilong Liu, and Guofu Zhou
Dilution of certain disordered organic semiconductors with an inert material can significantly improve current density in devices, but so far the design conditions for a large effect have not been elucidated, hampering application to e.g. OLEDs. In this work, three-dimensional kinetic Monte Carlo simulations are used to study the counterintuitive effect. The results show that dilution is a double-edged sword: The observed effect reflects a balance between a beneficial rise in current density due to reduction of charge traps, and a detrimental fall due to reduction of conducting material in the system. The simulation results are furthermore described well by an analytical model.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 014050] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Feiling Yang, Harm van Eersel, Jiawei Wang, Quan Niu, Peter A. Bobbert, Reinder Coehoorn, Feilong Liu, and Guofu Zhou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gate-tunable kinetic inductance parametric amplifier]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014052</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014052"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lukas Johannes Splitthoff, Jaap Joachim Wesdorp, Marta Pita-Vidal, Arno Bargerbos, Yu Liu, and Christian Kraglund Andersen
Reading out the state of a quantum system at low temperature is generally challenging, as weak quantum signals must be amplified while adding as little noise as possible. Also, some qubit types rely on external magnetic fields and require magnetic-field-compatible superconducting parametric amplifiers. Here an innovative amp design leverages the nonlinear response of the gate-tunable kinetic inductance of proximitized semiconducting nanowires. The tunability allows integration with superconducting quantum systems, thanks to minimal crosstalk, and this amp can work with semiconductor-based spin qubits and other hybrid systems in magnetic fields of 500 mT.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 014052] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lukas Johannes Splitthoff, Jaap Joachim Wesdorp, Marta Pita-Vidal, Arno Bargerbos, Yu Liu, and Christian Kraglund Andersen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Operational performance of crystal collimation with 6.37 $Z$ TeV Pb ion beams at the LHC]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.27.011002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.27.011002"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. D’Andrea, O. Aberle, R. Bruce, M. Butcher, M. Di Castro, R. Cai, I. Lamas, A. Masi, D. Mirarchi, S. Redaelli, R. Rossi, and W. Scandale
Crystals are now used for collimation in LHC operation.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 27, 011002] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. D’Andrea, O. Aberle, R. Bruce, M. Butcher, M. Di Castro, R. Cai, I. Lamas, A. Masi, D. Mirarchi, S. Redaelli, R. Rossi, and W. Scandale</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-Sensitivity ac-Charge Detection with a MHz-Frequency Fluxonium Qubit]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011007</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011007"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): B.-L. Najera-Santos, R. Rousseau, K. Gerashchenko, H. Patange, A. Riva, M. Villiers, T. Briant, P.-F. Cohadon, A. Heidmann, J. Palomo, M. Rosticher, H. le Sueur, A. Sarlette, W. C. Smith, Z. Leghtas, E. Flurin, T. Jacqmin, and S. Deléglise
Researchers have demonstrated an unprecedentedly low-frequency superconducting “fluxonium” qubit, which could facilitate experiments that probe macroscopic quantum phenomena.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011007] Published Wed Jan 24, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>B.-L. Najera-Santos, R. Rousseau, K. Gerashchenko, H. Patange, A. Riva, M. Villiers, T. Briant, P.-F. Cohadon, A. Heidmann, J. Palomo, M. Rosticher, H. le Sueur, A. Sarlette, W. C. Smith, Z. Leghtas, E. Flurin, T. Jacqmin, and S. Deléglise</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elucidating the roles of chemistry, compositional complexity, and short-range order in the dislocation energetics of body-centered-cubic concentrated solid solutions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.013608</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.013608"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wenqing Wang, Flynn Walsh, Robert O. Ritchie, and Mark Asta
In compositionally complex refractory alloys, the formation of chemical short-range order has been calculated to flatten the spatial distribution of dislocation core energies. This study examines the extent to which such “narrowing” effects are unique to many-component systems, or if these results are more generally applicable. The authors computationally investigate how system chemistry, compositional complexity, and the presence of chemical short-range order affect dislocation energy distributions in subsystems of the NbMoTaW alloy. Order-induced narrowing is ultimately found to depend more on chemistry than the number of components.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 013608] Published Wed Jan 24, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wenqing Wang, Flynn Walsh, Robert O. Ritchie, and Mark Asta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetostriction-Driven Muon Localization in an Antiferromagnetic Oxide]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.046701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.046701"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pietro Bonfà, Ifeanyi John Onuorah, Franz Lang, Iurii Timrov, Lorenzo Monacelli, Chennan Wang, Xiao Sun, Oleg Petracic, Giovanni Pizzi, Nicola Marzari, Stephen J. Blundell, and Roberto De Renzi
Small energy differences determine muon-sample interactions, providing a significant insight into muon-spin spectroscopy of magnetic oxides.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 046701] Published Wed Jan 24, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pietro Bonfà, Ifeanyi John Onuorah, Franz Lang, Iurii Timrov, Lorenzo Monacelli, Chennan Wang, Xiao Sun, Oleg Petracic, Giovanni Pizzi, Nicola Marzari, Stephen J. Blundell, and Roberto De Renzi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental Evidence for Millisecond–Timescale Structural Evolution Following the Microsecond–Timescale Folding of a Small Protein]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.048402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.048402"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. Blake Wilson, Wai-Ming Yau, and Robert Tycko
Researchers have used nuclear magnetic resonance to observe a previously unseen intermediate state in which the protein lingers for an unexpectedly long time.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 048402] Published Wed Jan 24, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. Blake Wilson, Wai-Ming Yau, and Robert Tycko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Koopman-based model predictive control with morphing surface: Regulating the flutter response of a foil with an active flap]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.014702</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.014702"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tso-Kang Wang and Kourosh Shoele
In this work, we demonstrated how model predictive control (MPC) can effectively manipulate a highly nonlinear foil-and-flap system to follow designated lift trajectories to sub-5% error. The surrogate model is built through a data-driven method merging fluidic and structural information which can be readily deployed to numerous fluid-structure interaction systems. The rapid optimization procedure utilized to generate the control signal can also be used for estimating ambient environmental change

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 014702] Published Wed Jan 24, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tso-Kang Wang and Kourosh Shoele</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optical conductivity and damping of plasmons due to electron-electron interaction]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.045431</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.045431"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Prachi Sharma, Alessandro Principi, Giovanni Vignale, and Dmitrii L. Maslov
The calculation of the optical conductivity of electrons in two-dimensions is a classic problem of many-body theory. It is inextricably linked with the problem of plasmon damping, where plasmons are collective oscillations of the electronic density. Here, the authors resolve discrepancies that existed in the prior literature and provide definitive results for the dependence of the optical conductivity upon wavelength, frequency, and temperature. The results are interpreted in terms of bulk and shear viscosities of the electron gas.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 045431] Published Wed Jan 24, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Prachi Sharma, Alessandro Principi, Giovanni Vignale, and Dmitrii L. Maslov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Estimating the volume of correlation sets in causal networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.012220</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.012220"/>
        <updated>2024-01-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Giulio Camillo, Pedro Lauand, Davide Poderini, Rafael Rabelo, and Rafael Chaves
The authors study the link between causal relations and quantum correlations. In particular, given a network of causal relationships between physical systems, the authors calculate how many classical, quantum, and “nonsignaling” types of correlations arise. They compare their method to other approaches, and find that the often-used inflation technique misses a significant portion of nonclassical behavior.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 012220] Published Wed Jan 24, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giulio Camillo, Pedro Lauand, Davide Poderini, Rafael Rabelo, and Rafael Chaves</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Efficient Tensor Network Simulation of IBM’s Eagle Kicked Ising Experiment]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.5.010308</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.5.010308"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Joseph Tindall, Matthew Fishman, E. Miles Stoudenmire, and Dries Sels
Improved classical methods for Hamiltonian simulation further shift the threshold for quantum utility.

[PRX Quantum 5, 010308] Published Tue Jan 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph Tindall, Matthew Fishman, E. Miles Stoudenmire, and Dries Sels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hybrid coherent control of magnons in a ferromagnetic phononic resonator excited by laser pulses]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.6.L012019</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.6.L012019"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexey V. Scherbakov, Alex D. Carr, Tetiana L. Linnik, Serhii M. Kukhtaruk, Andrew D. Armour, Achim Nadzeyka, Andrew W. Rushforth, Andrey V. Akimov, and Manfred Bayer
A femtosecond laser pulse triggers hybrid excitation of magnons in a ferromagnetic nanostructure via an instant broadband kick and also through quasiharmonic driving by phonons. By tuning the external magnetic field and exploiting the dependence of the phase of the broadband excitation on the laser fluence, the phase and amplitude of the coherent magnon response is manipulated.

[Phys. Rev. Research 6, L012019] Published Tue Jan 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexey V. Scherbakov, Alex D. Carr, Tetiana L. Linnik, Serhii M. Kukhtaruk, Andrew D. Armour, Achim Nadzeyka, Andrew W. Rushforth, Andrey V. Akimov, and Manfred Bayer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Surface termination effect of $\mathrm{SrTi}{\mathrm{O}}_{3}$ substrate on ultrathin $\mathrm{SrRu}{\mathrm{O}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.013605</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.013605"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Huiyu Wang, Zhen Wang, Zeeshan Ali, Enling Wang, Mohammad Saghayezhian, Jiandong Guo, Yimei Zhu, Jing Tao, and Jiandi Zhang
A well-defined substrate surface is crucial for the epitaxy of complex materials, especially for revealing intrinsic properties of films in ultrathin limit. Here by atomically precise growth and characterization, the origin for the lateral inhomogeneity of ultrathin SrRuO3 films due to the step effects of SrTiO3 (001) is revealed. Two distinct types of step propagation along the [011] and [01¯1] crystallographic direction is identified, respectively. In particular, the type-II [01¯1] step results in lateral discontinuity of monolayer SrRuO3 and originates from the SrO-terminated regions along the TiO2-terminated step edge, responsible for the distinct electronic and magnetic properties of monolayer SrRuO3.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 013605] Published Tue Jan 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Huiyu Wang, Zhen Wang, Zeeshan Ali, Enling Wang, Mohammad Saghayezhian, Jiandong Guo, Yimei Zhu, Jing Tao, and Jiandi Zhang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photonic Flatband Resonances in Multiple Light Scattering]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.043803</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.043803"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Thanh Xuan Hoang, Daniel Leykam, and Yuri Kivshar
Light–matter interactions in certain one-dimensional photonic materials can bring light nearly to a standstill, an effect that researchers show requires consideration of long-range interactions between the material’s components.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 043803] Published Tue Jan 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thanh Xuan Hoang, Daniel Leykam, and Yuri Kivshar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamics of a time-delayed relay system]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014223</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014223"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lucas Illing, Pierce Ryan, and Andreas Amann
Time-delayed relay systems, systems with switches transmitting a signal with a time delay, can be found in the biological world as well as in mechanical or electrical systems. In this paper, the authors model them using second-order linear delay differential equations and analyze their solutions, finding that, for the same values of the parameters, many stable solutions coexist.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 014223] Published Tue Jan 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucas Illing, Pierce Ryan, and Andreas Amann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chiral phonons and phononic birefringence in ferromagnetic metal–bulk acoustic resonator hybrids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024430</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024430"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Müller, J. Weber, F. Engelhardt, V. A. S. V. Bittencourt, T. Luschmann, M. Cherkasskii, M. Opel, S. T. B. Goennenwein, S. Viola Kusminskiy, S. Geprägs, R. Gross, M. Althammer, and H. Huebl
The magnetoelastic coupling of magnetic and elastic excitations enables the generation of elastic waves carrying angular momentum. In a quantum picture, this corresponds to a resonant conversion of magnons to chiral phonons and vice versa. This study showcases this conversion process using a simple and versatile experimental platform consisting of a metallic magnetic thin film on a crystalline substrate. These findings allow us to study the impact of crystal symmetry on angular momentum transport by phonons and investigate phononic birefringence.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 024430] Published Tue Jan 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Müller, J. Weber, F. Engelhardt, V. A. S. V. Bittencourt, T. Luschmann, M. Cherkasskii, M. Opel, S. T. B. Goennenwein, S. Viola Kusminskiy, S. Geprägs, R. Gross, M. Althammer, and H. Huebl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Itinerant ferromagnetism in transition metal dichalcogenide moiré superlattices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.045144</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.045144"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pawel Potasz, Nicolás Morales-Durán, Nai Chao Hu, and Allan H. MacDonald
Moiré superlattices give a unique opportunity to investigate controllable quantum systems. Previous studies of transition metal dichalcogenide heterobilayers mainly focused on magnetic order at half-filling or charge orders at partial fillings. Here, the authors investigate itinerant ferromagnetism in the vicinity of the van Hove singularity of moiré triangular superlattices. From many-body exact diagonalization calculations that shed light on the magnon spectra and the magnetic susceptibility, the Curie temperature is estimated to vary with moiré lattice constant, from a few to a few tens of kelvins.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 045144] Published Tue Jan 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pawel Potasz, Nicolás Morales-Durán, Nai Chao Hu, and Allan H. MacDonald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gapless fluctuations and exceptional points in semiconductor lasers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.045306</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.045306"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. H. Kwong, M. Em. Spotnitz, and R. Binder
Semiconductor lasers have formal analogies to Bardeen-Cooper-Schrieffer (BCS) superconductors. This work shows that, in analogy to gapless superconductivity, a gapless lasing parametric regime, in which the frequency gap in the fluctuation spectrum is closed, exists for steady-state semiconductor lasers. The gap opens when the laser intensity exceeds a threshold. This gapless-to-gapped transition occurs at a third-order exceptional point.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 045306] Published Tue Jan 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. H. Kwong, M. Em. Spotnitz, and R. Binder</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coherent control of molecular rotation in superfluid helium]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.013110</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.013110"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexander A. Milner, Ian MacPhail-Bartley, Katarina Preocanin, Shroyon Dasgupta, Xuanshan Peng, and Valery Milner
The authors experimentally demonstrate control of molecular rotation in bulk superfluid ^{4}He. The authors show that both the degree of rotational excitation of metastable helium dimers and the directionality of molecular rotation can be controlled by different aspects of the pulse trains.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 013110] Published Tue Jan 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexander A. Milner, Ian MacPhail-Bartley, Katarina Preocanin, Shroyon Dasgupta, Xuanshan Peng, and Valery Milner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Classical Purcell factors and spontaneous emission decay rates in a linear gain medium]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.013513</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.013513"/>
        <updated>2024-01-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Juanjuan Ren, Sebastian Franke, Becca VanDrunen, and Stephen Hughes
The authors derive a correction to the spontaneous emission rate and the classical Purcell factor in linear media that includes gain and loss within the framework of a classical light-matter theory. The results fully recover a recently presented quantum mechanical form, establishing an essential classical-to-quantum correspondence of spontaneous emission, and are extended to also account for local field effects.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 013513] Published Tue Jan 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Juanjuan Ren, Sebastian Franke, Becca VanDrunen, and Stephen Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Colloidal gelation induced by ring polymers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.6.013079</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.6.013079"/>
        <updated>2024-01-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Esmaeel Moghimi, Iurii Chubak, Maria Kaliva, Parvin Kiany, Taihyun Chang, Junyoung Ahn, Nikolaos Patelis, Georgios Sakellariou, Sergei A. Egorov, Dimitris Vlassopoulos, and Christos N. Likos
When nonadsorbing ring polymers are added in a fluid suspension of big, spherical colloids, solid gels are formed. Joint experimental, computational, and theoretical work shows that these gels are much stronger than those formed by the addition of linear polymer chains.

[Phys. Rev. Research 6, 013079] Published Mon Jan 22, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Esmaeel Moghimi, Iurii Chubak, Maria Kaliva, Parvin Kiany, Taihyun Chang, Junyoung Ahn, Nikolaos Patelis, Georgios Sakellariou, Sergei A. Egorov, Dimitris Vlassopoulos, and Christos N. Likos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spectroscopic Evidence of Kondo-Induced Quasiquartet in ${\mathrm{CeRh}}_{2}{\mathrm{As}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.046401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.046401"/>
        <updated>2024-01-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Denise S. Christovam, Miguel Ferreira-Carvalho, Andrea Marino, Martin Sundermann, Daisuke Takegami, Anna Melendez-Sans, Ku Ding Tsuei, Zhiwei Hu, Sahana Rößler, Manuel Valvidares, Maurits W. Haverkort, Yu Liu, Eric D. Bauer, Liu Hao Tjeng, Gertrud Zwicknagl, and Andrea Severing
Temperature dependent x-ray absorption spectroscopy experiments on CeRh2As2 offers direct evidence for the coupling of the Kondo interaction and crystal-field states.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 046401] Published Mon Jan 22, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Denise S. Christovam, Miguel Ferreira-Carvalho, Andrea Marino, Martin Sundermann, Daisuke Takegami, Anna Melendez-Sans, Ku Ding Tsuei, Zhiwei Hu, Sahana Rößler, Manuel Valvidares, Maurits W. Haverkort, Yu Liu, Eric D. Bauer, Liu Hao Tjeng, Gertrud Zwicknagl, and Andrea Severing</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Composite-fermion pairing at half-filled and quarter-filled lowest Landau level]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.035306</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.035306"/>
        <updated>2024-01-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anirban Sharma, Ajit C. Balram, and J. K. Jain
The physical origin of the fractional quantum Hall effect at the half-filled lowest Landau level in wide quantum wells has remained a puzzle since its discovery three decades ago. This work presents quantitative calculations supporting the formation of a p-wave topological “superconductor” of composite fermions (CFs) here. CFs are predicted to form f-wave pairs at the quarter-filled Landau level in wide quantum wells. CF pairing is thus seen as the principal mechanism underlying the even-denominator fractional quantum Hall effect.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 035306] Published Mon Jan 22, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anirban Sharma, Ajit C. Balram, and J. K. Jain</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Superexchange coupling of donor qubits in silicon]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014038</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014038"/>
        <updated>2024-01-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mushita M. Munia, Serajum Monir, Edyta N. Osika, Michelle Y. Simmons, and Rajib Rahman
Spin coupling of non-nearest-neighbor qubits is of interest to enhance connectivity in quantum computing architectures. Solving and predicting many-body problems exactly is computationally challenging, though, so the approach has remained largely unexplored. This study uses a full configuration-interaction technique combined with atomistic tight-binding calculations to investigate a non-nearest-neighbor exchange-coupling mechanism analogous to superexchange in magnetic materials. This coupling turn out to be less susceptible to charge noise than nearest-neighbor coupling, and so has the potential to reduce local qubit crosstalk and gate densities in silicon-based quantum architectures.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 014038] Published Mon Jan 22, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mushita M. Munia, Serajum Monir, Edyta N. Osika, Michelle Y. Simmons, and Rajib Rahman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inertia Induces Strong Orientation Fluctuations of Nonspherical Atmospheric Particles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.034101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.034101"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Bhowmick, J. Seesing, K. Gustavsson, J. Guettler, Y. Wang, A. Pumir, B. Mehlig, and G. Bagheri
Experiments with small falling particles show that their orientations oscillate—which may help explain the settling of volcanic ash and the formation of snow.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 034101] Published Fri Jan 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Bhowmick, J. Seesing, K. Gustavsson, J. Guettler, Y. Wang, A. Pumir, B. Mehlig, and G. Bagheri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Characterization and Control of the Run-and-Tumble Dynamics of <i>Escherichia Coli</i>]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.038302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.038302"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christina Kurzthaler, Yongfeng Zhao, Nan Zhou, Jana Schwarz-Linek, Clemence Devailly, Jochen Arlt, Jian-Dong Huang, Wilson C. K. Poon, Thomas Franosch, Julien Tailleur, and Vincent A. Martinez
A new technique could allow researchers to distinguish the swimming motion of a species of microorganisms without the need to track individuals within a population.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 038302] Published Fri Jan 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christina Kurzthaler, Yongfeng Zhao, Nan Zhou, Jana Schwarz-Linek, Clemence Devailly, Jochen Arlt, Jian-Dong Huang, Wilson C. K. Poon, Thomas Franosch, Julien Tailleur, and Vincent A. Martinez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantitative characterization of run-and-tumble statistics in bulk bacterial suspensions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014612</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014612"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yongfeng Zhao, Christina Kurzthaler, Nan Zhou, Jana Schwarz-Linek, Clemence Devailly, Jochen Arlt, Jian-Dong Huang, Wilson C. K. Poon, Thomas Franosch, Vincent A. Martinez, and Julien Tailleur
A new technique could allow researchers to distinguish the swimming motion of a species of microorganisms without the need to track individuals within a population.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 014612] Published Fri Jan 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yongfeng Zhao, Christina Kurzthaler, Nan Zhou, Jana Schwarz-Linek, Clemence Devailly, Jochen Arlt, Jian-Dong Huang, Wilson C. K. Poon, Thomas Franosch, Vincent A. Martinez, and Julien Tailleur</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bounds on the equation of state from QCD inequalities and lattice QCD]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.014020</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.014020"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuki Fujimoto and Sanjay Reddy
The equation of state for nuclear matter is essential to understanding neutron stars. Using strict QCD inequalities and input from numerical simulations on the lattice, the authors derive useful bounds on the baryon and energy densities, which are relevant to isospin symmetric matter at densities probed by heavy ion collisions.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 014020] Published Fri Jan 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuki Fujimoto and Sanjay Reddy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetic antiskyrmions in two-dimensional van der Waals magnets engineered by layer stacking]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024426</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024426"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kai Huang, Edward Schwartz, Ding-Fu Shao, Alexey A. Kovalev, and Evgeny Y. Tsymbal
Antiskyrmions, like skyrmions, are topologically protected magnetic quasiparticles, but exhibit greater stability and no transverse motion compared to skyrmions. This study employs ab initio calculations to investigate the polar layer stacking of two monolayers of a two-dimensional magnetic material CrI3, which can lead to the emergence of antiskyrmions. Atomistic spin dynamics simulations demonstrate the realization of antiskyrmions in Mn-doped CrI3 and shows that their spin texture can be switched by ferroelectric polarization of the polar bilayer.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 024426] Published Fri Jan 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kai Huang, Edward Schwartz, Ding-Fu Shao, Alexey A. Kovalev, and Evgeny Y. Tsymbal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hubbard parameters for programmable tweezer arrays]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.013318</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.013318"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hao-Tian Wei, Eduardo Ibarra-García-Padilla, Michael L. Wall, and Kaden R. A. Hazzard
The authors develop a method to compute the Hubbard-model parameters for tunnel-coupled tweezer arrays given the trap parameters. The method also solves the inverse problem of finding trap configurations given desired Hubbard parameters, providing tools for using tunnel-coupled tweezer arrays.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 013318] Published Fri Jan 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hao-Tian Wei, Eduardo Ibarra-García-Padilla, Michael L. Wall, and Kaden R. A. Hazzard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental realization of Lorentz boosts of space-time wave packets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.013509</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.013509"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Murat Yessenov, Miguel Romer, Naoki Ichiji, and Ayman F. Abouraddy
The authors present an experimental procedure that is analogous to Lorentz boosts of space-time wave packets (STWPs), in that the physical transformation is identical to the mathematical impact of a Lorentz transformation except for an overall Doppler shift to the carrier. Their work indicates that a Lorentz boost of a STWP results in another STWP.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 013509] Published Fri Jan 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Murat Yessenov, Miguel Romer, Naoki Ichiji, and Ayman F. Abouraddy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Broken Kramers Degeneracy in Altermagnetic MnTe]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.036702</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.036702"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Suyoung Lee, Sangjae Lee, Saegyeol Jung, Jiwon Jung, Donghan Kim, Yeonjae Lee, Byeongjun Seok, Jaeyoung Kim, Byeong Gyu Park, Libor Šmejkal, Chang-Jong Kang, and Changyoung Kim
Spectroscopic data suggest that thin films of a certain semiconducting material can exhibit altermagnetism, a new and fundamental form of magnetism.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 036702] Published Thu Jan 18, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Suyoung Lee, Sangjae Lee, Saegyeol Jung, Jiwon Jung, Donghan Kim, Yeonjae Lee, Byeongjun Seok, Jaeyoung Kim, Byeong Gyu Park, Libor Šmejkal, Chang-Jong Kang, and Changyoung Kim</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emergence of Competing Orders and Possible Quantum Spin Liquid in $\mathrm{SU}(N)$ Fermions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.036704</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.036704"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xue-Jia Yu, Shao-Hang Shi, Limei Xu, and Zi-Xiang Li
A realistic SU(N) interacting fermionic model reveals exotic quantum magnetic phases that occur at intermediate N, where the competition between distinct ordering tendencies gives rise to an intermediate quantum spin liquid phase featuring nontrivial topological order.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 036704] Published Thu Jan 18, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xue-Jia Yu, Shao-Hang Shi, Limei Xu, and Zi-Xiang Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Percolation and Topological Properties of Temporal Higher-Order Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.037401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.037401"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Leonardo Di Gaetano, Federico Battiston, and Michele Starnini
A hidden-variable formalism allows for the characterization of topological properties of temporal networks with higher-order interactions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 037401] Published Thu Jan 18, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leonardo Di Gaetano, Federico Battiston, and Michele Starnini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conformations, correlations, and instabilities of a flexible fiber in an active fluid]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.013102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.013102"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Scott Weady, David B. Stein, Alexandra Zidovska, and Michael J. Shelley
Many biological systems rely on interactions between active processes and passive, deformable structures to properly function. An important example is chromatin in the cell nucleus, where ATP-powered processes, such as transcription or DNA repair, act on the chromatin fiber and influence its motion. Motivated by this system, in this study we develop and analyze a model of a flexible fiber in an active suspension as an analog to a chromatin fiber in an active environment - the nucleoplasm. Interactions between the suspension and the fiber lead to a novel bend instability, and nonlinear simulations identify coherent motions and conformations of the fiber over long timescales.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 013102] Published Thu Jan 18, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Scott Weady, David B. Stein, Alexandra Zidovska, and Michael J. Shelley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing the photon emissivity of the quark-gluon plasma without an inverse problem in lattice QCD]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.014507</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.014507"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marco Cè, Tim Harris, Ardit Krasniqi, Harvey B. Meyer, and Csaba Török
One of the most important applications of lattice gauge theory is the computation of transport coefficients at nonzero temperature. The authors compute moments of the photon emissivity with respect to the imaginary frequency, and find promising results.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 014507] Published Thu Jan 18, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marco Cè, Tim Harris, Ardit Krasniqi, Harvey B. Meyer, and Csaba Török</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recombination of ${B}_{c}$ mesons in ultrarelativistic heavy-ion collisions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.014906</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.014906"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Biaogang Wu, Zhanduo Tang, Min He, and Ralf Rapp
The large production of the heavy charm and bottom quarks in heavy-ion collisions over that in pp collisions provides key signatures of the formation of the hot and strongly interacting phase known as the quark-gluon plasma. This paper reports on calculations of yields of Bc+ mesons, consisting of a bottom and a charm quark, in Pb + Pb collisions at 5.02 TeV/nucleon at the LHC. The authors compare the results of their transport model with recent CMS data and attribute the observed enhancement to recombination processes of heavy quarks with large phase-space densities in a quark-gluon plasma.

[Phys. Rev. C 109, 014906] Published Thu Jan 18, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Biaogang Wu, Zhanduo Tang, Min He, and Ralf Rapp</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optically trapped microspheres are high-bandwidth acoustic transducers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014031</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014031"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): L.E. Hillberry and M.G. Raizen
This work studies optically trapped microspheres as flow sensors for the purpose of acoustic transduction in air. While traditional microphones are sensitive to pressure variations and have a peak bandwidth of about 200 kHz, the optically trapped microsphere is sensitive to velocity variations and resolves waveforms with frequency content in the megahertz range. Variations of this method could find applications in near-field acoustic metrology for vibrations, surface waves, and small-scale blast waves; in medicine for ultrasonic imaging in proton cancer therapy; and in bubble-chamber searches for dark matter.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 014031] Published Thu Jan 18, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L.E. Hillberry and M.G. Raizen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Trapping of Slow Electrons in the Energy Domain]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.035001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.035001"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maor Eldar, Zhaopin Chen, Yiming Pan, and Michael Krüger
Numerical investigation of the phase-matched interaction of slow electrons with a strong optical field unveils a tunable trapping, opening the door for manipulating free electrons in the low-energy regime.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 035001] Published Wed Jan 17, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maor Eldar, Zhaopin Chen, Yiming Pan, and Michael Krüger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonvolatile Switching of Large Nonreciprocal Optical Absorption at Shortwave Infrared Wavelengths]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.036901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.036901"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kenta Kimura and Tsuyoshi Kimura
At low temperatures, crystals of lithium nickel phosphate transmit short-wavelength infrared light much more strongly in one direction than in the other.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 036901] Published Wed Jan 17, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kenta Kimura and Tsuyoshi Kimura</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimized nuclear energy density functionals including long-range pion contributions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.014319</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.014319"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): L. Zurek, S. K. Bogner, R. J. Furnstahl, R. Navarro Pérez, N. Schunck, and A. Schwenk
Nuclear energy-density functionals successfully reproduce properties of nuclei across almost the entire nuclear chart. However, nearly all available functionals are phenomenological in nature. Here, a step toward connecting the functionals to realistic underlying nuclear forces is made by taking the long-range contributions from chiral effective field theory along with a phenomenological Skyrme part. This involves no new parameters and results in a significant improvement in the description of nuclear data.

[Phys. Rev. C 109, 014319] Published Wed Jan 17, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L. Zurek, S. K. Bogner, R. J. Furnstahl, R. Navarro Pérez, N. Schunck, and A. Schwenk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voltage-time dilemma and stochastic threshold-voltage variation in pure-silver atomic switches]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014027</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014027"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anna Nyáry, Zoltán Balogh, Máté Vigh, Botond Sánta, László Pósa, and András Halbritter
Silver plays a prominent role as an active material in resistive-switching memory devices (memristors) based on electrochemical metallization. Such a structure contains in its active volume nanoscale Ag filaments, which can be used as artificial synapses in neural-network applications. Meanwhile, a fundamentally different type of resistive switching occurs in an atomic wire of pure Ag, where an embedding, ion-hosting environment is absent. This comparative study clarifies the characteristics and origins of the latter, purely atomic switching phenomenon, highlighting its importance in silver-based memristive devices as the active volume approaches truly atomic dimensions.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 014027] Published Wed Jan 17, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Nyáry, Zoltán Balogh, Máté Vigh, Botond Sánta, László Pósa, and András Halbritter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proof-of-principle ${e}^{+}$ source for future colliders]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.27.013401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.27.013401"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. Vallis, P. Craievich, M. Schär, R. Zennaro, B. Auchmann, H. H. Braun, M. I. Besana, M. Duda, R. Fortunati, H. Garcia-Rodrigues, D. Hauenstein, R. Ischebeck, E. Ismaili, P. Juranić, J. Kosse, A. Magazinik, F. Marcellini, T. Michlmayr, S. Müller, M. Pedrozzi, R. Rotundo, G. L. Orlandi, M. Seidel, N. Strohmaier, and M. Zykova
A positron source demonstrator with the potential to increase the yield by an order of magnitude.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 27, 013401] Published Wed Jan 17, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Vallis, P. Craievich, M. Schär, R. Zennaro, B. Auchmann, H. H. Braun, M. I. Besana, M. Duda, R. Fortunati, H. Garcia-Rodrigues, D. Hauenstein, R. Ischebeck, E. Ismaili, P. Juranić, J. Kosse, A. Magazinik, F. Marcellini, T. Michlmayr, S. Müller, M. Pedrozzi, R. Rotundo, G. L. Orlandi, M. Seidel, N. Strohmaier, and M. Zykova</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonequilibrium Response for Markov Jump Processes: Exact Results and Tight Bounds]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.037101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.037101"/>
        <updated>2024-01-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Timur Aslyamov and Massimiliano Esposito
A novel linear-algebra method opens the way to efficiently study a broad class of responses for nonequilibrium systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 037101] Published Tue Jan 16, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Timur Aslyamov and Massimiliano Esposito</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thermodynamic bound on quantum state discrimination]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014119</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014119"/>
        <updated>2024-01-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): José Polo-Gómez
The limitations that thermodynamics imposes on quantum information theory are investigated in this paper, which examines an ideal gas with an internal quantum degree of freedom undergoing a cycle. By considering a demon capable of distinguishing two quantum states, the author shows that the ability to distinguish quantum states is bounded by the second law of thermodynamics.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 014119] Published Tue Jan 16, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>José Polo-Gómez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neutron radiography of an anisotropic drainage flow]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014609</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014609"/>
        <updated>2024-01-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Artem Skrypnik, Katie Cole, Tobias Lappan, Pablo R. Brito-Parada, Stephen J. Neethling, Pavel Trtik, Kerstin Eckert, and Sascha Heitkam
Usually, gravity causes liquid to drain out of a foam vertically, but simulations have predicted that if the foam is sheared, the drainage will be anisotropic. This paper describes an experimental verification of that prediction by neutron radiography, which shows that the vertical drainage flow is indeed deflected horizontally.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 014609] Published Tue Jan 16, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Artem Skrypnik, Katie Cole, Tobias Lappan, Pablo R. Brito-Parada, Stephen J. Neethling, Pavel Trtik, Kerstin Eckert, and Sascha Heitkam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All-optical dual-axis zero-field atomic magnetometer using light-shift modulation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014023</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014023"/>
        <updated>2024-01-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xiaoyu Li, Bangcheng Han, Kaixuan Zhang, Ziao Liu, Shuying Wang, Yifan Yan, and Jixi Lu
Researchers have achieved dual-axis magnetic-field detection using an atomic magnetometer architecture with only optical instruments.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 014023] Published Tue Jan 16, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiaoyu Li, Bangcheng Han, Kaixuan Zhang, Ziao Liu, Shuying Wang, Yifan Yan, and Jixi Lu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Development of Neutron Interferometer Using Multilayer Mirrors and Measurements of Neutron-Nuclear Scattering Length with Pulsed Neutron Source]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.023402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.023402"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Takuhiro Fujiie, Masahiro Hino, Takuya Hosobata, Go Ichikawa, Masaaki Kitaguchi, Kenji Mishima, Yoshichika Seki, Hirohiko M. Shimizu, and Yutaka Yamagata
Researchers have demonstrated a mirror-based neutron interferometer that should be more sensitive to beyond-standard-model particle interactions than previous instruments.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 023402] Published Fri Jan 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Takuhiro Fujiie, Masahiro Hino, Takuya Hosobata, Go Ichikawa, Masaaki Kitaguchi, Kenji Mishima, Yoshichika Seki, Hirohiko M. Shimizu, and Yutaka Yamagata</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synchronization of Bloch Oscillations in a Strongly Coupled Pair of Small Josephson Junctions: Evidence for a Shapiro-like Current Step]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.027001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.027001"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fabian Kaap, David Scheer, Fabian Hassler, and Sergey Lotkhov
High-precision measurements of the oscillations generated by a superconducting device suggest that an improved electric-current-calibration standard should be possible.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 027001] Published Fri Jan 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fabian Kaap, David Scheer, Fabian Hassler, and Sergey Lotkhov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accelerated Adiabatic Passage of a Single Electron Spin Qubit in Quantum Dots]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.027002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.027002"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xiao-Fei Liu, Yuta Matsumoto, Takafumi Fujita, Arne Ludwig, Andreas D. Wieck, and Akira Oiwa
Schemes for shortcuts to adiabaticity are demonstrated in gate-defined quantum dots based on transitionless quantum driving.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 027002] Published Fri Jan 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiao-Fei Liu, Yuta Matsumoto, Takafumi Fujita, Arne Ludwig, Andreas D. Wieck, and Akira Oiwa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dispersion and deformation of molecular patterns written in turbulent air]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.014502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.014502"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Willem van de Water, Nico Dam, and Enrico Calzavarini
This letter “H” is written in turbulent air by tagging molecules in the focus of intense laser beams that cross in space. In the course of 40 microseconds, turbulence deforms and disperses the pattern. It could be used as a way to measure the velocity of the turbulent eddies. However, more importantly, it reveals the intricate interplay between molecular diffusion and turbulent dispersion.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 014502] Published Fri Jan 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Willem van de Water, Nico Dam, and Enrico Calzavarini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distinct universality classes of diffusive transport from full counting statistics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024417</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024417"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sarang Gopalakrishnan, Alan Morningstar, Romain Vasseur, and Vedika Khemani
The authors provide an analytic theory of the transport of magnetization in a set of interacting anisotropic spin chains. Even though these are many-body systems with diffusive transport on average, the full distribution that gives rise to that average is far from Gaussian – with fluctuations that, unlike conventional diffusion, are comparable to the mean. This is an example of how systems with the same hydrodynamics can belong to distinct dynamical universality classes.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 024417] Published Fri Jan 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarang Gopalakrishnan, Alan Morningstar, Romain Vasseur, and Vedika Khemani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Radio-frequency-modulated artificial synapses based on magnetic tunnel junctions with perpendicular magnetic anisotropy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014020</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014020"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kexin Zeng, Yawen Luo, Like Zhang, Huayao Tu, Yanxiang Luo, Xuan Zhang, Bin Fang, and Zhongming Zeng
Artificial neural networks (ANNs) based on the microwave properties of magnetic tunnel junctions (MTJs) have an advantage in recognizing rf signals without digital-to-analog conversion. However, so far there has been no good way to exploit frequency multiplexing in MTJ-based ANNs. To this end, the authors explore changing the perpendicular magnetic anisotropy between a Co-Fe-B free layer and MgO barrier. Their spintronic synapse with adjustable positive and negative weights can classify rf signals with an accuracy exceeding 96%, comparable to that of equivalent software-based neural networks. This work may well pave the way for the development of rf-oriented hardware ANNs.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 014020] Published Fri Jan 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kexin Zeng, Yawen Luo, Like Zhang, Huayao Tu, Yanxiang Luo, Xuan Zhang, Bin Fang, and Zhongming Zeng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Light-induced microwave noise in superconducting microwave-optical transducers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014022</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014022"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mingrui Xu, Chunzhen Li, Yuntao Xu, and Hong X. Tang
Microwave-to-optical transduction is expected to play a pivotal role in scaling up superconducting quantum processors and facilitating their long-distance communication via optical fiber, but a notable hurdle here is light-induced microwave noise. This study investigates the mechanisms that create such noise in a thin-film LiNbO3 device. Three distinct noise sources, with unique time constants spanning orders of magnitude, are identified. The authors also investigate the power dependence of each noise component, and offer potential strategies for mitigation. The insights gained from this work provide important design guidelines for efficient, low-noise transduction.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 014022] Published Fri Jan 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mingrui Xu, Chunzhen Li, Yuntao Xu, and Hong X. Tang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evidence for the Higgs Boson Decay to a $Z$ Boson and a Photon at the LHC]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.021803</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.021803"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): G. Aad et al. (ATLAS Collaboration, CMS Collaboration)
The Large Hadron Collider’s ATLAS and CMS collaborations have analyzed data of a rare Higgs-boson decay, finding a hint of a disagreement with standard-model predictions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 021803] Published Thu Jan 11, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>G. Aad &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (ATLAS Collaboration, CMS Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ginzburg-Landau Theory of Flat-Band Superconductors with Quantum Metric]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.026002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.026002"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shuai A. Chen and K. T. Law
An application of Ginzburg-Landau theory to superconducting twisted bilayer graphene determines the coherence length and the upper critical field, which are in agreement with recent experiments.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 026002] Published Thu Jan 11, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shuai A. Chen and K. T. Law</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Germanium Vacancy in Diamond Quantum Memory Exceeding 20 ms]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.026901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.026901"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Katharina Senkalla, Genko Genov, Mathias H. Metsch, Petr Siyushev, and Fedor Jelezko
An experiment demonstrates a record long quantum coherence time that exceeds 20 milliseconds for a germanium vacancy in diamond.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 026901] Published Thu Jan 11, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharina Senkalla, Genko Genov, Mathias H. Metsch, Petr Siyushev, and Fedor Jelezko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fate of Boltzmann’s Breathers: Stokes Hypothesis and Anomalous Thermalization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.027101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.027101"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. I. García de Soria, P. Maynar, David Guéry-Odelin, and Emmanuel Trizac
Boltzmann breathers can thermalize at long times due to a damping mechanism related to the bulk viscosity for finite densities.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 027101] Published Thu Jan 11, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. I. García de Soria, P. Maynar, David Guéry-Odelin, and Emmanuel Trizac</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marangoni vortex rings in miscible spreading]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.L012701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.L012701"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anurag Pant and Baburaj. A Puthenveettil
This work investigates the dynamics of a unique, radially expanding vortex ring in a water layer when a miscible, volatile drop of ethanol spreads as a film on the air-water interface. The study unravels the link between the dynamics at the interface and the generation of vorticity in the water layer below it. A novel scaling is proposed for the radius and velocity of such vortex rings, where they are shown to be dependent on time as well as the properties of the drop and the substrate.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, L012701] Published Thu Jan 11, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anurag Pant and Baburaj. A Puthenveettil</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Supernova emission of secretly interacting neutrino fluid: Theoretical foundations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.023017</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.023017"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Damiano F. G. Fiorillo, Georg G. Raffelt, and Edoardo Vitagliano
The paper examines theoretically the possibility that neutrinos in supernova cores act as a self-coupled fluid. It follows systematically from first principles the fluid’s diffusive transport through the core to the surface, and its expansion into space.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 023017] Published Thu Jan 11, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano F. G. Fiorillo, Georg G. Raffelt, and Edoardo Vitagliano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fundamental and Second-Order Superregular Breathers in Vector Fields]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.027201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.027201"/>
        <updated>2024-01-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chong Liu, Shao-Chun Chen, and Nail Akhmediev
An exact theory for superregular breathers in Manakov systems is derived, with possible applications to a wide range of nonlinear wave phenomena.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 027201] Published Wed Jan 10, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chong Liu, Shao-Chun Chen, and Nail Akhmediev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upper bounds on superconducting and excitonic phase stiffness for interacting isolated narrow bands]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024507</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024507"/>
        <updated>2024-01-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dan Mao and Debanjan Chowdhury
This work develops a systematic theoretical framework to determine the low-energy effective “diamagnetic” response associated with superconductivity and excitonic superfluidity in strongly interacting electronic models hosting isolated nearly flat bands. The results can be used to derive upper bounds on the transition temperatures for superconductivity and excitonic superfluidity without making any mean-field type approximations. The same theoretical framework can also be extended with very few modifications, to address questions related to ferromagnetism in flat bands and magnetic circular dichroism.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 024507] Published Wed Jan 10, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Mao and Debanjan Chowdhury</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vibrations and transitions across barrier of strained nanoribbons at finite temperature]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.016001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.016001"/>
        <updated>2024-01-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Paul Z. Hanakata, Sourav S. Bhabesh, David Yllanes, David R. Nelson, and Mark J. Bowick
Thermalized crystalline sheets, such as graphene liberated from a substrate, are driven by height fluctuations. The authors study the nonlinear dynamics of doubly-clamped nanoribbons as prototypical graphene resonators. Such ribbons exhibit a thermalized version of Euler buckling, with both up and down local minima. Treating the ribbon as a Brownian particle confined to a double-well potential, they determine transition rates across the two wells and oscillations inside a given well via molecular dynamics simulations. The dynamical behavior found is very different from Arrhenius behavior. The rate-controlling exponential factor depends only on the geometry, as opposed to the temperature, providing a new pathway for the experimental control of thermalized two-dimensional metamaterials.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 016001] Published Tue Jan 09, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Z. Hanakata, Sourav S. Bhabesh, David Yllanes, David R. Nelson, and Mark J. Bowick</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Suppression of Richtmyer-Meshkov Instability via Special Pairs of Shocks and Phase Transitions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.024001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.024001"/>
        <updated>2024-01-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): W. J. Schill, M. R. Armstrong, J. H. Nguyen, D. M. Sterbentz, D. A. White, L. X. Benedict, R. N. Rieben, A. Hoff, H. E. Lorenzana, J. L. Belof, B. M. La Lone, and M. D. Staska
Neutralization of a shock-generated Richtmyer-Meshkov instability at the interface between heavy and light materials using timed double-shock wave fronts is demonstrated experimentally and verified numerically.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 024001] Published Tue Jan 09, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>W. J. Schill, M. R. Armstrong, J. H. Nguyen, D. M. Sterbentz, D. A. White, L. X. Benedict, R. N. Rieben, A. Hoff, H. E. Lorenzana, J. L. Belof, B. M. La Lone, and M. D. Staska</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Formation and mechanics of fire ant rafts as an active self-healing membrane]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014607</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014607"/>
        <updated>2024-01-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chung-Hao Chen, Ting-Heng Hsieh, Hong-Yue Huang, Yu-Chuan Cheng, and Tzay-Ming Hong
The rate at which a raft made of ants is stretched determines its properties because the ants take time to fix holes.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 014607] Published Tue Jan 09, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chung-Hao Chen, Ting-Heng Hsieh, Hong-Yue Huang, Yu-Chuan Cheng, and Tzay-Ming Hong</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exotic quantum liquids in Bose-Hubbard models with spatially modulated symmetries]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014406</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014406"/>
        <updated>2024-01-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pablo Sala, Yizhi You, Johannes Hauschild, and Olexei Motrunich
This work investigates the zero-temperature physics of generalized Bose-Hubbard models, which conserve finite Fourier momenta of the particle number. Analytical and numerical calculations predict a novel quasi-long-range order phase, in addition to more conventional Mott insulators. The former is characterized by a two-species Luttinger liquid in the infrared, with microscopic expectation values dressed by oscillatory contributions. The authors also conjecture that this phase is destroyed by the unbinding of topological defects along the temporal direction even when they are confined along the transverse direction.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 014406] Published Tue Jan 09, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pablo Sala, Yizhi You, Johannes Hauschild, and Olexei Motrunich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental nuclear quadrupole resonance and computational study of the structurally refined topological semimetal ${\mathrm{TaSb}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.035116</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.035116"/>
        <updated>2024-01-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Fujii, O. Janson, H. Yasuoka, H. Rosner, Yu. Prots, U. Burkhardt, M. Schmidt, and M. Baenitz
The electric field gradient (EFG) and magnetic excitation of TaSb2 were studied using nuclear quadrupole resonance (NQR) in a single crystal. The EFG parameters determined by measuring all expected NQR lines were corroborated by density functional theory (DFT) calculations. Despite the good agreement between the measured and calculated Sommerfeld coefficients, the spin-lattice relaxation rate was not captured by the DFT band calculations. To overcome this discrepancy, the authors propose a site-dependent in-gap state with an average energy gap of ~7 meV for the Sb sites and ~22 meV for the Ta site, which are much smaller than the semimetallic gap.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 035116] Published Tue Jan 09, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Fujii, O. Janson, H. Yasuoka, H. Rosner, Yu. Prots, U. Burkhardt, M. Schmidt, and M. Baenitz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental implementation of an efficient test of quantumness]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.012610</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.012610"/>
        <updated>2024-01-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Laura Lewis, Daiwei Zhu, Alexandru Gheorghiu, Crystal Noel, Or Katz, Bahaa Harraz, Qingfeng Wang, Andrew Risinger, Lei Feng, Debopriyo Biswas, Laird Egan, Thomas Vidick, Marko Cetina, and Christopher Monroe
The authors implement a noninteractive test of quantumness, or an algorithm for verifying whether an untrusted device is capable of quantum computation, on an ion-trap quantum computer. Their results clearly exceed the classical bound.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 012610] Published Tue Jan 09, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Lewis, Daiwei Zhu, Alexandru Gheorghiu, Crystal Noel, Or Katz, Bahaa Harraz, Qingfeng Wang, Andrew Risinger, Lei Feng, Debopriyo Biswas, Laird Egan, Thomas Vidick, Marko Cetina, and Christopher Monroe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Excitation protocols for nonlinear phononics in bismuth and antimony]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.015202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.015202"/>
        <updated>2024-01-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anubhab Haldar, Zhengjie Huang, Xuedan Ma, Pierre Darancet, and Sahar Sharifzadeh
Coherent interactions between electromagnetic waves and extended vibrational degrees of freedom in solids (phonons) enable the stabilization of non-equilibrium states of matter with potentially desirable properties. However, the breakdown of the harmonic approximation in a material experiencing a structural phase transition results in large anharmonic deviations that limit the applicability of standard illumination protocols based on periodic drives. In this study, the authors propose a new illumination protocol that enables amplification of vibrations far into the non-linear regime for broken-symmetry materials.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 015202] Published Mon Jan 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anubhab Haldar, Zhengjie Huang, Xuedan Ma, Pierre Darancet, and Sahar Sharifzadeh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of $CP$ Violation in ${B}^{0}→ψ(→{ℓ}^{+}{ℓ}^{−}){K}_{S}^{0}(→{π}^{+}{π}^{−})$ Decays]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.021801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.021801"/>
        <updated>2024-01-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Aaij et al. (LHCb Collaboration)
The quark-mixing CP-violation angle β is measured with the greatest precision to date.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 021801] Published Mon Jan 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Aaij &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHCb Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-energy acceleration phenomena in extreme-radiation–plasma interactions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.015203</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.015203"/>
        <updated>2024-01-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. C. Faure, D. Tordeux, L. Gremillet, and M. Lemoine
Powerful astrophysical sources are known to interact with their surroundings via extreme radiation-plasma interactions resulting from large quantities of emitted nonthermal radiation. This paper studies the physical processes involved in such interactions, combining analytical approximations with numerical simulations, and unveils a complex sequence of particle acceleration processes.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 015203] Published Mon Jan 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. C. Faure, D. Tordeux, L. Gremillet, and M. Lemoine</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Squeezing and quantum approximate optimization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.012413</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.012413"/>
        <updated>2024-01-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gopal Chandra Santra, Fred Jendrzejewski, Philipp Hauke, and Daniel J. Egger
The authors study the connection between the solution of the quantum approximate optimization algorithm (QAOA) and the generation of squeezed states. In doing so, they reveal a tight connection between the two seemingly unrelated fields of quantum metrology and computing. They also suggest the potential use of squeezing as a benchmark for assessing the quality of quantum algorithms.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 012413] Published Mon Jan 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gopal Chandra Santra, Fred Jendrzejewski, Philipp Hauke, and Daniel J. Egger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smectic and Soap Bubble Optofluidic Lasers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011002"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zala Korenjak and Matjaž Humar
Using a soap bubble, researchers have created a laser that could act as a sensitive sensor for environmental parameters including atmospheric pressure.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011002] Published Fri Jan 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zala Korenjak and Matjaž Humar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First-principles study of topological invariants of Weyl points in continuous media]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.6.013017</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.6.013017"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Guilherme R. Fonseca, Filipa R. Prudêncio, Mário G. Silveirinha, and Paloma A. Huidobro
A first-principles formalism that enables the topological characterization of Weyl points in three-dimensional dispersive photonic continua is introduced. The chirality of Weyl points is computed through gap Chern numbers and through direct computation of the Berry curvature, in both cases solely using the photonic Green’s function.

[Phys. Rev. Research 6, 013017] Published Fri Jan 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guilherme R. Fonseca, Filipa R. Prudêncio, Mário G. Silveirinha, and Paloma A. Huidobro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fracton Self-Statistics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.016604</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.016604"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hao Song, Nathanan Tantivasadakarn, Wilbur Shirley, and Michael Hermele
By way of an algebraic basis for their computation, fracton self-statistics is shown to be a key factor in the characterization of fracton order.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 016604] Published Fri Jan 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hao Song, Nathanan Tantivasadakarn, Wilbur Shirley, and Michael Hermele</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[$d$-Mon: A Transmon with Strong Anharmonicity Based on Planar $c$-Axis Tunneling Junction between $d$-Wave and $s$-Wave Superconductors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.017002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.017002"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hrishikesh Patel, Vedangi Pathak, Oguzhan Can, Andrew C. Potter, and Marcel Franz
A proposed new design of superconducting qubits uses Josephson junctions made with a high-Tc d-wave superconductor overlaying a conventional s-wave superconductor to increase their coherence time and stability in the presence of noise.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 017002] Published Fri Jan 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hrishikesh Patel, Vedangi Pathak, Oguzhan Can, Andrew C. Potter, and Marcel Franz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Superconducting Qubit Based on Twisted Cuprate Van der Waals Heterostructures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.017003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.017003"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Valentina Brosco, Giuseppe Serpico, Valerii Vinokur, Nicola Poccia, and Uri Vool
A proposed new design of superconducting qubits uses Josephson junctions made with a high-Tc d-wave superconductor overlaying a conventional s-wave superconductor to increase their coherence time and stability in the presence of noise.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 017003] Published Fri Jan 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Valentina Brosco, Giuseppe Serpico, Valerii Vinokur, Nicola Poccia, and Uri Vool</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Definition of fragmentation functions and the violation of sum rules]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.016006</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.016006"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): John Collins and Ted C. Rogers
The authors discuss how in QCD, processes which describe how final state hadrons arise from a parton in hard scattering are sensitive to the Wilson line necessary for gauge invariance. This affects some sum rules, notably that for charge conservation.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 016006] Published Fri Jan 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Collins and Ted C. Rogers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GWTC-2.1: Deep extended catalog of compact binary coalescences observed by LIGO and Virgo during the first half of the third observing run]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.022001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.022001"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Abbott et al. (The LIGO Scientific Collaboration and the Virgo Collaboration)
GWTC-2.1 is a catalog of gravitational wave events from compact binary coalescences from the first half of the third observing run of Advanced LIGO and Advanced Virgo. It improves on GWTC-2, which covered the same period but with less refined analysis methods. GWTC-2.1 identifies 8 new events, all identified as sourced by binary black holes with one exception identified as a neutron star-black hole coalescence. These events expand significantly on the parameters characterizing the sources of observed gravitational-wave transients.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 022001] Published Fri Jan 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Abbott &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (The LIGO Scientific Collaboration and the Virgo Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonequilibrium Schwinger-Keldysh formalism for density matrix states: Analytic properties and implications in cosmology]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.025004</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.025004"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Andrei O. Barvinsky and Nikita Kolganov
Motivated by cosmological Hartle-Hawking and microcanonical density matrix prescriptions for the quantum state of the Universe, the authors develop a Schwinger-Keldysh in-in formalism for generic non-equilibrium systems with an initial density matrix. For generic density matrices of the Gaussian type, they develop the generating functionals of the in-in Green’s functions and discuss how “particle interpretation” relates to the density matrix parameters.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 025004] Published Fri Jan 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrei O. Barvinsky and Nikita Kolganov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlinear and Negative Effective Diffusivity of Interlayer Excitons in Moiré-Free Heterobilayers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.016202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.016202"/>
        <updated>2024-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Edith Wietek, Matthias Florian, Jonas Göser, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Alexander Högele, Mikhail M. Glazov, Alexander Steinhoff, and Alexey Chernikov
Interlayer excitons in van der Waals heterostructures diffuse rapidly, with diffusion coefficients about 1000 times larger than previously seen, in the absence of moiré- and disorder-induced localization.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 016202] Published Thu Jan 04, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edith Wietek, Matthias Florian, Jonas Göser, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Alexander Högele, Mikhail M. Glazov, Alexander Steinhoff, and Alexey Chernikov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of Terahertz Spin Hall Conductivity Spectrum in GaAs with Optical Spin Injection]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.016301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.016301"/>
        <updated>2024-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tomohiro Fujimoto, Takayuki Kurihara, Yuta Murotani, Tomohiro Tamaya, Natsuki Kanda, Changsu Kim, Jun Yoshinobu, Hidefumi Akiyama, Takeo Kato, and Ryusuke Matsunaga
Spin Hall conductivity is observed in GaAs at room temperature via a circularly polarized terahertz pump-probe setup.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 016301] Published Thu Jan 04, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tomohiro Fujimoto, Takayuki Kurihara, Yuta Murotani, Tomohiro Tamaya, Natsuki Kanda, Changsu Kim, Jun Yoshinobu, Hidefumi Akiyama, Takeo Kato, and Ryusuke Matsunaga</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analog vacuum decay from vacuum initial conditions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.023506</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.023506"/>
        <updated>2024-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexander C. Jenkins, Jonathan Braden, Hiranya V. Peiris, Andrew Pontzen, Matthew C. Johnson, and Silke Weinfurtner
The authors study how phase transitions in ultracold atomic gases mimic relativistic vacuum decay, improving on previous analyses by incorporating the effects of quantum fluctuations over and above the classical equations of motion. This is designed to test early Universe physics via tabletop experiments.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 023506] Published Thu Jan 04, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexander C. Jenkins, Jonathan Braden, Hiranya V. Peiris, Andrew Pontzen, Matthew C. Johnson, and Silke Weinfurtner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>