<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-02-13T00:57:32.973Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-02-13T00:57:32.973Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Result of the <span class="sc">Majorana</span> <span class="sc">Demonstrator</span>’s Search for Neutrinoless Double-$β$ Decay in $^{76}\mathrm{Ge}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.062501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.062501"/>
        <updated>2023-02-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): I. J. Arnquist et al. (Majorana Collaboration)
The final results from the Majorana Demonstrator’s search for neutrinoless double-beta decay in 76Ge set an upper limit on the half-life of this decay to be T1/2>8.3×1025 years.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 062501] Published Fri Feb 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>I. J. Arnquist &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;span class="sc"&gt;Majorana&lt;/span&gt; Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Non-Hermitian Spectral Flows and Berry-Chern Monopoles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.066601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.066601"/>
        <updated>2023-02-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lucien Jezequel and Pierre Delplace
A generalization of the correspondence between a spectral flow and the topological charges to non-Hermitian systems leads to the emergence of Berry-Chern monopoles.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 066601] Published Fri Feb 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucien Jezequel and Pierre Delplace</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Juggling soliton: A new kind of wave-particle entity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.024401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.024401"/>
        <updated>2023-02-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Camila Sandivari, Jacob Egge, Belén Barraza, Leonardo Gordillo, and Nicolás Mujica
High-amplitude localized waves in a narrow channel can juggle large-sized droplets for tens of thousands of cycles without coalescing. The wave launches and softly catches the drop at every cycle, and laterally traps it. This system can be considered the gravity-wave analog of optical tweezers.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 024401] Published Fri Feb 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Camila Sandivari, Jacob Egge, Belén Barraza, Leonardo Gordillo, and Nicolás Mujica</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universality of grain boundary phases in fcc metals: Case study on high-angle [111] symmetric tilt grain boundaries]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.054103</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.054103"/>
        <updated>2023-02-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tobias Brink, Lena Langenohl, Hanna Bishara, and Gerhard Dehm
It has been reported that different ordered structures can appear at the same grain boundaries. Thermodynamically, they can be regarded as interface phases (“complexions”). The authors use atomistic simulations to show that several fcc transition and post-transition metals exhibit the same two grain boundary phases in [111] tilt grain boundaries. This remains true even when using unphysical pair potentials, highlighting that the occurrence of different grain boundary phases is not an exceptional special case, but common across different materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 054103] Published Fri Feb 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tobias Brink, Lena Langenohl, Hanna Bishara, and Gerhard Dehm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Separability and entanglement in superpositions of quantum states]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.022413</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.022413"/>
        <updated>2023-02-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Saronath Halder and Ujjwal Sen
In bipartite quantum systems, mixtures of entangled and product states are always entangled, but superpositions of the same states may not be. Here, the authors detail the conditions for separability of such superpositions and outline applications in local quantum state discrimination.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 022413] Published Fri Feb 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Saronath Halder and Ujjwal Sen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Positronium density measurements using polaritonic effects]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.023306</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.023306"/>
        <updated>2023-02-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Erika Cortese, David B. Cassidy, and Simone De Liberato
The authors develop a theoretical proposal for the formation of polaritons in a gas of positronium atoms and the real-time measurement of positronium densities in present-day experimental setups. The results could be an important step towards the achievement of positronium BEC.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 023306] Published Fri Feb 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erika Cortese, David B. Cassidy, and Simone De Liberato</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Superradiant Droplet Emission from Parametrically Excited Cavities]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.064002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.064002"/>
        <updated>2023-02-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Valeri Frumkin, John W. M. Bush, and Konstantinos Papatryfonos
Experiments reveal a hydrodynamic analog of an important effect in quantum optics called superradiance.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 064002] Published Thu Feb 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Valeri Frumkin, John W. M. Bush, and Konstantinos Papatryfonos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canopy elastic turbulence: Spontaneous formation of waves in beds of slender microposts]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.023301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.023301"/>
        <updated>2023-02-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Charlotte de Blois, Simon J. Haward, and Amy Q. Shen
A microfluidic canopy flow device, formed from a large array of slender polymeric pillars within a glass microchannel, is subjected to viscoelastic flow in the regime of elastic turbulence. The system results in the spontaneous emergence of waves in the form of propagating regions of low flow velocity compared to the bulk, also inducing Monami-like waves in the canopy if the pillars are flexible. Due to the analogies with classical (inertial) canopy turbulence, this new phenomenon is named “canopy elastic turbulence”.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 023301] Published Thu Feb 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charlotte de Blois, Simon J. Haward, and Amy Q. Shen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entanglement dynamics and phase transitions of the Floquet cluster spin chain]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.085116</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.085116"/>
        <updated>2023-02-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alberto D. Verga
One of the challenges in quantum information is to create quantum states that can be used as resources, for instance, in the measurement-based model of quantum computing. Here, the author investigates the generation, through a dynamical phase transition, of a topological entangled state, by the Floquet evolution of a chain of spins, whose ground state is the so-called cluster state, acted upon by a quantum walker. The nonergodic phase is characterized by the emergence of magnetic order, persistent at long times.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 085116] Published Thu Feb 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alberto D. Verga</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[One-dimensional projection of two-dimensional systems using spiral boundary conditions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L081104</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L081104"/>
        <updated>2023-02-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Masahiro Kadosawa, Masaaki Nakamura, Yukinori Ohta, and Satoshi Nishimoto
The spiral boundary conditions can project any two-dimensional or three-dimensional lattice onto a one-dimensional periodic chain with translational symmetry. It enables one to apply efficiently the existing one-dimensional techniques, such as density-matrix renormalization group (DMRG), bosonization, Jordan-Wigner transformation, etc., to studies of lattice systems in higher dimensions. Here, the authors demonstrate the utility of spiral boundary conditions by performing analytical and DMRG calculations for square and honeycomb lattice problems. Thus, the spiral boundary conditions emerge as a principal option in condensed matter physics.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L081104] Published Thu Feb 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Masahiro Kadosawa, Masaaki Nakamura, Yukinori Ohta, and Satoshi Nishimoto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Searches for Massive Neutrinos with Mechanical Quantum Sensors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.010315</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.010315"/>
        <updated>2023-02-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Daniel Carney, Kyle G. Leach, and David C. Moore
Searching for heavy sterile neutrinos in the keV–MeV mass range is possible with a nanometer-scale, optically levitated quantum sensor.

[PRX Quantum 4, 010315] Published Wed Feb 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Carney, Kyle G. Leach, and David C. Moore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Influence of chirp and carrier-envelope phase on noninteger high-harmonic generation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.054305</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.054305"/>
        <updated>2023-02-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maximilian Graml, Maximilian Nitsch, Adrian Seith, Ferdinand Evers, and Jan Wilhelm
For high-harmonic generation, an intense laser pulse is targeted on a substrate producing high-frequency electromagnetic radiation. The high-harmonic spectrum emitted is strongly influenced by the properties of the substrate material and the laser pulse waveform. Here, the authors derive a simple analytical formula that describes the relation between laser pulse parameters and peak positions in the high-harmonic spectrum. The formula explains quantitatively why the high-harmonic spectrum may peak at frequencies that are not integer multiples of the laser pumping frequency.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 054305] Published Wed Feb 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maximilian Graml, Maximilian Nitsch, Adrian Seith, Ferdinand Evers, and Jan Wilhelm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin-dependent coupling of supercurrent and nonequilibrium quasiparticles in high-field superconductors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.054504</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.054504"/>
        <updated>2023-02-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): P. Maier and D. Beckmann
The interplay of the spin degree of freedom with supercurrents is investigated here in the context of superconducting spintronics. Based on a recent theoretical prediction, the authors experimentally demonstrate a spin-dependent coupling of supercurrent and nonequilibrium quasiparticles. The coupling appears when the superconductor is subject to a large spin splitting, in this case a Zeeman splitting induced by an applied magnetic field. The results may be useful for the mutual control of spin-polarized supercurrents and quasiparticles in superconducting spintronics devices.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 054504] Published Wed Feb 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>P. Maier and D. Beckmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ultra-Large-Scale Deterministic Entanglement Containing $2×20\text{ }400$ Optical Modes Based on Time-Delayed Quantum Interferometer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.060801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.060801"/>
        <updated>2023-02-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yanfen Zhou, Wei Wang, Tingting Song, Xutong Wang, Qiqi Zhu, Kai Zhang, Shengshuai Liu, and Jietai Jing
A time-delayed quantum interferometer is used to generate deterministic continuous-variable entanglement with 40800 optical modes.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 060801] Published Tue Feb 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yanfen Zhou, Wei Wang, Tingting Song, Xutong Wang, Qiqi Zhu, Kai Zhang, Shengshuai Liu, and Jietai Jing</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exotic Compact Objects and the Fate of the Light-Ring Instability]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.061401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.061401"/>
        <updated>2023-02-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pedro V. P. Cunha, Carlos Herdeiro, Eugen Radu, and Nicolas Sanchis-Gual
The results of new simulations negate the argument that some objects thought to be black holes are instead hypothetical exotic systems called bosonic stars.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 061401] Published Tue Feb 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pedro V. P. Cunha, Carlos Herdeiro, Eugen Radu, and Nicolas Sanchis-Gual</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scalings and decay of homogeneous, nearly isotropic turbulence behind a jet array]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.024603</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.024603"/>
        <updated>2023-02-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shiyong Tan, Xu Xu, Yinghe Qi, and Rui Ni
In the study of dispersed multiphase turbulence, using a jet array has shown promise in creating intense homogeneous, nearly isotropic turbulence with high dissipation rates in water and wind tunnels. However, the scaling of turbulent characteristics with jet nozzle diameter, velocity, and downstream location has not been fully explored. Our research, combined with previous experiments focusing on near-field measurements, offers a comprehensive understanding of the decay of kinetic energy and energy dissipation rate, as well as the flow inhomogeneity and anisotropy generated by a jet array.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 024603] Published Tue Feb 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shiyong Tan, Xu Xu, Yinghe Qi, and Rui Ni</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trajectory dependence of electronic energy-loss straggling at keV ion energies]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.085110</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.085110"/>
        <updated>2023-02-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Lohmann, R. Holeňák, P. L. Grande, and D. Primetzhofer
Accurate knowledge of ion energy deposition in materials is imperative for a wealth of scientific and technological applications. Here, the authors measure the energy-loss straggling, i.e., the energy distribution variance of transmitted ions, for keV ions of H, He, B, and Si in Si membranes. Straggling exhibits a significant trajectory dependence for all ions. Studying the velocity dependence of electronic energy-loss straggling and calculating transport cross sections, the authors obtain strong evidence for contributions of electron-promotion events to ion energy loss at low velocities.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 085110] Published Tue Feb 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Lohmann, R. Holeňák, P. L. Grande, and D. Primetzhofer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing neutral triple gauge couplings at the LHC and future hadron colliders]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.035005</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.035005"/>
        <updated>2023-02-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): John Ellis, Hong-Jian He, and Rui-Qing Xiao
Many searches for new physics can be parameterized by higher-dimension operators in effective field theories. In this work, the authors show a consistent translation of dimension-8 operators into triple gauge boson form factors and analyze the expected experimental reach. Incorporating the full Standard Model symmetry requires an additional term which has been neglected in earlier work, leading to significantly different results.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 035005] Published Mon Feb 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Ellis, Hong-Jian He, and Rui-Qing Xiao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effective two-body approach to the hierarchical three-body problem: Quadrupole to 1PN]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.044011</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.044011"/>
        <updated>2023-02-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Adrien Kuntz, Francesco Serra, and Enrico Trincherini
The dynamics of binaries can be significantly affected by the presence of other bodies. This manuscript considers the hierarchical three-body problem where a third body is far compared to the distance scale of the binary. The authors make significant progress in developing a two-body approximation scheme in which corrections to the dynamics can be systematically computed at long timescales in comparison to the orbital periods characterizing the problem. The power of the method is demonstrated by computing post-Newtonian and multipole corrections.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 044011] Published Mon Feb 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrien Kuntz, Francesco Serra, and Enrico Trincherini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Laser-induced Coulomb explosion imaging of alkali-metal dimers on helium nanodroplets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.023104</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.023104"/>
        <updated>2023-02-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Henrik H. Kristensen, Lorenz Kranabetter, Constant A. Schouder, Jacqueline Arlt, Frank Jensen, and Henrik Stapelfeldt
The authors use velocity-map imaging following Coulomb explosion of doubly ionized alkali homodimers on the surface of a helium nanodroplet to map out the distribution of internuclear distances in both the ground and lowest triplet state. They find that the distributions are generally broader than the internuclear wave function, which they attribute to resonance effects in the initial multiphoton ionization of the dimer and interaction of the ions with the He droplet.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 023104] Published Mon Feb 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Henrik H. Kristensen, Lorenz Kranabetter, Constant A. Schouder, Jacqueline Arlt, Frank Jensen, and Henrik Stapelfeldt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Probe of Sub-GeV Dark Matter beyond the Cosmological Expectation with the COHERENT CsI Detector at the SNS]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.051803</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.051803"/>
        <updated>2023-02-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. Akimov et al.
Hypothetical accelerator-produced light scalar particles, within a mass range around 25 MeV, for the first time are ruled out from being all of the expected dark matter.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 051803] Published Fri Feb 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. Akimov &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enrichment of Scavenged Particles in Jet Drops Determined by Bubble Size and Particle Position]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.054001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.054001"/>
        <updated>2023-02-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lena Dubitsky, Oliver McRae, and James C. Bird
Experiments reveal new details of the process by which contaminants in the ocean could reach the atmosphere through the bursting of bubbles in foam.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 054001] Published Fri Feb 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lena Dubitsky, Oliver McRae, and James C. Bird</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rocket drops: The self-propulsion of supercooled freezing drops]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L021601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L021601"/>
        <updated>2023-02-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Claudiu A. Stan, Armin Kalita, Sebastian Marte, Thomas F. Kaldawi, Philip R. Willmott, and Sébastien Boutet
Supercooled water drops move spontaneously while freezing in vacuum. This self-propulsion phenomenon is caused by an enhanced evaporation rate from the frozen regions of the drops. The evaporating molecules carry momentum, and the drops acquire an opposite momentum, the same as in rocket propulsion.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, L021601] Published Fri Feb 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claudiu A. Stan, Armin Kalita, Sebastian Marte, Thomas F. Kaldawi, Philip R. Willmott, and Sébastien Boutet</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Asteroids for ultralight dark-photon dark-matter detection]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.043004</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.043004"/>
        <updated>2023-02-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Michael A. Fedderke and Anubhav Mathur
This forward looking work considers the technical requirements for a post-LISA gravitational wave detector in the μHz frequency regime. The novel goal is to detect changes in the separation between asteroids in the Solar System as a probe for “dark-photon dark matter.”

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 043004] Published Fri Feb 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael A. Fedderke and Anubhav Mathur</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Membrane-Based Optomechanical Accelerometry]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.024011</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.024011"/>
        <updated>2023-02-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mitul Dey Chowdhury, Aman R. Agrawal, and Dalziel J. Wilson
Cavity optomechanical accelerometers promise ultrahigh sensitivity, in situ calibration, and radiation-pressure stabilization for e.g. chip-scale gravimetry or dark-matter searches. However, platforms that meet the unique technical demands are difficult to fabricate. The authors demonstrate a simple, scalable setup with an optical cavity based on a pair of vertically integrated Si3N4 membranes of different stiffnesses. Radiation-pressure cooling of membrane motion enables resolution of chip acceleration to better than 10−7g, over a bandwidth of several kilohertz. A cryogenic array of these devices could be used to search for weak inertial forces due to dark matter.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 024011] Published Fri Feb 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mitul Dey Chowdhury, Aman R. Agrawal, and Dalziel J. Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entanglement of Trapped-Ion Qubits Separated by 230 Meters]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.050803</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.050803"/>
        <updated>2023-02-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): V. Krutyanskiy, M. Galli, V. Krcmarsky, S. Baier, D. A. Fioretto, Y. Pu, A. Mazloom, P. Sekatski, M. Canteri, M. Teller, J. Schupp, J. Bate, M. Meraner, N. Sangouard, B. P. Lanyon, and T. E. Northup
Researchers have achieved long-distance entanglement between two calcium ions, each of which lies in a different building, showing that trapped ions could be used to create quantum networks.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 050803] Published Thu Feb 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>V. Krutyanskiy, M. Galli, V. Krcmarsky, S. Baier, D. A. Fioretto, Y. Pu, A. Mazloom, P. Sekatski, M. Canteri, M. Teller, J. Schupp, J. Bate, M. Meraner, N. Sangouard, B. P. Lanyon, and T. E. Northup</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stochastic gravitational waves from postinflationary structure formation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.043503</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.043503"/>
        <updated>2023-02-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Benedikt Eggemeier, Jens C. Niemeyer, Karsten Jedamzik, and Richard Easther
The authors study the (stochastic background) gravitational wave signal from the gravitational collapse of fluctuations in the inflation condensate following inflation and the signal’s possible detection in current and future experiments. They manage to quantify this largely unexplored gravitational wave source in the primordial universe and show it might have present-day observable consequences, opening with this a potential window into the earliest moments after the Big Bang.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 043503] Published Thu Feb 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benedikt Eggemeier, Jens C. Niemeyer, Karsten Jedamzik, and Richard Easther</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First detection of the atomic $^{18}\mathrm{O}$ isotope in the mesosphere and lower thermosphere of Earth]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.013072</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.013072"/>
        <updated>2023-02-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Helmut Wiesemeyer, Rolf Güsten, Rebeca Aladro, Bernd Klein, Heinz-Wilhelm Hübers, Heiko Richter, Urs U. Graf, Matthias Justen, Yoko Okada, and Jürgen Stutzki
The magnetic dipole transitions between the fine-structure ground-state levels of atomic oxygen residing in the mesosphere and the lower thermosphere of Earth are measured in absorption against the Moon. The small isotope shifts allow determining the 16O/18O abundance ratio in this remote environment, found to be typical of isotopic oxygen fractionations in the lower atmosphere and to significantly fall below the solar wind value.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 013072] Published Wed Feb 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helmut Wiesemeyer, Rolf Güsten, Rebeca Aladro, Bernd Klein, Heinz-Wilhelm Hübers, Heiko Richter, Urs U. Graf, Matthias Justen, Yoko Okada, and Jürgen Stutzki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlinear spin current of photoexcited magnons in collinear antiferromagnets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.064403</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.064403"/>
        <updated>2023-02-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kosuke Fujiwara, Sota Kitamura, and Takahiro Morimoto
Generation of spin currents is currently actively studied from the viewpoint of magnon spintronics. Here, the authors propose that ac electric field can excite magnons and induce nonlinear spin currents in antiferromagnets with broken inversion symmetry. In particular, they show that linearly polarized light generates magnon spin shift current that originates from the nontrivial geometry of the magnon band and is closely related to the electronic shift current in semiconductors. The authors demonstrate that the photoinduced spin current is accessible for measurements in the multiferroic compound Mn2Mo3O8.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 064403] Published Wed Feb 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kosuke Fujiwara, Sota Kitamura, and Takahiro Morimoto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joint analysis of Dark Energy Survey Year 3 data and CMB lensing from SPT and <i>Planck</i>. I. Construction of CMB lensing maps and modeling choices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.023529</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.023529"/>
        <updated>2023-01-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Y. Omori et al. (DES and SPT Collaborations)
Using cross-correlation measurements and an updated cosmic-microwave-background lensing map, researchers determine cosmological parameters with greater precision.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 023529] Published Tue Jan 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Y. Omori &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (DES and SPT Collaborations)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joint analysis of Dark Energy Survey Year 3 data and CMB lensing from SPT and $Planck$. II. Cross-correlation measurements and cosmological constraints]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.023530</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.023530"/>
        <updated>2023-01-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. Chang et al. (DES & SPT Collaborations)
Using cross-correlation measurements and an updated cosmic-microwave-background lensing map, researchers determine cosmological parameters with greater precision.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 023530] Published Tue Jan 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. Chang &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (DES &amp; SPT Collaborations)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Joint analysis of Dark Energy Survey Year 3 data and CMB lensing from SPT and <i>Planck</i>. III. Combined cosmological constraints]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.023531</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.023531"/>
        <updated>2023-01-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. M. C. Abbott et al. (DES and SPT Collaborations)
Using cross-correlation measurements and an updated cosmic-microwave-background lensing map, researchers determine cosmological parameters with greater precision.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 023531] Published Tue Jan 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. M. C. Abbott &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (DES and SPT Collaborations)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migration of Ga vacancies and interstitials in $β\text{−}{\mathrm{Ga}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.024109</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.024109"/>
        <updated>2023-01-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ymir K. Frodason, Joel B. Varley, Klaus Magnus H. Johansen, Lasse Vines, and Chris G. Van de Walle
The authors present a systematic and comprehensive theoretical study of Ga vacancy and interstitial migration in monoclinic gallium sesquioxide, based on hybrid functional calculations and the nudged elastic band technique. Notably, it is shown that the Ga vacancy can form a favorable three-split configuration, consisting of three Ga vacancies and two Ga interstitials, which enables migration with a dramatically lower migration barrier than previously calculated, further demonstrating the important role of split vacancies in this material.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 024109] Published Tue Jan 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ymir K. Frodason, Joel B. Varley, Klaus Magnus H. Johansen, Lasse Vines, and Chris G. Van de Walle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pressure-induced metallization and superconductivity in the layered van der Waals semiconductor GaTe]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.024512</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.024512"/>
        <updated>2023-01-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jin Jiang, Xuliang Chen (陈绪亮), Shuyang Wang, Chao An, Ying Zhou, Min Zhang, Yonghui Zhou, and Zhaorong Yang
Investigations show that the physical properties of the layered van der Waals semiconductor GaTe are strongly layer dependent. Here, the authors systematically study its properties by using external pressure as a tuning knob. They first find pressure-induced metallization and superconductivity simultaneously occurring at ~3 GPa, presumably owing to a quasi-two-dimensional to three-dimensional structural crossover and to an electronic phase transition due to a change of the bonding nature between layers from weak van der Waals interaction to strong Coulomb coupling. A second distinct superconducting phase is then observed at ~10 GPa due to a structural transition.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 024512] Published Tue Jan 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jin Jiang, Xuliang Chen (陈绪亮), Shuyang Wang, Chao An, Ying Zhou, Min Zhang, Yonghui Zhou, and Zhaorong Yang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search for the Majorana Nature of Neutrinos in the Inverted Mass Ordering Region with KamLAND-Zen]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.051801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.051801"/>
        <updated>2023-01-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Abe et al. (KamLAND-Zen Collaboration)
Detecting neutrinoless double-beta decay would confirm that the neutrino is its own antiparticle. Data from the KamLAND-Zen experiment contain no strong evidence of such events, constraining neutrino properties.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 051801] Published Mon Jan 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Abe &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (KamLAND-Zen Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Homophily-Based Social Group Formation in a Spin Glass Self-Assembly Framework]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.057401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.057401"/>
        <updated>2023-01-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jan Korbel, Simon D. Lindner, Tuan Minh Pham, Rudolf Hanel, and Stefan Thurner
Homophilic interactions drive the formation dynamics of social groups, according to a model of opinions expressed on social networks which uses a spin-glass framework.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 057401] Published Mon Jan 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jan Korbel, Simon D. Lindner, Tuan Minh Pham, Rudolf Hanel, and Stefan Thurner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KamNet: An integrated spatiotemporal deep neural network for rare event searches in KamLAND-Zen]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.014323</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.014323"/>
        <updated>2023-01-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Li, Z. Fu, C. Grant, H. Ozaki, I. Shimizu, H. Song, A. Takeuchi, and L. A. Winslow
Searches for rare events employ customized detectors with large fiducial mass to effectively reduce background. Leveraging recent breakthroughs in geometric deep learning and spatiotemporal analysis, this work presents a novel machine-learning algorithm (KamNet) as a new, robust tool to maximize the information provided by the kiloton-scale KamLAND liquid-scintillator detector. Adding a so-called “attention mechanism” to KamNet, the authors demonstrate that this enhanced machine-learning approach can increase the sensitivity of the KamLAND-Zen experiment to zero-neutrino- and two-neutrino double-β decay. That mechanism also elucidates the underlying physics KamNet is using for background rejection.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, 014323] Published Mon Jan 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Li, Z. Fu, C. Grant, H. Ozaki, I. Shimizu, H. Song, A. Takeuchi, and L. A. Winslow</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confronting anomalous kaon correlations measured in Pb-Pb collisions at $\sqrt{{s}_{NN}}=2.76$ TeV]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.014913</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.014913"/>
        <updated>2023-01-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Joseph I. Kapusta, Scott Pratt, and Mayank Singh
This paper uses simple models to interpret recent measurements of anomalously strong correlations between neutral and charged kaon production performed at the LHC for high-energy heavy-ion collisions. Thermal models, including charge conservation effects, are found to be insufficient to explain the data for the most central collisions. More exotic conjectures involving coherent emission can reproduce the observations if 30% of the kaons are emitted from coherent sources in the most central collisions. Such coherence might be related to the melting and re-freezing of the QCD vacuum.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, 014913] Published Mon Jan 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joseph I. Kapusta, Scott Pratt, and Mayank Singh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forgetting Leads to Chaos in Attractor Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011009</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011009"/>
        <updated>2023-01-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ulises Pereira-Obilinovic, Johnatan Aljadeff, and Nicolas Brunel
A model for information storage in the brain reveals how memories decay with age.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 011009] Published Fri Jan 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ulises Pereira-Obilinovic, Johnatan Aljadeff, and Nicolas Brunel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wealth dynamics in a market with information asymmetries]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.014305</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.014305"/>
        <updated>2023-01-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. R. Bosco de Magalhães
Simulations of the behavior of individual financial traders show that imperfect market knowledge increases risk but not overall losses.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, 014305] Published Fri Jan 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. R. Bosco de Magalhães</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[<i>Ab initio</i> calculation of the $β$-decay spectrum of $^{6}\mathrm{He}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.015503</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.015503"/>
        <updated>2023-01-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): G. B. King, A. Baroni, V. Cirigliano, S. Gandolfi, L. Hayen, E. Mereghetti, S. Pastore, and M. Piarulli
Searches for new physics can be conducted by brute force or, like the perihelion shift of Mercury, looking for subtle but persistent discrepancies. This detailed paper carries out high-precision calculations of the β-decay spectrum of 6He, and estimates the experimental precision needed to reveal hints of charged-current interactions beyond the Standard Model and/or sterile neutrinos.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, 015503] Published Fri Jan 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>G. B. King, A. Baroni, V. Cirigliano, S. Gandolfi, L. Hayen, E. Mereghetti, S. Pastore, and M. Piarulli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ramp compression of tantalum to multiterapascal pressures: Constraints of the thermal equation of state to 2.3 TPa and 5000 K]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.014109</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.014109"/>
        <updated>2023-01-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. G. Gorman, C. J. Wu, R. F. Smith, L. X. Benedict, C. J. Prisbrey, W. Schill, S. A. Bonev, Z. C. Long, P. Söderlind, D. Braun, D. C. Swift, R. Briggs, T. J. Volz, E. F. O'Bannon, P. M. Celliers, D. E. Fratanduono, J. H. Eggert, S. J. Ali, and J. M. McNaney
The authors use intense laser pulses to compress solid tantalum to pressures in excess of 20 million atmospheres. By combing their experimental measurements with existing high-pressure, high-temperature data on Ta, they can create an experimentally bounded high-temperature equation of state that is valid up to multiterapascal pressures and thousands of degrees kelvin. The equation of state may serve as a useful pressure standard at the extreme compressions and elevated temperatures now achievable in state-of-the-art static compression experiments. This work also provides a clear road map for building an accurate high-temperature equation of state catalogue of materials at extreme conditions.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 014109] Published Fri Jan 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. G. Gorman, C. J. Wu, R. F. Smith, L. X. Benedict, C. J. Prisbrey, W. Schill, S. A. Bonev, Z. C. Long, P. Söderlind, D. Braun, D. C. Swift, R. Briggs, T. J. Volz, E. F. O'Bannon, P. M. Celliers, D. E. Fratanduono, J. H. Eggert, S. J. Ali, and J. M. McNaney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Erbium and thulium on MgO(100)/Ag(100) as candidates for single atom qubits]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.045427</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.045427"/>
        <updated>2023-01-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Reale, A. Singha, S. L. Ahmed, D. Krylov, L. Colazzo, C. Wolf, C. S. Casari, A. Barla, E. Fernandes, F. Patthey, M. Pivetta, S. Rusponi, H. Brune, and F. Donati
Lanthanide atoms on surfaces are prospective platforms for realizing atomic-scale quantum logic units. Here, the authors combine scanning tunneling microscopy, x-ray magnetic circular dichroism, density functional theory, and atomic multiplet calculations to identify the quantum level structure of erbium and thulium atoms on MgO(100)/Ag(100), and to estimate their performance as spin qubits. Their analysis reveals that both atoms have a ground state that is suitable to perform efficient quantum coherent operations.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 045427] Published Fri Jan 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Reale, A. Singha, S. L. Ahmed, D. Krylov, L. Colazzo, C. Wolf, C. S. Casari, A. Barla, E. Fernandes, F. Patthey, M. Pivetta, S. Rusponi, H. Brune, and F. Donati</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inverse Orbital Torque via Spin-Orbital Intertwined States]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014069</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014069"/>
        <updated>2023-01-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): E. Santos, J.E. Abrão, Dongwook Go, L.K. de Assis, Yuriy Mokrousov, J.B.S. Mendes, and A. Azevedo
Spin torque induced by orbital current has become of great interest, as it allows the use of lighter elements in the development of advanced spin-orbitronic devices. Meanwhile, the inverse orbital torque (IOT) effect, in which an orbital current creates a charge current, has been difficult to detect. This study uses pumped spin-orbital current in Y3Fe5O12/Pt/CuOx heterostructures to investigate the IOT effect. Mixed spin-orbital states propagate to the Pt/CuOx interface and create a much stronger transverse charge current than that created without the CuOx coating. This inverse orbital Rashba-Edelstein effect can be used to advance applications in spintronics.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 014069] Published Fri Jan 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>E. Santos, J.E. Abrão, Dongwook Go, L.K. de Assis, Yuriy Mokrousov, J.B.S. Mendes, and A. Azevedo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of Wave-Packet Branching through an Engineered Conical Intersection]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011008</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011008"/>
        <updated>2023-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christopher S. Wang, Nicholas E. Frattini, Benjamin J. Chapman, Shruti Puri, S. M. Girvin, Michel H. Devoret, and Robert J. Schoelkopf
A quantum device shows promise for simulating molecular dynamics in a difficult-to-model photochemical process that is relevant to vision.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 011008] Published Thu Jan 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher S. Wang, Nicholas E. Frattini, Benjamin J. Chapman, Shruti Puri, S. M. Girvin, Michel H. Devoret, and Robert J. Schoelkopf</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Absolute frequency referencing for swept dual-comb spectroscopy with midinfrared quantum cascade lasers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.013047</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.013047"/>
        <updated>2023-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): K. N. Komagata, V. J. Wittwer, T. Südmeyer, L. Emmenegger, and M. Gianella
A scheme to calibrate a frequency-swept frequency comb against a reference laser is developed. Its application to a dual-comb spectrometer based on midinfrared quantum cascade lasers results in molecular spectra with high-frequency accuracy at fast refresh rates.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 013047] Published Thu Jan 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>K. N. Komagata, V. J. Wittwer, T. Südmeyer, L. Emmenegger, and M. Gianella</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information flows in macroscopic Maxwell's demons]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.014136</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.014136"/>
        <updated>2023-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nahuel Freitas and Massimiliano Esposito
Maxwell’s demon works by rectifying microscopic fluctuations, but recently an implementation was proposed that can continue to work at macroscopic scales. This paper studies that proposal in more detail, with a particular focus on the flows of information.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, 014136] Published Thu Jan 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nahuel Freitas and Massimiliano Esposito</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stability of the Pb divalent state in insulating and metallic $\mathrm{PbCr}{\mathrm{O}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.024107</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.024107"/>
        <updated>2023-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jianfa Zhao, Shu-Chih Haw, Xiao Wang, Lipeng Cao, Hong-Ji Lin, Chien-Te Chen, Christoph J. Sahle, Arata Tanaka, Jin-Ming Chen, Changqing Jin, Zhiwei Hu, and Liu Hao Tjeng
PbCrO3 is a perovskite that undergoes a large volume collapse and concurrently an insulator-metal transition with pressure. While one may think that the volume collapse can be associated with conversion of Pb2+ ions to the smaller Pb4+, the spectroscopic measurements in this experiment reveal that the Pb ions remain divalent. Instead, the Cr ions undergo a transition from a charge-disproportionated 2Cr3+/Cr6+ configuration to a homogenous Cr4+ with pressure. Thus, the authors can explain the insulating/metallic nature of PbCrO3 at low/high pressures, respectively.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 024107] Published Thu Jan 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jianfa Zhao, Shu-Chih Haw, Xiao Wang, Lipeng Cao, Hong-Ji Lin, Chien-Te Chen, Christoph J. Sahle, Arata Tanaka, Jin-Ming Chen, Changqing Jin, Zhiwei Hu, and Liu Hao Tjeng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Critical magnetic fields and electron pairing in magic-angle twisted bilayer graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.024509</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.024509"/>
        <updated>2023-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wei Qin, Bo Zou, and Allan H. MacDonald
The microscopic mechanism of superconductivity in magic-angle twisted bilayer graphene (MATBG) is currently under active debate. The authors propose here that valuable constraints are implied by the band-filling dependences of the critical temperature and the critical magnetic field, which together define an average Fermi velocity. They show that a robust inverse correlation between the critical temperature and the average Fermi velocity holds in models with band-filling independent pairing interactions. The absence of such an association in experiments suggests that the pairing glue in MATBG is strongly band-filling dependent.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 024509] Published Thu Jan 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wei Qin, Bo Zou, and Allan H. MacDonald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cavity-mediated superconductor–ferromagnetic-insulator coupling]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.035147</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.035147"/>
        <updated>2023-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Andreas T. G. Janssønn, Henning G. Hugdal, Arne Brataas, and Sol H. Jacobsen
Here, the authors develop a versatile effective theory of distant, cavity-mediated interactions between a ferromagnetic insulator and a superconductor. This remote sensing scheme enables their subjection to different drives and temperatures, and yields a numerically appreciable effective anisotropy field across the ferromagnetic insulator. It enables the study of their interactions across longer distances and without the same disruption of system orders as in conventional proximity structures.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 035147] Published Thu Jan 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andreas T. G. Janssønn, Henning G. Hugdal, Arne Brataas, and Sol H. Jacobsen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlocal Ventilating Metasurfaces]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014067</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014067"/>
        <updated>2023-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yihuan Zhu, Ruizhi Dong, Dongxing Mao, Xu Wang, and Yong Li
A traditional metasurface is composed of metaunits that are elaborately designed to provide a precise local response, and these metaunits also inevitably impact mutual radiation from each other, affecting the global response of the metasurface. Beyond those nonlocal metasurfaces that utilize such radiation coupling to promote efficiency in wave manipulation, in this study the coupling effect also serves as a powerful tool for engineering the spectrum, showcased by an acoustic open metasurface that allows airflow while blocking sound in a dramatically extended frequency band. This finding offers an efficient approach for broadband wave manipulation in a hybrid nonlocal manner.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 014067] Published Thu Jan 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yihuan Zhu, Ruizhi Dong, Dongxing Mao, Xu Wang, and Yong Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Curvature-Regulated Multiphase Patterns in Tori]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.048201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.048201"/>
        <updated>2023-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ting Wang, Zhijun Dai, Michel Potier-Ferry, and Fan Xu
A new model explains the wrinkling patterns seen in nature’s donut-shaped objects, such as those found in jellyfish.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 048201] Published Wed Jan 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ting Wang, Zhijun Dai, Michel Potier-Ferry, and Fan Xu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Temperature dependence of the energy band gap in ${\mathrm{ZrTe}}_{5}$: Implications for the topological phase]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L041202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L041202"/>
        <updated>2023-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): I. Mohelsky, J. Wyzula, B. A. Piot, G. D. Gu, Q. Li, A. Akrap, and M. Orlita
Recently, zirconium pentatelluride (ZrTe5) has received a lot of attention, both theoretical and experimental. In spite of this, no consensus has been established so far about the basic nature of the electronic states in ZrTe5 with regard to whether this material is a strong or weak topological insulator. Here, the authors use Landau-level spectroscopy to deduce the temperature dependence of the energy band gap in ZrTe5. The observed behavior – a monotonic increase with T – implies, when confronted with theoretical expectations, that ZrTe5 is a weak topological insulator.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L041202] Published Wed Jan 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>I. Mohelsky, J. Wyzula, B. A. Piot, G. D. Gu, Q. Li, A. Akrap, and M. Orlita</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tunable hole spin-photon interaction based on $\mathtt{g}$-matrix modulation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L041303</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L041303"/>
        <updated>2023-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): V. P. Michal, J. C. Abadillo-Uriel, S. Zihlmann, R. Maurand, Y.-M. Niquet, and M. Filippone
The large spin-orbit interaction of holes in semiconductors is key to achieving strong spin-photon coupling in spin circuit-QED experiments. Here, the authors show that for a single hole this coupling is “reciprocally sweet”, meaning that the coupling can be tuned from fully transverse (allowing coherent spin rotations) to fully longitudinal (modulating the spin resonance frequency). Based on the longitudinal coupling, the authors highlight how distant spin-spin coupling and parametrically driven spin readout can be achieved.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L041303] Published Wed Jan 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>V. P. Michal, J. C. Abadillo-Uriel, S. Zihlmann, R. Maurand, Y.-M. Niquet, and M. Filippone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hedgehog orbital texture in $p$-type tellurium and the antisymmetric nonreciprocal Hall response]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.014204</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.014204"/>
        <updated>2023-01-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gabriele P. Maruggi, Jaime Ferreira, Elisa Baggio-Saitovitch, Carsten Enderlein, and Marcello B. Silva Neto
What are Weyl fermions? How do they arise in semiconductors? Which conditions make possible their observation and what signatures do they leave in transport? The authors thoroughly address all these questions in tellurium. Weyl fermions are hedgehogs in reciprocal space, namely, their orbital moments are parallel to their wave vectors. They arise in time reversal invariant semiconductors that feature lack of inversion symmetry. They can be observed in optically active, spatially dispersive media. They lead to two novel, antisymmetric, nonreciprocal Hall responses: the anomalous and planar Hall effects, herein fully characterized theoretically and measured experimentally via Hall transport.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 014204] Published Tue Jan 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gabriele P. Maruggi, Jaime Ferreira, Elisa Baggio-Saitovitch, Carsten Enderlein, and Marcello B. Silva Neto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fano Combs in the Directional Mie Scattering of a Water Droplet]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.043804</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.043804"/>
        <updated>2023-01-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Javier Tello Marmolejo, Adriana Canales, Dag Hanstorp, and Ricardo Méndez-Fragoso
Captivating patterns found in the light scattered by an evaporating water droplet could be used to infer the properties of the droplet as it shrinks.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 043804] Published Tue Jan 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Javier Tello Marmolejo, Adriana Canales, Dag Hanstorp, and Ricardo Méndez-Fragoso</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two-Dimensional Topological Insulator State in Cadmium Arsenide Thin Films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.046201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.046201"/>
        <updated>2023-01-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexander C. Lygo, Binghao Guo, Arman Rashidi, Victor Huang, Pablo Cuadros-Romero, and Susanne Stemmer
Utilizing surface state hybridization, a 2D topological insulator state has been demonstrated in 20 nm thin film of a 3D topological insulator, Cd3As2, using gate-voltage-tuned magnetotransport measurements.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 046201] Published Tue Jan 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexander C. Lygo, Binghao Guo, Arman Rashidi, Victor Huang, Pablo Cuadros-Romero, and Susanne Stemmer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Staggered scheme for the compressible fluctuating hydrodynamics of multispecies fluid mixtures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.015305</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.015305"/>
        <updated>2023-01-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ishan Srivastava, Daniel R. Ladiges, Andy J. Nonaka, Alejandro L. Garcia, and John B. Bell
Fluctuating hydrodynamics, a method that incorporates fluctuations into the continuum description of fluids, can only be solved when simplifying assumptions are made. This paper describes an approach that extends the method by using a staggered spatial discretization, and the results compare well with previous work and other methods.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, 015305] Published Tue Jan 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ishan Srivastava, Daniel R. Ladiges, Andy J. Nonaka, Alejandro L. Garcia, and John B. Bell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bismuth antiphase domain wall: A three-dimensional manifestation of the Su-Schrieffer-Heeger model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.045135</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.045135"/>
        <updated>2023-01-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jinwoong Kim, Cheng-Yi Huang, Hsin Lin, David Vanderbilt, and Nicholas Kioussis
The Su-Schrieffer-Heeger model describes the soliton excitations in polyacetylene due to the formation of antiphase domain walls from the alternating bond pattern. The topology of the two domains is characterized by trivial (0) and nontrivial (π) Zak phases, indicating a dimerization-dependent Zak phase. Here, it is demonstrated that pristine Bi also exhibits 0 and π Zak phases depending on the dimerization and develops topological states at antiphase domain walls as a three-dimensional analog of the Su-Schrieffer-Heeger model.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 045135] Published Tue Jan 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jinwoong Kim, Cheng-Yi Huang, Hsin Lin, David Vanderbilt, and Nicholas Kioussis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hyperspectral Three-Dimensional Refractive-Index Imaging Using Snapshot Optical Tomography]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014064</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014064"/>
        <updated>2023-01-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yongjin Sung
A material’s refractive index is a major input for the light-scattering analysis of microscopic particles and label-free optical imaging of biological tissues. Existing techniques for measuring the refractive index of a nonspherical specimen over a wide wavelength range are typically slow, because they require recording so many orientations and wavelengths of the laser illuminating the specimen. Here researchers demonstrate hyperspectral three-dimensional (3D) refractive-index imaging at high throughput using snapshot optical tomography, which can record a 3D map of the refractive index in a single snapshot, in combination with a wavelength-scanning laser.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 014064] Published Tue Jan 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yongjin Sung</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optical Guiding in 50-Meter-Scale Air Waveguides]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011006</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011006"/>
        <updated>2023-01-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Goffin, I. Larkin, A. Tartaro, A. Schweinsberg, A. Valenzuela, E. W. Rosenthal, and H. M. Milchberg
A waveguide sculpted in air with lasers transmits light over a distance of nearly 50 meters, which is 60 times farther than previous air-waveguide schemes.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 011006] Published Mon Jan 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Goffin, I. Larkin, A. Tartaro, A. Schweinsberg, A. Valenzuela, E. W. Rosenthal, and H. M. Milchberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synchronous Observation of Bell Nonlocality and State-Dependent Contextuality]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.040201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.040201"/>
        <updated>2023-01-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Peng Xue, Lei Xiao, G. Ruffolo, A. Mazzari, T. Temistocles, M. Terra Cunha, and R. Rabelo
Theoretical and experimental results demonstrate that Bell nonlocality and contextuality tests can be witnessed at the same time, contrary to a previous theorem.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 040201] Published Mon Jan 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peng Xue, Lei Xiao, G. Ruffolo, A. Mazzari, T. Temistocles, M. Terra Cunha, and R. Rabelo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thermal Convection in a Central Force Field Mediated by Sound]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.034002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.034002"/>
        <updated>2023-01-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): John P. Koulakis, Yotam Ofek, Seth Pree, and Seth Putterman
A recently discovered acoustic effect allows a hot gas to simulate the gravity-induced convection within a star or giant planet.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 034002] Published Fri Jan 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John P. Koulakis, Yotam Ofek, Seth Pree, and Seth Putterman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Growth of Mesoscale Ordered Two-Dimensional Hydrogen-Bond Organic Framework with the Observation of Flat Band]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.036203</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.036203"/>
        <updated>2023-01-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Minghu Pan, Xin Zhang, Yinong Zhou, Pengdong Wang, Qi Bian, Hang Liu, Xingyue Wang, Xiaoyin Li, Aixi Chen, Xiaoxu Lei, Shaojian Li, Zhengwang Cheng, Zhibin Shao, Haoxuan Ding, Jianzhi Gao, Fangsen Li, and Feng Liu
Topological flat bands are observed in a self-assembled monolayer of a 2D hydrogen bond organic framework.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 036203] Published Fri Jan 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Minghu Pan, Xin Zhang, Yinong Zhou, Pengdong Wang, Qi Bian, Hang Liu, Xingyue Wang, Xiaoyin Li, Aixi Chen, Xiaoxu Lei, Shaojian Li, Zhengwang Cheng, Zhibin Shao, Haoxuan Ding, Jianzhi Gao, Fangsen Li, and Feng Liu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discovering Quantum Phase Transitions with Fermionic Neural Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.036401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.036401"/>
        <updated>2023-01-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gino Cassella, Halvard Sutterud, Sam Azadi, N. D. Drummond, David Pfau, James S. Spencer, and W. M. C. Foulkes
A specific neural network based on a representation of the wave function guided by the quantum mechanical variational principle alone without reference to experimental data predicts electronic ground states in condensed matter without a priori knowledge of the system.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 036401] Published Fri Jan 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gino Cassella, Halvard Sutterud, Sam Azadi, N. D. Drummond, David Pfau, James S. Spencer, and W. M. C. Foulkes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phototaxis of <i>Chlamydomonas</i> arises from a tuned adaptive photoresponse shared with multicellular Volvocine green algae]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.014404</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.014404"/>
        <updated>2023-01-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kyriacos C. Leptos, Maurizio Chioccioli, Silvano Furlan, Adriana I. Pesci, and Raymond E. Goldstein
Many microorganisms have the ability to move toward a light source, and the authors study this process in Chlamydomonas, a unicellular member of a family of green algae. They show that the mechanism is shared with multicellular green algae in the same family, shedding light on the evolutionary transition from unicellular to multicellular organisms.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, 014404] Published Fri Jan 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kyriacos C. Leptos, Maurizio Chioccioli, Silvano Furlan, Adriana I. Pesci, and Raymond E. Goldstein</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Long-term simulations of dynamical ejecta: Homologous expansion and kilonova properties]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.023016</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.023016"/>
        <updated>2023-01-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anna Neuweiler, Tim Dietrich, Mattia Bulla, Swami Vivekanandji Chaurasia, Stephan Rosswog, and Maximiliano Ujevic
Binary neutron star mergers result in relatively long-lived transient states known as kilonovae. By developing methods that allow numerical relativity simulations to describe far longer periods of time than previously possible, the assumptions used in radiative transfer simulations of the ejecta are subjected to scrutiny and a far more nuanced picture is developed indicating when the assumptions become valid.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 023016] Published Fri Jan 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Neuweiler, Tim Dietrich, Mattia Bulla, Swami Vivekanandji Chaurasia, Stephan Rosswog, and Maximiliano Ujevic</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Densities and momentum distributions in $A≤12$ nuclei from chiral effective field theory interactions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.014314</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.014314"/>
        <updated>2023-01-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Piarulli, S. Pastore, R. B. Wiringa, S. Brusilow, and R. Lim
This study presents calculations of one- and two-body densities in both coordinate and momentum space for various nuclei up to 12C, using the phenomenological AV18+UX and various Norfolk NN + NNN χEFT interactions. It features new calculations of the pair density as a function of both pair separation and center-of-mass, as well as the two-body momentum distribution for short- and long-range pairs differentiated by a pair separation boundary. The full set of results are available online for general use by the nuclear physics community and are intended to provide useful insights into the short-range structure of nuclei and various reaction processes.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, 014314] Published Fri Jan 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Piarulli, S. Pastore, R. B. Wiringa, S. Brusilow, and R. Lim</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin-orbit enhancement in Si/SiGe heterostructures with oscillating Ge concentration]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.035418</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.035418"/>
        <updated>2023-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Benjamin D. Woods, M. A. Eriksson, Robert Joynt, and Mark Friesen
Electrons in Si/SiGe quantum dots are a promising platform for quantum computation. Many leading designs, however, rely on synthetic spin-orbit coupling arising from micromagnets, leading to challenges in scaling. Here, it is shown that the intrinsic spin-orbit coupling of the conduction-band valleys can be enhanced by over an order of magnitude by including Ge concentration oscillations of an appropriate wavelength within the quantum-well region. This enables fast spin manipulation using electric dipole spin resonance in the absence of micromagnets.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 035418] Published Thu Jan 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin D. Woods, M. A. Eriksson, Robert Joynt, and Mark Friesen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Characterizing random-singlet state in two-dimensional frustrated quantum magnets and implications for the double perovskite ${\mathrm{Sr}}_{2}{\mathrm{CuTe}}_{1−x}{\mathrm{W}}_{x}{\mathrm{O}}_{6}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L020407</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L020407"/>
        <updated>2023-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Huan-Da Ren, Tian-Yu Xiong, Han-Qing Wu, D. N. Sheng, and Shou-Shu Gong
Understanding disorder-induced exotic states in two-dimensional magnets is one of the central topics in the study of frustrated magnetism. Here, the authors focus on the randomness-induced disordered phase in the spin-½ J1−J2 square-lattice Heisenberg model with a strong bond randomness, by using large-scale density matrix renormalization group (DMRG) simulations. The results not only reveal the absent spin-glass order, but also identify the power-law decay of the average spin correlation and the exponential decay of the typical spin correlation. These all agree with the corresponding behavior in the one-dimensional random-singlet state and characterize the random-singlet nature of this disordered phase. This shows that DMRG simulations provide opportunities for exploring the disorder effect in two-dimensional magnets.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L020407] Published Thu Jan 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Huan-Da Ren, Tian-Yu Xiong, Han-Qing Wu, D. N. Sheng, and Shou-Shu Gong</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raman Wavelength Conversion in Ionic Liquids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014052</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014052"/>
        <updated>2023-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rotem Kupfer, Furong Wang, James F. Wishart, Marcus Babzien, Mikhail N. Polyanskiy, Igor V. Pogorelsky, Triveni Rao, Luca Cultrera, Navid Vafaei-Najafabadi, and Mark A. Palmer
Artificial salts that are liquid at room temperature can be used to efficiently tune the wavelength of a laser source.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 014052] Published Thu Jan 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rotem Kupfer, Furong Wang, James F. Wishart, Marcus Babzien, Mikhail N. Polyanskiy, Igor V. Pogorelsky, Triveni Rao, Luca Cultrera, Navid Vafaei-Najafabadi, and Mark A. Palmer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unconventional Charge-to-Spin Conversion in Graphene/${\mathrm{Mo}\mathrm{Te}}_{2}$ van der Waals Heterostructures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014053</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014053"/>
        <updated>2023-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nerea Ontoso, C. K. Safeer, Franz Herling, Josep Ingla-Aynés, Haozhe Yang, Zhendong Chi, Beatriz Martin-Garcia, Iñigo Robredo, Maia G. Vergniory, Fernando de Juan, M. Reyes Calvo, Luis E. Hueso, and Fèlix Casanova
Spin-charge interconversion phenomena are important ingredients for the development of post-CMOS spin-based logic and magnetic memory technologies. Device design is often limited, though, by the fact that in most systems conversion occurs only if charge current, spin current, and spin polarization are mutually orthogonal. The authors find that in graphene/MoTe2 van der Waals heterostructures, charge currents injected in any spatial direction contribute to the same particular spin-polarization direction, thanks to a combination of strong spin-orbit proximity effects and broken crystal symmetries. This insight points to efficient spin-current generation and flexible device design.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 014053] Published Thu Jan 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nerea Ontoso, C. K. Safeer, Franz Herling, Josep Ingla-Aynés, Haozhe Yang, Zhendong Chi, Beatriz Martin-Garcia, Iñigo Robredo, Maia G. Vergniory, Fernando de Juan, M. Reyes Calvo, Luis E. Hueso, and Fèlix Casanova</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search for entanglement in the decay dynamics and anisotropic emission of a pair of $\mathrm{H}(2p)$ atoms produced by XUV photodissociation of ${\text{H}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.013109</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.013109"/>
        <updated>2023-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Dochain, B. Fabre, C. Lauzin, and X. Urbain
In this article, the authors experimentally investigate the possibility to produce a pair of entangled photons from the photodissociation of H2. They study the dynamics of the two-photon emission and introduce a simple model, assuming a transition from Hund’s case (a) to Hund’s case (c), to reproduce the measured angular distributions satisfactorily.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 013109] Published Thu Jan 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Dochain, B. Fabre, C. Lauzin, and X. Urbain</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exact solutions for the electromagnetic fields of a flying focus]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.013513</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.013513"/>
        <updated>2023-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. Ramsey, A. Di Piazza, M. Formanek, P. Franke, D. H. Froula, B. Malaca, W. B. Mori, J. R. Pierce, T. T. Simpson, J. Vieira, M. Vranic, K. Weichman, and J. P. Palastro
A laser beam’s peak intensity may be programmed to move at an arbitrary velocity by adjusting the focal time and location of its frequencies, temporal slices, or annuli. Such “flying focus” beams show promise in enabling new laser-matter applications. To assess these possibilities, the authors analytically describe the electromagnetic fields of flying-focus pulses with arbitrary polarization and orbital angular momentum.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 013513] Published Thu Jan 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. Ramsey, A. Di Piazza, M. Formanek, P. Franke, D. H. Froula, B. Malaca, W. B. Mori, J. R. Pierce, T. T. Simpson, J. Vieira, M. Vranic, K. Weichman, and J. P. Palastro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search for Cosmic-Ray Boosted Sub-GeV Dark Matter Using Recoil Protons at Super-Kamiokande]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.031802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.031802"/>
        <updated>2023-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): K. Abe et al. (Super-Kamiokande Collaboration)
Interactions with cosmic rays could make low-mass dark matter particles detectable by neutrino observatories. But an analysis of two decades’ worth of data shows no signs of the particles.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 031802] Published Wed Jan 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>K. Abe &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (Super-Kamiokande Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unsupervised Data-Driven Classification of Topological Gapped Systems with Symmetries]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.036601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.036601"/>
        <updated>2023-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yang Long and Baile Zhang
An unsupervised learning approach leads to the classification of topological gapped systems without a priori knowledge of topological invariants.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 036601] Published Wed Jan 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yang Long and Baile Zhang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transmittable Nonreciprocal Cloaking]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014051</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014051"/>
        <updated>2023-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mojtaba Dehmollaian, Guillaume Lavigne, and Christophe Caloz
Offering a potential pathway to the fantasy of invisibility, cloaking has been a most popular concept since its introduction over 15 years ago. This article furthers the concept by making the cloak transmittable, so as to allow “transmitting without being seen”. This special cloak consists of a concentric set of bianisotropic metasurfaces with a nonreciprocal innermost element, and allows the entity sitting at its center to transmit information at will in a desired direction while remaining invisible in all other directions. Such cloaks may find application in e.g. stealth technology, blockage avoidance, optical illusion, and cooling.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 014051] Published Wed Jan 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mojtaba Dehmollaian, Guillaume Lavigne, and Christophe Caloz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kerr Enhanced Backaction Cooling in Magnetomechanics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.033601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.033601"/>
        <updated>2023-01-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. Zoepfl, M. L. Juan, N. Diaz-Naufal, C. M. F. Schneider, L. F. Deeg, A. Sharafiev, A. Metelmann, and G. Kirchmair
Photons in a nonlinear cavity perform “negative” work on a mechanical oscillator, cooling it toward its ground state.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 033601] Published Tue Jan 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. Zoepfl, M. L. Juan, N. Diaz-Naufal, C. M. F. Schneider, L. F. Deeg, A. Sharafiev, A. Metelmann, and G. Kirchmair</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charge order with unusual star-of-David lattice in monolayer ${\mathrm{NbTe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L041105</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L041105"/>
        <updated>2023-01-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Taiki Taguchi, Katsuaki Sugawara, Hirofumi Oka, Tappei Kawakami, Yasuaki Saruta, Takemi Kato, Kosuke Nakayama, Seigo Souma, Takashi Takahashi, Tomoteru Fukumura, and Takafumi Sato
The authors fabricated a new two-dimensional material, monolayer NbTe2, and investigated its electronic states. They discovered a charge-density wave with a √19×√19 periodicity, accompanied by partially occupied metallic star-of-David clusters of Nb atoms, which is in sharp contrast to the fully occupied Mott-insulating monolayer NbSe2. Such an intriguing difference is found to originate from the underlying fermiology and hidden-Fermi-surface nesting. The present result lays the foundation for manipulating the two-dimensional Mott-insulator phase.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L041105] Published Tue Jan 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Taiki Taguchi, Katsuaki Sugawara, Hirofumi Oka, Tappei Kawakami, Yasuaki Saruta, Takemi Kato, Kosuke Nakayama, Seigo Souma, Takashi Takahashi, Tomoteru Fukumura, and Takafumi Sato</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>