<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2024-02-17T00:43:25.410Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2024-02-17T00:43:25.410Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic structure of nitrogen-doped lutetium hydrides]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.L021801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.L021801"/>
        <updated>2024-02-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Adam Denchfield, Hyowon Park, and Russell J. Hemley
Hydrides at high pressures constitute the only materials to be superconducting above 200 K, and are typically marked by an appreciable hydrogen density of states and van Hove singularities at the Fermi energy. Given the recent interest in nitrogen-doped lutetium hydride, the authors focused on finding the structures which would have electronic properties that could plausibly support high-temperature superconductivity within a narrow pressure range. They have identified a narrow range of stoichiometries Lu8H23−xN with hydrogen-dominant conduction states, and found one structure which exhibits a very large hydrogen density of states with an extremely sharp van Hove singularity, whose properties may therefore change dramatically under pressure.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, L021801] Published Fri Feb 16, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Denchfield, Hyowon Park, and Russell J. Hemley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voltage-Controlled Magnon Transistor via Tuning Interfacial Exchange Coupling]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076701"/>
        <updated>2024-02-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Y. Z. Wang, T. Y. Zhang, J. Dong, P. Chen, G. Q. Yu, C. H. Wan, and X. F. Han
Researchers have demonstrated that magnetic spin waves called magnons can be controlled by voltage and thus could operate more efficiently as information carriers in future devices.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 076701] Published Fri Feb 16, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Y. Z. Wang, T. Y. Zhang, J. Dong, P. Chen, G. Q. Yu, C. H. Wan, and X. F. Han</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Field-Induced Hybridization of Moiré Excitons in ${\mathrm{MoSe}}_{2}/{\mathrm{WS}}_{2}$ Heterobilayers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076902"/>
        <updated>2024-02-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Borislav Polovnikov, Johannes Scherzer, Subhradeep Misra, Xin Huang, Christian Mohl, Zhijie Li, Jonas Göser, Jonathan Förste, Ismail Bilgin, Kenji Watanabe, Takashi Taniguchi, Alexander Högele, and Anvar S. Baimuratov
Laser modulation spectroscopy on a MoSe2/WS2 heterostructure shows an intricate interplay of both intra- and interlayer moiré excitons and allows to determine unambiguously the nature of the observed optical resonances.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 076902] Published Fri Feb 16, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Borislav Polovnikov, Johannes Scherzer, Subhradeep Misra, Xin Huang, Christian Mohl, Zhijie Li, Jonas Göser, Jonathan Förste, Ismail Bilgin, Kenji Watanabe, Takashi Taniguchi, Alexander Högele, and Anvar S. Baimuratov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Excited-state geometry relaxation of point defects in monolayer hexagonal boron nitride]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085127</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085127"/>
        <updated>2024-02-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexander Kirchhoff, Thorsten Deilmann, and Michael Rohlfing
Optical excitation and deexcitation processes are governed by the dependence of the involved energy levels on the atom positions. This geometry dependence is calculated here for several defects in h-BN, e.g., CBVN, within constrained density functional theory and many-body perturbation theory. The investigated Stokes shifts show distinct differences compared to experiments. For the Tamm-Dancoff approximation, an approximation frequently employed in the calculation of exciton energies in crystalline solids, the authors find small but significant influence for defect systems.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 085127] Published Fri Feb 16, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexander Kirchhoff, Thorsten Deilmann, and Michael Rohlfing</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of New Isotopes in the Fragmentation of $^{198}\mathrm{Pt}$ at FRIB]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.072501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.072501"/>
        <updated>2024-02-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): O. B. Tarasov, A. Gade, K. Fukushima, M. Hausmann, E. Kwan, M. Portillo, M. Smith, D. S. Ahn, D. Bazin, R. Chyzh, S. Giraud, K. Haak, T. Kubo, D. J. Morrissey, P. N. Ostroumov, I. Richardson, B. M. Sherrill, A. Stolz, S. Watters, D. Weisshaar, and T. Zhang
Less than a year after its opening, the Facility for Rare Isotope Beams produced five never-before-seen isotopes for observation, a success that researchers say highlights the discovery potential of the facility.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 072501] Published Thu Feb 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>O. B. Tarasov, A. Gade, K. Fukushima, M. Hausmann, E. Kwan, M. Portillo, M. Smith, D. S. Ahn, D. Bazin, R. Chyzh, S. Giraud, K. Haak, T. Kubo, D. J. Morrissey, P. N. Ostroumov, I. Richardson, B. M. Sherrill, A. Stolz, S. Watters, D. Weisshaar, and T. Zhang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discovery of New Isotopes $^{160}\mathrm{Os}$ and $^{156}\mathrm{W}$: Revealing Enhanced Stability of the $N=82$ Shell Closure on the Neutron-Deficient Side]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.072502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.072502"/>
        <updated>2024-02-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): H. B. Yang (杨华彬) et al.
Adding what seems like too many protons to a nucleus can increase one measure of its stability.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 072502] Published Thu Feb 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>H. B. Yang (杨华彬) &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Shot Noise Does Not Generally Detect Pairing in Mesoscopic Superconducting Tunnel Junctions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076001"/>
        <updated>2024-02-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jiasen Niu, Koen M. Bastiaans, Jian-Feng Ge, Ruchi Tomar, John Jesudasan, Pratap Raychaudhuri, Max Karrer, Reinhold Kleiner, Dieter Koelle, Arnaud Barbier, Eduard F. C. Driessen, Yaroslav M. Blanter, and Milan P. Allan
Shot noise measurements in Nb-based superconducting tunnel junctions indicate that transparency channels obscure pairing in noise measurements, a common roadblock in measurements in such junctions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 076001] Published Thu Feb 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jiasen Niu, Koen M. Bastiaans, Jian-Feng Ge, Ruchi Tomar, John Jesudasan, Pratap Raychaudhuri, Max Karrer, Reinhold Kleiner, Dieter Koelle, Arnaud Barbier, Eduard F. C. Driessen, Yaroslav M. Blanter, and Milan P. Allan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of double-kink states in multivalley acoustic crystals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.054109</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.054109"/>
        <updated>2024-02-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xiao-Hui Gou, Hua-Shan Lai, Xiao-Chen Sun, Si-Yuan Yu, Y. B. Chen, Cheng He, and Yan-Feng Chen
Graphene structures usually accommodate one pair of Dirac cones, naturally forming a single kink valley state after symmetry breaking. The authors report here that acoustic S-graphene, i.e., a carbon allotrope of graphene, can harbor two pairs of Dirac cones, further shaping double-kink valley states. By selectively exciting different symmetric or antisymmetric branches, robust yet tunable superdirectional sound radiation is experimentally demonstrated. This study could double the degrees of freedom for valleytronics and help in the design of unique functional devices.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 054109] Published Thu Feb 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiao-Hui Gou, Hua-Shan Lai, Xiao-Chen Sun, Si-Yuan Yu, Y. B. Chen, Cheng He, and Yan-Feng Chen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonreciprocal spin-wave transport in an asymmetric three-dimensional magnonic coupler]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.024031</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.024031"/>
        <updated>2024-02-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A.A. Grachev, S.A. Odintsov, E.N. Beginin, and A.V. Sadovnikov
The use of elementary quanta of magnetic excitation—magnons, or spin waves—as carriers of information attracts more and more interest, as transferring the magnetic moment (spin) of an electron without transferring its electric charge avoids the heat generation inherent in CMOS technology. This study aims to exploit directed spin-wave propagation in a structure composed of parallel stripes of thin-film yttrium iron garnet, forming an asymmetric three-dimensional coupler geometry. This approach has the potential to enhance the density of functional elements in three-dimensional magnonic networks.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 024031] Published Thu Feb 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A.A. Grachev, S.A. Odintsov, E.N. Beginin, and A.V. Sadovnikov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantifying the Properties of Nonproductive Attempts at Thermally Activated Energy-Barrier Crossing through Direct Observation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011017</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011017"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aaron Lyons, Anita Devi, Noel Q. Hoffer, and Michael T. Woodside
Researchers have measured short-timescale fluctuations in metastable systems, uncovering information about failed attempts to cross the barriers that define the metastable state.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011017] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aaron Lyons, Anita Devi, Noel Q. Hoffer, and Michael T. Woodside</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum oscillations in kagome metals ${\mathrm{CsTi}}_{3}{\mathrm{Bi}}_{5}$ and ${\mathrm{RbTi}}_{3}{\mathrm{Bi}}_{5}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024003"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zackary Rehfuss, Christopher Broyles, David Graf, Yongkang Li, Hengxin Tan, Zhen Zhao, Jiali Liu, Yuhang Zhang, Xiaoli Dong, Haitao Yang, Hongjun Gao, Binghai Yan, and Sheng Ran
We explore quantum oscillations in the kagome metals CsTi3Bi5 and RbTi3Bi5, using high magnetic fields and low temperatures. We reveal new quantum oscillation frequencies in CsTi3Bi5, showing a complex Fermi surface that matches density functional theory predictions. Interestingly, the Rb compound exhibits notably different results from the Cs compound, despite theoretical expectations of similarity. This work deepens our understanding of the electronic intricacies within kagome lattice systems and spotlights their role as a playground for unearthing novel quantum states. Our findings pave the way for future investigations in the quantum behaviors of kagome metals, offering insights for advanced material development.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 024003] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zackary Rehfuss, Christopher Broyles, David Graf, Yongkang Li, Hengxin Tan, Zhen Zhao, Jiali Liu, Yuhang Zhang, Xiaoli Dong, Haitao Yang, Hongjun Gao, Binghai Yan, and Sheng Ran</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological diffusive metal in amorphous transition metal monosilicides]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.L021201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.L021201"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Selma Franca and Adolfo G. Grushin
Transition metal monosilicides RhSi and CoSi have intriguing physical properties such as long Fermi arc surface states and unusual optical responses. These features originate from multifold fermions - higher spin generalizations of Weyl quasiparticles that are protected by crystalline symmetries. Since these materials are prone to intrinsic disorder, the authors theoretically study topological properties of amorphous RhSi and CoSi. Using the spectral localizer, they find that multifold fermions survive disorder strengths that convert the semimetal into a diffusive metal phase. These conclusions are supported by photoemission simulations showing the presence of Fermi arcs in the corresponding disorder range.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, L021201] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Selma Franca and Adolfo G. Grushin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal Features of Entanglement Entropy in the Honeycomb Hubbard Model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076502"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jonathan D’Emidio, Román Orús, Nicolas Laflorencie, and Fernando de Juan
The entanglement entropy of two-dimensional interacting fermions can be simulated with quantum Monte Carlo techniques.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 076502] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan D’Emidio, Román Orús, Nicolas Laflorencie, and Fernando de Juan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arresting of interfacial phase separation with an imposed flow]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.024003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.024003"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ryuta X. Suzuki, Shoji Seya, Takahiko Ban, Manoranjan Mishra, and Yuichiro Nagatsu
We experimentally investigate displacement of a more viscous liquid by a less viscous one in a Hele-Shaw cell using an aqueous two phase system, where phase separation occurs in the growing liquid-liquid interfacial region, by varying the injection flow rate and the phase separation rate. We show that the degree of the interfacial phase separation scales as a unique function of the ratio of the flow and phase separation rates and it decreases with the ratio. These results demonstrate that the interfacial phase separation is arrested by the imposed flow and determined by competition between the flow and phase separation rates. The arresting effect and the mechanism are numerically verified.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 024003] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ryuta X. Suzuki, Shoji Seya, Takahiko Ban, Manoranjan Mishra, and Yuichiro Nagatsu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mean-field method for generic conductance-based integrate-and-fire neurons with finite timescales]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.024406</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.024406"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marcelo P. Becker and Marco A. P. Idiart
This article presents a mean-field method to determine the transfer function that describes the behavior of spiking neurons in a network. The authors extend a Fokker-Planck approach to the case of conductance-based integrate-and-fire neurons with various sources of noise, and find good agreement with data from simulations.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 024406] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marcelo P. Becker and Marco A. P. Idiart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toward accurate modeling of line-intensity mapping one-point statistics: Including extended profiles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.043517</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.043517"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): José Luis Bernal
The authors construct an analytic model of the line-intensity mapping (LIM) probability density field to include sources extended in angle and frequency, thus contributing to more than one observational resolution element. Preliminary simulation-based testing shows promise, encouraging further LIM development.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 043517] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>José Luis Bernal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantitative feasibility study of sequential neutron captures using intense lasers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.025802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.025802"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vojtěch Horný, Sophia N. Chen, Xavier Davoine, Laurent Gremillet, and Julien Fuchs
Laser-generated nucleosynthesis remains out of reach of present-day technology—but more powerful lasers could eventually make it possible.

[Phys. Rev. C 109, 025802] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vojtěch Horný, Sophia N. Chen, Xavier Davoine, Laurent Gremillet, and Julien Fuchs</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic heterogeneity at the experimental glass transition predicted by transferable machine learning]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.064205</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.064205"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gerhard Jung, Giulio Biroli, and Ludovic Berthier
Dynamic heterogeneities represent a critical aspect of glassy dynamics, and their analysis constitutes a fundamental step in understanding the essence of the glass transition. The authors employ physics-inspired machine learning to predict the microscopic structural relaxation from amorphous configurations of deeply supercooled liquids. Leveraging the transferability in temperature of the trained networks enables the prediction of dynamic heterogeneities at the experimental glass transition temperature, thereby circumventing the prohibitively large computational cost associated with conventional simulation methods at such low temperatures.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 064205] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gerhard Jung, Giulio Biroli, and Ludovic Berthier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ground-state phase diagram and superconductivity of the doped Hubbard model on six-leg square cylinders]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085121</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085121"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yi-Fan Jiang, Thomas P. Devereaux, and Hong-Chen Jiang
The authors employ the density-matrix renormalization group to investigate the doped Hubbard model on six-leg square cylinders. It uncovers a rich quantum phase diagram, intricately sensitive to next-nearest-neighbor electron hopping (t′). The positive-t′ region shows a robust d-wave superconducting phase with intertwined superconducting and charge-density-wave orders. In contrast, the negative-t′ side remains insulating, where doped holes form either long-range charge stripe order at small t′ or a holon Wigner crystal with one doped hole per emergent unit cell and short-range spin correlations at larger t’.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 085121] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yi-Fan Jiang, Thomas P. Devereaux, and Hong-Chen Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coherence of group-IV color centers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085414</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085414"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Isaac B. W. Harris and Dirk Englund
Group-IV color centers in diamond are a promising platform for quantum entanglement distribution experiments. However, they suffer from a phonon-mediated decoherence mechanism that limits the maximum temperature at which they can operate. This theoretical work develops a model that accurately predicts coherence time, and further predicts regimes in which the coherence can be extended, potentially leading to higher-temperature operation.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 085414] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaac B. W. Harris and Dirk Englund</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum light-field microscopy for volumetric imaging with extreme depth of field]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.024029</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.024029"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yingwen Zhang, Duncan England, Antony Orth, Ebrahim Karimi, and Benjamin Sussman
Light-field microscopy (LFM) extracts volumetric data from a specimen by simultaneously capturing the positional and angular information of light rays emanating from the sample. While conventional LFM requires a compromise between depth of field (DOF) and resolution, this work introduces a quantum approach to eliminate this compromise by harnessing position-momentum entanglement of photon pairs. Compared to conventional LFM at the same resolution, the quantum approach can yield up to tenfold improvement in DOF. This work illustrates the power of utilizing multidimensional entanglement in microscopy and hopefully will inspire further innovations in the field.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 024029] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yingwen Zhang, Duncan England, Antony Orth, Ebrahim Karimi, and Benjamin Sussman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Loss features in ultracold $^{162}\mathrm{Dy}$ gases: Two- versus three-body processes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.023319</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.023319"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maxime Lecomte, Alexandre Journeaux, Loan Renaud, Jean Dalibard, and Raphael Lopes
The authors study the low-field loss features in ultracold thermal samples of 162Dy by examining the density and temperature dependence of various loss features. They demonstrate that a majority of loss features are accurately described by a two-body loss rate instead of the commonly assumed three-body rate.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 023319] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maxime Lecomte, Alexandre Journeaux, Loan Renaud, Jean Dalibard, and Raphael Lopes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ternary Oxides of $s$- and $p$-Block Metals for Photocatalytic Solar-to-Hydrogen Conversion]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXEnergy.3.013007</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXEnergy.3.013007"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Simon Gelin, Nicole E. Kirchner-Hall, Rowan R. Katzbaer, Monica J. Theibault, Yihuang Xiong, Wayne Zhao, Mohammed M. Khan, Eric Andrewlavage, Paul Orbe, Steven M. Baksa, Matteo Cococcioni, Iurii Timrov, Quinn Campbell, Héctor Abruña, Raymond E. Schaak, and Ismaila Dabo
Computational materials design is combined with synthesis and electrochemical characterization to propose nine oxide semiconductors as water-splitting photocatalysts.

[PRX Energy 3, 013007] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Gelin, Nicole E. Kirchner-Hall, Rowan R. Katzbaer, Monica J. Theibault, Yihuang Xiong, Wayne Zhao, Mohammed M. Khan, Eric Andrewlavage, Paul Orbe, Steven M. Baksa, Matteo Cococcioni, Iurii Timrov, Quinn Campbell, Héctor Abruña, Raymond E. Schaak, and Ismaila Dabo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic Allometry of Nuclei in Early Embryos of <i>Caenorhabditis elegans</i>]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011016</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011016"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rolf Fickentscher, Tomoko Ozawa, Akatsuki Kimura, and Matthias Weiss
By monitoring a tiny worm’s embryonic cells, researchers have deduced that the availability of material for the membrane of a cell’s nucleus constrains the volume of the nucleus.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011016] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rolf Fickentscher, Tomoko Ozawa, Akatsuki Kimura, and Matthias Weiss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plasmonic vortices host magnetoelectric interactions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.6.013163</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.6.013163"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Atreyie Ghosh, Sena Yang, Yanan Dai, W. Vincent Liu, and Hrvoje Petek
Plasmonic vortices are found to host pseudoscalar 𝙀∙𝘽 fields that are odd under parity 𝒫 and time 𝒯 inversion, but even under the joint 𝒫𝒯 symmetry, enabling them to drive the magnetoelectric response and act as a source of the axion field.

[Phys. Rev. Research 6, 013163] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Atreyie Ghosh, Sena Yang, Yanan Dai, W. Vincent Liu, and Hrvoje Petek</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nanoscale dynamics of hydrogen in ${\mathrm{VO}}_{2}$ studied by $μ\mathrm{SR}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024602"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): H. Okabe, M. Hiraishi, A. Koda, Y. Matsushita, T. Ohsawa, N. Ohashi, and R. Kadono
Vanadium dioxide (VO2) is a promising next-generation electronic material for artificial neural networks. Here, the authors use muon spin spectroscopy to provide a microscopic basis for understanding nanoscale hydrogen diffusion in VO2, using muons as a microscopic simulator of dilute hydrogen. This innovation allows the authors to investigate the dynamics of trace hydrogen in nanoscale regions such as thin films, which is very difficult to achieve with conventional methods. This study is expected not only to make a significant contribution to the development of VO2 devices but also to provide a unique method for observing the dynamics of hydrogen at the nanoscale.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 024602] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>H. Okabe, M. Hiraishi, A. Koda, Y. Matsushita, T. Ohsawa, N. Ohashi, and R. Kadono</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exponential Capacity of Dense Associative Memories]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.077301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.077301"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Carlo Lucibello and Marc Mézard
A statistical mechanics analysis allows for the computation of asymptotic thresholds for pattern retrieval in the context of dense associative memories.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 077301] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carlo Lucibello and Marc Mézard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eigenvector continuation for the pairing Hamiltonian]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.024311</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.024311"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Companys Franzke, A. Tichai, K. Hebeler, and A. Schwenk
This work reports on an emulator for the evaluation of many-body observables based on an eigenvector continuation (EC) framework as an example of a reduced-basis method for a detailed study of the exactly solvable pairing Hamiltonian that serves as a model for nuclear superfluidity. EC is established as a robust resummation tool for many-body perturbation theory even though the bare perturbative expansion breaks down. The authors obtain a reliable, computation-saving, description of the exact solution with a small number of training points, provided these are taken from both sides of the pairing phase transition.

[Phys. Rev. C 109, 024311] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Companys Franzke, A. Tichai, K. Hebeler, and A. Schwenk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ternary quasifission in collisions of actinide nuclei]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.024316</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.024316"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. D. Zhang, B. Li, D. Vretenar, T. Nikšić, Z. X. Ren, P. W. Zhao, and J. Meng
Far away from the heaviest known nuclei, an island of relatively stable nuclei should exist in the nuclear chart. Reaching that island of stability requires a nuclear reaction that will transfer a large number of nucleons from one nucleus to another, such as in the collision of two actinide nuclei, which are heavy and already neutron-rich. In one particular collision scenario, ternary quasifission, the composite system formed by the two colliding nuclei is not in equilibrium, splitting into three fragments, instead of the more commonly observed binary fission process. The authors report a systematic study of ternary quasifission in 238U + 238U collisions in a microscopic framework that has been successfully applied to various nuclear phenomena. They find that including octupole deformation has a pronounced effect on the formation of the middle fragment. For tail-to-tail and tail-to-side collisions, the model calculations predict the formation of very heavy neutron-rich systems in certain energy intervals, a result that is potentially interesting for the synthesis of superheavy elements.

[Phys. Rev. C 109, 024316] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. D. Zhang, B. Li, D. Vretenar, T. Nikšić, Z. X. Ren, P. W. Zhao, and J. Meng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atomic corrections for the unique first-forbidden $β$ transition of $^{187}\mathrm{Re}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.025501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.025501"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): O. Niţescu, R. Dvornický, and F. Šimkovic
The shape of the spectrum of electrons emitted in β decay near the highest (endpoint) energy offers a direct way to determine the absolute values of neutrino masses. The authors reexamine one of the most promising candidates for determining the neutrino mass scale, the unique first-forbidden β transition from 187Re(5/2+) to 187Os(1/2−). Their results show that exchange effects between the emitted electrons and the atomic bound electrons can considerably impact the shape of the electron spectrum near the endpoint. The authors conclude that atomic effects, especially the exchange effect, should be considered in current and future investigations of the neutrino mass scale from β decays.

[Phys. Rev. C 109, 025501] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>O. Niţescu, R. Dvornický, and F. Šimkovic</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Radiative decay branching ratio of the Hoyle state]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.025801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.025801"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zifeng Luo (罗梓锋), M. Barbui, J. Bishop, G. Chubarian, V. Z. Goldberg, E. Harris, E. Koshchiy, C. E. Parker, M. Roosa, A. Saastamoinen, D. P. Scriven, and G. V. Rogachev
In 1954 Fred Hoyle postulated that a 7.65 MeV excited state in 12C had to exist for carbon-based life to develop on Earth. During stellar helium burning, such a state allows a short-lived 8Be, formed from two α particles, to resonantly react with a third α particle to form this state which can decay to the 12C ground state via γ or electron-positron pair emission. The branching fraction for this radiative decay determines the amount of 12C produced in stars. A recent experiment suggested that the decay was significantly different from previous results from the 1960’s and 1970’s, adding considerable uncertainty to this important reaction. This paper uses modern detection technology to remeasure the branching ratio with reduced uncertainties compared with the new result and confirms that the earlier results were correct, thus significantly reducing the uncertainty in stellar 12C production.

[Phys. Rev. C 109, 025801] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zifeng Luo (罗梓锋), M. Barbui, J. Bishop, G. Chubarian, V. Z. Goldberg, E. Harris, E. Koshchiy, C. E. Parker, M. Roosa, A. Saastamoinen, D. P. Scriven, and G. V. Rogachev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[${\mathrm{Bi}}_{2}{\mathrm{YbO}}_{4}\mathrm{Cl}$: A two-dimensional square-lattice compound with ${J}_{\text{eff}}=\frac{1}{2}$ magnetic moments]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.075128</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.075128"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): V. K. Singh, K. Nam, M. Barik, K. Boya, E. Kermarrec, P. Khuntia, Kee Hoon Kim, S. Bhowal, and B. Koteswararao
P. W. Anderson once proposed a “resonating valence bond” ground state of a 2D square lattice, an exotic disordered state formed by spin-pair superposition due to large quantum zero-point motion. However, perfect square-lattice materials realized so far exhibit long-range order with a reduced ordered moment. Here, the authors introduce a new quantum magnet, Bi2YbO4Cl, synthesized by the hydrothermal method. This compound realizes spin-orbit entangled moments in a 2D square lattice and maintains spin disorder down to several millikelvin temperatures.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 075128] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>V. K. Singh, K. Nam, M. Barik, K. Boya, E. Kermarrec, P. Khuntia, Kee Hoon Kim, S. Bhowal, and B. Koteswararao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Laser-Induced Electron Diffraction in Chiral Molecules]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011015</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011015"/>
        <updated>2024-02-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Debobrata Rajak, Sandra Beauvarlet, Omer Kneller, Antoine Comby, Raluca Cireasa, Dominique Descamps, Baptiste Fabre, Jimena D. Gorfinkiel, Julien Higuet, Stéphane Petit, Shaked Rozen, Hartmut Ruf, Nicolas Thiré, Valérie Blanchet, Nirit Dudovich, Bernard Pons, and Yann Mairesse
A technique that can determine the chirality of a molecule using that molecule’s own electrons could allow researchers to probe the dynamical behavior of chiral molecules on very short timescales.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011015] Published Mon Feb 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Debobrata Rajak, Sandra Beauvarlet, Omer Kneller, Antoine Comby, Raluca Cireasa, Dominique Descamps, Baptiste Fabre, Jimena D. Gorfinkiel, Julien Higuet, Stéphane Petit, Shaked Rozen, Hartmut Ruf, Nicolas Thiré, Valérie Blanchet, Nirit Dudovich, Bernard Pons, and Yann Mairesse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anomalous Aharonov-Bohm Interference in the Presence of Edge Reconstruction]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076301"/>
        <updated>2024-02-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sourav Biswas, Hemanta Kumar Kundu, Rajarshi Bhattacharyya, Vladimir Umansky, and Moty Heiblum
Subtleties in edge-structure reconstruction may critically affect Aharonov-Bohm oscillations in a quantum Hall interferometer.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 076301] Published Mon Feb 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sourav Biswas, Hemanta Kumar Kundu, Rajarshi Bhattacharyya, Vladimir Umansky, and Moty Heiblum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing Quantum Phases in Ultra-High-Mobility Two-Dimensional Electron Systems Using Surface Acoustic Waves]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076501"/>
        <updated>2024-02-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mengmeng Wu, Xiao Liu, Renfei Wang, Yoon Jang Chung, Adbhut Gupta, Kirk W. Baldwin, Loren Pfeiffer, Xi Lin, and Yang Liu
Deforming the quantum phase with a nondestructive current flowing through the sample shows that the system becomes more incompressible when hosting a current.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 076501] Published Mon Feb 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mengmeng Wu, Xiao Liu, Renfei Wang, Yoon Jang Chung, Adbhut Gupta, Kirk W. Baldwin, Loren Pfeiffer, Xi Lin, and Yang Liu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elastic electron scattering from deformed and oriented odd-$A$ nuclei]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.024312</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.024312"/>
        <updated>2024-02-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): P. Sarriguren
Deformation is a common property of nuclei, typically deduced from excitation spectra and γ-transition rates. Such deduction is more difficult for odd-A nuclei. In this paper, Sarriguren shows how one can use the interference between monopole and quadrupole Coulomb form factors in electron scattering off polarized odd-A nuclei to obtain detailed information on the quadrupole deformation, including its sign.

[Phys. Rev. C 109, 024312] Published Mon Feb 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>P. Sarriguren</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physics of the Majorana superconducting qubit hybrids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085410</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085410"/>
        <updated>2024-02-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. B. Karki, K. A. Matveev, and Ivar Martin
Realizing perfectly decoupled Majorana zero modes (MZMs) – the key element of proposed topological quantum computers – remains a challenge so far. Fortunately, even a few imperfect MZMs can be used to qualitatively extend the behavior of standard superconducting qubits. Such hybrid devices take advantage of the interplay of Cooper pair tunneling, coherent single-electron tunneling, and Majorana hybridization. Here, the authors offer a detailed description and present various analytical approaches to addressing the complex behavior of the MZM-superconducting qubit hybrid. Some practical applications of such a hybrid device are highlighted.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 085410] Published Mon Feb 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. B. Karki, K. A. Matveev, and Ivar Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Insights from HST into Ultramassive Galaxies and Early-Universe Cosmology]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.061002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.061002"/>
        <updated>2024-02-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nashwan Sabti, Julian B. Muñoz, and Marc Kamionkowski
The new JWST observatory is revealing far more bright galaxies in the early Universe than anyone predicted, and astrophysicists have more than one explanation for the puzzle.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 061002] Published Fri Feb 09, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nashwan Sabti, Julian B. Muñoz, and Marc Kamionkowski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perturbed Ion Temperature and Toroidal Flow Profile Measurements in Rotating Neoclassical Tearing Mode Magnetic Islands]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.065107</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.065107"/>
        <updated>2024-02-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): L. Bardóczi, A. Dudkovskaia, R. J. La Haye, J. D. Callen, C. Chrystal, and M. Podesta
Detailed measurements of the plasma structure in and around magnetic islands caused by neoclassical tearing modes (NTM) in the DIII-D tokamak help constrain theoretical models predicting the NTM onset threshold scaling for ITER and other future tokamaks.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 065107] Published Fri Feb 09, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L. Bardóczi, A. Dudkovskaia, R. J. La Haye, J. D. Callen, C. Chrystal, and M. Podesta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spectroscopic Signatures of Fractionalization in Octupolar Quantum Spin Ice]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.066502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.066502"/>
        <updated>2024-02-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Félix Desrochers and Yong Baek Kim
A comprehensive theoretical study of octupolar quantum spin ice shows that the dynamical spin structure factor is characterized by a broad continuum with three distinctive peaks which could be confirmed with inelastic neutron scattering measurements.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 066502] Published Fri Feb 09, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Félix Desrochers and Yong Baek Kim</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[$π$ Phase Interlayer Shift and Stacking Fault in the Kagome Superconductor ${\mathrm{CsV}}_{3}{\mathrm{Sb}}_{5}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.066501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.066501"/>
        <updated>2024-02-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Feng Jin, Wei Ren, Mingshu Tan, Mingtai Xie, Bingru Lu, Zheng Zhang, Jianting Ji, and Qingming Zhang
Observation of the stacking fault in the charge-density-wave phase of the kagome superconductor CsV3Sb5 offers structural insights to comprehend the entanglement between superconductivity and charge density waves in that system.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 066501] Published Thu Feb 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Feng Jin, Wei Ren, Mingshu Tan, Mingtai Xie, Bingru Lu, Zheng Zhang, Jianting Ji, and Qingming Zhang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of Higher-Order Nodal-Line Semimetal in Phononic Crystals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.066601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.066601"/>
        <updated>2024-02-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Qiyun Ma, Zhenhang Pu, Liping Ye, Jiuyang Lu, Xueqin Huang, Manzhu Ke, Hailong He, Weiyin Deng, and Zhengyou Liu
The sound waves in a fabricated material exhibit topological features in one, two, and three dimensions—demonstrating an acoustic version of a higher-order nodal-line semimetal.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 066601] Published Thu Feb 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qiyun Ma, Zhenhang Pu, Liping Ye, Jiuyang Lu, Xueqin Huang, Manzhu Ke, Hailong He, Weiyin Deng, and Zhengyou Liu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bichromatic Rabi Control of Semiconductor Qubits]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.067001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.067001"/>
        <updated>2024-02-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Valentin John, Francesco Borsoi, Zoltán György, Chien-An Wang, Gábor Széchenyi, Floor van Riggelen-Doelman, William I. L. Lawrie, Nico W. Hendrickx, Amir Sammak, Giordano Scappucci, András Pályi, and Menno Veldhorst
Coherent bichromatic Rabi control of quantum dot hole spin qubits can be used to control large qubit arrays.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 067001] Published Thu Feb 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Valentin John, Francesco Borsoi, Zoltán György, Chien-An Wang, Gábor Széchenyi, Floor van Riggelen-Doelman, William I. L. Lawrie, Nico W. Hendrickx, Amir Sammak, Giordano Scappucci, András Pályi, and Menno Veldhorst</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Instability and rupture of sheared viscous liquid nanofilms]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.024201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.024201"/>
        <updated>2024-02-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vira Dhaliwal, Christian Pedersen, Kheireddin Kadri, Guillaume Miquelard-Garnier, Cyrille Sollogoub, Jorge Peixinho, Thomas Salez, and Andreas Carlson
Liquid nanofilms are subject to rupture due to intermolecular forces triggered by surface perturbations arising from thermal fluctuations. When a shear stress is imposed at the free surface it becomes stable in the direction of shear, but perturbations can still grow in the perpendicular direction to the shear.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 024201] Published Thu Feb 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vira Dhaliwal, Christian Pedersen, Kheireddin Kadri, Guillaume Miquelard-Garnier, Cyrille Sollogoub, Jorge Peixinho, Thomas Salez, and Andreas Carlson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Buckling kinetics of graphene membranes under uniaxial compression]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.L023001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.L023001"/>
        <updated>2024-02-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aristotelis P. Sgouros, Evangelos Drougkas, Spyros V. Kallivokas, and Doros N. Theodorou
This work provides a framework for determining the buckling kinetics of membranes under compressive stress. The authors investigate a model of graphene with molecular dynamics simulations and find three regimes: I. Buckling time increases with temperature, II. Buckling time decreases with temperature, and III. Buckling time is independent of temperature.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, L023001] Published Thu Feb 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aristotelis P. Sgouros, Evangelos Drougkas, Spyros V. Kallivokas, and Doros N. Theodorou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Noncoplanar and chiral spin states on the way towards Néel ordering in fullerene Heisenberg models]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.054410</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.054410"/>
        <updated>2024-02-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Attila Szabó, Sylvain Capponi, and Fabien Alet
The authors obtain here the symmetry-resolved low-energy spectrum of the Heisenberg model on fullerene geometries using a neural-network-based variational technique. They also develop a theoretical framework, based on Anderson towers of states, to interpret these spectra. The authors find that the hexagonal faces of the fullerenes favour incipient Néel ordering, which is, however, frustrated by the pentagonal faces. This brings about exotic noncoplanar and chiral magnetic ordering, with possible interesting ramifications for fullerene superconductivity.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 054410] Published Thu Feb 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Attila Szabó, Sylvain Capponi, and Fabien Alet</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flat bands promoted by Hund's rule coupling in the candidate double-layer high-temperature superconductor ${\mathrm{La}}_{3}{\mathrm{Ni}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{7}$ under high pressure]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L081105</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L081105"/>
        <updated>2024-02-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yingying Cao and Yi-feng Yang
This work describes systematic strongly correlated electronic structure calculations for the candidate double-layer high-temperature superconductor La3Ni2O7 under pressure. These reveal the localized-itinerant duality of Ni dz2 electrons, flat dz2 and dx2−y2 quasiparticle bands, and strong interlayer antiferromagnetic correlations due to the interplay of orbital-selective Mott, Hund, and Kondo physics. These results imply a two-component theory with possibly preformed interlayer pairing for the high-temperature superconductivity in pressurized La3Ni2O7. The strange metallicity in the normal state is also explained from the quasiparticle lifetimes.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, L081105] Published Thu Feb 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yingying Cao and Yi-feng Yang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using non-Markovian dynamics in effective-negative-temperature-based transient quantum Otto engines]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.022207</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.022207"/>
        <updated>2024-02-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Arghya Maity and Ahana Ghoshal
Conventional quantum Otto engines based on effective-negative-temperature reservoirs rely on an assumption of perfect thermalization. In this study, the authors investigate the impact of non-Markovianity in these engines by terminating strokes before reaching thermal equilibrium, revealing that higher non-Markovianity enhances maximum efficiency but reduces overall performance over an extended period of functioning time. The authors also identify a class of effective-negative-temperature-based necessarily transient quantum Otto engines.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 022207] Published Thu Feb 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Arghya Maity and Ahana Ghoshal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Active Matter under Control: Insights from Response Theory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011012</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011012"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Luke K. Davis, Karel Proesmans, and Étienne Fodor
A theoretical study finds that the most energy-efficient way to control an active-matter system is to drive it at finite speed—unlike passive-matter systems.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011012] Published Wed Feb 07, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke K. Davis, Karel Proesmans, and Étienne Fodor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orbital degree of freedom in high entropy oxides]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024404</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024404"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jiaqiang Yan, Abinash Kumar, Miaofang Chi, Matthew Brahlek, Thomas Z. Ward, and Michael A. McGuire
Understanding strongly correlated physics of electronic-driven orbital ordering in transition metal compounds has presented many long-standing questions. Utilizing high-entropy oxides have enabled understanding that disorder can unlock an unusual intermixing of orbital and spin in the rare-earth vanadate, RVO3, which shows that the average and variance of ionic radius determine and control unusual properties of the spin and orbital order. The ability to systematically control variance of the local structure in high-quality crystals which hold constant charge and spin is crucial for a deeper understanding and exploring unanswered decades-old question regarding the physics of the Kugel-Khomskii compounds.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 024404] Published Wed Feb 07, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jiaqiang Yan, Abinash Kumar, Miaofang Chi, Matthew Brahlek, Thomas Z. Ward, and Michael A. McGuire</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Collective Relaxation Dynamics in a Three-Dimensional Lattice Glass Model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.067101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.067101"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yoshihiko Nishikawa and Ludovic Berthier
A recently developed lattice model produces an unexpected prediction combination for the rearrangements of particles inside a supercooled liquid turning into a glass.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 067101] Published Wed Feb 07, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yoshihiko Nishikawa and Ludovic Berthier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Error channels in quantum nondemolition measurements on spin systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085302"/>
        <updated>2024-02-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Benjamin Joecker, Holly G. Stemp, Irene Fernández de Fuentes, Mark A. I. Johnson, and Andrea Morello
Quantum nondemolition measurements (QNDMs) are a precious resource for quantum computing. They are an integral part of the surface code, the holy grail of quantum error correction, and can boost initialization and readout fidelities through repeated measurements. In spin systems, scalable QNDMS are achievable by coupling to ancillary spins read via charge reservoirs. Here, the authors develop a model to quantify how small deviations from true QNDMs in real spin system can introduce bit-flip errors and analyze how they can be minimized.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 085302] Published Wed Feb 07, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin Joecker, Holly G. Stemp, Irene Fernández de Fuentes, Mark A. I. Johnson, and Andrea Morello</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adiabatic Cooper pair splitter]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L081402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L081402"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fredrik Brange, Riya Baruah, and Christian Flindt
By adiabatically changing the energy levels of two quantum dots, theoreticians predict that it should be possible to control the splitting of Cooper pairs from a superconductor. Such an adiabatic Cooper pair splitter could serve as an on-demand source of entangled electrons in future solid-state quantum technologies.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, L081402] Published Tue Feb 06, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fredrik Brange, Riya Baruah, and Christian Flindt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three-wave-mixing quantum-limited kinetic inductance parametric amplifier operating at 6 T near 1 K]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.024011</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.024011"/>
        <updated>2024-02-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Frasca, C. Roy, G. Beaulieu, and P. Scarlino
Parametric amplifiers are essential in modern quantum technology, for enhancing weak signals with the minimal added noise of half a photon, and for working at higher temperatures and magnetic fields than Josephson junctions can handle. The authors present a kinetic inductance parametric amplifier (KIPA) that excels in dynamic range, operational temperature, and magnetic field resilience, and offers quantum-limited amplification. This KIPA’s robust performance and compatibility promise transformative impacts on quantum information processing and low-temperature quantum research.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 024011] Published Tue Feb 06, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Frasca, C. Roy, G. Beaulieu, and P. Scarlino</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microwave Photon-Number Amplification]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011011</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011011"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Albert, J. Griesmar, F. Blanchet, U. Martel, N. Bourlet, and M. Hofheinz
A new photon-number amplification scheme, which combines the advantages of a single-photon detector and a power meter, could lead to new photon-detection possibilities in quantum-sensing and quantum-computing applications.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011011] Published Mon Feb 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Albert, J. Griesmar, F. Blanchet, U. Martel, N. Bourlet, and M. Hofheinz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Achievement of Target Gain Larger than Unity in an Inertial Fusion Experiment]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.065102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.065102"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): H. Abu-Shawareb et al. (The Indirect Drive ICF Collaboration)
Scientists have now vetted details of the 2022 laser-powered fusion reaction that produced more energy than it consumed.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 065102] Published Mon Feb 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>H. Abu-Shawareb &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (The Indirect Drive ICF Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Energy Principles of Scientific Breakeven in an Inertial Fusion Experiment]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.065103</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.065103"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): O. A. Hurricane, D. A. Callahan, D. T. Casey, A. R. Christopherson, A. L. Kritcher, O. L. Landen, S. A. Maclaren, R. Nora, P. K. Patel, J. Ralph, D. Schlossberg, P. T. Springer, C. V. Young, and A. B. Zylstra
Scientists have now vetted details of the 2022 laser-powered fusion reaction that produced more energy than it consumed.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 065103] Published Mon Feb 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>O. A. Hurricane, D. A. Callahan, D. T. Casey, A. R. Christopherson, A. L. Kritcher, O. L. Landen, S. A. Maclaren, R. Nora, P. K. Patel, J. Ralph, D. Schlossberg, P. T. Springer, C. V. Young, and A. B. Zylstra</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hohlraum Reheating from Burning NIF Implosions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.065104</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.065104"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. S. Rubery, M. D. Rosen, N. Aybar, O. L. Landen, L. Divol, C. V. Young, C. Weber, J. Hammer, J. D. Moody, A. S. Moore, A. L. Kritcher, A. B. Zylstra, O. Hurricane, A. E. Pak, S. MacLaren, G. Zimmerman, J. Harte, and T. Woods
Scientists have now vetted details of the 2022 laser-powered fusion reaction that produced more energy than it consumed.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 065104] Published Mon Feb 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. S. Rubery, M. D. Rosen, N. Aybar, O. L. Landen, L. Divol, C. V. Young, C. Weber, J. Hammer, J. D. Moody, A. S. Moore, A. L. Kritcher, A. B. Zylstra, O. Hurricane, A. E. Pak, S. MacLaren, G. Zimmerman, J. Harte, and T. Woods</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observations and properties of the first laboratory fusion experiment to exceed a target gain of unity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.025203</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.025203"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Pak et al.
The target gain greater than unity achieved in a recent fusion experiment was made possible by using additional laser energy at fixed power and controlling sources of degradation. This resulted in increased compression of the fuel and a high fusion yield corresponding to a novel physical regime. This paper describes the experimental evidence for these critical aspects and new observables.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 025203] Published Mon Feb 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Pak &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Design of the first fusion experiment to achieve target energy gain $G&gt;1$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.025204</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.025204"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. L. Kritcher et al.
In 2022, a National Ignition Facility controlled-fusion experiment reached a target gain G>1, with the fusion energy produced exceeding the amount of laser energy required to drive the target. This result was obtained thanks to careful design described in this paper. This design has been shown to be robust and allows a better understanding of the physical conditions necessary to reach ignition.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 025204] Published Mon Feb 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. L. Kritcher &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nucleon axial and pseudoscalar form factors using twisted-mass fermion ensembles at the physical point]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.034503</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.034503"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Constantia Alexandrou, Simone Bacchio, Martha Constantinou, Jacob Finkenrath, Roberto Frezzotti, Bartosz Kostrzewa, Giannis Koutsou, Gregoris Spanoudes, and Carsten Urbach (Extended Twisted Mass Collaboration)
The authors compute the axial and pseudoscalar nucleon form factors for 2+1+1 flavors, light, strange, and charm, with physical quark masses in lattice QCD with a controlled continuum extrapolation. The results are compared with other lattice determinations, finding good agreement, and with experimental extractions, showing some tensions.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 034503] Published Mon Feb 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Constantia Alexandrou, Simone Bacchio, Martha Constantinou, Jacob Finkenrath, Roberto Frezzotti, Bartosz Kostrzewa, Giannis Koutsou, Gregoris Spanoudes, and Carsten Urbach (Extended Twisted Mass Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[$M1$ neutrino transport within the numerical-relativistic code BAM with application to low mass binary neutron star mergers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.044012</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.044012"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Federico Schianchi, Henrique Gieg, Vsevolod Nedora, Anna Neuweiler, Maximiliano Ujevic, Mattia Bulla, and Tim Dietrich
A crucial ingredient in accurate simulations of neutron star-neutron star and neutron star-black hole mergers is the inclusion of neutrino transport and its effects on the physics and astrophysics of these phenomena. The authors implement a neutrino radiative transport scheme in their general relativistic hydrodynamics code, BAM, do more accurately simulate these mergers and map the effects of neutrino transport on the ejecta from neutron star-neutron star mergers.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 044012] Published Mon Feb 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Federico Schianchi, Henrique Gieg, Vsevolod Nedora, Anna Neuweiler, Maximiliano Ujevic, Mattia Bulla, and Tim Dietrich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Einstein–de Haas torque as a discrete spectroscopic probe allows nanomechanical measurement of a magnetic resonance]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.064404</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.064404"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): K. R. Fast, J. E. Losby, G. Hajisalem, P. E. Barclay, and M. R. Freeman
The Einstein-de Haas (EdH) effect is a consequence of angular momentum conservation wherein a physical rotation of a magnetic body results from a change in magnetization. A micromechanical resonator supporting a ladder of resonances is used to explore the inherent frequency dependence of torque resulting from this rotation in a thin-film permalloy sample, utilizing cavity optomechanical readout. Giant EdH torques are found at a gyrotropic magnetic resonance in the permalloy, which overlaps a high-order mechanical resonance of the sensor.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 064404] Published Mon Feb 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>K. R. Fast, J. E. Losby, G. Hajisalem, P. E. Barclay, and M. R. Freeman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entropy and de Haas–van Alphen oscillations of a three-dimensional marginal Fermi liquid]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.075107</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.075107"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): P. A. Nosov, Yi-Ming Wu, and S. Raghu
The free energy of metals in a magnetic field exhibits oscillations, influencing thermodynamics and transport. Typically, these oscillations are interpreted using the Lifshitz-Kosevich theory, which assumes nearly free electrons. Here, the authors study quantum oscillations in three-dimensional metals near quantum phase transitions, where electrons are strongly-coupled. Naive extensions of the Lifshitz-Kosevich formula to this state result in a finite zero-temperature entropy, contradicting the laws of thermodynamics. They authors propose a new thermodynamically consistent theory of magneto-oscillations, yielding a distinct temperature dependence of the oscillation amplitudes.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 075107] Published Mon Feb 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>P. A. Nosov, Yi-Ming Wu, and S. Raghu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Landau quantization near generalized Van Hove singularities: Magnetic breakdown and orbit networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L081103</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L081103"/>
        <updated>2024-02-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): V. A. Zakharov, A. Mert Bozkurt, A. R. Akhmerov, and D. O. Oriekhov
Several of the recently discovered 2D layered quantum materials host higher-order Van Hove singularities near the charge neutrality point. The authors develop here a universal description for magnetic breakdown near different types of higher-order Van Hove singularities. The observation of such a magnetic breakdown via measurement of quantum oscillations or longitudinal bulk conductance in a quantum Hall bar allows for reconstruction of a Fermi surface and classification of the corresponding saddle point in dispersion.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, L081103] Published Mon Feb 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>V. A. Zakharov, A. Mert Bozkurt, A. R. Akhmerov, and D. O. Oriekhov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information content of note transitions in the music of J. S. Bach]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.6.013136</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.6.013136"/>
        <updated>2024-02-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Suman Kulkarni, Sophia U. David, Christopher W. Lynn, and Dani S. Bassett
A study combines methods from network science, information theory, and cognitive science to examine the information present in note transitions within music composed by J. S. Bach. It identifies and explains differences in information content across various compositional forms based on their network structure.

[Phys. Rev. Research 6, 013136] Published Fri Feb 02, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Suman Kulkarni, Sophia U. David, Christopher W. Lynn, and Dani S. Bassett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How a Soft Rod Wraps around a Rotating Cylinder]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.058204</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.058204"/>
        <updated>2024-02-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marie Tani and Hirofumi Wada
As a string winds around a cylinder, a switch occurs from tight winding to looser winding, a behavior that could be relevant for natural phenomena.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 058204] Published Fri Feb 02, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marie Tani and Hirofumi Wada</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Terahertz field driven giant nonlinear phonon response in ferroelectric semiconductor In-doped (Sn,Pb)Te]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L081102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L081102"/>
        <updated>2024-02-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): H. Handa, Y. Okamura, R. Yoshimi, A. Tsukazaki, K. S. Takahashi, Y. Tokura, and Y. Takahashi
Recent advances in high-field terahertz technologies can unveil the nonlinear response of elementary excitations. This work finds large-amplitude coherent phonon dynamics in the fully anharmonic regime by intense terahertz excitation of the ferroelectric semiconductor In-doped (Sn,Pb)Te. The high-field resonant drive of soft phonons induces the dramatic shift of transient phonon frequency near the ferroelectric transition point. This highly nonlinear terahertz response quantitatively reveals a phonon potential dominated by strong anharmonicity and temporal lattice dynamics with giant atomic displacement.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, L081102] Published Fri Feb 02, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>H. Handa, Y. Okamura, R. Yoshimi, A. Tsukazaki, K. S. Takahashi, Y. Tokura, and Y. Takahashi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emergent Collective Motion of Self-Propelled Condensate Droplets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.058203</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.058203"/>
        <updated>2024-02-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marcus Lin, Philseok Kim, Sankara Arunachalam, Rifan Hardian, Solomon Adera, Joanna Aizenberg, Xi Yao, and Dan Daniel
Water droplets can exhibit complex collective motions when they condense on a thin oil film.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 058203] Published Thu Feb 01, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marcus Lin, Philseok Kim, Sankara Arunachalam, Rifan Hardian, Solomon Adera, Joanna Aizenberg, Xi Yao, and Dan Daniel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Water-Wave Vortices and Skyrmions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.054003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.054003"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Daria A. Smirnova, Franco Nori, and Konstantin Y. Bliokh
Interference in plane-wave combinations of water waves is predicted to give rise to structures that are usually found in optical, elastic, and quantum systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 054003] Published Wed Jan 31, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daria A. Smirnova, Franco Nori, and Konstantin Y. Bliokh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theory of Defect-Induced Crystal Field Perturbations in Rare-Earth Magnets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.056703</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.056703"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christopher E. Patrick, Yixuan Huang, Laura H. Lewis, and Julie B. Staunton
A first-principles method which quantifies the effect of defects on macroscopic properties describes accurately the magnetic anisotropy energy of rare-earth systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 056703] Published Wed Jan 31, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher E. Patrick, Yixuan Huang, Laura H. Lewis, and Julie B. Staunton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strongly Coupled Spin Waves and Surface Acoustic Waves at Room Temperature]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.056704</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.056704"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yunyoung Hwang, Jorge Puebla, Kouta Kondou, Carlos Gonzalez-Ballestero, Hironari Isshiki, Carlos Sánchez Muñoz, Liyang Liao, Fa Chen, Wei Luo, Sadamichi Maekawa, and Yoshichika Otani
Strong coupling between magnons and phonons has been demonstrated using an on-chip surface acoustic wave resonator device containing a thin rectangular film of CoFeB.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 056704] Published Wed Jan 31, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yunyoung Hwang, Jorge Puebla, Kouta Kondou, Carlos Gonzalez-Ballestero, Hironari Isshiki, Carlos Sánchez Muñoz, Liyang Liao, Fa Chen, Wei Luo, Sadamichi Maekawa, and Yoshichika Otani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Autothermotaxis of volatile drops]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.L012001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.L012001"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pallav Kant, Mathieu Souzy, Nayoung Kim, Devaraj van der Meer, and Detlef Lohse
We present an extraordinary phenomenon that emerges from seemingly simple ingredients: a volatile droplet deposited on a highly wetting and heat-conducting warm substrate. Contrary to prevailing intuition that the deposited droplet would spread more and evaporate faster, we find that the droplet instead undergoes contraction and in addition it spontaneously and erratically moves, for substrate temperatures well below the boiling point of the liquid. We term this remarkable phenomenon “Autothermotaxis” and show that it originates from the thermal Marangoni flow in the droplet which undergoes an instability. The thermal Marangoni flow is also the reason for the contraction of the droplet.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, L012001] Published Wed Jan 31, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pallav Kant, Mathieu Souzy, Nayoung Kim, Devaraj van der Meer, and Detlef Lohse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Supernovalike explosions of massive rotating stars from disks surrounding a black hole]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.023031</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.023031"/>
        <updated>2024-01-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sho Fujibayashi, Alan Tsz-Lok Lam, Masaru Shibata, and Yuichiro Sekiguchi
Black-hole forming collapse of massive stars are studied using general relativistic viscous radiation hydrodynamics with axial symmetry. The authors uncover a rich set of phenomena: a supernova-like explosion mechanism driven by viscous and shock heating resulting in the expulsion of a significant fraction of the energy, rapidly spinning black hole formation, and the generation of highly energetic jets and associated gamma-ray bursts.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 023031] Published Wed Jan 31, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sho Fujibayashi, Alan Tsz-Lok Lam, Masaru Shibata, and Yuichiro Sekiguchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Structure and lattice excitations of the copper substituted lead oxyapatite ${\mathrm{Pb}}_{9.06(7)}{\mathrm{Cu}}_{0.94(6)}{({\mathrm{PO}}_{3.92(4)})}_{6}{\mathrm{O}}_{0.96(3)}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.014605</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.014605"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Qiang Zhang, Yingdong Guan, Yongqiang Cheng, Lujin Min, Jong K. Keum, Zhiqiang Mao, and Matthew B. Stone
There was significant discussion regarding the potential for room-temperature superconductivity in the copper-substituted lead apatite which has come to be known as LK-99. Neutron diffraction and spectroscopy were employed to examine this compound. We did not observe a superconducting resonance, nor did we observe any predicted Cu-induced structural distortion between 5 and 300 K. No magnetic long-range order or magnetic excitations were detected in this temperature range. We have determined a favored substitution site of copper at the Pb1 site. This may provide crucial insights into the absence of structural distortion and superconductivity in LK-99.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 014605] Published Tue Jan 30, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qiang Zhang, Yingdong Guan, Yongqiang Cheng, Lujin Min, Jong K. Keum, Zhiqiang Mao, and Matthew B. Stone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two-Pole Nature of the $\mathrm{Λ}(1405)$ Resonance from Lattice QCD]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.051901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.051901"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): John Bulava, Bárbara Cid-Mora, Andrew D. Hanlon, Ben Hörz, Daniel Mohler, Colin Morningstar, Joseph Moscoso, Amy Nicholson, Fernando Romero-López, Sarah Skinner, and André Walker-Loud (Baryon Scattering (BaSc) Collaboration)
The first lattice QCD computation of πΣ−K¯N scattering amplitudes supports the two-pole nature of the puzzling Λ(1405) resonance.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 051901] Published Tue Jan 30, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Bulava, Bárbara Cid-Mora, Andrew D. Hanlon, Ben Hörz, Daniel Mohler, Colin Morningstar, Joseph Moscoso, Amy Nicholson, Fernando Romero-López, Sarah Skinner, and André Walker-Loud (Baryon Scattering (BaSc) Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental Characterization of Defect-Induced Phonon Lifetime Shortening]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.056202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.056202"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Boyao Liu, Jack Kelsall, David J. Ward, and Andrew P. Jardine
The scattering of helium atoms off a crystal surface reveals how defects in the crystal’s lattice influence its ability to transport heat.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 056202] Published Tue Jan 30, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Boyao Liu, Jack Kelsall, David J. Ward, and Andrew P. Jardine</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lattice QCD study of $π\mathrm{Σ}−\overline{K}N$ scattering and the $\mathrm{Λ}(1405)$ resonance]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.014511</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.014511"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): John Bulava, Bárbara Cid-Mora, Andrew D. Hanlon, Ben Hörz, Daniel Mohler, Colin Morningstar, Joseph Moscoso, Amy Nicholson, Fernando Romero-López, Sarah Skinner, and André Walker-Loud (Baryon Scattering (BaSc) Collaboration)
The first lattice QCD computation of πΣ-K̅ N scattering amplitudes supports the two-pole nature of the puzzling Λ(1405) resonance.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 014511] Published Tue Jan 30, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Bulava, Bárbara Cid-Mora, Andrew D. Hanlon, Ben Hörz, Daniel Mohler, Colin Morningstar, Joseph Moscoso, Amy Nicholson, Fernando Romero-López, Sarah Skinner, and André Walker-Loud (Baryon Scattering (BaSc) Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variational density functional perturbation theory for metals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014317</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014317"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xavier Gonze, Samare Rostami, and Christian Tantardini
Density Functional Perturbation Theory (DFPT) is a proven method for analyzing molecular and solid responses to perturbations. For metals, challenges arise due to Fermi-Dirac statistics and electronic bands crossing the Fermi energy. This work focuses on variational DFPT for metals, examining the convexity of the entropy function of occupation numbers. It emphasizes benefits from resmearing Fermi-Dirac broadening at finite temperature, details variational expressions for free energy derivatives, and addresses inaccuracies in unperturbed wavefunctions. The formalism is implemented in the ABINIT software.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 014317] Published Tue Jan 30, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xavier Gonze, Samare Rostami, and Christian Tantardini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breakdown of chiral edge modes in topological magnon insulators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024441</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024441"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jonas Habel, Alexander Mook, Josef Willsher, and Johannes Knolle
Topological magnon edge modes have been proposed for the realization of robust, low-loss spintronic devices. However, ubiquitous many-body interactions that do not preserve particle number significantly compromise their topological protection. The authors show here that these interactions can lead to significant edge mode damping, hybridization with bulk modes, and coupling between edge modes on opposite sides. These findings pose challenges for the experimental realization of topological magnon edge modes, but can be overcome by the application of large magnetic fields.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 024441] Published Tue Jan 30, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonas Habel, Alexander Mook, Josef Willsher, and Johannes Knolle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic structure, magnetic correlations, and superconducting pairing in the reduced Ruddlesden-Popper bilayer ${\mathrm{La}}_{3}{\mathrm{Ni}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{6}$ under pressure: Different role of ${d}_{3{z}^{2}−{r}^{2}}$ orbital compared with ${\mathrm{La}}_{3}{\mathrm{Ni}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{7}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.045151</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.045151"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yang Zhang, Ling-Fang Lin, Adriana Moreo, Thomas A. Maier, and Elbio Dagotto
The authors investigate here two bilayer nickelates under pressure, establishing substantial qualitative differences between the two systems. They find that the d3z2−r2 orbital in La3Ni2O6 and La3Ni2O7 plays a different role: one “active” orbital (dx2−y2) vs two “active” orbitals (eg), respectively. The Fermi surface only has two sheets in La3Ni2O6, with the γ pocket absent, different from La3Ni2O7. They also find that La3Ni2O6 is far from a superconducting instability. Moreover, they do not observe changes in the electronic density in La3Ni2O6 under pressure.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 045151] Published Tue Jan 30, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yang Zhang, Ling-Fang Lin, Adriana Moreo, Thomas A. Maier, and Elbio Dagotto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emergence of composite many-body exciton states in ${\mathrm{WS}}_{2}$ and ${\mathrm{MoSe}}_{2}$ monolayers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L041304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L041304"/>
        <updated>2024-01-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Choi, J. Li, D. Van Tuan, H. Dery, and S. A. Crooker
When electron-hole pairs (excitons) are photoexcited into semiconductors containing a Fermi sea of mobile charges, they can form bound states known variously as trions, tetrons, or exciton-polarons. Crucially, the interaction occurs with those mobile carriers possessing distinguishable quantum numbers (e.g., spin). In monolayer TMD semiconductors, the availability of both spin and valley quantum numbers allows excitons to interact, simultaneously, with more than one type of quantum-mechanically distinguishable carrier. This leads to new types of composite excitons (e.g., six-particle “hexcitons”), which appear as distinct resonances in optical spectra.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, L041304] Published Tue Jan 30, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Choi, J. Li, D. Van Tuan, H. Dery, and S. A. Crooker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crystal Thermal Transport in Altermagnetic ${\mathrm{RuO}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.056701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.056701"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xiaodong Zhou, Wanxiang Feng, Run-Wu Zhang, Libor Šmejkal, Jairo Sinova, Yuriy Mokrousov, and Yugui Yao
A first-principles calculation reveals a novel class of anomalous thermal transport effects in the altermagnet RuO2.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 056701] Published Mon Jan 29, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiaodong Zhou, Wanxiang Feng, Run-Wu Zhang, Libor Šmejkal, Jairo Sinova, Yuriy Mokrousov, and Yugui Yao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Integrability of a Globally Coupled Complex Riccati Array: Quadratic Integrate-and-Fire Neurons, Phase Oscillators, and All in Between]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.057201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.057201"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rok Cestnik and Erik A. Martens
A new approach to solving arrays of two-dimensional differential equations may allow researchers to go beyond the one-dimensional oscillator paradigm.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 057201] Published Mon Jan 29, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rok Cestnik and Erik A. Martens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effects of mirror birefringence and its fluctuations to laser interferometric gravitational wave detectors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.022009</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.022009"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuta Michimura, Haoyu Wang, Francisco Salces-Carcoba, Christopher Wipf, Aidan Brooks, Koji Arai, and Rana X. Adhikari
Crystalline materials in gravitational wave detectors as substrates and mirror coatings could provide many advantages. The authors carry out a theoretical study to quantify how birefringence and its fluctuations can limit the sensitivity of GW detectors and show ways to mitigate these effects through the orientation of the beam polarization and the crystalline material.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 022009] Published Mon Jan 29, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuta Michimura, Haoyu Wang, Francisco Salces-Carcoba, Christopher Wipf, Aidan Brooks, Koji Arai, and Rana X. Adhikari</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-induced inverse spin Hall effect in ${\mathrm{La}}_{0.67}{\mathrm{Sr}}_{0.33}{\mathrm{MnO}}_{3}$ films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014437</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014437"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pushpendra Gupta, In Jun Park, Anupama Swain, Abhisek Mishra, Vivek P. Amin, and Subhankar Bedanta
The authors report here the self-induced inverse spin Hall effect in epitaxial La0.67Sr0.33MnO3 (LSMO) films and perform first-principles calculations of the spin Hall conductivities of bulk LSMO. The LSMO films were prepared using pulsed laser deposition. The spin pumping voltage Vsp dominates over spin rectification effects, indicating the presence of appreciable spin-to-charge conversion in LSMO films. The spin Hall conductivity is calculated from first principles using density functional theory and the Kubo formalism, and the results qualitatively match with the experimental findings.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 014437] Published Mon Jan 29, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pushpendra Gupta, In Jun Park, Anupama Swain, Abhisek Mishra, Vivek P. Amin, and Subhankar Bedanta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three-dimensional imaging of integrated-circuit activity using quantum defects in diamond]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014055</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014055"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marwa Garsi, Rainer Stöhr, Andrej Denisenko, Farida Shagieva, Nils Trautmann, Ulrich Vogl, Badou Sene, Florian Kaiser, Andrea Zappe, Rolf Reuter, and Jörg Wrachtrup
Three-dimensional semiconductor chip architectures promise high-density memory and much faster computation, but self-heating and leakage currents still severely limit performance. While current-density mapping is crucial to studying these issues in situ, nondestructive imaging has been limited to two dimensions. The authors use ensembles of nitrogen-vacancy centers in diamond as nanoscale quantum sensors to probe all three vectorial components of magnetic fields associated with electric currents, for noninvasive imaging of three-dimensional currents in multilayer integrated circuits. Further improvements could reveal the local conductance of materials, to advance condensed matter physics.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 014055] Published Mon Jan 29, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marwa Garsi, Rainer Stöhr, Andrej Denisenko, Farida Shagieva, Nils Trautmann, Ulrich Vogl, Badou Sene, Florian Kaiser, Andrea Zappe, Rolf Reuter, and Jörg Wrachtrup</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Field test of continuous-variable quantum key distribution with a true local oscillator]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014056</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014056"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Brian P. Williams, Bing Qi, Muneer Alshowkan, Philip G. Evans, and Nicholas A. Peters
In quantum secure communication, continuous-variable quantum key distribution (CV-QKD) using a true local oscillator (LO) located at the receiver has been proposed to remove side-channel-attack vulnerabilities and reduce excess noise, but implementations have been confined to the lab. The authors demonstrate CV-QKD with a receiver-based true LO over a deployed fiber network, with coexistent classical communications. This represents a substantial technical and engineering advance over prior tabletop demonstrations.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 014056] Published Mon Jan 29, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian P. Williams, Bing Qi, Muneer Alshowkan, Philip G. Evans, and Nicholas A. Peters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analytical analysis for additional ionization peaks of He induced by chirped xuv pulses]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.013113</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.013113"/>
        <updated>2024-01-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yong-Kang Fang, Lei Geng, and Liang-You Peng
The authors study two-photon double ionization induced by chirped pulses, which shows additional features in the photoelectron energy spectrum compared to the case without chirp. They develop an analytical model that is able to shed light on the origin of these peaks, discovered in earlier theoretical work but unexplained until now.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 013113] Published Mon Jan 29, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yong-Kang Fang, Lei Geng, and Liang-You Peng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anisotropic anomalous transport in the kagome-based topological antiferromagnetic ${\mathrm{Mn}}_{3}\text{Ga}$ epitaxial thin films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.014204</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.014204"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Raju, Ralph Romero, III, Daisuke Nishio-Hamane, Ryota Uesugi, Mihiro Asakura, Zhenisbek Tagay, Tomoya Higo, N. P. Armitage, Collin Broholm, and Satoru Nakatsuji
Weyl semimetals based on Mn3X (X=Sn, Ge, Ga) are promising materials for antiferromagnetic (AFM) spintronics. Kagome spin structure formed by the Mn moments coupled to nontrivial band topology produces giant topological effects in these materials. Mn3Ga with the largest Néel temperature among this class of materials, is potentially useful for high-speed device applications. In this work, authors develop AFM epitaxial Mn3Ga films with controlled crystal orientation, accessing different orientation of Kagome planes formed by Mn moments. Detailed investigations through structural, magnetization, magnetoresistance, DC and terahertz electrical transport reveal the anisotropic transport signatures emerging from the nontrivial band topology.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 014204] Published Fri Jan 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Raju, Ralph Romero, III, Daisuke Nishio-Hamane, Ryota Uesugi, Mihiro Asakura, Zhenisbek Tagay, Tomoya Higo, N. P. Armitage, Collin Broholm, and Satoru Nakatsuji</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Centrifugal Flows Drive Reverse Rotation of Feynman’s Sprinkler]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.044003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.044003"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kaizhe Wang, Brennan Sprinkle, Mingxuan Zuo, and Leif Ristroph
Which direction would an S-shaped lawn sprinkler rotate if it were submerged and the flow were reversed? Experiments now provide a definitive answer.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 044003] Published Fri Jan 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kaizhe Wang, Brennan Sprinkle, Mingxuan Zuo, and Leif Ristroph</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Energy Gap of the Even-Denominator Fractional Quantum Hall State in Bilayer Graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.046603</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.046603"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexandre Assouline, Taige Wang, Haoxin Zhou, Liam A. Cohen, Fangyuan Yang, Ruining Zhang, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Roger S. K. Mong, Michael P. Zaletel, and Andrea F. Young
A large energy gap is seen for the even-denominator fractional state in bilayer graphene, making it a promising platform for studying non-Abelian anyons.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 046603] Published Fri Jan 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandre Assouline, Taige Wang, Haoxin Zhou, Liam A. Cohen, Fangyuan Yang, Ruining Zhang, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Roger S. K. Mong, Michael P. Zaletel, and Andrea F. Young</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quasicrystal of Binary Hard Spheres on a Plane Stabilized by Configurational Entropy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.048202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.048202"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Etienne Fayen, Laura Filion, Giuseppe Foffi, and Frank Smallenburg
Free-energy calculations demonstrate that configurational entropy stabilizes a dodecagonal quasicrystal in a binary mixture of hard spheres on a plane.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 048202] Published Fri Jan 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Etienne Fayen, Laura Filion, Giuseppe Foffi, and Frank Smallenburg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multiscale Richtmyer-Meshkov instability experiments to isolate the strain rate dependence of strength]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.015002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.015002"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Michael B. Prime, Saryu J. Fensin, David R. Jones, Joshua W. Dyer, and Daniel T. Martinez
This work describes Richtmyer-Meshkov experiments to measure the strain-rate sensitivity of copper in the high-rate regime. The authors extend the maximum strain rate by more than two orders of magnitude. At higher strain rates, their strength estimates show a steep increase that agrees well with extrapolations from some of the data in the literature. The work contributes to the important effort to understand how impacts can affect the strength of solids.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 015002] Published Fri Jan 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael B. Prime, Saryu J. Fensin, David R. Jones, Joshua W. Dyer, and Daniel T. Martinez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electrically sign-reversible topological Hall effect in a top-gated topological insulator ${(\mathrm{Bi},\mathrm{Sb})}_{2}{\mathrm{Te}}_{3}$ grown on europium iron garnet]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024432</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024432"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J.-F. Wong, K.-H. M. Chen, J.-M. Chia, Z.-P. Huang, S.-X. Wang, P.-T. Chen, L. B. Young, Y.-H. G. Lin, S.-F. Lee, C.-Y. Mou, M. Hong, and J. Kwo
The topological Hall effect (THE) is a Hall response that arises from the deflection of motion of charge carriers flowing through nontrivial spin textures. Here, the authors observe a significant THE and investigate its interplay with the spin-polarized topological surface states in a proximity-magnetized topological insulator/ferrimagnet heterostructure. Specifically, they demonstrate a sign change in THE via a top electrical gate as the Fermi level is tuned from the electron-doped to the hole-doped region of the gapped Dirac cone.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 024432] Published Fri Jan 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J.-F. Wong, K.-H. M. Chen, J.-M. Chia, Z.-P. Huang, S.-X. Wang, P.-T. Chen, L. B. Young, Y.-H. G. Lin, S.-F. Lee, C.-Y. Mou, M. Hong, and J. Kwo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Employing quasidegenerate optical modes for chiral sensing]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L041410</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L041410"/>
        <updated>2024-01-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. F. Almousa, T. Weiss, and E. A. Muljarov
The authors demonstrate here a linear splitting of quasidegenerate modes in the presence of chirality in optical systems. Employing the resonant-state expansion and two quasidegenerate modes, they reveal the transformation of the chirality effect on mode splitting from second to first order in the Pasteur parameter (ϰ). This linear effect is demonstrated for individual chiral particles and homogeneous chiral perturbations of metasurfaces. These findings deepen our understanding of chirality-induced mode splitting, opening prospects for innovative sensing schemes.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, L041410] Published Fri Jan 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. F. Almousa, T. Weiss, and E. A. Muljarov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tailoring Magnetism of Graphene Nanoflakes via Tip-Controlled Dehydrogenation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.046201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.046201"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chenxiao Zhao, Qiang Huang, Leoš Valenta, Kristjan Eimre, Lin Yang, Aliaksandr V. Yakutovich, Wangwei Xu, Ji Ma, Xinliang Feng, Michal Juríček, Roman Fasel, Pascal Ruffieux, and Carlo A. Pignedoli
Highly precise atomic scale manipulations correlated with theoretical calculations suggest changes in the spin states of a graphene island on Au(111) depending on which site was hydrogenated.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 046201] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chenxiao Zhao, Qiang Huang, Leoš Valenta, Kristjan Eimre, Lin Yang, Aliaksandr V. Yakutovich, Wangwei Xu, Ji Ma, Xinliang Feng, Michal Juríček, Roman Fasel, Pascal Ruffieux, and Carlo A. Pignedoli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin Polarons and Ferromagnetism in Doped Dilute Moiré-Mott Insulators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.046501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.046501"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Urban F. P. Seifert and Leon Balents
A small density of doped electrons couples to local moments in a moire-Mott insulator, constituting a novel mechanism for magnetic ordering in moire transition-metal dichalcogenides.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 046501] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Urban F. P. Seifert and Leon Balents</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bidirectional Multiphoton Communication between Remote Superconducting Nodes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.047001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.047001"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Joel Grebel, Haoxiong Yan, Ming-Han Chou, Gustav Andersson, Christopher R. Conner, Yash J. Joshi, Jacob M. Miller, Rhys G. Povey, Hong Qiao, Xuntao Wu, and Andrew N. Cleland
A device with qubits coupled to microwave resonators achieves transfer and entanglement of complex quantum states between superconducting nodes.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 047001] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joel Grebel, Haoxiong Yan, Ming-Han Chou, Gustav Andersson, Christopher R. Conner, Yash J. Joshi, Jacob M. Miller, Rhys G. Povey, Hong Qiao, Xuntao Wu, and Andrew N. Cleland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnon interactions in the quantum paramagnetic phase of ${\mathrm{CoNb}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{6}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014424</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014424"/>
        <updated>2024-01-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. A. Gallegos and A. L. Chernyshev
The strongly anisotropic quasi-one-dimensional ferromagnet CoNb2O6 in a transverse field has provided a spectacular realization of the magnon decay effect in its paramagnetic phase. A self-consistent theory is proposed to regularize unphysical divergences while preserving the integrity of the singular threshold phenomena of magnon decay, demonstrating quantitative agreement with the neutron scattering results throughout the field regime inaccessible by standard spin-wave theory. Phenomenological constraints on the model, connections of CoNb2O6 to the other anisotropic-exchange materials, and the effects of longitudinal fields are explored.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 014424] Published Thu Jan 25, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. A. Gallegos and A. L. Chernyshev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>