<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2024-01-21T00:53:09.296Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2024-01-21T00:53:09.296Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inertia Induces Strong Orientation Fluctuations of Nonspherical Atmospheric Particles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.034101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.034101"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Bhowmick, J. Seesing, K. Gustavsson, J. Guettler, Y. Wang, A. Pumir, B. Mehlig, and G. Bagheri
Experiments with small falling particles show that their orientations oscillate—which may help explain the settling of volcanic ash and the formation of snow.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 034101] Published Fri Jan 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Bhowmick, J. Seesing, K. Gustavsson, J. Guettler, Y. Wang, A. Pumir, B. Mehlig, and G. Bagheri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Characterization and Control of the Run-and-Tumble Dynamics of <i>Escherichia Coli</i>]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.038302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.038302"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christina Kurzthaler, Yongfeng Zhao, Nan Zhou, Jana Schwarz-Linek, Clemence Devailly, Jochen Arlt, Jian-Dong Huang, Wilson C. K. Poon, Thomas Franosch, Julien Tailleur, and Vincent A. Martinez
A new technique could allow researchers to distinguish the swimming motion of a species of microorganisms without the need to track individuals within a population.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 038302] Published Fri Jan 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christina Kurzthaler, Yongfeng Zhao, Nan Zhou, Jana Schwarz-Linek, Clemence Devailly, Jochen Arlt, Jian-Dong Huang, Wilson C. K. Poon, Thomas Franosch, Julien Tailleur, and Vincent A. Martinez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantitative characterization of run-and-tumble statistics in bulk bacterial suspensions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014612</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014612"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yongfeng Zhao, Christina Kurzthaler, Nan Zhou, Jana Schwarz-Linek, Clemence Devailly, Jochen Arlt, Jian-Dong Huang, Wilson C. K. Poon, Thomas Franosch, Vincent A. Martinez, and Julien Tailleur
A new technique could allow researchers to distinguish the swimming motion of a species of microorganisms without the need to track individuals within a population.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 014612] Published Fri Jan 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yongfeng Zhao, Christina Kurzthaler, Nan Zhou, Jana Schwarz-Linek, Clemence Devailly, Jochen Arlt, Jian-Dong Huang, Wilson C. K. Poon, Thomas Franosch, Vincent A. Martinez, and Julien Tailleur</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bounds on the equation of state from QCD inequalities and lattice QCD]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.014020</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.014020"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuki Fujimoto and Sanjay Reddy
The equation of state for nuclear matter is essential to understanding neutron stars. Using strict QCD inequalities and input from numerical simulations on the lattice, the authors derive useful bounds on the baryon and energy densities, which are relevant to isospin symmetric matter at densities probed by heavy ion collisions.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 014020] Published Fri Jan 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuki Fujimoto and Sanjay Reddy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetic antiskyrmions in two-dimensional van der Waals magnets engineered by layer stacking]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024426</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024426"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kai Huang, Edward Schwartz, Ding-Fu Shao, Alexey A. Kovalev, and Evgeny Y. Tsymbal
Antiskyrmions, like skyrmions, are topologically protected magnetic quasiparticles, but exhibit greater stability and no transverse motion compared to skyrmions. This study employs ab initio calculations to investigate the polar layer stacking of two monolayers of a two-dimensional magnetic material CrI3, which can lead to the emergence of antiskyrmions. Atomistic spin dynamics simulations demonstrate the realization of antiskyrmions in Mn-doped CrI3 and shows that their spin texture can be switched by ferroelectric polarization of the polar bilayer.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 024426] Published Fri Jan 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kai Huang, Edward Schwartz, Ding-Fu Shao, Alexey A. Kovalev, and Evgeny Y. Tsymbal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hubbard parameters for programmable tweezer arrays]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.013318</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.013318"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hao-Tian Wei, Eduardo Ibarra-García-Padilla, Michael L. Wall, and Kaden R. A. Hazzard
The authors develop a method to compute the Hubbard-model parameters for tunnel-coupled tweezer arrays given the trap parameters. The method also solves the inverse problem of finding trap configurations given desired Hubbard parameters, providing tools for using tunnel-coupled tweezer arrays.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 013318] Published Fri Jan 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hao-Tian Wei, Eduardo Ibarra-García-Padilla, Michael L. Wall, and Kaden R. A. Hazzard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental realization of Lorentz boosts of space-time wave packets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.013509</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.013509"/>
        <updated>2024-01-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Murat Yessenov, Miguel Romer, Naoki Ichiji, and Ayman F. Abouraddy
The authors present an experimental procedure that is analogous to Lorentz boosts of space-time wave packets (STWPs), in that the physical transformation is identical to the mathematical impact of a Lorentz transformation except for an overall Doppler shift to the carrier. Their work indicates that a Lorentz boost of a STWP results in another STWP.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 013509] Published Fri Jan 19, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Murat Yessenov, Miguel Romer, Naoki Ichiji, and Ayman F. Abouraddy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Broken Kramers Degeneracy in Altermagnetic MnTe]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.036702</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.036702"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Suyoung Lee, Sangjae Lee, Saegyeol Jung, Jiwon Jung, Donghan Kim, Yeonjae Lee, Byeongjun Seok, Jaeyoung Kim, Byeong Gyu Park, Libor Šmejkal, Chang-Jong Kang, and Changyoung Kim
Spectroscopic data suggest that thin films of a certain semiconducting material can exhibit altermagnetism, a new and fundamental form of magnetism.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 036702] Published Thu Jan 18, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Suyoung Lee, Sangjae Lee, Saegyeol Jung, Jiwon Jung, Donghan Kim, Yeonjae Lee, Byeongjun Seok, Jaeyoung Kim, Byeong Gyu Park, Libor Šmejkal, Chang-Jong Kang, and Changyoung Kim</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emergence of Competing Orders and Possible Quantum Spin Liquid in $\mathrm{SU}(N)$ Fermions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.036704</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.036704"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xue-Jia Yu, Shao-Hang Shi, Limei Xu, and Zi-Xiang Li
A realistic SU(N) interacting fermionic model reveals exotic quantum magnetic phases that occur at intermediate N, where the competition between distinct ordering tendencies gives rise to an intermediate quantum spin liquid phase featuring nontrivial topological order.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 036704] Published Thu Jan 18, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xue-Jia Yu, Shao-Hang Shi, Limei Xu, and Zi-Xiang Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Percolation and Topological Properties of Temporal Higher-Order Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.037401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.037401"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Leonardo Di Gaetano, Federico Battiston, and Michele Starnini
A hidden-variable formalism allows for the characterization of topological properties of temporal networks with higher-order interactions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 037401] Published Thu Jan 18, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leonardo Di Gaetano, Federico Battiston, and Michele Starnini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conformations, correlations, and instabilities of a flexible fiber in an active fluid]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.013102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.013102"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Scott Weady, David B. Stein, Alexandra Zidovska, and Michael J. Shelley
Many biological systems rely on interactions between active processes and passive, deformable structures to properly function. An important example is chromatin in the cell nucleus, where ATP-powered processes, such as transcription or DNA repair, act on the chromatin fiber and influence its motion. Motivated by this system, in this study we develop and analyze a model of a flexible fiber in an active suspension as an analog to a chromatin fiber in an active environment - the nucleoplasm. Interactions between the suspension and the fiber lead to a novel bend instability, and nonlinear simulations identify coherent motions and conformations of the fiber over long timescales.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 013102] Published Thu Jan 18, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Scott Weady, David B. Stein, Alexandra Zidovska, and Michael J. Shelley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing the photon emissivity of the quark-gluon plasma without an inverse problem in lattice QCD]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.014507</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.014507"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marco Cè, Tim Harris, Ardit Krasniqi, Harvey B. Meyer, and Csaba Török
One of the most important applications of lattice gauge theory is the computation of transport coefficients at nonzero temperature. The authors compute moments of the photon emissivity with respect to the imaginary frequency, and find promising results.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 014507] Published Thu Jan 18, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marco Cè, Tim Harris, Ardit Krasniqi, Harvey B. Meyer, and Csaba Török</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recombination of ${B}_{c}$ mesons in ultrarelativistic heavy-ion collisions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.014906</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.014906"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Biaogang Wu, Zhanduo Tang, Min He, and Ralf Rapp
The large production of the heavy charm and bottom quarks in heavy-ion collisions over that in pp collisions provides key signatures of the formation of the hot and strongly interacting phase known as the quark-gluon plasma. This paper reports on calculations of yields of Bc+ mesons, consisting of a bottom and a charm quark, in Pb + Pb collisions at 5.02 TeV/nucleon at the LHC. The authors compare the results of their transport model with recent CMS data and attribute the observed enhancement to recombination processes of heavy quarks with large phase-space densities in a quark-gluon plasma.

[Phys. Rev. C 109, 014906] Published Thu Jan 18, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Biaogang Wu, Zhanduo Tang, Min He, and Ralf Rapp</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optically trapped microspheres are high-bandwidth acoustic transducers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014031</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014031"/>
        <updated>2024-01-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): L.E. Hillberry and M.G. Raizen
This work studies optically trapped microspheres as flow sensors for the purpose of acoustic transduction in air. While traditional microphones are sensitive to pressure variations and have a peak bandwidth of about 200 kHz, the optically trapped microsphere is sensitive to velocity variations and resolves waveforms with frequency content in the megahertz range. Variations of this method could find applications in near-field acoustic metrology for vibrations, surface waves, and small-scale blast waves; in medicine for ultrasonic imaging in proton cancer therapy; and in bubble-chamber searches for dark matter.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 014031] Published Thu Jan 18, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L.E. Hillberry and M.G. Raizen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Trapping of Slow Electrons in the Energy Domain]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.035001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.035001"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maor Eldar, Zhaopin Chen, Yiming Pan, and Michael Krüger
Numerical investigation of the phase-matched interaction of slow electrons with a strong optical field unveils a tunable trapping, opening the door for manipulating free electrons in the low-energy regime.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 035001] Published Wed Jan 17, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maor Eldar, Zhaopin Chen, Yiming Pan, and Michael Krüger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonvolatile Switching of Large Nonreciprocal Optical Absorption at Shortwave Infrared Wavelengths]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.036901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.036901"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kenta Kimura and Tsuyoshi Kimura
At low temperatures, crystals of lithium nickel phosphate transmit short-wavelength infrared light much more strongly in one direction than in the other.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 036901] Published Wed Jan 17, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kenta Kimura and Tsuyoshi Kimura</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimized nuclear energy density functionals including long-range pion contributions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.014319</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.014319"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): L. Zurek, S. K. Bogner, R. J. Furnstahl, R. Navarro Pérez, N. Schunck, and A. Schwenk
Nuclear energy-density functionals successfully reproduce properties of nuclei across almost the entire nuclear chart. However, nearly all available functionals are phenomenological in nature. Here, a step toward connecting the functionals to realistic underlying nuclear forces is made by taking the long-range contributions from chiral effective field theory along with a phenomenological Skyrme part. This involves no new parameters and results in a significant improvement in the description of nuclear data.

[Phys. Rev. C 109, 014319] Published Wed Jan 17, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L. Zurek, S. K. Bogner, R. J. Furnstahl, R. Navarro Pérez, N. Schunck, and A. Schwenk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voltage-time dilemma and stochastic threshold-voltage variation in pure-silver atomic switches]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014027</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014027"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anna Nyáry, Zoltán Balogh, Máté Vigh, Botond Sánta, László Pósa, and András Halbritter
Silver plays a prominent role as an active material in resistive-switching memory devices (memristors) based on electrochemical metallization. Such a structure contains in its active volume nanoscale Ag filaments, which can be used as artificial synapses in neural-network applications. Meanwhile, a fundamentally different type of resistive switching occurs in an atomic wire of pure Ag, where an embedding, ion-hosting environment is absent. This comparative study clarifies the characteristics and origins of the latter, purely atomic switching phenomenon, highlighting its importance in silver-based memristive devices as the active volume approaches truly atomic dimensions.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 014027] Published Wed Jan 17, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anna Nyáry, Zoltán Balogh, Máté Vigh, Botond Sánta, László Pósa, and András Halbritter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proof-of-principle ${e}^{+}$ source for future colliders]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.27.013401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.27.013401"/>
        <updated>2024-01-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. Vallis, P. Craievich, M. Schär, R. Zennaro, B. Auchmann, H. H. Braun, M. I. Besana, M. Duda, R. Fortunati, H. Garcia-Rodrigues, D. Hauenstein, R. Ischebeck, E. Ismaili, P. Juranić, J. Kosse, A. Magazinik, F. Marcellini, T. Michlmayr, S. Müller, M. Pedrozzi, R. Rotundo, G. L. Orlandi, M. Seidel, N. Strohmaier, and M. Zykova
A positron source demonstrator with the potential to increase the yield by an order of magnitude.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 27, 013401] Published Wed Jan 17, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Vallis, P. Craievich, M. Schär, R. Zennaro, B. Auchmann, H. H. Braun, M. I. Besana, M. Duda, R. Fortunati, H. Garcia-Rodrigues, D. Hauenstein, R. Ischebeck, E. Ismaili, P. Juranić, J. Kosse, A. Magazinik, F. Marcellini, T. Michlmayr, S. Müller, M. Pedrozzi, R. Rotundo, G. L. Orlandi, M. Seidel, N. Strohmaier, and M. Zykova</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonequilibrium Response for Markov Jump Processes: Exact Results and Tight Bounds]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.037101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.037101"/>
        <updated>2024-01-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Timur Aslyamov and Massimiliano Esposito
A novel linear-algebra method opens the way to efficiently study a broad class of responses for nonequilibrium systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 037101] Published Tue Jan 16, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Timur Aslyamov and Massimiliano Esposito</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thermodynamic bound on quantum state discrimination]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014119</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014119"/>
        <updated>2024-01-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): José Polo-Gómez
The limitations that thermodynamics imposes on quantum information theory are investigated in this paper, which examines an ideal gas with an internal quantum degree of freedom undergoing a cycle. By considering a demon capable of distinguishing two quantum states, the author shows that the ability to distinguish quantum states is bounded by the second law of thermodynamics.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 014119] Published Tue Jan 16, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>José Polo-Gómez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neutron radiography of an anisotropic drainage flow]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014609</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014609"/>
        <updated>2024-01-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Artem Skrypnik, Katie Cole, Tobias Lappan, Pablo R. Brito-Parada, Stephen J. Neethling, Pavel Trtik, Kerstin Eckert, and Sascha Heitkam
Usually, gravity causes liquid to drain out of a foam vertically, but simulations have predicted that if the foam is sheared, the drainage will be anisotropic. This paper describes an experimental verification of that prediction by neutron radiography, which shows that the vertical drainage flow is indeed deflected horizontally.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 014609] Published Tue Jan 16, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Artem Skrypnik, Katie Cole, Tobias Lappan, Pablo R. Brito-Parada, Stephen J. Neethling, Pavel Trtik, Kerstin Eckert, and Sascha Heitkam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All-optical dual-axis zero-field atomic magnetometer using light-shift modulation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014023</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014023"/>
        <updated>2024-01-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xiaoyu Li, Bangcheng Han, Kaixuan Zhang, Ziao Liu, Shuying Wang, Yifan Yan, and Jixi Lu
Researchers have achieved dual-axis magnetic-field detection using an atomic magnetometer architecture with only optical instruments.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 014023] Published Tue Jan 16, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiaoyu Li, Bangcheng Han, Kaixuan Zhang, Ziao Liu, Shuying Wang, Yifan Yan, and Jixi Lu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Development of Neutron Interferometer Using Multilayer Mirrors and Measurements of Neutron-Nuclear Scattering Length with Pulsed Neutron Source]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.023402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.023402"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Takuhiro Fujiie, Masahiro Hino, Takuya Hosobata, Go Ichikawa, Masaaki Kitaguchi, Kenji Mishima, Yoshichika Seki, Hirohiko M. Shimizu, and Yutaka Yamagata
Researchers have demonstrated a mirror-based neutron interferometer that should be more sensitive to beyond-standard-model particle interactions than previous instruments.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 023402] Published Fri Jan 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Takuhiro Fujiie, Masahiro Hino, Takuya Hosobata, Go Ichikawa, Masaaki Kitaguchi, Kenji Mishima, Yoshichika Seki, Hirohiko M. Shimizu, and Yutaka Yamagata</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synchronization of Bloch Oscillations in a Strongly Coupled Pair of Small Josephson Junctions: Evidence for a Shapiro-like Current Step]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.027001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.027001"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fabian Kaap, David Scheer, Fabian Hassler, and Sergey Lotkhov
High-precision measurements of the oscillations generated by a superconducting device suggest that an improved electric-current-calibration standard should be possible.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 027001] Published Fri Jan 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fabian Kaap, David Scheer, Fabian Hassler, and Sergey Lotkhov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accelerated Adiabatic Passage of a Single Electron Spin Qubit in Quantum Dots]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.027002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.027002"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xiao-Fei Liu, Yuta Matsumoto, Takafumi Fujita, Arne Ludwig, Andreas D. Wieck, and Akira Oiwa
Schemes for shortcuts to adiabaticity are demonstrated in gate-defined quantum dots based on transitionless quantum driving.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 027002] Published Fri Jan 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiao-Fei Liu, Yuta Matsumoto, Takafumi Fujita, Arne Ludwig, Andreas D. Wieck, and Akira Oiwa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dispersion and deformation of molecular patterns written in turbulent air]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.014502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.014502"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Willem van de Water, Nico Dam, and Enrico Calzavarini
This letter “H” is written in turbulent air by tagging molecules in the focus of intense laser beams that cross in space. In the course of 40 microseconds, turbulence deforms and disperses the pattern. It could be used as a way to measure the velocity of the turbulent eddies. However, more importantly, it reveals the intricate interplay between molecular diffusion and turbulent dispersion.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 014502] Published Fri Jan 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Willem van de Water, Nico Dam, and Enrico Calzavarini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Distinct universality classes of diffusive transport from full counting statistics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024417</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024417"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sarang Gopalakrishnan, Alan Morningstar, Romain Vasseur, and Vedika Khemani
The authors provide an analytic theory of the transport of magnetization in a set of interacting anisotropic spin chains. Even though these are many-body systems with diffusive transport on average, the full distribution that gives rise to that average is far from Gaussian – with fluctuations that, unlike conventional diffusion, are comparable to the mean. This is an example of how systems with the same hydrodynamics can belong to distinct dynamical universality classes.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 024417] Published Fri Jan 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarang Gopalakrishnan, Alan Morningstar, Romain Vasseur, and Vedika Khemani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Radio-frequency-modulated artificial synapses based on magnetic tunnel junctions with perpendicular magnetic anisotropy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014020</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014020"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kexin Zeng, Yawen Luo, Like Zhang, Huayao Tu, Yanxiang Luo, Xuan Zhang, Bin Fang, and Zhongming Zeng
Artificial neural networks (ANNs) based on the microwave properties of magnetic tunnel junctions (MTJs) have an advantage in recognizing rf signals without digital-to-analog conversion. However, so far there has been no good way to exploit frequency multiplexing in MTJ-based ANNs. To this end, the authors explore changing the perpendicular magnetic anisotropy between a Co-Fe-B free layer and MgO barrier. Their spintronic synapse with adjustable positive and negative weights can classify rf signals with an accuracy exceeding 96%, comparable to that of equivalent software-based neural networks. This work may well pave the way for the development of rf-oriented hardware ANNs.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 014020] Published Fri Jan 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kexin Zeng, Yawen Luo, Like Zhang, Huayao Tu, Yanxiang Luo, Xuan Zhang, Bin Fang, and Zhongming Zeng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Light-induced microwave noise in superconducting microwave-optical transducers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014022</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.014022"/>
        <updated>2024-01-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mingrui Xu, Chunzhen Li, Yuntao Xu, and Hong X. Tang
Microwave-to-optical transduction is expected to play a pivotal role in scaling up superconducting quantum processors and facilitating their long-distance communication via optical fiber, but a notable hurdle here is light-induced microwave noise. This study investigates the mechanisms that create such noise in a thin-film LiNbO3 device. Three distinct noise sources, with unique time constants spanning orders of magnitude, are identified. The authors also investigate the power dependence of each noise component, and offer potential strategies for mitigation. The insights gained from this work provide important design guidelines for efficient, low-noise transduction.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 014022] Published Fri Jan 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mingrui Xu, Chunzhen Li, Yuntao Xu, and Hong X. Tang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evidence for the Higgs Boson Decay to a $Z$ Boson and a Photon at the LHC]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.021803</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.021803"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): G. Aad et al. (ATLAS Collaboration, CMS Collaboration)
The Large Hadron Collider’s ATLAS and CMS collaborations have analyzed data of a rare Higgs-boson decay, finding a hint of a disagreement with standard-model predictions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 021803] Published Thu Jan 11, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>G. Aad &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (ATLAS Collaboration, CMS Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ginzburg-Landau Theory of Flat-Band Superconductors with Quantum Metric]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.026002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.026002"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shuai A. Chen and K. T. Law
An application of Ginzburg-Landau theory to superconducting twisted bilayer graphene determines the coherence length and the upper critical field, which are in agreement with recent experiments.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 026002] Published Thu Jan 11, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shuai A. Chen and K. T. Law</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Germanium Vacancy in Diamond Quantum Memory Exceeding 20 ms]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.026901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.026901"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Katharina Senkalla, Genko Genov, Mathias H. Metsch, Petr Siyushev, and Fedor Jelezko
An experiment demonstrates a record long quantum coherence time that exceeds 20 milliseconds for a germanium vacancy in diamond.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 026901] Published Thu Jan 11, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katharina Senkalla, Genko Genov, Mathias H. Metsch, Petr Siyushev, and Fedor Jelezko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fate of Boltzmann’s Breathers: Stokes Hypothesis and Anomalous Thermalization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.027101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.027101"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. I. García de Soria, P. Maynar, David Guéry-Odelin, and Emmanuel Trizac
Boltzmann breathers can thermalize at long times due to a damping mechanism related to the bulk viscosity for finite densities.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 027101] Published Thu Jan 11, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. I. García de Soria, P. Maynar, David Guéry-Odelin, and Emmanuel Trizac</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marangoni vortex rings in miscible spreading]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.L012701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.L012701"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anurag Pant and Baburaj. A Puthenveettil
This work investigates the dynamics of a unique, radially expanding vortex ring in a water layer when a miscible, volatile drop of ethanol spreads as a film on the air-water interface. The study unravels the link between the dynamics at the interface and the generation of vorticity in the water layer below it. A novel scaling is proposed for the radius and velocity of such vortex rings, where they are shown to be dependent on time as well as the properties of the drop and the substrate.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, L012701] Published Thu Jan 11, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anurag Pant and Baburaj. A Puthenveettil</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Supernova emission of secretly interacting neutrino fluid: Theoretical foundations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.023017</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.023017"/>
        <updated>2024-01-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Damiano F. G. Fiorillo, Georg G. Raffelt, and Edoardo Vitagliano
The paper examines theoretically the possibility that neutrinos in supernova cores act as a self-coupled fluid. It follows systematically from first principles the fluid’s diffusive transport through the core to the surface, and its expansion into space.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 023017] Published Thu Jan 11, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damiano F. G. Fiorillo, Georg G. Raffelt, and Edoardo Vitagliano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fundamental and Second-Order Superregular Breathers in Vector Fields]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.027201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.027201"/>
        <updated>2024-01-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chong Liu, Shao-Chun Chen, and Nail Akhmediev
An exact theory for superregular breathers in Manakov systems is derived, with possible applications to a wide range of nonlinear wave phenomena.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 027201] Published Wed Jan 10, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chong Liu, Shao-Chun Chen, and Nail Akhmediev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upper bounds on superconducting and excitonic phase stiffness for interacting isolated narrow bands]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024507</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024507"/>
        <updated>2024-01-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dan Mao and Debanjan Chowdhury
This work develops a systematic theoretical framework to determine the low-energy effective “diamagnetic” response associated with superconductivity and excitonic superfluidity in strongly interacting electronic models hosting isolated nearly flat bands. The results can be used to derive upper bounds on the transition temperatures for superconductivity and excitonic superfluidity without making any mean-field type approximations. The same theoretical framework can also be extended with very few modifications, to address questions related to ferromagnetism in flat bands and magnetic circular dichroism.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 024507] Published Wed Jan 10, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Mao and Debanjan Chowdhury</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vibrations and transitions across barrier of strained nanoribbons at finite temperature]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.016001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.016001"/>
        <updated>2024-01-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Paul Z. Hanakata, Sourav S. Bhabesh, David Yllanes, David R. Nelson, and Mark J. Bowick
Thermalized crystalline sheets, such as graphene liberated from a substrate, are driven by height fluctuations. The authors study the nonlinear dynamics of doubly-clamped nanoribbons as prototypical graphene resonators. Such ribbons exhibit a thermalized version of Euler buckling, with both up and down local minima. Treating the ribbon as a Brownian particle confined to a double-well potential, they determine transition rates across the two wells and oscillations inside a given well via molecular dynamics simulations. The dynamical behavior found is very different from Arrhenius behavior. The rate-controlling exponential factor depends only on the geometry, as opposed to the temperature, providing a new pathway for the experimental control of thermalized two-dimensional metamaterials.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 016001] Published Tue Jan 09, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Z. Hanakata, Sourav S. Bhabesh, David Yllanes, David R. Nelson, and Mark J. Bowick</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Suppression of Richtmyer-Meshkov Instability via Special Pairs of Shocks and Phase Transitions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.024001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.024001"/>
        <updated>2024-01-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): W. J. Schill, M. R. Armstrong, J. H. Nguyen, D. M. Sterbentz, D. A. White, L. X. Benedict, R. N. Rieben, A. Hoff, H. E. Lorenzana, J. L. Belof, B. M. La Lone, and M. D. Staska
Neutralization of a shock-generated Richtmyer-Meshkov instability at the interface between heavy and light materials using timed double-shock wave fronts is demonstrated experimentally and verified numerically.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 024001] Published Tue Jan 09, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>W. J. Schill, M. R. Armstrong, J. H. Nguyen, D. M. Sterbentz, D. A. White, L. X. Benedict, R. N. Rieben, A. Hoff, H. E. Lorenzana, J. L. Belof, B. M. La Lone, and M. D. Staska</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Formation and mechanics of fire ant rafts as an active self-healing membrane]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014607</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.014607"/>
        <updated>2024-01-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chung-Hao Chen, Ting-Heng Hsieh, Hong-Yue Huang, Yu-Chuan Cheng, and Tzay-Ming Hong
The rate at which a raft made of ants is stretched determines its properties because the ants take time to fix holes.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 014607] Published Tue Jan 09, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chung-Hao Chen, Ting-Heng Hsieh, Hong-Yue Huang, Yu-Chuan Cheng, and Tzay-Ming Hong</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exotic quantum liquids in Bose-Hubbard models with spatially modulated symmetries]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014406</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014406"/>
        <updated>2024-01-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pablo Sala, Yizhi You, Johannes Hauschild, and Olexei Motrunich
This work investigates the zero-temperature physics of generalized Bose-Hubbard models, which conserve finite Fourier momenta of the particle number. Analytical and numerical calculations predict a novel quasi-long-range order phase, in addition to more conventional Mott insulators. The former is characterized by a two-species Luttinger liquid in the infrared, with microscopic expectation values dressed by oscillatory contributions. The authors also conjecture that this phase is destroyed by the unbinding of topological defects along the temporal direction even when they are confined along the transverse direction.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 014406] Published Tue Jan 09, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pablo Sala, Yizhi You, Johannes Hauschild, and Olexei Motrunich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental nuclear quadrupole resonance and computational study of the structurally refined topological semimetal ${\mathrm{TaSb}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.035116</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.035116"/>
        <updated>2024-01-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Fujii, O. Janson, H. Yasuoka, H. Rosner, Yu. Prots, U. Burkhardt, M. Schmidt, and M. Baenitz
The electric field gradient (EFG) and magnetic excitation of TaSb2 were studied using nuclear quadrupole resonance (NQR) in a single crystal. The EFG parameters determined by measuring all expected NQR lines were corroborated by density functional theory (DFT) calculations. Despite the good agreement between the measured and calculated Sommerfeld coefficients, the spin-lattice relaxation rate was not captured by the DFT band calculations. To overcome this discrepancy, the authors propose a site-dependent in-gap state with an average energy gap of ~7 meV for the Sb sites and ~22 meV for the Ta site, which are much smaller than the semimetallic gap.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 035116] Published Tue Jan 09, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Fujii, O. Janson, H. Yasuoka, H. Rosner, Yu. Prots, U. Burkhardt, M. Schmidt, and M. Baenitz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental implementation of an efficient test of quantumness]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.012610</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.012610"/>
        <updated>2024-01-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Laura Lewis, Daiwei Zhu, Alexandru Gheorghiu, Crystal Noel, Or Katz, Bahaa Harraz, Qingfeng Wang, Andrew Risinger, Lei Feng, Debopriyo Biswas, Laird Egan, Thomas Vidick, Marko Cetina, and Christopher Monroe
The authors implement a noninteractive test of quantumness, or an algorithm for verifying whether an untrusted device is capable of quantum computation, on an ion-trap quantum computer. Their results clearly exceed the classical bound.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 012610] Published Tue Jan 09, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Lewis, Daiwei Zhu, Alexandru Gheorghiu, Crystal Noel, Or Katz, Bahaa Harraz, Qingfeng Wang, Andrew Risinger, Lei Feng, Debopriyo Biswas, Laird Egan, Thomas Vidick, Marko Cetina, and Christopher Monroe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Excitation protocols for nonlinear phononics in bismuth and antimony]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.015202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.015202"/>
        <updated>2024-01-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anubhab Haldar, Zhengjie Huang, Xuedan Ma, Pierre Darancet, and Sahar Sharifzadeh
Coherent interactions between electromagnetic waves and extended vibrational degrees of freedom in solids (phonons) enable the stabilization of non-equilibrium states of matter with potentially desirable properties. However, the breakdown of the harmonic approximation in a material experiencing a structural phase transition results in large anharmonic deviations that limit the applicability of standard illumination protocols based on periodic drives. In this study, the authors propose a new illumination protocol that enables amplification of vibrations far into the non-linear regime for broken-symmetry materials.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 015202] Published Mon Jan 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anubhab Haldar, Zhengjie Huang, Xuedan Ma, Pierre Darancet, and Sahar Sharifzadeh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of $CP$ Violation in ${B}^{0}→ψ(→{ℓ}^{+}{ℓ}^{−}){K}_{S}^{0}(→{π}^{+}{π}^{−})$ Decays]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.021801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.021801"/>
        <updated>2024-01-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Aaij et al. (LHCb Collaboration)
The quark-mixing CP-violation angle β is measured with the greatest precision to date.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 021801] Published Mon Jan 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Aaij &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHCb Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-energy acceleration phenomena in extreme-radiation–plasma interactions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.015203</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.015203"/>
        <updated>2024-01-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. C. Faure, D. Tordeux, L. Gremillet, and M. Lemoine
Powerful astrophysical sources are known to interact with their surroundings via extreme radiation-plasma interactions resulting from large quantities of emitted nonthermal radiation. This paper studies the physical processes involved in such interactions, combining analytical approximations with numerical simulations, and unveils a complex sequence of particle acceleration processes.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 015203] Published Mon Jan 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. C. Faure, D. Tordeux, L. Gremillet, and M. Lemoine</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Squeezing and quantum approximate optimization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.012413</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.012413"/>
        <updated>2024-01-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gopal Chandra Santra, Fred Jendrzejewski, Philipp Hauke, and Daniel J. Egger
The authors study the connection between the solution of the quantum approximate optimization algorithm (QAOA) and the generation of squeezed states. In doing so, they reveal a tight connection between the two seemingly unrelated fields of quantum metrology and computing. They also suggest the potential use of squeezing as a benchmark for assessing the quality of quantum algorithms.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 012413] Published Mon Jan 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gopal Chandra Santra, Fred Jendrzejewski, Philipp Hauke, and Daniel J. Egger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smectic and Soap Bubble Optofluidic Lasers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011002"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zala Korenjak and Matjaž Humar
Using a soap bubble, researchers have created a laser that could act as a sensitive sensor for environmental parameters including atmospheric pressure.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011002] Published Fri Jan 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zala Korenjak and Matjaž Humar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First-principles study of topological invariants of Weyl points in continuous media]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.6.013017</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.6.013017"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Guilherme R. Fonseca, Filipa R. Prudêncio, Mário G. Silveirinha, and Paloma A. Huidobro
A first-principles formalism that enables the topological characterization of Weyl points in three-dimensional dispersive photonic continua is introduced. The chirality of Weyl points is computed through gap Chern numbers and through direct computation of the Berry curvature, in both cases solely using the photonic Green’s function.

[Phys. Rev. Research 6, 013017] Published Fri Jan 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guilherme R. Fonseca, Filipa R. Prudêncio, Mário G. Silveirinha, and Paloma A. Huidobro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fracton Self-Statistics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.016604</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.016604"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hao Song, Nathanan Tantivasadakarn, Wilbur Shirley, and Michael Hermele
By way of an algebraic basis for their computation, fracton self-statistics is shown to be a key factor in the characterization of fracton order.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 016604] Published Fri Jan 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hao Song, Nathanan Tantivasadakarn, Wilbur Shirley, and Michael Hermele</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[$d$-Mon: A Transmon with Strong Anharmonicity Based on Planar $c$-Axis Tunneling Junction between $d$-Wave and $s$-Wave Superconductors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.017002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.017002"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hrishikesh Patel, Vedangi Pathak, Oguzhan Can, Andrew C. Potter, and Marcel Franz
A proposed new design of superconducting qubits uses Josephson junctions made with a high-Tc d-wave superconductor overlaying a conventional s-wave superconductor to increase their coherence time and stability in the presence of noise.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 017002] Published Fri Jan 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hrishikesh Patel, Vedangi Pathak, Oguzhan Can, Andrew C. Potter, and Marcel Franz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Superconducting Qubit Based on Twisted Cuprate Van der Waals Heterostructures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.017003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.017003"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Valentina Brosco, Giuseppe Serpico, Valerii Vinokur, Nicola Poccia, and Uri Vool
A proposed new design of superconducting qubits uses Josephson junctions made with a high-Tc d-wave superconductor overlaying a conventional s-wave superconductor to increase their coherence time and stability in the presence of noise.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 017003] Published Fri Jan 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Valentina Brosco, Giuseppe Serpico, Valerii Vinokur, Nicola Poccia, and Uri Vool</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Definition of fragmentation functions and the violation of sum rules]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.016006</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.016006"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): John Collins and Ted C. Rogers
The authors discuss how in QCD, processes which describe how final state hadrons arise from a parton in hard scattering are sensitive to the Wilson line necessary for gauge invariance. This affects some sum rules, notably that for charge conservation.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 016006] Published Fri Jan 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Collins and Ted C. Rogers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GWTC-2.1: Deep extended catalog of compact binary coalescences observed by LIGO and Virgo during the first half of the third observing run]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.022001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.022001"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Abbott et al. (The LIGO Scientific Collaboration and the Virgo Collaboration)
GWTC-2.1 is a catalog of gravitational wave events from compact binary coalescences from the first half of the third observing run of Advanced LIGO and Advanced Virgo. It improves on GWTC-2, which covered the same period but with less refined analysis methods. GWTC-2.1 identifies 8 new events, all identified as sourced by binary black holes with one exception identified as a neutron star-black hole coalescence. These events expand significantly on the parameters characterizing the sources of observed gravitational-wave transients.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 022001] Published Fri Jan 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Abbott &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (The LIGO Scientific Collaboration and the Virgo Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonequilibrium Schwinger-Keldysh formalism for density matrix states: Analytic properties and implications in cosmology]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.025004</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.025004"/>
        <updated>2024-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Andrei O. Barvinsky and Nikita Kolganov
Motivated by cosmological Hartle-Hawking and microcanonical density matrix prescriptions for the quantum state of the Universe, the authors develop a Schwinger-Keldysh in-in formalism for generic non-equilibrium systems with an initial density matrix. For generic density matrices of the Gaussian type, they develop the generating functionals of the in-in Green’s functions and discuss how “particle interpretation” relates to the density matrix parameters.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 025004] Published Fri Jan 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrei O. Barvinsky and Nikita Kolganov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlinear and Negative Effective Diffusivity of Interlayer Excitons in Moiré-Free Heterobilayers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.016202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.016202"/>
        <updated>2024-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Edith Wietek, Matthias Florian, Jonas Göser, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Alexander Högele, Mikhail M. Glazov, Alexander Steinhoff, and Alexey Chernikov
Interlayer excitons in van der Waals heterostructures diffuse rapidly, with diffusion coefficients about 1000 times larger than previously seen, in the absence of moiré- and disorder-induced localization.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 016202] Published Thu Jan 04, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edith Wietek, Matthias Florian, Jonas Göser, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Alexander Högele, Mikhail M. Glazov, Alexander Steinhoff, and Alexey Chernikov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of Terahertz Spin Hall Conductivity Spectrum in GaAs with Optical Spin Injection]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.016301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.016301"/>
        <updated>2024-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tomohiro Fujimoto, Takayuki Kurihara, Yuta Murotani, Tomohiro Tamaya, Natsuki Kanda, Changsu Kim, Jun Yoshinobu, Hidefumi Akiyama, Takeo Kato, and Ryusuke Matsunaga
Spin Hall conductivity is observed in GaAs at room temperature via a circularly polarized terahertz pump-probe setup.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 016301] Published Thu Jan 04, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tomohiro Fujimoto, Takayuki Kurihara, Yuta Murotani, Tomohiro Tamaya, Natsuki Kanda, Changsu Kim, Jun Yoshinobu, Hidefumi Akiyama, Takeo Kato, and Ryusuke Matsunaga</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analog vacuum decay from vacuum initial conditions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.023506</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.023506"/>
        <updated>2024-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexander C. Jenkins, Jonathan Braden, Hiranya V. Peiris, Andrew Pontzen, Matthew C. Johnson, and Silke Weinfurtner
The authors study how phase transitions in ultracold atomic gases mimic relativistic vacuum decay, improving on previous analyses by incorporating the effects of quantum fluctuations over and above the classical equations of motion. This is designed to test early Universe physics via tabletop experiments.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 023506] Published Thu Jan 04, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexander C. Jenkins, Jonathan Braden, Hiranya V. Peiris, Andrew Pontzen, Matthew C. Johnson, and Silke Weinfurtner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fully <i>Ab Initio</i> Approach to Inelastic Atom-Surface Scattering]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.016203</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.016203"/>
        <updated>2024-01-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Michelle M. Kelley, Ravishankar Sundararaman, and Tomás A. Arias
The interactions of helium atoms with crystalline surfaces are so gentle and subtle that it has been challenging to describe them from first principles.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 016203] Published Wed Jan 03, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michelle M. Kelley, Ravishankar Sundararaman, and Tomás A. Arias</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Light-Induced Ideal Weyl Semimetal in HgTe via Nonlinear Phononics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.016603</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.016603"/>
        <updated>2024-01-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dongbin Shin, Angel Rubio, and Peizhe Tang
Calculations show that light-matter interactions via nonlinear phononics can lead to long-lived non-equilibrium lattice distortion in bulk HgTe, demonstrating a possible microscopic mechanism to control the material topology with light.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 016603] Published Wed Jan 03, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dongbin Shin, Angel Rubio, and Peizhe Tang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fingering Instability Accelerates Population Growth of a Proliferating Cell Collective]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.018402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.018402"/>
        <updated>2024-01-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yiyang Ye (叶毅扬) and Jie Lin (林杰)
A continuum model predicts a fingering instability at the leading front of a growing cell collective due to the feedback between pressure and growth rate, which could provide an evolutionary advantage.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 018402] Published Wed Jan 03, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yiyang Ye (叶毅扬) and Jie Lin (林杰)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bose-Einstein condensation in systems with flux equilibrium]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.014301"/>
        <updated>2024-01-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Victor S. L'vov, Anna Pomyalov, Sergey V. Nazarenko, Dmytro A. Bozhko, Alexander J. E. Kreil, Burkard Hillebrands, and Alexander A. Serga
Quasiparticles, created in dissipative nonlinear wave systems by external excitation, can form a Bose-Einstein condensate. The authors describe here the physical phenomena and conditions leading to condensation in various regimes of external excitation from weak and stationary to ultrastrong pumping. The authors have developed a stationary nonlinear theory of kinetic instability for the latter, supported by the experimental data for magnons, parametrically pumped in room-temperature films of yttrium iron garnet.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 014301] Published Wed Jan 03, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor S. L'vov, Anna Pomyalov, Sergey V. Nazarenko, Dmytro A. Bozhko, Alexander J. E. Kreil, Burkard Hillebrands, and Alexander A. Serga</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental and computational study of the core-level crossing transition in iridium at high pressure]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024101"/>
        <updated>2024-01-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. V. Storm, G. A. Woolman, C. M. Lonsdale, J. D. McHardy, M. J. Duff, G. J. Ackland, and M. I. McMahon
This static high-pressure x-ray diffraction study of iridium investigates previous reports of a core-level crossing at 80 GPa, whereby the authors find no evidence for such a transition. Further computational investigations reveal that a core-level crossing does occur in iridium, but only at 400 GPa. In addition, the efficacy of bismuth as a pressure-transmitting medium is demonstrated, maintaining a uniaxial stress component in the sample below 2% up to 159 GPa.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 024101] Published Wed Jan 03, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. V. Storm, G. A. Woolman, C. M. Lonsdale, J. D. McHardy, M. J. Duff, G. J. Ackland, and M. I. McMahon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological transition from nodal to nodeless Zeeman splitting in altermagnets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024404</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.024404"/>
        <updated>2024-01-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rafael M. Fernandes, Vanuildo S. de Carvalho, Turan Birol, and Rodrigo G. Pereira
Altermagnets are an unconventional type of magnetic state with various appealing properties, both from the fundamental and applied physics perspectives. By investigating the impact of spin-orbit coupling on these states, this work reveals that all altermagnets are intrinsically noncollinear and that their Zeeman splittings possess symmetry-protected nodal lines. These features endow altermagnets with a remarkable resilience against external magnetic fields.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 024404] Published Wed Jan 03, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rafael M. Fernandes, Vanuildo S. de Carvalho, Turan Birol, and Rodrigo G. Pereira</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spatial dispersion in silicon]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.035201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.035201"/>
        <updated>2024-01-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Subiao Bian, Razvigor Ossikovski, Adolf Canillas, Gerald Jellison, and Oriol Arteaga
Here, the complete determination of the spectroscopic permittivity tensor of crystalline silicon in consideration of spatial dispersion (SD) is presented. Using spectroscopic ellipsometry, two complex parameters, ε and p1 (wave-vector-dependent for SD), were measured, revealing significant findings. Remarkably, pronounced UV region anisotropy was observed in (110) silicon wafers, surpassing the NIR region by up to five orders of magnitude. In contrast, minimal anisotropy was detected in (100) plane measurements, supporting the proposed tensor model. Comparative analysis of (100) and (110) wafers, incorporating SD, showcased consistent ε values, contributing valuable insights into silicon’s behavior.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 035201] Published Wed Jan 03, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Subiao Bian, Razvigor Ossikovski, Adolf Canillas, Gerald Jellison, and Oriol Arteaga</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microwave spectroscopy of interacting Andreev spins]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.045302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.045302"/>
        <updated>2024-01-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. J. Wesdorp, F. J. Matute-Cañadas, A. Vaartjes, L. Grünhaupt, T. Laeven, S. Roelofs, L. J. Splitthoff, M. Pita-Vidal, A. Bargerbos, D. J. van Woerkom, P. Krogstrup, L. P. Kouwenhoven, C. K. Andersen, A. Levy Yeyati, B. van Heck, and G. de Lange
Andreev bound states are fermionic states localized in weak links between superconductors, which can be occupied with spinful quasiparticles. Recently, experiments embedding a nanowire Josephson junction into a superconducting circuit have enabled coherent manipulation of a single Andreev spin. However, these experiments remained limited to small magnetic fields. Here, the authors measure the microwave spectra of a nanowire Josephson junction in magnetic fields up to ∼ 250 mT and identify singlet, doublet, and triplet states of interacting Andreev spins.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 045302] Published Wed Jan 03, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. J. Wesdorp, F. J. Matute-Cañadas, A. Vaartjes, L. Grünhaupt, T. Laeven, S. Roelofs, L. J. Splitthoff, M. Pita-Vidal, A. Bargerbos, D. J. van Woerkom, P. Krogstrup, L. P. Kouwenhoven, C. K. Andersen, A. Levy Yeyati, B. van Heck, and G. de Lange</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Non-Hermitian Hamiltonians violate the eigenstate thermalization hypothesis]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L020201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L020201"/>
        <updated>2024-01-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Giorgio Cipolloni and Jonah Kudler-Flam
The eigenstate thermalization hypothesis (ETH) represents a cornerstone in the theoretical understanding of the emergence of thermal behavior in closed quantum systems. Here, the authors investigate to what extent the ETH holds for non-Hermitian Hamiltonians, relevant for open and monitored quantum systems, and come to the surprising conclusion that fluctuations are greatly enhanced, indicating the breakdown of thermalization.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, L020201] Published Wed Jan 03, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giorgio Cipolloni and Jonah Kudler-Flam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Classical analog of quantum models in synthetic dimensions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.013303</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.013303"/>
        <updated>2024-01-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Max Cohen, Max Casebolt, Yutan Zhang, Kaden R. A. Hazzard, and Richard Scalettar
The authors introduce a classical spin model motivated by the quantum Hamiltonian for synthetic-dimension systems based on ultracold molecules or Rydberg atoms. The authors use mean-field theory, Monte Carlo methods, and machine-learning approaches to study the phase diagram.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 013303] Published Wed Jan 03, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Max Cohen, Max Casebolt, Yutan Zhang, Kaden R. A. Hazzard, and Richard Scalettar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generalized Scaling and Model for Friction in Wall Turbulence]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.014001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.014001"/>
        <updated>2024-01-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shivsai Ajit Dixit, Abhishek Gupta, Harish Choudhary, and Thara Prabhakaran
A new theoretical framework allows scientists to accurately estimate the friction a surface experiences in a turbulent flow, such as an airplane wing flying through the sky.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 014001] Published Tue Jan 02, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shivsai Ajit Dixit, Abhishek Gupta, Harish Choudhary, and Thara Prabhakaran</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Schramm-Loewner Evolution in 2D Rigidity Percolation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.018201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.018201"/>
        <updated>2024-01-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nina Javerzat
New theoretical work explores the onset of rigidity in granular materials and other disordered systems by mapping out the edges of rigid regions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 018201] Published Tue Jan 02, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nina Javerzat</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing the edge states of Chern insulators using microwave impedance microscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235432</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235432"/>
        <updated>2023-12-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Taige Wang, Chen Wu, Masataka Mogi, Minoru Kawamura, Yoshinori Tokura, Zhi-Xun Shen, Yi–Zhuang You, and Monica T. Allen
Quantum anomalous Hall (QAH) insulators, known for their topological 1D conducting edge states, are a focus of many recent quantum material studies. Here, the authors overcome the challenges in direct imaging and analysis of edge states by exploiting the power of microwave impedance microscopy (MIM). By analyzing the resonance pattern of 1D edge plasmon excitations, MIM can discern true topological edge states from potential trivial ones. This approach significantly advances our understanding of QAH insulators and their topological edge states.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 235432] Published Fri Dec 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Taige Wang, Chen Wu, Masataka Mogi, Minoru Kawamura, Yoshinori Tokura, Zhi-Xun Shen, Yi–Zhuang You, and Monica T. Allen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Towards an experimental proof of the magnonic Aharonov-Casher effect]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L220404</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L220404"/>
        <updated>2023-12-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rostyslav O. Serha, Vitaliy I. Vasyuchka, Alexander A. Serga, and Burkard Hillebrands
The Aharonov-Casher effect is the accumulation of the wave function phase when a particle with magnetic moment passes through an electric field. This phenomenon is observed for real particles and predicted for quasiparticles such as magnons. Here, the authors investigate the impact of a strong electric field on the phase of dipolar spin waves exited in a ferromagnetic yttrium iron garnet (YIG) film and report the experimental results in favor of the magnonic Aharonov-Casher effect.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L220404] Published Fri Dec 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rostyslav O. Serha, Vitaliy I. Vasyuchka, Alexander A. Serga, and Burkard Hillebrands</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Possible explanation for the high superconducting ${T}_{c}$ in bcc Ti at high pressure]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.214523</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.214523"/>
        <updated>2023-12-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Antonio Sanna, Camilla Pellegrini, Simone di Cataldo, Gianni Profeta, and Lilia Boeri
By means of ab initio calculations, the authors show here that neither a conventional nor an unconventional pairing mechanism can justify the observed 26-K superconducting Tc in compressed bcc titanium. They reconcile experimental and theoretical results by assuming the presence of Ti vacancies. These induce a phonon softening that increases the electron-phonon coupling at high pressure, yielding an agreement with measurements over the full pressure range 150–300 GPa. The proposed mechanism applies to multiple types of defects and can occur in several simple metals.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 214523] Published Thu Dec 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Antonio Sanna, Camilla Pellegrini, Simone di Cataldo, Gianni Profeta, and Lilia Boeri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toward a global phase diagram of the fractional quantum anomalous Hall effect]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.245159</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.245159"/>
        <updated>2023-12-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aidan P. Reddy and Liang Fu
Recent experiments on tMoTe2 provide the first realization of the fractional quantum anomalous Hall effect. Synthesizing insights from an extensive exact diagonalization study, the authors present here a many-body phase diagram tMoTe2, in which lowest Landau level (LLL)-like features and non-LLL-like features coexist. The study highlights several guiding principles, including interaction-enhanced particle-hole asymmetry, that is expected to play an important role in general fractional quantum anomalous Hall systems.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 245159] Published Thu Dec 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aidan P. Reddy and Liang Fu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electron and hole doping of monolayer ${\mathrm{WSe}}_{2}$ induced by twisted ferroelectric hexagonal boron nitride]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.L121002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.L121002"/>
        <updated>2023-12-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Fraunié, R. Jamil, R. Kantelberg, S. Roux, L. Petit, E. Lepleux, L. Pacheco, K. Watanabe, T. Taniguchi, V. Jacques, L. Lombez, M. M. Glazov, B. Lassagne, X. Marie, and C. Robert
2D ferroelectric materials have attracted strong interest for their potential in future nanoelectronic devices. The recent discovery of 2D ferroelectricity in twisted layers of hexagonal boron nitride has opened the route to its integration into complex hybrid van der Waals heterostructures. Here the authors show that opposite polarizations in ferroelectric domains of a folded hBN layer imprint local n and p doping in a semiconducting WSe2 monolayer. They demonstrate that WSe2 can be used as an optical probe of ferroelectricity in hBN and show that doping can be controlled with the position of the semiconductor with respect to the ferroelectric interface.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, L121002] Published Wed Dec 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Fraunié, R. Jamil, R. Kantelberg, S. Roux, L. Petit, E. Lepleux, L. Pacheco, K. Watanabe, T. Taniguchi, V. Jacques, L. Lombez, M. M. Glazov, B. Lassagne, X. Marie, and C. Robert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Structures, charge density wave, and superconductivity of noncentrosymmetric $4{H}_{\mathrm{a}}\text{−}{\mathrm{NbSe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.224518</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.224518"/>
        <updated>2023-12-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Menghu Zhou, Yadong Gu, Shunli Ni, Binbin Ruan, Qiaoyu Liu, Qingsong Yang, Lewei Chen, Junkun Yi, Yunqing Shi, Genfu Chen, and Zhian Ren
Here, the authors report the charge density wave and superconductivity of noncentrosymmetric 4Ha-NbSe2. In particular, it exhibits a large upper critical field Hc2(0) well beyond the Pauli paramagnetic limit. Hc2(T) could be described by a two-band scenario that is also revealed via lower critical field and specific heat. The high Hc2 is expected to motivate the search of high-field superconductors in noncentrosymmetric materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 224518] Published Wed Dec 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Menghu Zhou, Yadong Gu, Shunli Ni, Binbin Ruan, Qiaoyu Liu, Qingsong Yang, Lewei Chen, Junkun Yi, Yunqing Shi, Genfu Chen, and Zhian Ren</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inhomogeneous excitation-regulated coherent strain wave in $2H\text{−}\mathrm{Mo}{\mathrm{Te}}_{2}$ revealed by ultrafast electron microscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.245426</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.245426"/>
        <updated>2023-12-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yongzhao Zhang, Shuaishuai Sun, Wentao Wang, Huanfang Tian, Jianqi Li, Jun Li, and Huaixin Yang
The potential to manipulate the coherent photoacoustic wave in 2H-MoTe2 is demonstrated here by adjusting the homogeneity of laser excitation. Homogeneous excitation results in out-of-phase intensity oscillations of the Friedel pairs, and only the fundamental frequency is detected. In contrast, inhomogeneous excitation leads to in-phase intensity oscillations and the emergence of a second harmonic component. These ultrafast electron diffraction results reveal that, as the flake thickness increases, the photoacoustic wave transforms from a standing wave with breathing motions to a soliton-like traveling wave.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 245426] Published Wed Dec 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yongzhao Zhang, Shuaishuai Sun, Wentao Wang, Huanfang Tian, Jianqi Li, Jun Li, and Huaixin Yang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hyperpolarization of nuclear spins: Polarization blockade]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043291</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043291"/>
        <updated>2023-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): O. T. Whaites, C. I. Ioannou, B. J. Pingault, G. L. van de Stolpe, T. H. Taminiau, and T. S. Monteiro
Sequences of periodic microwave pulses are used to efficiently transfer polarization from an NV defect electronic spin in diamond to surrounding nuclei, at specific resonant periods. It’s theoretically and experimentally demonstrated that the presence of a “blocking spin,” a nuclear spin with similar precession frequency but stronger coupling, leads to expulsion of polarization resonances of other nuclear spins from the central resonant period region, affecting the efficiency of the polarization protocol.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 043291] Published Tue Dec 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>O. T. Whaites, C. I. Ioannou, B. J. Pingault, G. L. van de Stolpe, T. H. Taminiau, and T. S. Monteiro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conformal Invariance and Multifractality at Anderson Transitions in Arbitrary Dimensions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.266401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.266401"/>
        <updated>2023-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jaychandran Padayasi and Ilya Gruzberg
Conformal invariance and Abelian fusion constrain the spectrum of multifractal exponents to be quadratic in its arguments in any dimension greater than two.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 266401] Published Tue Dec 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaychandran Padayasi and Ilya Gruzberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Field theory of a superconductor with repulsion]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.214521</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.214521"/>
        <updated>2023-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Amir Dalal, Jonathan Ruhman, and Vladyslav Kozii
Superconductivity, the state of zero resistance in metals, involves electrons forming a quantum liquid of pairs. However, here lies a conundrum; electrons repel each other due to the electric force, so why should they bind? The answer to this question was provided a long time ago by Pierre Morel and Phillip Anderson. However, to date, there is no existing generalization of Morel-Anderson theory that gives a comprehensive understanding of the properties of real superconductors. This paper bridges the gap by outlining a path to generalize their theory into a “quantum field theory”. Surprisingly, this theory is controlled by a unique point in configuration space (“saddle point”). Utilizing mathematical techniques, the authors can exploit this saddle point to reveal insights into superconductor properties, such as the break point in a magnetic field.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 214521] Published Tue Dec 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amir Dalal, Jonathan Ruhman, and Vladyslav Kozii</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neutralization of impurities by continuous-wave excitation of high-$n$ Rydberg excitons]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235212</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235212"/>
        <updated>2023-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Heckötter, B. Panda, K. Brägelmann, M. Harati, and M. Aßmann
Rydberg excitons are electron-hole pairs excited to high principle quantum numbers (n), that can be addressed in the semiconductor Cu2O. Embedded in a crystalline environment, the highest Rydberg states typically suffer from the presence electric stray fields induced by charged impurities. Here, the authors show a technique to neutralize these impurities by the excitation of Rydberg excitons. The result is an overall improvement of the absorption spectrum’s quality in terms of increased oscillator strengths and narrower linewidths, approaching the Fourier limit.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 235212] Published Tue Dec 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Heckötter, B. Panda, K. Brägelmann, M. Harati, and M. Aßmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Injection mechanisms in a <i>III</i>-nitride light-emitting diode as seen by self-emissive electron microscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.064045</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.064045"/>
        <updated>2023-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tanay Tak, Cameron W. Johnson, Wan Ying Ho, Feng Wu, Mylène Sauty, Steve Rebollo, Andreas K. Schmid, Jacques Peretti, Yuh-Renn Wu, Claude Weisbuch, and James S. Speck
While charge carriers in electronics are fundamental to device operation, little is empirically known about their spatial distribution under standard operating conditions. The authors develop a technique for self-emissive electron microscopy that allows them to image electrons close to their point of generation in operando. Increased electron emission, and thus carrier density, is observed at the ridges of V-shaped defects in a green LED, confirming that the sidewalls of these defects allow lateral carrier injection⏤a necessity for increasing efficiency. Measuring the spatial distribution of carriers with this technique can inform the design of superior devices.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 064045] Published Tue Dec 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tanay Tak, Cameron W. Johnson, Wan Ying Ho, Feng Wu, Mylène Sauty, Steve Rebollo, Andreas K. Schmid, Jacques Peretti, Yuh-Renn Wu, Claude Weisbuch, and James S. Speck</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theory of hydrodynamic phenomena in optical mesh lattices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.063517</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.063517"/>
        <updated>2023-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hannah M. Price, Martin Wimmer, Monika Monika, Ulf Peschel, and Iacopo Carusotto
The authors develop a theoretical description of superfluidlike phenomena in an optical mesh lattice, a system composed of two fiber loops coupled via a beam splitter. The results provide analytical and numerical interpretation of previous experimental observations and predict physical effects stemming from the spatiotemporally periodic geometry.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 063517] Published Tue Dec 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah M. Price, Martin Wimmer, Monika Monika, Ulf Peschel, and Iacopo Carusotto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>