<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-09-14T00:42:54.963Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-09-14T00:42:54.963Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimality Pressures toward Lateralization of Complex Brain Functions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031028</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031028"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Luís F. Seoane
A mathematical model shows how increased intricacy of cognitive tasks can break the mirror symmetry of the brain’s neural network.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 031028] Published Wed Sep 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luís F. Seoane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Floquet Engineering of Black Phosphorus upon Below-Gap Pumping]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116401"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shaohua Zhou, Changhua Bao, Benshu Fan, Fei Wang, Haoyuan Zhong, Hongyun Zhang, Peizhe Tang, Wenhui Duan, and Shuyun Zhou
Light-induced band engineering in black phosphorus by pumping below the band gap is experimentally demonstrated, which might extend Floquet engineering to more quantum materials.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116401] Published Wed Sep 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shaohua Zhou, Changhua Bao, Benshu Fan, Fei Wang, Haoyuan Zhong, Hongyun Zhang, Peizhe Tang, Wenhui Duan, and Shuyun Zhou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enhancement of Second-Order Non-Hermitian Skin Effect by Magnetic Fields]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116601"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chang-An Li, Björn Trauzettel, Titus Neupert, and Song-Bo Zhang
The second-order non-Hermitian skin effect is robust and can even be enhanced by magnetic fields, which is in contrast to the first-order non-Hermitian skin effect.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116601] Published Wed Sep 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chang-An Li, Björn Trauzettel, Titus Neupert, and Song-Bo Zhang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental Observation of Critical Scaling in Magnetic Dynamic Phase Transitions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116701"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Quintana and A. Berger
Magneto-optical experiments on ultrathin uniaxial cobalt films reveal (for the first time) critical behavior in such systems, and also show indications of dimensional crossover, with the films exhibiting 2D dynamical and 3D thermodynamic behavior.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116701] Published Wed Sep 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Quintana and A. Berger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maximally localized exciton Wannier functions for solids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125118</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125118"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jonah B. Haber, Diana Y. Qiu, Felipe H. da Jornada, and Jeffrey B. Neaton
Over 25 years ago, Marzari and Vanderbilt introduced maximally localized Wannier functions (MLWFs), the most compact real-space representation of electronic wavefunctions in solids. Here, the authors put forward a generalization of this scheme for excitons, correlated electron-hole pairs that dictate the optical properties of materials. Much as MLWFs have transformed our understanding of electrons in solids, from chemical bonding to polarization to topology, these maximally localized exciton Wannier functions should deepen our understanding of photophysical and excited-state phenomena of materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 125118] Published Wed Sep 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonah B. Haber, Diana Y. Qiu, Felipe H. da Jornada, and Jeffrey B. Neaton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimal single-qubit tomography: Realization of locally optimal measurements on a quantum computer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.032605</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.032605"/>
        <updated>2023-09-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bacui Li, Lorcán O. Conlon, Ping Koy Lam, and Syed M. Assad
The authors map qubit tomography to a quantum multiparameter estimation problem and find the optimal single-qubit measurements. Using a quantum computing demonstration they show that the optimal separable measurement bound can be saturated.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 032605] Published Wed Sep 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bacui Li, Lorcán O. Conlon, Ping Koy Lam, and Syed M. Assad</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chemotactic Motility-Induced Phase Separation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.118301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.118301"/>
        <updated>2023-09-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hongbo Zhao, Andrej Košmrlj, and Sujit S. Datta
Chemotaxis and motility-induced phase separation compete against each other in systems of active particles.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 118301] Published Tue Sep 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hongbo Zhao, Andrej Košmrlj, and Sujit S. Datta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Renormalization group for measurement and entanglement phase transitions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.104203</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.104203"/>
        <updated>2023-09-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Adam Nahum and Kay Jörg Wiese
Field theoretic renormalization group is applied to measurement and entanglement phase transitions. The renormalization group flows for both random tensor networks and monitored systems show that, in high dimensions, there exist distinct weak- and strong-coupling universality classes for these phase transitions. In addition, one of the field theories exhibits a supersymmetry that leads to dimensional reduction by four.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 104203] Published Tue Sep 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Nahum and Kay Jörg Wiese</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inhomogeneity-induced time-reversal symmetry breaking in cuprate twist junctions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L100505</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L100505"/>
        <updated>2023-09-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Andrew C. Yuan, Yaar Vituri, Erez Berg, Boris Spivak, and Steven A. Kivelson
The lowest-order Josephson coupling between d-wave superconductors vanishes by symmetry when the twist angle is close to 45 degrees. The authors propose here an “order by disorder” mechanism, whereby spatial fluctuations in the local Josephson coupling generate an effective higher-order coupling, leading to a time reversal symmetry breaking superconducting phase at the twisted interface. This mechanism may offer an explanation for recent experiments in twist junctions between high-Tc cuprate superconductors. These findings have broader implications for high-Tc cuprate physics, requiring a local admixture of an s-wave component in the d-wave order parameter.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L100505] Published Tue Sep 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew C. Yuan, Yaar Vituri, Erez Berg, Boris Spivak, and Steven A. Kivelson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In and Out-of-Equilibrium <i>Ab Initio</i> Theory of Electrons and Phonons]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031026</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031026"/>
        <updated>2023-09-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gianluca Stefanucci, Robert van Leeuwen, and Enrico Perfetto
A new set of equations captures the dynamical interplay of electrons and vibrations in crystals and forms a basis for computational studies.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 031026] Published Mon Sep 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gianluca Stefanucci, Robert van Leeuwen, and Enrico Perfetto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evidence for Suppression of Structure Growth in the Concordance Cosmological Model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.111001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.111001"/>
        <updated>2023-09-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nhat-Minh Nguyen, Dragan Huterer, and Yuewei Wen
A joint analysis of data from the CMB, weak lensing, peculiar velocities, and galaxy clustering, shows that an extension of the concordance cosmological model which includes the suppression of the growth of cosmic structure can alleviate two widely discussed cosmological tensions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 111001] Published Mon Sep 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nhat-Minh Nguyen, Dragan Huterer, and Yuewei Wen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paramagnetic Singularities of the Orbital Magnetism in Graphene with a Moiré Potential]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.116201"/>
        <updated>2023-09-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Vallejo Bustamante, R. Ribeiro-Palau, C. Fermon, M. Pannetier-Lecoeur, K. Watanabe, T. Tanigushi, R. Deblock, S. Guéron, M. Ferrier, J. N. Fuchs, G. Montambaux, F. Piéchon, and H. Bouchiat
Magnetization measurements on graphene/hBN samples in a wide range of chemical potential reveal paramagnetism at saddle points of the moiré band structure.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 116201] Published Mon Sep 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Vallejo Bustamante, R. Ribeiro-Palau, C. Fermon, M. Pannetier-Lecoeur, K. Watanabe, T. Tanigushi, R. Deblock, S. Guéron, M. Ferrier, J. N. Fuchs, G. Montambaux, F. Piéchon, and H. Bouchiat</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frequency-domain approach to self-force in hyperbolic scattering]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.064017</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.064017"/>
        <updated>2023-09-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christopher Whittall and Leor Barack
The self-force problem in gravity is an approach to the two-body problem in which the mass ratio is extreme enough that the smaller-mass body can be usefully treated as a test particle to the lowest order in the mass ratio. In this paper, frequency domain methods, which are particularly suited for bound orbital motion, are developed in an innovative way so that they can be applied to study hyperbolic scattering in the “toy” problem of a scalar charge. Frequency domain methods as developed here may prove to be a promising approach to the full gravitational self-force problem.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 064017] Published Mon Sep 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher Whittall and Leor Barack</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep learning extraction of band structure parameters from density of states: A case study on trilayer graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125411</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125411"/>
        <updated>2023-09-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Paul Henderson, Areg Ghazaryan, Alexander A. Zibrov, Andrea F. Young, and Maksym Serbyn
Harnessing the power of deep learning, researchers have developed a novel method to fit the band structure parameters of complex 2D materials, such as trilayer graphene. By training neural networks on simulated data for the density of states, and then minimizing the effective distance between network-generated images and experimental data, the authors obtain here accurate predictions of tight-binding parameters, validating their results against literature values. This method can be easily extended to other complex two-dimensional materials, as well as to other experimental techniques.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 125411] Published Mon Sep 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Henderson, Areg Ghazaryan, Alexander A. Zibrov, Andrea F. Young, and Maksym Serbyn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Acoustically Induced Spin Resonances of Silicon-Vacancy Centers in $4H$-SiC]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034017</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034017"/>
        <updated>2023-09-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Vasselon, A. Hernández-Mínguez, M. Hollenbach, G.V. Astakhov, and P.V. Santos
Silicon vacancies in 4H-SiC are color centers with promising applications in quantum technologies, but spin control of the centers generated in a hexagonal local crystallographic environment has yet to be demonstrated above cryogenic temperatures. The authors use the dynamic strain of surface acoustic waves to overcome this limitation and efficiently excite spin transitions in the excited states of these color centers up to room temperature. The acoustic spin control of silicon vacancies opens possibilities for the implementation of efficient quantum spin control and sensing protocols using spin optomechanics.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 034017] Published Mon Sep 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Vasselon, A. Hernández-Mínguez, M. Hollenbach, G.V. Astakhov, and P.V. Santos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nanoscale Transport during Liquid Film Thinning Inhibits Bubble Coalescing Behavior in Electrolyte Solutions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.104003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.104003"/>
        <updated>2023-09-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bo Liu, Rogerio Manica, Qingxia Liu, Zhenghe Xu, Evert Klaseboer, and Qiang Yang
Observations of air-bubble mergers in water explain why dissolved salt slows this process and leads to foam.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 104003] Published Fri Sep 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bo Liu, Rogerio Manica, Qingxia Liu, Zhenghe Xu, Evert Klaseboer, and Qiang Yang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two-way photoeffectlike occupancy dynamics in a single (InGa)As quantum dot]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125301"/>
        <updated>2023-09-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pavel Sterin, Kai Hühn, Mikhail M. Glazov, Jens Hübner, and Michael Oestreich
Spin noise spectroscopy on single quantum dots (QDs) has matured to a highly efficient method to study the spin and charge dynamics of semiconductor quantum dots, including the subtle impact of their surroundings. Here, the authors extend the theory and the experimental technique of optical spin noise spectroscopy to high magnetic fields and study the fundamental mechanisms of decharging and recharging of (InGa)As QDs at quasiresonant and nonresonant optical excitation. The resulting photoinduced two-way charge dynamics in single QDs is not only interesting from the fundamental point of view but plays an important role in many quantum dot based photonic devices, such as optically addressable qubits or reliable single-photon emitters.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 125301] Published Fri Sep 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pavel Sterin, Kai Hühn, Mikhail M. Glazov, Jens Hübner, and Michael Oestreich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Error mitigation for quantum approximate optimization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.032408</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.032408"/>
        <updated>2023-09-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anita Weidinger, Glen Bigan Mbeng, and Wolfgang Lechner
Quantum error mitigation involves reducing errors in hybrid quantum-classical algorithms, which is particularly relevant for near-term noisy quantum devices. The authors introduce an error mitigation technique based on redundant parity encoding of logical variables. They demonstrate the use of this technique by applying it to the quantum approximate optimization algorithm.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 032408] Published Fri Sep 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anita Weidinger, Glen Bigan Mbeng, and Wolfgang Lechner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simulations of a frequency-chirped magneto-optical trap of MgF]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.033105</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.033105"/>
        <updated>2023-09-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kayla J. Rodriguez, Nickolas H. Pilgram, Daniel S. Barker, Stephen P. Eckel, and Eric B. Norrgard
The authors present a theoretical analysis of a frequency-chirped molecular magneto-optical trap (MOT) that may open the way for efficient cooling of a class of light molecules. They show that this approach can increase the capture velocity of the MOT which could be used to capture more molecules from typical molecular sources and, in some cases, perhaps remove the need for laser slowing before capture in the MOT.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 033105] Published Fri Sep 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kayla J. Rodriguez, Nickolas H. Pilgram, Daniel S. Barker, Stephen P. Eckel, and Eric B. Norrgard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Active nematics on flat surfaces: From droplet motility and scission to active wetting]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033165</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033165"/>
        <updated>2023-09-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rodrigo C. V. Coelho, Hélio R. J. C. Figueiredo, and Margarida M. Telo da Gama
Active nematic droplets on surfaces are studied at different activities on a wide range of surfaces. The analysis provides a global description of the dynamical regimes reported for active nematic droplets, such as active wetting, propulsion, and chaotic motion, and it reveals the dimensionless parameters that characterize the dynamics of droplets on surfaces.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 033165] Published Thu Sep 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rodrigo C. V. Coelho, Hélio R. J. C. Figueiredo, and Margarida M. Telo da Gama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Failure of Topological Invariants in Strongly Correlated Matter]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.106601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.106601"/>
        <updated>2023-09-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jinchao Zhao, Peizhi Mai, Barry Bradlyn, and Philip Phillips
When zeros appear in the Green’s function, as in strongly correlated systems, the invariant N3 for the two-dimensional quantum anomalous Hall insulator does not necessarily encode a topological invariant of the ground state, in contrast to expectations.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 106601] Published Thu Sep 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jinchao Zhao, Peizhi Mai, Barry Bradlyn, and Philip Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global and Local Connectivities Describe Hydrogen Intercalation in Metal Oxides]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.108001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.108001"/>
        <updated>2023-09-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Evan V. Miu, James R. McKone, and Giannis Mpourmpakis
The reactivity of a material is describable using only the arrangement of its atoms, a finding that could be used to speed up the search for new catalytic materials.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 108001] Published Thu Sep 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Evan V. Miu, James R. McKone, and Giannis Mpourmpakis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How the fine structure of the electric double layer and the flow affect morphological instability in electrodeposition]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.093701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.093701"/>
        <updated>2023-09-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): I. Rubinstein and B. Zaltzman
Dendrite formation due to morphological instability in cathodic electrodeposition of a metal and related fluid flows are investigated. We show that the electric double layer fine structure and the finite electrode reaction rate regularize the electrodeposition front short-wave singularity and select a range of unstable perturbation modes. The critical wavelength corresponds to the fastest growing mode and scales with the electric double layer width and the reaction-diffusion length. The emerging electroconvective (electroosmotic) flow in the nonequilibrium regime selects the cathodic diffusion layer width as the dominant length scale for morphological instability and emerging dendrites.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 093701] Published Thu Sep 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>I. Rubinstein and B. Zaltzman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Attributing equity gaps to course structure in introductory physics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.020126</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.020126"/>
        <updated>2023-09-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): David J. Webb and Cassandra A. Paul
Changes to the structure of introductory physics courses can eliminate some demographic grade gaps.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 19, 020126] Published Wed Sep 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David J. Webb and Cassandra A. Paul</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tritium Beta Spectrum Measurement and Neutrino Mass Limit from Cyclotron Radiation Emission Spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.102502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.102502"/>
        <updated>2023-09-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Ashtari Esfahani et al. (Project 8 Collaboration)
The first frequency-based limit on the neutrino’s mass sets the stage for next-generation experiments.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 102502] Published Wed Sep 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Ashtari Esfahani &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (Project 8 Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>