<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-01-11T00:54:43.861Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-01-11T00:54:43.862Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Origin of the Reactor Antineutrino Anomalies in Light of a New Summation Model with Parametrized ${β}^{−}$ Transitions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.021801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.021801"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Letourneau, V. Savu, D. Lhuillier, T. Lasserre, T. Materna, G. Mention, X. Mougeot, A. Onillon, L. Perisse, and M. Vivier
A new analysis finds that discrepancies between reactor neutrino experiments and theory may be the result of errors in the analysis of electron data that form the basis of the neutrino predictions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 021801] Published Tue Jan 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Letourneau, V. Savu, D. Lhuillier, T. Lasserre, T. Materna, G. Mention, X. Mougeot, A. Onillon, L. Perisse, and M. Vivier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multinucleon transfer mechanism in $^{250}\mathrm{Cf}+^{232}\mathrm{Th}$ collisions using the quantal transport description based on the stochastic mean-field approach]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.014609</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.014609"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Ayik, M. Arik, O. Yilmaz, B. Yilmaz, and A. S. Umar
The production of elements close to the superheavy island of stability, with Z>100, is one of the most appealing challenges in nuclear physics. Based on a stochastic extension of the time-dependent Hartree-Fock theory, this article presents accurate microscopic calculations of multinucleon transfer for the 250Cf+232Th system at Ec.m.=950 MeV. Isotope production cross sections are described without any adjustable parameters, thus providing a benchmark to new experimental searches.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, 014609] Published Tue Jan 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Ayik, M. Arik, O. Yilmaz, B. Yilmaz, and A. S. Umar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal topological marker]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.045111</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.045111"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wei Chen
The topological order of Dirac models in any dimension and symmetry class can be mapped to lattice sites by a universal topological marker. From the topological operator that extracts this marker, one can further define a nonlocal marker that detects topological phase transitions. Several prototype models such as the Su-Schrieffer-Heeger model, Majorana chain, Chern insulator, Bernevig-Hughes-Zhang model, chiral and helical p-wave superconductors, three-dimensional time-reversal symmetric topological insulators, among many others, are employed to demonstrate the ubiquity of these markers.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 045111] Published Tue Jan 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wei Chen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nature of visons in the perturbed ferromagnetic and antiferromagnetic Kitaev honeycomb models]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.045114</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.045114"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chuan Chen and Inti Sodemann Villadiego
The Kitaev honeycomb model features emergent anyons in the form of a Majorana fermion and a non-Abelian excitation known as the vison. While visons are static in the ideal model, certain perturbations can induce their motion. Here, it is demonstrated that the vison dynamics induced by Zeeman perturbations are sharply distinct in the ferromagnetic versus the antiferromagnetic model. Namely, in the ferromagnetic model the vison has a trivial translational symmetry and zero Berry curvature, whereas in the antiferromagnetic model it experiences a π flux per unit cell and has two bands with opposite Chern numbers, leading to an intrinsic contribution to the thermal Hall effect.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 045114] Published Tue Jan 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chuan Chen and Inti Sodemann Villadiego</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generation of Circulating Cavity Magnon Polaritons]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014030</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014030"/>
        <updated>2023-01-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jeremy Bourhill, Weichao Yu, Vincent Vlaminck, Gerrit E. W. Bauer, Giuseppe Ruoso, and Vincent Castel
In a circulating cavity magnon polariton (quantized spin wave plus photon, resonating in a microwave chamber), the hybrid state and a noninteracting photonic state rotate in opposite directions—an important phenomenon for generating chiral states of electromagnetic modes in cavity magnonics and microwave engineering, to impart angular momentum upon standing waves. This study demonstrates the unidirectional nature of the mode propagation, paving the way for the generation of a high-power microwave beam with high coherence and narrow bandwidth. The authors also demonstrate how the unidirectional mode propagation results in nonreciprocity of the mode’s transmission amplitudes and phases.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 014030] Published Tue Jan 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jeremy Bourhill, Weichao Yu, Vincent Vlaminck, Gerrit E. W. Bauer, Giuseppe Ruoso, and Vincent Castel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Buoyancy-Induced Convection Driven by Frontal Polymerization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.028101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.028101"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Y. Gao, J. E. Paul, M. Chen, L. Hong, L. P. Chamorro, N. R. Sottos, and P. H. Geubelle
A model of frontal polymerization for a reaction-diffusion-convection fluid enables fabrication of polymeric materials with controllable patterns and heterogeneous properties in closed-mold systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 028101] Published Mon Jan 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Y. Gao, J. E. Paul, M. Chen, L. Hong, L. P. Chamorro, N. R. Sottos, and P. H. Geubelle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mechanical impact on a breath figure]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.013601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.013601"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): L. Betti, C. Cohen, and X. Noblin
We performed a new experiment of mechanical impact on a plate supporting a breath figure on its bottom surface. Although breath figures mature usually slowly, we show that the droplets pattern evolves here dramatically in a few milliseconds leading to a strong droplets number reduction above a threshold in acceleration. We interpret this by the droplets radii oscillations produced which then induce droplets contacting and coalescing with each other in a fascinating manner. Introducing an effective Bond number, coupling the droplets’ average initial radii and the acceleration amplitude, leads to a data collapse on a single master curve.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 013601] Published Mon Jan 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L. Betti, C. Cohen, and X. Noblin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fermi operator expansion method for nuclei and inhomogeneous matter with a nuclear energy density functional]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.015802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.015802"/>
        <updated>2023-01-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Takashi Nakatsukasa
Calculations for nuclear structure at high excitation energy or of nuclear matter in explosive stellar phenomena and neutron stars require intensive computations. The author tests the performance of a numerical method based on Fermi operator expansion that requires neither diagonalization nor Gram-Schmidt orthonormalization. The approach is suitable for massively parallel computing with distributed memory, and the calculations promise to scale well for large space sizes. Applied to finite nuclei and inhomogeneous nuclear matter, the method is efficient at high temperature, and the calculations clearly show the liquid-gas phase transition.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, 015802] Published Mon Jan 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Takashi Nakatsukasa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robustness and Universality in Organelle Size Control]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.018401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.018401"/>
        <updated>2023-01-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kiandokht Panjtan Amiri, Asa Kalish, and Shankar Mukherji
A new “bursty growth” model for organelles—internal components of biological cells—helps explain observed size fluctuations.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 018401] Published Fri Jan 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kiandokht Panjtan Amiri, Asa Kalish, and Shankar Mukherji</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andreev reflection spectroscopy in strongly paired superconductors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L020502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L020502"/>
        <updated>2023-01-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Cyprian Lewandowski, Étienne Lantagne-Hurtubise, Alex Thomson, Stevan Nadj-Perge, and Jason Alicea
One of the challenges in the pursuit of solid state BEC superconductors is the need for unambiguous experimental signatures. Here, the authors propose a new signature, relying on Andreev reflection, which distinguishes BEC from BCS superconductors. They demonstrate that, in a standard tunneling spectroscopy setup, a BEC superconductor exhibits suppressed Andreev reflection; however, if the tunneling barrier becomes a potential well, then appreciable Andreev reflection can be revived. Their predictions can be probed in various architectures that are also discussed.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L020502] Published Fri Jan 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cyprian Lewandowski, Étienne Lantagne-Hurtubise, Alex Thomson, Stevan Nadj-Perge, and Jason Alicea</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intense continuous cold-atom source]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.013302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.013302"/>
        <updated>2023-01-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): William Huntington, Jeremy Glick, Michael Borysow, and Daniel J. Heinzen
The authors demonstrate an intense, continuous cold atomic beam generated via postnozzle seeding of a supersonic 4He jet with 7Li atoms, which is comparable to the highest flux sources based on laser cooling. The technique could potentially be widely applicable to any paramagnetic atom or molecule.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 013302] Published Fri Jan 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>William Huntington, Jeremy Glick, Michael Borysow, and Daniel J. Heinzen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring the Regime of Fragmentation in Strongly Tilted Fermi-Hubbard Chains]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.010201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.010201"/>
        <updated>2023-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Thomas Kohlert, Sebastian Scherg, Pablo Sala, Frank Pollmann, Bharath Hebbe Madhusudhana, Immanuel Bloch, and Monika Aidelsburger
A strongly tilted 1D Fermi-Hubbard model shows signatures of Hilbert-space fragmentation in its relaxation dynamics.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 010201] Published Thu Jan 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Kohlert, Sebastian Scherg, Pablo Sala, Frank Pollmann, Bharath Hebbe Madhusudhana, Immanuel Bloch, and Monika Aidelsburger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of Acoustic Non-Hermitian Bloch Braids and Associated Topological Phase Transitions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.017201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.017201"/>
        <updated>2023-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Qicheng Zhang, Yitong Li, Huanfa Sun, Xun Liu, Luekai Zhao, Xiling Feng, Xiying Fan, and Chunyin Qiu
Topologically braided non-Hermitian Bloch bands in acoustics are synthesized by a simple binary cavity-tube system.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 017201] Published Thu Jan 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qicheng Zhang, Yitong Li, Huanfa Sun, Xun Liu, Luekai Zhao, Xiling Feng, Xiying Fan, and Chunyin Qiu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gravity currents in the cabbeling regime]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.014502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.014502"/>
        <updated>2023-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Andrew P. Grace, Marek Stastna, Kevin G. Lamb, and K. Andrea Scott
Freshwater has been shown to have a maximum density at about four degrees Celsius, and this leads to a phenomenon known as cabbeling. Cabbeling occurs when masses of water on different sides of the temperature of maximum density mix and create a denser mass. What happens when intruding and ambient temperatures in a gravity current are on opposite sides of the temperature of maximum density? How does cabbeling affect the evolution characteristics of gravity currents, and what sort of long term behavior arises?

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 014502] Published Thu Jan 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew P. Grace, Marek Stastna, Kevin G. Lamb, and K. Andrea Scott</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valence and magnetism in ${\mathrm{EuPd}}_{3}{\mathrm{S}}_{4}$ and ${(\mathrm{Y},\mathrm{La})}_{x}{\mathrm{Eu}}_{1−x}{\mathrm{Pd}}_{3}{\mathrm{S}}_{4}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.014402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.014402"/>
        <updated>2023-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. H. Ryan, Sergey L. Bud'ko, Brinda Kuthanazhi, and Paul C. Canfield
The double Dirac candidate EuPd3S4 appears to exhibit a roughly 50:50 mixture of Eu2+ and Eu3+. Substituting yttrium rapidly drives the remaining europium divalent, whereas lanthanum has the opposite effect. Analysis shows that average site volumes play a dominant role in the valence distribution suggesting that local strains matter more than electron count. Remarkably, lanthanum substitution also promotes valence instability leading to the appearance of intermediate valence “Eu2.5+”, the fraction of which increases with both lanthanum content and temperature. Extrapolation of the onset temperature to zero lanthanum predicts Tonset ∼ 340 K matching recent reports of a structural transition attributed to a loss of valence order.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 014402] Published Thu Jan 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. H. Ryan, Sergey L. Bud'ko, Brinda Kuthanazhi, and Paul C. Canfield</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optical properties and carrier localization in the layered phosphide ${\mathrm{EuCd}}_{2}{\mathrm{P}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.045106</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.045106"/>
        <updated>2023-01-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. C. Homes, Z.-C. Wang, K. Fruhling, and F. Tafti
The layered phosphide EuCd2P2 is a poor metal that is distinguished by an anomalous increase in the resistivity at ≃18 K, well above the Napos{e}el transition at TN≃11.5 K, by nearly two orders of magnitude, before reverting back to a metallic state below TN. The addition and removal of free carriers has a small effect on the optical conductivity. However, it has a dramatic effect on the electronic screening of the infrared-active lattice modes, yielding dramatically different line shapes in the reflectivity (see image), providing clues to the mechanism driving this unusual behavior.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 045106] Published Thu Jan 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. C. Homes, Z.-C. Wang, K. Fruhling, and F. Tafti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charge-induced phase transition in encapsulated $\mathrm{Hf}{\mathrm{Te}}_{2}$ nanoribbons]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.L013001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.L013001"/>
        <updated>2023-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Derek Popple, Mehmet Dogan, Tony Vo Hoang, Scott Stonemeyer, Peter Ercius, Karen C. Bustillo, Marvin Cohen, and Alex Zettl
Reversibly altering the physical structure of a material on-demand can lead to direct manipulation of its electronic properties. In this work a localized electron beam is used to switch regions of nanotube-encapsulated HfTe2 nanoribbons between the metallic 1T phase and the previously experimentally inaccessible semiconducting 1H phase. The change is observed in-situ in a high-resolution transmission electron microscope. Complementary theoretical studies provide details of the electronic structure of each phase and the phase change energetics.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, L013001] Published Wed Jan 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Derek Popple, Mehmet Dogan, Tony Vo Hoang, Scott Stonemeyer, Peter Ercius, Karen C. Bustillo, Marvin Cohen, and Alex Zettl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological Speed Limit]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.010402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.010402"/>
        <updated>2023-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tan Van Vu and Keiji Saito
Quantum speed limits due to underlying topological structure are derived and applied to chemical reactions and interacting bosons.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 010402] Published Wed Jan 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tan Van Vu and Keiji Saito</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Control over Berry Curvature Dipole with Electric Field in ${\mathrm{WTe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.016301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.016301"/>
        <updated>2023-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xing-Guo Ye, Huiying Liu, Peng-Fei Zhu, Wen-Zheng Xu, Shengyuan A. Yang, Nianze Shang, Kaihui Liu, and Zhi-Min Liao
Charge transport experiments in thin exfoliated flakes of WTe2 suggest the existence of an electric-field tunable Berry curvature.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 016301] Published Wed Jan 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xing-Guo Ye, Huiying Liu, Peng-Fei Zhu, Wen-Zheng Xu, Shengyuan A. Yang, Nianze Shang, Kaihui Liu, and Zhi-Min Liao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Double-diffusive transport in multicomponent vertical convection]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.013501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.013501"/>
        <updated>2023-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christopher J. Howland, Roberto Verzicco, and Detlef Lohse
At steep ice faces submerged in the ocean, convection is driven by differences in salt concentration, yet ablation of the ice is controlled by a mixture of heat and salt fluxes. The differing molecular diffusivities of heat and salt play a key role in setting these fluxes due to thin, diffusive boundary layers at the ice-ocean interface. We analyze such boundary layers by simulating convection between two vertical plates of fixed temperature and salinity, and varying their relative diffusivities, finding that the ratio of fluxes transitions between scaling regimes at a critical Prandtl number. These results provide physical insight for future parameterization of steep ice-ocean interfaces.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 013501] Published Wed Jan 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher J. Howland, Roberto Verzicco, and Detlef Lohse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microscopic study of fusion reactions with a weakly bound nucleus: Effects of deformed halo]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.L011601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.L011601"/>
        <updated>2023-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xiang-Xiang Sun (孙向向) and Lu Guo (郭璐)
New modeling explains the relatively high fusion reaction probabilities of halo nuclei, which are composed of a dense core surrounded by a “satellite” of one or two nucleons.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, L011601] Published Wed Jan 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiang-Xiang Sun (孙向向) and Lu Guo (郭璐)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interplay between Geometry, Fluid Dynamics, and Structure in the Ventricles of the Human Heart]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014006</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014006"/>
        <updated>2023-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dario Collia, Giulia Pedrizzetti, Tomoyuki Sato, Daisuke Matsubara, Luigino Zovatto, Massimiliano Gei, Anirban Banerjee, and Gianni Pedrizzetti
Heart failure is a progressive pathology that represents the main life-threatening cardiac disease. Its models are typically based on clinical observations and are not consistently predictive. This study employs an approach based on both fluid dynamics and solid mechanics to uncover the flow-tissue interplay that may anticipate the development of heart failure. The physiological fluid-structure interaction is analyzed in children with a single right ventricle (SRV), where the right ventricle has been surgically transformed to take on the role of an underdeveloped left ventricle. The results provide a physics-based explanation for the observed clinical outcome in these patients.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 014006] Published Wed Jan 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dario Collia, Giulia Pedrizzetti, Tomoyuki Sato, Daisuke Matsubara, Luigino Zovatto, Massimiliano Gei, Anirban Banerjee, and Gianni Pedrizzetti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Subnanometer Control of the Heteroepitaxial Growth of Multimicrometer-Thick $\mathrm{Ge}$/($\mathrm{Si}$,$\mathrm{Ge}$) Quantum Cascade Structures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014011</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014011"/>
        <updated>2023-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Enrico Talamas Simola, Michele Montanari, Cedric Corley-Wiciak, Luciana Di Gaspare, Luca Persichetti, Marvin H. Zöllner, Markus A. Schubert, Tommaso Venanzi, Marina Cagnon Trouche, Michele Ortolani, Francesco Mattioli, Gianfranco Sfuncia, Giuseppe Nicotra, Giovanni Capellini, Michele Virgilio, and Monica De Seta
Thick Ge/(Si,Ge) multiple-quantum-well heterostructures are interesting for silicon-integrated optoelectronic devices operating in the midinfrared and terahertz spectral regions. The epitaxy of such structures becomes increasingly challenging as their thickness increases, due to the accumulation of strain and defects. This study proves that ultrahigh-vacuum chemical vapor deposition allows for subnanometer control of the compositional profile throughout micrometer-thick strain-compensated multilayered structures with very low defect density. Here terahertz spectroscopy plus numerical simulation allows characterization at higher sensitivity and resolution than standard techniques.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 014011] Published Wed Jan 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Enrico Talamas Simola, Michele Montanari, Cedric Corley-Wiciak, Luciana Di Gaspare, Luca Persichetti, Marvin H. Zöllner, Markus A. Schubert, Tommaso Venanzi, Marina Cagnon Trouche, Michele Ortolani, Francesco Mattioli, Gianfranco Sfuncia, Giuseppe Nicotra, Giovanni Capellini, Michele Virgilio, and Monica De Seta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anomaly detection at the European X-ray Free Electron Laser using a parity-space-based method]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.012801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.012801"/>
        <updated>2023-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Eichler, J. Branlard, and J. H. K. Timm
A new parity space method is used to detect anomalies in the operation of large-scale superconducting accelerators.
[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 26, 012801] Published Wed Jan 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Eichler, J. Branlard, and J. H. K. Timm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SuperKEKB vacuum system operation in the last 6 years operation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.013201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.013201"/>
        <updated>2023-01-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Y. Suetsugu, K. Shibata, T. Ishibashi, M. Shirai, S. Terui, K. Kanazawa, H. Hisamatsu, and M. L. Yao
The vacuum-system performance for the SuperKEKB electron and positron rings will inform the vacuum design of future high-current storage rings.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 26, 013201] Published Wed Jan 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Y. Suetsugu, K. Shibata, T. Ishibashi, M. Shirai, S. Terui, K. Kanazawa, H. Hisamatsu, and M. L. Yao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anomalous Diffusion of Deformable Particles in a Honeycomb Network]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.014001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.014001"/>
        <updated>2023-01-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zaiyi Shen, Franck Plouraboué, Juho S. Lintuvuori, Hengdi Zhang, Mehdi Abbasi, and Chaouqi Misbah
Researchers have studied how irregularly shaped particles travel through microchannels. Their work could have relevance to the transport of red blood cells through capillaries.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 014001] Published Tue Jan 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zaiyi Shen, Franck Plouraboué, Juho S. Lintuvuori, Hengdi Zhang, Mehdi Abbasi, and Chaouqi Misbah</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Imaging an Acoustic Topological Edge Mode on a Patterned Substrate with Microwave Impedance Microscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.014001"/>
        <updated>2023-01-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Y. Nii and Y. Onose
The topological properties of an acoustic metamaterial’s phononic band structure would be useful for developing functional acoustic and thermal devices. While previous demonstrations of topological properties have been limited to low-frequency airborne sound, high-frequency acoustic waveguides utilizing the topological edge state are increasingly in demand for quantum technologies, sensing, and microwave communication. In this work, the authors use innovative microscopy to visualize topological acoustic edge states at frequencies as high as 2.4 GHz on a patterned substrate, which bodes well for the feasibility of topological surface-acoustic-wave devices.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 014001] Published Tue Jan 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Y. Nii and Y. Onose</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strong Kinetic-Inductance Kerr Nonlinearity with Titanium Nitride Nanowires]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064088</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064088"/>
        <updated>2022-12-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chaitali Joshi, Wenyuan Chen, Henry G. LeDuc, Peter K. Day, and Mohammad Mirhosseini
The kinetic inductance of charge carriers in disordered superconductors provides a broadband low-loss source of nonlinear electromagnetic response. This work investigates TiN nanowires as an alternative to Josephson junctions for applications involving elevated temperatures, higher frequencies, and strong magnetic fields. An extreme nanowire geometry for TiN microwave resonators leads to current-density concentration and enhanced self-Kerr coefficient, yielding a nonlinearity-to-loss ratio as high as 21% and quality factor exceeding 10,000. Such devices may find application in quantum frequency conversion of microwave photons, and with improvement might attain strong quantum nonlinearity.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 064088] Published Wed Dec 28, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chaitali Joshi, Wenyuan Chen, Henry G. LeDuc, Peter K. Day, and Mohammad Mirhosseini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quasibound state in the $\overline{K}NNN$ system]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.106.064006</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.106.064006"/>
        <updated>2022-12-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. V. Shevchenko
The attractive nature of the antikaon-nucleon interaction suggests that few-body systems of antikaons and nucleons can exist. The author presents a new study of the exotic K¯NNN system. Four-body Faddeev-type equations are used to evaluate the binding energy and the width of the quasi-bound state in the system. The dependence of the results on the two-body antikaon-nucleon and nucleon-nucleon interactions is quantified.

[Phys. Rev. C 106, 064006] Published Tue Dec 27, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. V. Shevchenko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Langevin dynamics of generalized spins as SU($N$) coherent states]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.235154</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.235154"/>
        <updated>2022-12-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): David Dahlbom, Cole Miles, Hao Zhang, Cristian D. Batista, and Kipton Barros
Quantum spin states often contain additional structure beyond the usual angular momentum dipole. The classical Landau-Lifshitz spin dynamics may be generalized to model the coupled dynamics of dipoles, quadrupoles, and higher order multipoles. This paper introduces temperature-dependent Langevin noise and damping terms to the generalized spin dynamics. High numerical efficiency is possible by working with coherent states in the Schrödinger picture. The method is illustrated via simulation of magnetic skyrmion dynamics both in and out of equilibrium.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 235154] Published Tue Dec 27, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Dahlbom, Cole Miles, Hao Zhang, Cristian D. Batista, and Kipton Barros</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fracturing in Wet Granular Media Illuminated by Photoporomechanics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064081</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064081"/>
        <updated>2022-12-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yue Meng, Wei Li, and Ruben Juanes
Unraveling the complex behavior of wet granular media has been challenging, because the effective stresses transmitted through the particles have remained unobservable. The authors use their recently developed extension of photoelasticity for coupled fluid-granular systems to image particle stresses during fracture by air injection in an oil-saturated granular pack. They discover two states of the granular medium evolving with the fractures, plus an “effective-stress shadow” behind the propagating fracture tips. This study points out the power of photoporomechanics for studying coupled fluid-solid processes in granular media, including energy recovery, gas venting, and geohazards.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 064081] Published Tue Dec 27, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yue Meng, Wei Li, and Ruben Juanes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum speed limit of a noisy continuous-variable system]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.062438</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.062438"/>
        <updated>2022-12-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wei Wu and Jun-Hong An
The quantum speed limit quantifies the minimum time it takes for a system to evolve under the constraint of quantum mechanics. Here, the authors investigate the quantum speed limit in a continuous-variable system undergoing non-Markovian noise. Their results imply that this limit may be steerable with the use of spectral engineering.

[Phys. Rev. A 106, 062438] Published Tue Dec 27, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wei Wu and Jun-Hong An</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parity and Singlet-Triplet High-Fidelity Readout in a Silicon Double Quantum Dot at 0.5 K]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.3.040335</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.3.040335"/>
        <updated>2022-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): David J. Niegemann, Victor El-Homsy, Baptiste Jadot, Martin Nurizzo, Bruna Cardoso-Paz, Emmanuel Chanrion, Matthieu Dartiailh, Bernhard Klemt, Vivien Thiney, Christopher Bäuerle, Pierre-André Mortemousque, Benoit Bertrand, Heimanu Niebojewski, Maud Vinet, Franck Balestro, Tristan Meunier, and Matias Urdampilleta
Rapid and high-fidelity single-shot readout of spins is demonstrated by combining scalable fabrication technology, Pauli spin blockade, and rf reflectometry on a single-lead quantum dot.

[PRX Quantum 3, 040335] Published Mon Dec 26, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David J. Niegemann, Victor El-Homsy, Baptiste Jadot, Martin Nurizzo, Bruna Cardoso-Paz, Emmanuel Chanrion, Matthieu Dartiailh, Bernhard Klemt, Vivien Thiney, Christopher Bäuerle, Pierre-André Mortemousque, Benoit Bertrand, Heimanu Niebojewski, Maud Vinet, Franck Balestro, Tristan Meunier, and Matias Urdampilleta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tensor electromagnetism and emergent elasticity in jammed solids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.065004</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.065004"/>
        <updated>2022-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jishnu N. Nampoothiri, Michael D'Eon, Kabir Ramola, Bulbul Chakraborty, and Subhro Bhattacharjee
The classical theory of elasticity has trouble describing disordered jammed solids, such as sandpiles, because they have no unique reference configurations (e.g. a crystal structure). This paper presents a description based on force and torque balance that does not need a reference configuration, and that has a formal similarity with a generalized theory of electromagnetism.

[Phys. Rev. E 106, 065004] Published Mon Dec 26, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jishnu N. Nampoothiri, Michael D'Eon, Kabir Ramola, Bulbul Chakraborty, and Subhro Bhattacharjee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interwoven atypical quantum states in ${\mathrm{CeLiBi}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.214433</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.214433"/>
        <updated>2022-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mitchell M. Bordelon, Clément Girod, Filip Ronning, Km Rubi, Neil Harrison, Joe D. Thompson, Clarina dela Cruz, Sean M. Thomas, Eric D. Bauer, and Priscila F. S. Rosa
Typically, exotic quantum phases reside in different materials, but they can coexist given ideal conditions. This underexplored regime is realized in CeLiBi2, which is found to exhibit multiple atypical quantum phases including incommensurate cycloidal magnetic order, hard-axis metamagnetism, large and linear magnetoresistance, and mobile ultralight carriers. These results indicate that CeLiBi2 is an ideal material to experimentally and theoretically explore simultaneous quantum phenomena and their interdependent relationships.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 214433] Published Mon Dec 26, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mitchell M. Bordelon, Clément Girod, Filip Ronning, Km Rubi, Neil Harrison, Joe D. Thompson, Clarina dela Cruz, Sean M. Thomas, Eric D. Bauer, and Priscila F. S. Rosa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enhanced skyrmion metastability under applied strain in FeGe]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.214434</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.214434"/>
        <updated>2022-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. T. Littlehales, L. A. Turnbull, M. N. Wilson, M. T. Birch, H. Popescu, N. Jaouen, J. A. T. Verezhak, G. Balakrishnan, and P. D. Hatton
Magnetic skyrmions offer a rich variety of exotic behaviors that have fascinated researchers in recent years. Here, the authors study the effects of mechanical strain on skyrmions in FeGe with x-ray magnetic holographic imaging and small angle x-ray scattering, and demonstrate enhancement of the metastable skyrmion energy barriers. Real-space imaging of the magnetization allows the authors to quantify the impact of strain on the magnetic spin textures, and discuss the effects of helical reorientations on skyrmion stability and metastability.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 214434] Published Mon Dec 26, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. T. Littlehales, L. A. Turnbull, M. N. Wilson, M. T. Birch, H. Popescu, N. Jaouen, J. A. T. Verezhak, G. Balakrishnan, and P. D. Hatton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Temperature-dependent zero-field splittings in graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.245141</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.245141"/>
        <updated>2022-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. Bray, K. Maussang, C. Consejo, J. A. Delgado-Notario, S. Krishtopenko, I. Yahniuk, S. Gebert, S. Ruffenach, K. Dinar, E. Moench, J. Eroms, K. Indykiewicz, B. Jouault, J. Torres, Y. M. Meziani, W. Knap, A. Yurgens, S. D. Ganichev, and F. Teppe
The topological bandgap of graphene induced by intrinsic spin-orbit coupling is so narrow that it was experimentally identified for the first time only in 2019. In this work, the authors use a specific electron spin resonance technique, based on photoconductivity measurements using graphene-based terahertz detectors, to probe zero-field splittings of graphene as a function of temperature. They demonstrate experimentally that the intrinsic spin-orbit coupling and the staggered sublattice potential, which reduces the topological gap, are both temperature dependent.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 245141] Published Mon Dec 26, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. Bray, K. Maussang, C. Consejo, J. A. Delgado-Notario, S. Krishtopenko, I. Yahniuk, S. Gebert, S. Ruffenach, K. Dinar, E. Moench, J. Eroms, K. Indykiewicz, B. Jouault, J. Torres, Y. M. Meziani, W. Knap, A. Yurgens, S. D. Ganichev, and F. Teppe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Untrained Physically Informed Neural Network for Image Reconstruction of Magnetic Field Sources]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064076</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064076"/>
        <updated>2022-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A.E.E. Dubois, D.A. Broadway, A. Stark, M.A. Tschudin, A.J. Healey, S.D. Huber, J.-P. Tetienne, E. Greplova, and P. Maletinsky
Magnetic materials are a vital resource in designing energy-efficient information technologies. To try to learn how magnetism develops in ultrathin systems, we measure, but deducing the physics afterward is an ill-posed problem. This study uses neural networks to facilitate the reconstruction of the underlying magnetic textures of thin magnets through measurements of their stray fields. The technique is surprisingly robust to experimental noise, and can reliably reconstruct magnetism in arbitrary directions. Importantly, prior training of the network is not required, and the technique is broadly applicable for solving ill-posed inverse problems when the forward problem is well defined.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 064076] Published Mon Dec 26, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A.E.E. Dubois, D.A. Broadway, A. Stark, M.A. Tschudin, A.J. Healey, S.D. Huber, J.-P. Tetienne, E. Greplova, and P. Maletinsky</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flows in Straws: Viscous Flows in One-Dimensional Metamaterial]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064077</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064077"/>
        <updated>2022-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Peter Breitman, Michael Pukshansky, Anna Zigelman, Ezra Ben Abu, Ofek Peretz, Sefi Givli, and Amir D. Gat
The authors study the interaction between a viscous flow and a one-dimensional mechanical metamaterial composed of bistable unit cells, much like a drinking straw. Their twofold model shows excellent agreement with experimental results. While prior studies have focused on tailoring unit-cell structure to obtain a desired multistable behavior, here the viscous fluid allows tuning of rate-dependent properties and nonlocal interaction between unit cells. The ability to manipulate both structural and nonlocal rate-related properties points to the development of smart materials with tunable kinetic relations, large reversible deformations, and tailored dynamic properties.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 064077] Published Mon Dec 26, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Breitman, Michael Pukshansky, Anna Zigelman, Ezra Ben Abu, Ofek Peretz, Sefi Givli, and Amir D. Gat</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retrieving information from a black hole using quantum machine learning]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.062434</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.062434"/>
        <updated>2022-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lorenzo Leone, Salvatore F. E. Oliviero, Stefano Piemontese, Sarah True, and Alioscia Hamma
Information can be retrieved from a black hole that is sufficiently scrambling, assuming that the retriever has perfect control of the emitted Hawking radiation and perfect knowledge of the internal dynamics of the black hole. In this paper, the authors show that for black holes modeled by a certain class of random quantum circuits, information can be retrieved by using quantum machine learning to analyze out-of-time-order correlation functions.

[Phys. Rev. A 106, 062434] Published Mon Dec 26, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lorenzo Leone, Salvatore F. E. Oliviero, Stefano Piemontese, Sarah True, and Alioscia Hamma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fate of the critical endpoint at large ${N}_{c}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.116016</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.116016"/>
        <updated>2022-12-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Péter Kovács, Győző Kovács, and Francesco Giacosa
The authors study the phase diagram of QCD-like theories, in the plane of temperature and chemical potential, using a Polyakov loop model. As the number of colors increases, a crossover line for the chiral transition enlarges, splits from that for deconfinement, and then turns into a first order line for deconfinement.

[Phys. Rev. D 106, 116016] Published Fri Dec 23, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Péter Kovács, Győző Kovács, and Francesco Giacosa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Holographic entropy production in a Bjorken expanding hot and dense strongly coupled quantum fluid]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.126023</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.126023"/>
        <updated>2022-12-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Romulo Rougemont and Willians Barreto
The authors study the dynamics of droplets of quark-gluon plasma created in heavy iron collisions. The relativistic quantum fluid undergoes Bjorken flow expansion and is modeled as conformal N=4 supersymmetric Yang-Mills plasma. In particular, they investigate the holographic entropy production far from equilibrium where the horizon area is no longer a proper measure for the entropy but the area of a dynamic apparent horizon is assumed to be the right dual observable.

[Phys. Rev. D 106, 126023] Published Fri Dec 23, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Romulo Rougemont and Willians Barreto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Higher derivative corrections and ${\mathrm{AdS}}_{5}$ black holes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.L121903</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.L121903"/>
        <updated>2022-12-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nikolay Bobev, Vasil Dimitrov, Valentin Reys, and Annelien Vekemans
The authors investigate the precise holography between a 5d gauged supergravity and the dual superconformal field theory (CFT) on the 4d boundary. They show that four-derivative contributions to the action of supersymmetric black holes on the supergravity site matches precisely with certain subleading terms in the CFT index which are determined by anomalies.

[Phys. Rev. D 106, L121903] Published Fri Dec 23, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nikolay Bobev, Vasil Dimitrov, Valentin Reys, and Annelien Vekemans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Applications of persistent homology in nuclear collisions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.106.064912</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.106.064912"/>
        <updated>2022-12-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Greg Hamilton, Travis Dore, and Christopher Plumberg
This paper applies methods of persistent homology—an approach used in topological data analysis to identify and study features that persist over different length scales—to heavy-ion collision data. It introduces a novel set of observables for the quantitative characterization of nuclear collisions and of their evolution. The work offers new ways to analyze the long-range flow correlations that have been interpreted theoretically with relativistic fluid dynamical models.

[Phys. Rev. C 106, 064912] Published Fri Dec 23, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Greg Hamilton, Travis Dore, and Christopher Plumberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symmetry-dependent ultrafast manipulation of nanoscale magnetic domains]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.224424</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.224424"/>
        <updated>2022-12-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nanna Zhou Hagström et al.
There are conflicting reports that ~100 femtosecond optical pumping causes ultrafast magnetic domain rearrangement. Such rearrangement implies a potential for unprecedented domain wall speeds. Ultrafast distortions in diffraction features via magnetic small angle x-ray scattering have been seen in some studies, while they have been absent in others. Here, the controversy is resolved by measuring a sample with domain-pattern symmetry varying from labyrinths to stripes. Importantly, spatial rearrangement occurs with labyrinths but not with stripes, suggesting novel and unexpected physics yet to be understood.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 224424] Published Fri Dec 23, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nanna Zhou Hagström &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Resonant Nanopumps: ac Gate Voltages in Conical Nanopores Induce Directed Electrolyte Flow]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.264501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.264501"/>
        <updated>2022-12-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aaron D. Ratschow, Doyel Pandey, Benno Liebchen, Somnath Bhattacharyya, and Steffen Hardt
A design for a nanopump that uses an alternating electric field could allow researchers greater control over nanoscale fluid flows.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 264501] Published Thu Dec 22, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aaron D. Ratschow, Doyel Pandey, Benno Liebchen, Somnath Bhattacharyya, and Steffen Hardt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phonon Thermal Hall Conductivity from Scattering with Collective Fluctuations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.12.041031</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.12.041031"/>
        <updated>2022-12-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Léo Mangeolle, Leon Balents, and Lucile Savary
For a long time, researchers assumed that phonons could not contribute to the so-called thermal Hall effect because of their lack of charge and spin. New work challenges this assumption.

[Phys. Rev. X 12, 041031] Published Wed Dec 21, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Léo Mangeolle, Leon Balents, and Lucile Savary</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Constraints on Heavy Decaying Dark Matter from 570 Days of LHAASO Observations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.261103</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.261103"/>
        <updated>2022-12-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zhen Cao et al. (LHAASO Collaboration)
The first measurements from a newly built gamma-ray observatory have been analyzed for signs of the decay of heavy dark matter, putting a lower limit on the hypothetical particles’ lifetime.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 261103] Published Wed Dec 21, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhen Cao &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHAASO Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin Berry curvature of the Haldane model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.235423</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.235423"/>
        <updated>2022-12-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Simon Michel and Michael Potthoff
The nearly adiabatic dynamics of magnetic moments exchange coupled to the spinful Haldane model, i.e., to a prototypical Chern insulator, is non-Hamiltonian due to the geometric spin torque. This results from the spin Berry curvature, which determines the feedback of the Berry phase, accumulated in the electron system, to the spin dynamics. Here, the authors study the spin Berry curvature in different parameter regimes, near a topological phase transition, and for magnetic moments coupled to the zigzag edge in a nanoribbon geometry.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 235423] Published Wed Dec 21, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Michel and Michael Potthoff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thermal conductivity and theory of inelastic scattering of phonons by collective fluctuations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.245139</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.245139"/>
        <updated>2022-12-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Léo Mangeolle, Leon Balents, and Lucile Savary
Understanding thermal Hall conductivity poses a theoretical challenge in insulators, where low-energy excitations carry no charge. In undoped cuprates, where the signal is large, we expect phonons contribute significantly to the effect. While there is no obvious universal mechanism whereby phonons break time-reversal symmetry and acquire chirality, this paper provides a general treatment of the phonon Hall effect from the inelastic scattering of phonons off of other excitations in quantum materials. As an application, magnetoelastic coupling in square-lattice Néel antiferromagnets is investigated thoroughly using the formalism developed in the first part of the paper.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 245139] Published Wed Dec 21, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Léo Mangeolle, Leon Balents, and Lucile Savary</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetic Imaging with Spin Defects in Hexagonal Boron Nitride]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.L061002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.L061002"/>
        <updated>2022-12-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): P. Kumar, F. Fabre, A. Durand, T. Clua-Provost, J. Li, J.H. Edgar, N. Rougemaille, J. Coraux, X. Marie, P. Renucci, C. Robert, I. Robert-Philip, B. Gil, G. Cassabois, A. Finco, and V. Jacques
This work bridges research on two-dimensional (2D) materials and quantum sensing technology by demonstrating that optically active spin defects in hexagonal boron nitride can be used for quantitative magnetic field imaging. As proof of concept, the authors image the magnetic field produced by CrTe2, a room-temperature van der Waals ferromagnet. This h-BN-based magnetic sensor offers high flexibility and the ability to be placed in atomic-scale proximity to a target sample, and thus is expected to find numerous applications in 2D materials research by offering a simple means to probe in situ the physics of van der Waals heterostructures.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, L061002] Published Wed Dec 21, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>P. Kumar, F. Fabre, A. Durand, T. Clua-Provost, J. Li, J.H. Edgar, N. Rougemaille, J. Coraux, X. Marie, P. Renucci, C. Robert, I. Robert-Philip, B. Gil, G. Cassabois, A. Finco, and V. Jacques</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Imaging the Ultrafast Coherent Control of a Skyrmion Crystal]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.12.041030</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.12.041030"/>
        <updated>2022-12-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Phoebe Tengdin, Benoit Truc, Alexey Sapozhnik, Lingyao Kong, Nina del Ser, Simone Gargiulo, Ivan Madan, Thomas Schönenberger, Priya R. Baral, Ping Che, Arnaud Magrez, Dirk Grundler, Henrik M. Rønnow, Thomas Lagrange, Jiadong Zang, Achim Rosch, and Fabrizio Carbone
Researchers control the rotation of a periodic array of magnetic quasiparticles by illuminating the system with a series of precisely timed polarized laser pulses.

[Phys. Rev. X 12, 041030] Published Tue Dec 20, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoebe Tengdin, Benoit Truc, Alexey Sapozhnik, Lingyao Kong, Nina del Ser, Simone Gargiulo, Ivan Madan, Thomas Schönenberger, Priya R. Baral, Ping Che, Arnaud Magrez, Dirk Grundler, Henrik M. Rønnow, Thomas Lagrange, Jiadong Zang, Achim Rosch, and Fabrizio Carbone</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin-wave study of magnetic perpendicular surface anisotropy in single crystalline MgO/Fe/MgO films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.6.124409</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.6.124409"/>
        <updated>2022-12-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Solano, O. Gladii, P. Kuntz, Y. Henry, D. Halley, and M. Bailleul
The authors report an experimental separation of the two perpendicular surface anisotropies present in MgO/Fe/MgO epitaxial films through a careful study of inhomogeneous magnetization dynamics. This is achieved by combining the strengths of two experimental techniques: the frequency broadband capabilities of ferromagnetic resonance and the precise determination of non-reciprocal propagation via propagating spin wave spectroscopy. This new experimental approach allows to separate the top and bottom perpendicular surface anisotropies often measured together in thin films, and it provides new light into the technologically-relevant ferromagnet/MgO interfaces and their effect on spin waves.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 6, 124409] Published Tue Dec 20, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Solano, O. Gladii, P. Kuntz, Y. Henry, D. Halley, and M. Bailleul</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Current-enabled optical conductivity of superconductors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L220504</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L220504"/>
        <updated>2022-12-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Michał Papaj and Joel E. Moore
While optical techniques are fundamental in the investigation of the superconducting state, in many clean superconductors the combination of particle-hole and inversion symmetries prevents momentum-conserving transitions. Here, the authors show that by driving supercurrent through the sample optical transitions across the superconducting gap become allowed even in clean single-band systems. As the signal depends strongly on the superconducting pairing as well as on the underlying normal state, supercurrent-driven optical conductivity provides a new way of determining the superconducting state properties.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L220504] Published Tue Dec 20, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michał Papaj and Joel E. Moore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of the Temperature Decrease in Evaporating Soap Films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.268001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.268001"/>
        <updated>2022-12-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): François Boulogne, Frédéric Restagno, and Emmanuelle Rio
The film surrounding a soap bubble can be up to 8 °C cooler than the environment, a finding that has implications for bubble stability.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 268001] Published Mon Dec 19, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>François Boulogne, Frédéric Restagno, and Emmanuelle Rio</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optical properties of SiV and GeV color centers in nanodiamonds under hydrostatic pressures up to 180 GPa]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.214109</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.214109"/>
        <updated>2022-12-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Baptiste Vindolet, Marie-Pierre Adam, Loïc Toraille, Mayeul Chipaux, Antoine Hilberer, Géraud Dupuy, Lukas Razinkovas, Audrius Alkauskas, Gergő Thiering, Adam Gali, Mary De Feudis, Midrel Wilfried Ngandeu Ngambou, Jocelyn Achard, Alexandre Tallaire, Martin Schmidt, Christoph Becher, and Jean-François Roch
The silicon-vacancy (SiV) and germanium-vacancy (GeV) centers in diamond have a sharp photoluminescence with high brightness. In this work, the photoluminescence of these centers is measured up to 180 GPa using nanodiamonds integrated in a diamond anvil cell. The results show blueshifts in the mean emission energy determined by the atomic radii of the impurity. The agreement with ab initio calculations based on the lattice compression of diamond demonstrates the potential of these centers for sensing under extreme pressure conditions.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 214109] Published Mon Dec 19, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Baptiste Vindolet, Marie-Pierre Adam, Loïc Toraille, Mayeul Chipaux, Antoine Hilberer, Géraud Dupuy, Lukas Razinkovas, Audrius Alkauskas, Gergő Thiering, Adam Gali, Mary De Feudis, Midrel Wilfried Ngandeu Ngambou, Jocelyn Achard, Alexandre Tallaire, Martin Schmidt, Christoph Becher, and Jean-François Roch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effects of leakage on the realization of a discrete time crystal in a chain of singlet-triplet qubits]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.245419</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.245419"/>
        <updated>2022-12-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Robert E. Throckmorton and S. Das Sarma
A chain of singlet-triplet qubits can be an excellent realization of the Ising model, which is in turn a good platform for realizing a discrete time crystal (DTC). However, leakage of the qubits out of their computational subspace may be a problem for such a realization. The authors show that, while leakage is indeed a serious problem for the realization of a DTC, it is not insurmountable - one can mitigate leakage by applying a magnetic field that alternates from one qubit to the next.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 245419] Published Mon Dec 19, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert E. Throckmorton and S. Das Sarma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interplay of ferromagnetism and spin-orbit coupling in ${\mathrm{Sr}}_{4}{\mathrm{Ru}}_{3}{\mathrm{O}}_{10}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L241107</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L241107"/>
        <updated>2022-12-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Izidor Benedičič, Masahiro Naritsuka, Luke C. Rhodes, Christopher Trainer, Yoshiko Nanao, Aaron B. Naden, Rosalba Fittipaldi, Veronica Granata, Mariateresa Lettieri, Antonio Vecchione, and Peter Wahl
Metamagnetic materials enable control of the ground state through applied magnetic fields. Understanding the microscopic origin of metamagnetism promises tuneability for new technological functionalities. Here, the authors use quasiparticle interference, magnetization measurements, and dilatometry in vector magnetic fields to establish the interplay between magnetism, spin-orbit coupling, microscopic electronic structure, and crystal structure of the trilayer ruthenate Sr4Ru3O10. These results reveal a surprising anisotropy in the properties of the material, highlighting the role of spin-orbit coupling.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L241107] Published Mon Dec 19, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Izidor Benedičič, Masahiro Naritsuka, Luke C. Rhodes, Christopher Trainer, Yoshiko Nanao, Aaron B. Naden, Rosalba Fittipaldi, Veronica Granata, Mariateresa Lettieri, Antonio Vecchione, and Peter Wahl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improved Coherent One-Way Quantum key Distribution for High-Loss Channels]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064053</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064053"/>
        <updated>2022-12-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Emilien Lavie and Charles C.-W. Lim
Coherent one-way quantum key distribution (COW-QKD) is a popular cryptography protocol, due to its fairly simple implementation and passive measurement device. Its security analysis is challenging, though, and extra assumptions or modifications are typically employed. Here the authors propose minor modifications to COW-QKD’s prepared states while retaining the original, fully passive measurement device, and generalize the “universal squashing” framework to analyze their system’s security. The results suggest that performance should be comparable to upper bounds from the literature, making this protocol a viable alternative to one based on phase-modulated coherent states.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 064053] Published Mon Dec 19, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emilien Lavie and Charles C.-W. Lim</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tight Bounds on the Convergence of Noisy Random Circuits to the Uniform Distribution]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.3.040329</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.3.040329"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Abhinav Deshpande, Pradeep Niroula, Oles Shtanko, Alexey V. Gorshkov, Bill Fefferman, and Michael J. Gullans
Properties of noisy random circuits are investigated, uncovering relevant consequences for the tightness of proof techniques in the field of quantum computational advantage.

[PRX Quantum 3, 040329] Published Fri Dec 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhinav Deshpande, Pradeep Niroula, Oles Shtanko, Alexey V. Gorshkov, Bill Fefferman, and Michael J. Gullans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Noise-Induced Quantum Synchronization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.250601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.250601"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Finn Schmolke and Eric Lutz
Noise-induced synchronization can occur in the quantum regime as well as the classical, and by applying noise to a single spin in an arbitrarily long chain, one can synchronize the entire chain.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 250601] Published Fri Dec 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Finn Schmolke and Eric Lutz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[de Sitter Bubbles from Anti–de Sitter Fluctuations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.251104</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.251104"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anxo Biasi, Oleg Evnin, and Spyros Sypsas
A theoretical model shows that de Sitter geometries may emerge locally in globally anti-de Sitter spacetimes via unstable fluctuations.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 251104] Published Fri Dec 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anxo Biasi, Oleg Evnin, and Spyros Sypsas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonmonotonic Friction due to Water Capillary Adhesion and Hydrogen Bonding at Multiasperity Interfaces]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.256101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.256101"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Liang Peng, Feng-Chun Hsia, Sander Woutersen, Mischa Bonn, Bart Weber, and Daniel Bonn
Experiments suggest that hydrogen bonding explains why a wet surface can have nearly twice as much friction as a dry surface.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 256101] Published Fri Dec 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liang Peng, Feng-Chun Hsia, Sander Woutersen, Mischa Bonn, Bart Weber, and Daniel Bonn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effect of scatterer interactions on photon transport in diffusing wave spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.064609</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.064609"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nicholas Sbalbi, Qi Li, and Eric M. Furst
Diffusing wave spectroscopy is a light scattering technique that is used to study the dynamics soft materials such as suspensions and gels. In this paper the authors show how interactions between the scattering particles affect the results: the effect is negligible if the scatterers are large enough, but it is significant when the particles are sufficiently small.

[Phys. Rev. E 106, 064609] Published Fri Dec 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicholas Sbalbi, Qi Li, and Eric M. Furst</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coexistence of trihexagonal and star-of-David pattern in the charge density wave of the kagome superconductor $A{\mathrm{V}}_{3}{\mathrm{Sb}}_{5}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L241106</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L241106"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yong Hu (胡勇), Xianxin Wu (吴贤新), Brenden R. Ortiz, Xinloong Han (韩欣龙), Nicholas C. Plumb, Stephen D. Wilson, Andreas P. Schnyder, and Ming Shi (史明)
Understanding the nature of the exotic CDW order is of crucial importance for uncovering its origin in the kagome superconductors AV3Sb5. Here, using angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy, the authors reveal characteristic double-band splittings and band reconstructions as well as band-folding gaps in the CDW phase. By combining the findings with density functional theory calculations, they demonstrate that two representative distortions in the kagome lattice - the star of David and the trihexagonal ones - intrinsically coexist in the CDW of CsV3Sb5.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L241106] Published Fri Dec 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yong Hu (胡勇), Xianxin Wu (吴贤新), Brenden R. Ortiz, Xinloong Han (韩欣龙), Nicholas C. Plumb, Stephen D. Wilson, Andreas P. Schnyder, and Ming Shi (史明)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Real-space Mott-Anderson electron localization with long-range interactions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.4.043192</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.4.043192"/>
        <updated>2022-12-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Antoine Marie, Derk P. Kooi, Juri Grossi, Michael Seidl, Ziad H. Musslimani, Klaas J. H. Giesbertz, and Paola Gori-Giorgi
Electrons that are delocalized in space because of quantum effects can become localized by an external disordered potential (Anderson localization) or by their mutual Coulomb repulsion (Mott/Wigner localization). A simple model addresses what happens when both effects are present, how to quantify the degree of localization, and whether approximate methods can capture the relevant physics.

[Phys. Rev. Research 4, 043192] Published Thu Dec 15, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Antoine Marie, Derk P. Kooi, Juri Grossi, Michael Seidl, Ziad H. Musslimani, Klaas J. H. Giesbertz, and Paola Gori-Giorgi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Liquid-Liquid Transition in Water from First Principles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.255702</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.255702"/>
        <updated>2022-12-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Thomas E. Gartner, III, Pablo M. Piaggi, Roberto Car, Athanassios Z. Panagiotopoulos, and Pablo G. Debenedetti
Computations support the 30-year-old idea that supercooled liquid water can undergo a transition between high- and low-density states.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 255702] Published Thu Dec 15, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas E. Gartner, III, Pablo M. Piaggi, Roberto Car, Athanassios Z. Panagiotopoulos, and Pablo G. Debenedetti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing Spin Dynamics on Diamond Surfaces Using a Single Quantum Sensor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.3.040328</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.3.040328"/>
        <updated>2022-12-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bo L. Dwyer, Lila V.H. Rodgers, Elana K. Urbach, Dolev Bluvstein, Sorawis Sangtawesin, Hengyun Zhou, Yahia Nassab, Mattias Fitzpatrick, Zhiyang Yuan, Kristiaan De Greve, Eric L. Peterson, Helena Knowles, Tamara Sumarac, Jyh-Pin Chou, Adam Gali, V.V. Dobrovitski, Mikhail D. Lukin, and Nathalie P. de Leon
A detailed analysis of the coherence decay of a nanoscale sensor shows that ubiquitous spins on the diamond surface are mobile and reveals the potential of local sensors to investigate the dynamics of complex systems.

[PRX Quantum 3, 040328] Published Wed Dec 14, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bo L. Dwyer, Lila V.H. Rodgers, Elana K. Urbach, Dolev Bluvstein, Sorawis Sangtawesin, Hengyun Zhou, Yahia Nassab, Mattias Fitzpatrick, Zhiyang Yuan, Kristiaan De Greve, Eric L. Peterson, Helena Knowles, Tamara Sumarac, Jyh-Pin Chou, Adam Gali, V.V. Dobrovitski, Mikhail D. Lukin, and Nathalie P. de Leon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phason-Dominated Thermal Transport in Fresnoite]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.255901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.255901"/>
        <updated>2022-12-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. E. Manley, A. F. May, B. L. Winn, D. L. Abernathy, R. Sahul, and R. P. Hermann
Heat-transport measurements and neutron-scattering spectroscopy probe a form of thermal conduction based on excitations called phasons.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 255901] Published Wed Dec 14, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. E. Manley, A. F. May, B. L. Winn, D. L. Abernathy, R. Sahul, and R. P. Hermann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chirality-induced intrinsic charge rectification in a tellurium-based field-effect transistor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L220403</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L220403"/>
        <updated>2022-12-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Daichi Hirobe, Yoji Nabei, and Hiroshi M. Yamamoto
Chiral conductors exhibit spin-related charge rectification but its controllability is largely unexplored. Here, the authors combine chiral charge rectification with a field-effect transistor of tellurium. They demonstrate a gate-variable hundredfold enhancement of the rectification efficiency and enable quantitative comparison with theoretical calculations which considered chiral spin-momentum locking alongside the Zeeman effect. With this comparison across a wide range of temperature, an unexpected deviation from the conventional theory is revealed, which hints at the relevance of chirality-induced spin selectivity at higher temperatures.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L220403] Published Wed Dec 14, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daichi Hirobe, Yoji Nabei, and Hiroshi M. Yamamoto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Autonomous Estimation of High-Dimensional Coulomb Diamonds from Sparse Measurements]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064040</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064040"/>
        <updated>2022-12-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anasua Chatterjee, Fabio Ansaloni, Torbjørn Rasmussen, Bertram Brovang, Federico Fedele, Heorhii Bohuslavskyi, Oswin Krause, and Ferdinand Kuemmeth
In spin-based quantum processors, each quantum dot of a qubit is populated by exactly one electron, which requires careful tuning of each gate voltage such that it lies inside the charge-stability region (the “Coulomb diamond”) associated with the dot array. However, mapping the boundary of a multidimensional Coulomb diamond by traditional dense raster scanning would take years, so the authors develop a sparse acquisition technique that autonomously learns Coulomb-diamond boundaries from a small number of measurements. Here we have hardware-triggered line searches in the gate-voltage space of a silicon quadruple dot, with smart search directions proposed by an active-learning algorithm.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 064040] Published Wed Dec 14, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anasua Chatterjee, Fabio Ansaloni, Torbjørn Rasmussen, Bertram Brovang, Federico Fedele, Heorhii Bohuslavskyi, Oswin Krause, and Ferdinand Kuemmeth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extraterrestrial Axion Search with the Breakthrough Listen Galactic Center Survey]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.251102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.251102"/>
        <updated>2022-12-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Joshua W. Foster, Samuel J. Witte, Matthew Lawson, Tim Linden, Vishal Gajjar, Christoph Weniger, and Benjamin R. Safdi
A neutron star’s ultrastrong magnetic field could create the conditions for uncloaking a promising dark matter candidate.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 251102] Published Tue Dec 13, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joshua W. Foster, Samuel J. Witte, Matthew Lawson, Tim Linden, Vishal Gajjar, Christoph Weniger, and Benjamin R. Safdi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>