<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2022-12-19T00:51:08.397Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2022-12-19T00:51:08.397Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tight Bounds on the Convergence of Noisy Random Circuits to the Uniform Distribution]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.3.040329</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.3.040329"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Abhinav Deshpande, Pradeep Niroula, Oles Shtanko, Alexey V. Gorshkov, Bill Fefferman, and Michael J. Gullans
Properties of noisy random circuits are investigated, uncovering relevant consequences for the tightness of proof techniques in the field of quantum computational advantage.

[PRX Quantum 3, 040329] Published Fri Dec 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhinav Deshpande, Pradeep Niroula, Oles Shtanko, Alexey V. Gorshkov, Bill Fefferman, and Michael J. Gullans</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Noise-Induced Quantum Synchronization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.250601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.250601"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Finn Schmolke and Eric Lutz
Noise-induced synchronization can occur in the quantum regime as well as the classical, and by applying noise to a single spin in an arbitrarily long chain, one can synchronize the entire chain.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 250601] Published Fri Dec 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Finn Schmolke and Eric Lutz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[de Sitter Bubbles from Anti–de Sitter Fluctuations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.251104</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.251104"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anxo Biasi, Oleg Evnin, and Spyros Sypsas
A theoretical model shows that de Sitter geometries may emerge locally in globally anti-de Sitter spacetimes via unstable fluctuations.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 251104] Published Fri Dec 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anxo Biasi, Oleg Evnin, and Spyros Sypsas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonmonotonic Friction due to Water Capillary Adhesion and Hydrogen Bonding at Multiasperity Interfaces]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.256101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.256101"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Liang Peng, Feng-Chun Hsia, Sander Woutersen, Mischa Bonn, Bart Weber, and Daniel Bonn
Experiments suggest that hydrogen bonding explains why a wet surface can have nearly twice as much friction as a dry surface.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 256101] Published Fri Dec 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liang Peng, Feng-Chun Hsia, Sander Woutersen, Mischa Bonn, Bart Weber, and Daniel Bonn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effect of scatterer interactions on photon transport in diffusing wave spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.064609</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.064609"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nicholas Sbalbi, Qi Li, and Eric M. Furst
Diffusing wave spectroscopy is a light scattering technique that is used to study the dynamics soft materials such as suspensions and gels. In this paper the authors show how interactions between the scattering particles affect the results: the effect is negligible if the scatterers are large enough, but it is significant when the particles are sufficiently small.

[Phys. Rev. E 106, 064609] Published Fri Dec 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicholas Sbalbi, Qi Li, and Eric M. Furst</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coexistence of trihexagonal and star-of-David pattern in the charge density wave of the kagome superconductor $A{\mathrm{V}}_{3}{\mathrm{Sb}}_{5}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L241106</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L241106"/>
        <updated>2022-12-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yong Hu (胡勇), Xianxin Wu (吴贤新), Brenden R. Ortiz, Xinloong Han (韩欣龙), Nicholas C. Plumb, Stephen D. Wilson, Andreas P. Schnyder, and Ming Shi (史明)
Understanding the nature of the exotic CDW order is of crucial importance for uncovering its origin in the kagome superconductors AV3Sb5. Here, using angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy, the authors reveal characteristic double-band splittings and band reconstructions as well as band-folding gaps in the CDW phase. By combining the findings with density functional theory calculations, they demonstrate that two representative distortions in the kagome lattice - the star of David and the trihexagonal ones - intrinsically coexist in the CDW of CsV3Sb5.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L241106] Published Fri Dec 16, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yong Hu (胡勇), Xianxin Wu (吴贤新), Brenden R. Ortiz, Xinloong Han (韩欣龙), Nicholas C. Plumb, Stephen D. Wilson, Andreas P. Schnyder, and Ming Shi (史明)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Real-space Mott-Anderson electron localization with long-range interactions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.4.043192</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.4.043192"/>
        <updated>2022-12-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Antoine Marie, Derk P. Kooi, Juri Grossi, Michael Seidl, Ziad H. Musslimani, Klaas J. H. Giesbertz, and Paola Gori-Giorgi
Electrons that are delocalized in space because of quantum effects can become localized by an external disordered potential (Anderson localization) or by their mutual Coulomb repulsion (Mott/Wigner localization). A simple model addresses what happens when both effects are present, how to quantify the degree of localization, and whether approximate methods can capture the relevant physics.

[Phys. Rev. Research 4, 043192] Published Thu Dec 15, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Antoine Marie, Derk P. Kooi, Juri Grossi, Michael Seidl, Ziad H. Musslimani, Klaas J. H. Giesbertz, and Paola Gori-Giorgi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Liquid-Liquid Transition in Water from First Principles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.255702</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.255702"/>
        <updated>2022-12-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Thomas E. Gartner, III, Pablo M. Piaggi, Roberto Car, Athanassios Z. Panagiotopoulos, and Pablo G. Debenedetti
Computations support the 30-year-old idea that supercooled liquid water can undergo a transition between high- and low-density states.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 255702] Published Thu Dec 15, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas E. Gartner, III, Pablo M. Piaggi, Roberto Car, Athanassios Z. Panagiotopoulos, and Pablo G. Debenedetti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing Spin Dynamics on Diamond Surfaces Using a Single Quantum Sensor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.3.040328</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.3.040328"/>
        <updated>2022-12-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bo L. Dwyer, Lila V.H. Rodgers, Elana K. Urbach, Dolev Bluvstein, Sorawis Sangtawesin, Hengyun Zhou, Yahia Nassab, Mattias Fitzpatrick, Zhiyang Yuan, Kristiaan De Greve, Eric L. Peterson, Helena Knowles, Tamara Sumarac, Jyh-Pin Chou, Adam Gali, V.V. Dobrovitski, Mikhail D. Lukin, and Nathalie P. de Leon
A detailed analysis of the coherence decay of a nanoscale sensor shows that ubiquitous spins on the diamond surface are mobile and reveals the potential of local sensors to investigate the dynamics of complex systems.

[PRX Quantum 3, 040328] Published Wed Dec 14, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bo L. Dwyer, Lila V.H. Rodgers, Elana K. Urbach, Dolev Bluvstein, Sorawis Sangtawesin, Hengyun Zhou, Yahia Nassab, Mattias Fitzpatrick, Zhiyang Yuan, Kristiaan De Greve, Eric L. Peterson, Helena Knowles, Tamara Sumarac, Jyh-Pin Chou, Adam Gali, V.V. Dobrovitski, Mikhail D. Lukin, and Nathalie P. de Leon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phason-Dominated Thermal Transport in Fresnoite]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.255901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.255901"/>
        <updated>2022-12-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. E. Manley, A. F. May, B. L. Winn, D. L. Abernathy, R. Sahul, and R. P. Hermann
Heat-transport measurements and neutron-scattering spectroscopy probe a form of thermal conduction based on excitations called phasons.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 255901] Published Wed Dec 14, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. E. Manley, A. F. May, B. L. Winn, D. L. Abernathy, R. Sahul, and R. P. Hermann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chirality-induced intrinsic charge rectification in a tellurium-based field-effect transistor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L220403</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L220403"/>
        <updated>2022-12-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Daichi Hirobe, Yoji Nabei, and Hiroshi M. Yamamoto
Chiral conductors exhibit spin-related charge rectification but its controllability is largely unexplored. Here, the authors combine chiral charge rectification with a field-effect transistor of tellurium. They demonstrate a gate-variable hundredfold enhancement of the rectification efficiency and enable quantitative comparison with theoretical calculations which considered chiral spin-momentum locking alongside the Zeeman effect. With this comparison across a wide range of temperature, an unexpected deviation from the conventional theory is revealed, which hints at the relevance of chirality-induced spin selectivity at higher temperatures.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L220403] Published Wed Dec 14, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daichi Hirobe, Yoji Nabei, and Hiroshi M. Yamamoto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Autonomous Estimation of High-Dimensional Coulomb Diamonds from Sparse Measurements]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064040</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064040"/>
        <updated>2022-12-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anasua Chatterjee, Fabio Ansaloni, Torbjørn Rasmussen, Bertram Brovang, Federico Fedele, Heorhii Bohuslavskyi, Oswin Krause, and Ferdinand Kuemmeth
In spin-based quantum processors, each quantum dot of a qubit is populated by exactly one electron, which requires careful tuning of each gate voltage such that it lies inside the charge-stability region (the “Coulomb diamond”) associated with the dot array. However, mapping the boundary of a multidimensional Coulomb diamond by traditional dense raster scanning would take years, so the authors develop a sparse acquisition technique that autonomously learns Coulomb-diamond boundaries from a small number of measurements. Here we have hardware-triggered line searches in the gate-voltage space of a silicon quadruple dot, with smart search directions proposed by an active-learning algorithm.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 064040] Published Wed Dec 14, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anasua Chatterjee, Fabio Ansaloni, Torbjørn Rasmussen, Bertram Brovang, Federico Fedele, Heorhii Bohuslavskyi, Oswin Krause, and Ferdinand Kuemmeth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extraterrestrial Axion Search with the Breakthrough Listen Galactic Center Survey]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.251102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.251102"/>
        <updated>2022-12-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Joshua W. Foster, Samuel J. Witte, Matthew Lawson, Tim Linden, Vishal Gajjar, Christoph Weniger, and Benjamin R. Safdi
A neutron star’s ultrastrong magnetic field could create the conditions for uncloaking a promising dark matter candidate.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 251102] Published Tue Dec 13, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joshua W. Foster, Samuel J. Witte, Matthew Lawson, Tim Linden, Vishal Gajjar, Christoph Weniger, and Benjamin R. Safdi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hidden-nucleons neural-network quantum states for the nuclear many-body problem]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.4.043178</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.4.043178"/>
        <updated>2022-12-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alessandro Lovato, Corey Adams, Giuseppe Carleo, and Noemi Rocco
Understanding how protons and neutrons self-organize to form atomic nuclei requires solving the nuclear many-body Schrödinger equation. This work addresses this nontrivial task through a neural network quantum states ansatz that involves additional “hidden” degrees of freedom to improve the accuracy of the solution systemically. Light and medium-mass nuclei’s energy and spatial density distributions are in excellent agreement with those obtained utilizing exact-diagonalization and diffusion Monte Carlo approaches.

[Phys. Rev. Research 4, 043178] Published Mon Dec 12, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alessandro Lovato, Corey Adams, Giuseppe Carleo, and Noemi Rocco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improved Measurement of Solar Neutrinos from the Carbon-Nitrogen-Oxygen Cycle by Borexino and Its Implications for the Standard Solar Model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.252701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.252701"/>
        <updated>2022-12-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Appel et al. (Borexino Collaboration)
A study of neutrinos from the Sun has measured the signal from the so-called CNO cycle, offering a direct measure of the elemental abundances in the Sun’s core.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 252701] Published Mon Dec 12, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Appel &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (Borexino Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Layer formation in a stably stratified fluid cooled from above: Towards an analog for Jupiter and other gas giants]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.7.124501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.7.124501"/>
        <updated>2022-12-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. R. Fuentes, A. Cumming, and E. H. Anders
Composition gradients in the interior of Jupiter can affect and even suppress convective motions. In some situations, a composition gradient can trigger the formation of multiple convective layers separated by sharp diffusive interfaces, preventing further mixing. This fluid state, called layered convection, has been proposed to occur in giant planets. However, it is not guaranteed that secondary convective layers can form and survive underneath a turbulent convection zone. Our simulations find that below an evolving convection zone, layer formation is difficult and the fluid always fully mixes. This may have bearing on the survival of composition gradients in Jupiter’s interior.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 7, 124501] Published Mon Dec 12, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. R. Fuentes, A. Cumming, and E. H. Anders</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perturbation theory of large scale structure in the $\mathrm{Λ}\mathrm{CDM}$ Universe: Exact time evolution and the two-loop power spectrum]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.123504</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.123504"/>
        <updated>2022-12-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Matteo Fasiello, Tomohiro Fujita, and Zvonimir Vlah
The large-scale structure (LSS) of the Universe is obviously nonlinear and very complicated. However, the scale of onset of nonlinearity is well separated from the size of the Universe which makes a large portion of the structure formation modes accessible to perturbation theory (PT). The latter is itself complicated by the time dependence of the λCDM background. The authors provide an exact all-order recursive solution for the PT kernels, which allows them to go beyond the Einstein-de Sitter approximation for the time dependence, and quantify the deviation at the two-loop level in the 10% range, a deviation detectible with upcoming observations.

[Phys. Rev. D 106, 123504] Published Mon Dec 12, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matteo Fasiello, Tomohiro Fujita, and Zvonimir Vlah</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlocal conductance spectroscopy of Andreev bound states in gate-defined InAs/Al nanowires]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L241301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L241301"/>
        <updated>2022-12-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Andreas Pöschl, Alisa Danilenko, Deividas Sabonis, Kaur Kristjuhan, Tyler Lindemann, Candice Thomas, Michael J. Manfra, and Charles M. Marcus
Andreev bound states emerge as excitations in semiconducting InAs, proximitized by superconducting Al. These states can be a mixture of electron and hole and their structure is determined by material parameters, external magnetic field, and gate voltages. Nonlocal conductance is a differential measurement of the current carried by Andreev bound states through a quasi-one-dimensional nanowire, and it can reveal the charge character of the states given by the BCS charge.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L241301] Published Mon Dec 12, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andreas Pöschl, Alisa Danilenko, Deividas Sabonis, Kaur Kristjuhan, Tyler Lindemann, Candice Thomas, Michael J. Manfra, and Charles M. Marcus</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coherent Coupling between Phonons, Magnons, and Photons]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.243601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.243601"/>
        <updated>2022-12-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zhen Shen, Guan-Ting Xu, Mai Zhang, Yan-Lei Zhang, Yu Wang, Cheng-Zhe Chai, Chang-Ling Zou, Guang-Can Guo, and Chun-Hua Dong
A pair of microspheres can convert microwave signals over a wide frequency range into optical signals, which will be essential for future quantum technologies.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 243601] Published Fri Dec 09, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhen Shen, Guan-Ting Xu, Mai Zhang, Yan-Lei Zhang, Yu Wang, Cheng-Zhe Chai, Chang-Ling Zou, Guang-Can Guo, and Chun-Hua Dong</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measured Potential Profile in a Quantum Anomalous Hall System Suggests Bulk-Dominated Current Flow]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.246602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.246602"/>
        <updated>2022-12-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ilan T. Rosen, Molly P. Andersen, Linsey K. Rodenbach, Lixuan Tai, Peng Zhang, Kang L. Wang, M. A. Kastner, and David Goldhaber-Gordon
Current flows primarily through the incompressible bulk of quantum anomalous Hall systems, and not through edges as was previously thought true for both quantum Hall and quantum anomalous Hall systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 246602] Published Fri Dec 09, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ilan T. Rosen, Molly P. Andersen, Linsey K. Rodenbach, Lixuan Tai, Peng Zhang, Kang L. Wang, M. A. Kastner, and David Goldhaber-Gordon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sea urchin sperm exploit extremum seeking control to find the egg]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.L062401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.L062401"/>
        <updated>2022-12-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mahmoud Abdelgalil, Yasser Aboelkassem, and Haithem Taha
When searching for an egg, sea urchin sperm typically switch between two distinct navigation modes, depending on the relative orientation of their velocity with respect to the chemical gradient of the attractant released from the egg. This paper demonstrates that this navigational strategy can be described by the control algorithm known as extremum seeking. There is no need to define a threshold mechanism to explain the switching behavior, as suggested by previous work. This interdisciplinary work could serve as bridge between scientific communities.

[Phys. Rev. E 106, L062401] Published Fri Dec 09, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mahmoud Abdelgalil, Yasser Aboelkassem, and Haithem Taha</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New constraints on dark matter from superconducting nanowires]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.112005</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.112005"/>
        <updated>2022-12-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yonit Hochberg, Benjamin V. Lehmann, Ilya Charaev, Jeff Chiles, Marco Colangelo, Sae Woo Nam, and Karl K. Berggren
A superconducting nanowire detector places new bounds on how a hypothetical lightweight dark matter particle interacts with electrons.

[Phys. Rev. D 106, 112005] Published Fri Dec 09, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yonit Hochberg, Benjamin V. Lehmann, Ilya Charaev, Jeff Chiles, Marco Colangelo, Sae Woo Nam, and Karl K. Berggren</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entanglement phases in large-$N$ hybrid Brownian circuits with long-range couplings]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.224305</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.224305"/>
        <updated>2022-12-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Subhayan Sahu, Shao-Kai Jian, Gregory Bentsen, and Brian Swingle
The interplay of unitary gates and quantum measurements leads to quantum many-body states with unique patterns of entanglement, and can even drive phase transitions between distinct entanglement phases. Here, the authors construct analytically solvable models to study the effects of long-range coupling on such measurement-induced phases, and also provide a minimal theoretical understanding of the phases and the phase transition in both spin and fermionic models. They show that power law couplings and measurements result in a rich entanglement phase diagram, including robust dynamical quantum phases with good error correcting properties, namely a power-law code distance.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 224305] Published Fri Dec 09, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Subhayan Sahu, Shao-Kai Jian, Gregory Bentsen, and Brian Swingle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robust Fe divalent state in one-unit-cell $\mathrm{FeSe}/{\mathrm{SrTiO}}_{3}$ thin films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.245112</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.245112"/>
        <updated>2022-12-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jingdong Shen, Wenxiang Jiang, Fengfeng Zhu, Guan-yong Wang, Huayao Li, Gan Zhao, Qian Li, Wensheng Yan, Wanli Yang, Yi-De Chuang, Jin-feng Jia, Dong Qian, L. Andrew Wray, and Lin Miao
The one-unit-cell FeSe thin film on SrTiO3 with superconductive Tc above 60K with unique electronic structures and magnetic excitations is reported here. The authors studied FeSe/STO thin films with x-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS), resonant inelastic x-ray scattering (RIXS), and atomic multiplet simulation. The work clarifies that FeSe thin films (1UC to 10UC) are shown with pure low-spin 3d6 electronic occupancy. Besides, the 3d6 state in 1UC FeSe/STO is more robust under oxidization. This study calls for a high-resolution RIXS exploration of the pristine 1UC FeSe/STO thin film to reveal the many-body excitations.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 245112] Published Fri Dec 09, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jingdong Shen, Wenxiang Jiang, Fengfeng Zhu, Guan-yong Wang, Huayao Li, Gan Zhao, Qian Li, Wensheng Yan, Wanli Yang, Yi-De Chuang, Jin-feng Jia, Dong Qian, L. Andrew Wray, and Lin Miao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Persistent current oscillations in a double-ring quantum gas]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.4.043171</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.4.043171"/>
        <updated>2022-12-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Bland, I. V. Yatsuta, M. Edwards, Y. O. Nikolaieva, A. O. Oliinyk, A. I. Yakimenko, and N. P. Proukakis
By introducing a repulsive barrier at the interface between two density-coupled rings of ultracold atoms, a persistent current can oscillate between the rings. The phenomenon persists indefinitely in the limit of zero temperature, but it decays at finite temperature and can even be suppressed completely in the limit of large damping.

[Phys. Rev. Research 4, 043171] Published Thu Dec 08, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Bland, I. V. Yatsuta, M. Edwards, Y. O. Nikolaieva, A. O. Oliinyk, A. I. Yakimenko, and N. P. Proukakis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perturbative Confinement in Thermal Yang-Mills Theories Induced by Imaginary Angular Velocity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.242002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.242002"/>
        <updated>2022-12-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shi Chen, Kenji Fukushima, and Yusuke Shimada
A mathematical framework where gluons rotate with an imaginary angular velocity provides new insight into the problem of color confinement.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 242002] Published Thu Dec 08, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shi Chen, Kenji Fukushima, and Yusuke Shimada</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of a Strongly Isospin-Mixed Doublet in $^{26}\mathrm{Si}$ via $β$-Delayed Two-Proton Decay of $^{26}\mathrm{P}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.242502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.242502"/>
        <updated>2022-12-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. J. Liu (刘嘉健) et al. (RIBLL Collaboration)
The isospin mixing between two daughter states from the beta-delayed proton decay of 26P is three times larger than any previously observed mixing.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 242502] Published Thu Dec 08, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. J. Liu (刘嘉健) &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (RIBLL Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mitigation of the turbulence within an arteriovenous fistula with a stent implantation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.7.123101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.7.123101"/>
        <updated>2022-12-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sanjiv Gunasekera, Tracie Barber, Olivia Ng, Shannon Thomas, Ramon Varcoe, and Charitha de Silva
Transitional flow within an arteriovenous fistula (AVF) leads to vascular disease, which can be treated by implanting a stent. Large Eddy Simulations of blood flow within a patient-specific AVF revealed the significantly higher turbulent behavior in the Stent-absent AVF when compared to the Stented AVF. This finding provides key understanding of the reasons behind the success of this treatment strategy from a fluid dynamics perspective.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 7, 123101] Published Thu Dec 08, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sanjiv Gunasekera, Tracie Barber, Olivia Ng, Shannon Thomas, Ramon Varcoe, and Charitha de Silva</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Foot function enabled by human walking dynamics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.064405</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.064405"/>
        <updated>2022-12-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Daniel Renjewski, Susanne Lipfert, and Michael Günther
When humans walk, our feet act as levers rather than landing pads as previously thought.

[Phys. Rev. E 106, 064405] Published Thu Dec 08, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Renjewski, Susanne Lipfert, and Michael Günther</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coherence Properties of Electron-Beam-Activated Emitters in Hexagonal Boron Nitride Under Resonant Excitation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064021</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064021"/>
        <updated>2022-12-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jake Horder, Simon J.U. White, Angus Gale, Chi Li, Kenji Watanabe, Takashi Taniguchi, Mehran Kianinia, Igor Aharonovich, and Milos Toth
Lattice defects in two-dimensional materials are compelling sources of single photons for applications in quantum information processing. However, the range of emission wavelengths is broad, the defect types vary and the atomic structures of most are unknown, and the inability to fabricate defects systematically on demand has limited progress. This work leverages a robust, site-specific fabrication technique to produce arrays of blue quantum emitters for study via cryogenic spectroscopy. The authors characterize processes that limit emitter coherence and observe Rabi oscillations, demonstrating the potential of these defects for scalable quantum technologies.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 064021] Published Thu Dec 08, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jake Horder, Simon J.U. White, Angus Gale, Chi Li, Kenji Watanabe, Takashi Taniguchi, Mehran Kianinia, Igor Aharonovich, and Milos Toth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Echo-enhanced molecular orientation at high temperatures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.L061101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.L061101"/>
        <updated>2022-12-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ilia Tutunnikov, Long Xu, Yehiam Prior, and Ilya Sh. Averbukh
Efficient molecular orientation at high temperatures is induced by a terahertz pulse with the help of an intense nonresonant laser prepulse that dissects rotational phase space to narrow filaments. The authors use the echo effect to synchronize the terahertz response of all the filaments, leading to much enhanced orientation compared to other techniques.

[Phys. Rev. A 106, L061101] Published Thu Dec 08, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ilia Tutunnikov, Long Xu, Yehiam Prior, and Ilya Sh. Averbukh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Near-Monochromatic Tuneable Cryogenic Niobium Electron Field Emitter]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.244802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.244802"/>
        <updated>2022-12-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. W. Johnson, A. K. Schmid, M. Mankos, R. Röpke, N. Kerker, E. K. Wong, D. F. Ogletree, A. M. Minor, and A. Stibor
Researchers have demonstrated a new electron field emitter with unprecedented brightness and spectral purity, promising a breakthrough in electron microscope spectroscopy.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 244802] Published Wed Dec 07, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. W. Johnson, A. K. Schmid, M. Mankos, R. Röpke, N. Kerker, E. K. Wong, D. F. Ogletree, A. M. Minor, and A. Stibor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic Response of an Electron Gas: Towards the Exact Exchange-Correlation Kernel]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.246401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.246401"/>
        <updated>2022-12-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): James P. F. LeBlanc, Kun Chen, Kristjan Haule, Nikolay V. Prokof’ev, and Igor S. Tupitsyn
The first accurate prediction of the dynamic charge response and its characterization in terms of the exchange-correlation kernel comes from a new technique based on combining analytic considerations, quantum field theory rules for Feynman diagrams, and stochastic Monte Carlo sampling.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 246401] Published Wed Dec 07, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James P. F. LeBlanc, Kun Chen, Kristjan Haule, Nikolay V. Prokof’ev, and Igor S. Tupitsyn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quasiparticle Interference as a Direct Experimental Probe of Bulk Odd-Frequency Superconducting Pairing]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.247001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.247001"/>
        <updated>2022-12-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Debmalya Chakraborty and Annica M. Black-Schaffer
An innovative technique will allow scientists to probe superconductivity involving an unusual type of electron pairing called odd-frequency pairing.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 247001] Published Wed Dec 07, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Debmalya Chakraborty and Annica M. Black-Schaffer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effects of relaxation on the photovoltaic effect and possibility for photocurrent within the transparent region]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.235110</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.235110"/>
        <updated>2022-12-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yugo Onishi, Hikaru Watanabe, Takahiro Morimoto, and Naoto Nagaosa
In this work, the authors explore the possibility of photocurrents in metals that break both inversion and time-reversal symmetries within the transparent region, i.e., where neither Drude absorption nor interband transitions can occur. The authors show that the photocurrent is O(ωJ/γ) with the frequency of the induced current ωJ and the scattering rate γ when ωJ ≪ γ. While dc photocurrent vanishes for finite γ, the theory here also indicates that nonvanishing photocurrent can appear even in the transparent region if ω ≫ γ.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 235110] Published Wed Dec 07, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yugo Onishi, Hikaru Watanabe, Takahiro Morimoto, and Naoto Nagaosa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[<i>In Situ</i> Measurement of Electron Energy Evolution in a Laser-Plasma Accelerator]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.244801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.244801"/>
        <updated>2022-12-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Bohlen, T. Brümmer, F. Grüner, C. A. Lindstrøm, M. Meisel, T. Staufer, M. J. V. Streeter, M. C. Veale, J. C. Wood, R. D’Arcy, K. Põder, and J. Osterhoff
Researchers have demonstrated a noninvasive technique for measuring the energy evolution of an electron bunch inside a laser-plasma accelerator.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 244801] Published Tue Dec 06, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Bohlen, T. Brümmer, F. Grüner, C. A. Lindstrøm, M. Meisel, T. Staufer, M. J. V. Streeter, M. C. Veale, J. C. Wood, R. D’Arcy, K. Põder, and J. Osterhoff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gender differences in students’ self-efficacy in introductory physics courses in which women outnumber men predict their grade]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.18.020142</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.18.020142"/>
        <updated>2022-12-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sonja Cwik and Chandralekha Singh
It is important for physics instructors to focus on increasing women’s self-efficacy and other motivational beliefs in the introductory course; these can influence students’ persistence and engagement in the course and can also impact later course and career choices.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 18, 020142] Published Mon Dec 05, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sonja Cwik and Chandralekha Singh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Measurement Resolves Key Astrophysical Fe XVII Oscillator Strength Problem]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.245001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.245001"/>
        <updated>2022-12-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Steffen Kühn, Charles Cheung, Natalia S. Oreshkina, René Steinbrügge, Moto Togawa, Sonja Bernitt, Lukas Berger, Jens Buck, Moritz Hoesch, Jörn Seltmann, Florian Trinter, Christoph H. Keitel, Mikhail G. Kozlov, Sergey G. Porsev, Ming Feng Gu, F. Scott Porter, Thomas Pfeifer, Maurice A. Leutenegger, Zoltán Harman, Marianna S. Safronova, José R. Crespo López-Urrutia, and Chintan Shah
Researchers have solved a long-standing puzzle surrounding iron emission lines, which are used to characterize laboratory and astrophysical plasmas.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 245001] Published Mon Dec 05, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steffen Kühn, Charles Cheung, Natalia S. Oreshkina, René Steinbrügge, Moto Togawa, Sonja Bernitt, Lukas Berger, Jens Buck, Moritz Hoesch, Jörn Seltmann, Florian Trinter, Christoph H. Keitel, Mikhail G. Kozlov, Sergey G. Porsev, Ming Feng Gu, F. Scott Porter, Thomas Pfeifer, Maurice A. Leutenegger, Zoltán Harman, Marianna S. Safronova, José R. Crespo López-Urrutia, and Chintan Shah</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing the Critical Nucleus Size in the Metal-Insulator Phase Transition of ${\mathrm{VO}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.245701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.245701"/>
        <updated>2022-12-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lei Jin, Yin Shi, Frances I. Allen, Long-Qing Chen, and Junqiao Wu
A textbook theory for the freezing of water also explains the growth of a new phase in a more complicated phase transition of a different material.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 245701] Published Mon Dec 05, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lei Jin, Yin Shi, Frances I. Allen, Long-Qing Chen, and Junqiao Wu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nutational switching in ferromagnets and antiferromagnets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.214403</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.214403"/>
        <updated>2022-12-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lucas Winter, Sebastian Großenbach, Ulrich Nowak, and Levente Rózsa
At very short time scales, inertial effects separate the magnetic moment from the angular momentum, resulting in nutation. Here, it is demonstrated that a resonant excitation of nutation can switch the orientation of the magnetic moments within picoseconds. 90° and 180° switching can be realized in both ferromagnets and antiferromagnets, surpassing the switching speed achievable by any procedure based on spin precession.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 214403] Published Mon Dec 05, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucas Winter, Sebastian Großenbach, Ulrich Nowak, and Levente Rózsa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fully self-consistent finite-temperature $GW$ in Gaussian Bloch orbitals for solids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.235104</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.235104"/>
        <updated>2022-12-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chia-Nan Yeh, Sergei Iskakov, Dominika Zgid, and Emanuel Gull
Fully self-consistent GW is a many-body perturbation theory based on an approximation to the Luttinger-Ward functional. The method satisfies certain conservation laws and thermodynamic consistency, and the self-consistent framework allows us to systematically include strong correlations. Fully self-consistent GW calculations of real materials have so far been hampered by their high computational cost. This paper presents algorithmic improvements and implementation details for the fully self-consistent GW method that make such calculations routinely possible and documents the performance of the method via examples from several materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 235104] Published Mon Dec 05, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chia-Nan Yeh, Sergei Iskakov, Dominika Zgid, and Emanuel Gull</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Semiconductor Bloch equation analysis of optical Stark and Bloch-Siegert shifts in monolayer ${\mathrm{WSe}}_{2}$ and ${\mathrm{MoS}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.235304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.235304"/>
        <updated>2022-12-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. O. Slobodeniuk, P. Koutenský, M. Bartoš, F. Trojánek, P. Malý, T. Novotný, and M. Kozák
Transition metal dichalcogenide monolayers possess two nonequivalent valleys in the extrema of their band structure. It turns out that off-resonant circularly polarized light affects the electronic excitations in each valley dissimilarly. Such a phenomenon leads to different shifts of the excitonic transitions in nonequivalent valleys of the monolayer. Here, the authors report on a theoretical investigation of such valley-selective transient shifts of both 1sA and 1sB exciton transitions in MoS2 and WSe2 monolayers. The study is based on the semiconductor Bloch equations, where, contrary to the previous studies, the many-body Coulomb interaction effects are properly included. The theoretical estimates of the excitonic shifts are in a good agreement with these novel experimental results.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 235304] Published Mon Dec 05, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. O. Slobodeniuk, P. Koutenský, M. Bartoš, F. Trojánek, P. Malý, T. Novotný, and M. Kozák</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-field transport and hot-electron noise in GaAs from first-principles calculations: Role of two-phonon scattering]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.245201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.245201"/>
        <updated>2022-12-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Peishi S. Cheng, Jiace Sun, Shi-Ning Sun, Alexander Y. Choi, and Austin J. Minnich
The scattering of electrons by phonons in semiconductors has been assumed to be dominated by the lowest-order process involving a single phonon. Using a new numerical approach to incorporate the next-leading-order process involving two phonons into high-field transport calculations from first principles, the authors find here that the two-phonon process contributes nearly as much as the single-phonon process to high-field transport phenomena. This finding resolves a long-standing discrepancy regarding the strength of intervalley scattering in GaAs as determined from different experimental methods.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 245201] Published Mon Dec 05, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peishi S. Cheng, Jiace Sun, Shi-Ning Sun, Alexander Y. Choi, and Austin J. Minnich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Efficient simulation of dynamics in two-dimensional quantum spin systems with isometric tensor networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.245102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.245102"/>
        <updated>2022-12-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sheng-Hsuan Lin, Michael P. Zaletel, and Frank Pollmann
Simulating the dynamics of finite two-dimensional (2D) quantum many-body systems poses challenges to numerical methods due to the exponential growth of the many-body Hilbert space. In this work, the authors explore the variational power of recently introduced isometric tensor network states (isoTNS) — a subset of general tensor-network states that allow an efficient numerical simulation. As a efficient tool to find ground states, the variational density matrix renormalization group (DMRG2) is introduced. It is then demonstrated that dynamical correlation functions for the 2D transverse field Ising model and the Kitaev Honeycomb model can be obtained.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 245102] Published Fri Dec 02, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sheng-Hsuan Lin, Michael P. Zaletel, and Frank Pollmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coincidence postselection for genuine multipartite nonlocality: Causal diagrams and threshold efficiencies]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.062202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.062202"/>
        <updated>2022-12-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Valentin Gebhart and Augusto Smerzi
In a crucial step for securing many existing quantum technologies, the authors use causal diagrams to close the detection loophole in multipartite nonlocality demonstrations. Their results also imply that genuine N-partite nonlocality can be created from N independent photon sources.

[Phys. Rev. A 106, 062202] Published Fri Dec 02, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Valentin Gebhart and Augusto Smerzi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First-Principles Calculations of Shallow Acceptor-Carbon Complexes in $\mathrm{Si}$: A Potential-Patching Method with a Hybrid-Functional Correction]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064001"/>
        <updated>2022-12-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jun Kang and Lin-Wang Wang
Shallow impurities play critical roles in the applications of semiconductor materials, but their simulations through first-principles calculations are challenging due to the delocalized nature of the impurity wave function. The authors propose a first-principles approach to study shallow impurities, which allows simulations of extremely large supercells to obtain converged impurity levels and wave functions. The method is applied to acceptor-carbon complexes in silicon and yields good agreement with experiments. This work thus presents a feasible approach for accurate simulations of shallow impurities and can provide helpful insights to assist experimental dopant engineering.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 064001] Published Thu Dec 01, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jun Kang and Lin-Wang Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Triplet-Polaron-Annihilation-Induced Degradation of Organic Light-Emitting Diodes Based on Thermally Activated Delayed Fluorescence]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.064002"/>
        <updated>2022-12-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bas van der Zee, Yungui Li, Gert-Jan A.H. Wetzelaer, and Paul W.M. Blom
Organic light-emitting diodes (OLEDs) based on thermally activated delayed fluorescence (TADF) are alternatives to today’s commercial phosphorescent OLEDs with heavy-metal dopants, but their limited stability remains a key issue. This work provides a quantitative insight into the degradation mechanisms. The authors reproduce the voltage and light output using a recently developed device model, and find that triplet-polaron annihilation is the driving force behind the formation of degradation traps. This understanding leads to the experimental demonstration of enhanced device lifetime, and will provide guidance towards improved stability of TADF OLEDs.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 064002] Published Thu Dec 01, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bas van der Zee, Yungui Li, Gert-Jan A.H. Wetzelaer, and Paul W.M. Blom</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quick Quantum Steering: Overcoming Loss and Noise with Qudits]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.12.041023</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.12.041023"/>
        <updated>2022-11-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vatshal Srivastav, Natalia Herrera Valencia, Will McCutcheon, Saroch Leedumrongwatthanakun, Sébastien Designolle, Roope Uola, Nicolas Brunner, and Mehul Malik
Researchers demonstrate a loss-tolerant method for so-called quantum steering, a phenomenon that could give quantum communication networks complete security.

[Phys. Rev. X 12, 041023] Published Wed Nov 30, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vatshal Srivastav, Natalia Herrera Valencia, Will McCutcheon, Saroch Leedumrongwatthanakun, Sébastien Designolle, Roope Uola, Nicolas Brunner, and Mehul Malik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rubric-based holistic review: A promising route to equitable graduate admissions in physics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.18.020140</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.18.020140"/>
        <updated>2022-11-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nicholas T. Young, K. Tollefson, Remco G. T. Zegers, and Marcos D. Caballero
Rubric-based admissions processes increase equity in graduate admissions.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 18, 020140] Published Wed Nov 30, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicholas T. Young, K. Tollefson, Remco G. T. Zegers, and Marcos D. Caballero</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fundamental Limitation on the Detectability of Entanglement]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.230503</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.230503"/>
        <updated>2022-11-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pengyu Liu, Zhenhuan Liu, Shu Chen, and Xiongfeng Ma
A systematic method to upper bound the detection capability of various entanglement criteria reveals a fundamental trade-off between efficiency and effectiveness.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 230503] Published Wed Nov 30, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pengyu Liu, Zhenhuan Liu, Shu Chen, and Xiongfeng Ma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal Kardar-Parisi-Zhang Dynamics in Integrable Quantum Systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.230602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.230602"/>
        <updated>2022-11-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bingtian Ye, Francisco Machado, Jack Kemp, Ross B. Hutson, and Norman Y. Yao
Numerical evidence based on sophisticated tensor network methods supports a stronger conjecture that Kardar-Parisi-Zhang dynamics occurs in all integrable spin chains with non-Abelian symmetry and corresponding integrable Floquet models.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 230602] Published Wed Nov 30, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bingtian Ye, Francisco Machado, Jack Kemp, Ross B. Hutson, and Norman Y. Yao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin Hall Effect of Light via Momentum-Space Topological Vortices around Bound States in the Continuum]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.236101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.236101"/>
        <updated>2022-11-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jiajun Wang, Lei Shi, and Jian Zi
The spin Hall effect of light in photonic crystal slabs via momentum-space topological vortices around bound states in the continuum reveals intriguing spin-related topological effects.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 236101] Published Wed Nov 30, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jiajun Wang, Lei Shi, and Jian Zi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electric Field-Controlled Damping Switches of Coupled Dirac Plasmons]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.237402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.237402"/>
        <updated>2022-11-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Huayang Zhang, Xiaodong Fan, Dongli Wang, Dongbo Zhang, Xiaoguang Li, and Changgan Zeng
A novel approach to actively control the lifetime of the graphene plasmon in a double-layer graphene system is efficient and implementable in other systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 237402] Published Wed Nov 30, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Huayang Zhang, Xiaodong Fan, Dongli Wang, Dongbo Zhang, Xiaoguang Li, and Changgan Zeng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Argon equation of state data to 1 TPa: Shock compression experiments and simulations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.174114</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.174114"/>
        <updated>2022-11-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Seth Root, Chad A. McCoy, Kyle R. Cochrane, John H. Carpenter, Raymond W. Lemke, Luke Shulenburger, Thomas R. Mattsson, and Philip A. Sterne
Cryogenic liquid noble gases, because of their noble nature and monatomic fluid behavior, are ideal for comparing experiments and theory at high pressures and temperatures. Using both magnetically accelerated flyer plates and laser-driven decaying shocks, the authors obtain here high-precision measurements on shock-compressed liquid argon to 1 TPa. The data are used to calibrate two different EOS models. The results show that even if two models are calibrated to the same data set, they can exhibit different responses at extreme conditions.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 174114] Published Wed Nov 30, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Seth Root, Chad A. McCoy, Kyle R. Cochrane, John H. Carpenter, Raymond W. Lemke, Luke Shulenburger, Thomas R. Mattsson, and Philip A. Sterne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Antiferromagnetic fluctuations and orbital-selective Mott transition in the van der Waals ferromagnet ${\text{Fe}}_{3−x}{\text{GeTe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L180409</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L180409"/>
        <updated>2022-11-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xiaojian Bai, Frank Lechermann, Yaohua Liu, Yongqiang Cheng, Alexander I. Kolesnikov, Feng Ye, Travis J. Williams, Songxue Chi, Tao Hong, Garrett E. Granroth, Andrew F. May, and Stuart Calder
Fe3−xGeTe2 is one of the most intensely studied quasi-two-dimensional layered materials of recent times. It can be exfoliated down to a monolayer and has promising applications in room-temperature magnetoelectronics. Here, the authors use neutron scattering and first-principle calculations to study its fundamental magnetic and electronic properties. A rare orbital selective Mott transition was identified that drives the emergence of antiferromagnetic fluctuations within the ferromagnetic order, opening a new avenue in understanding the coexistence of itinerant and local moments and the heavy-fermion physics in this 3d electron system.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L180409] Published Wed Nov 30, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiaojian Bai, Frank Lechermann, Yaohua Liu, Yongqiang Cheng, Alexander I. Kolesnikov, Feng Ye, Travis J. Williams, Songxue Chi, Tao Hong, Garrett E. Granroth, Andrew F. May, and Stuart Calder</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Compact High-Resolution Absolute-Gravity Gradiometer Based on Atom Interferometers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.054091</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.054091"/>
        <updated>2022-11-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wei Lyu, Jia-Qi Zhong, Xiao-Wei Zhang, Wu Liu, Lei Zhu, Wei-Hao Xu, Xi Chen, Biao Tang, Jin Wang, and Ming-Sheng Zhan
Measurement of the absolute-gravity gradient is of great significance in metrology, geophysics, and industries such as autonomous navigation. However, its applications are limited by the dimensions of the gradiometer and the complicated systematic errors. The authors present a high-resolution atom-gravity gradiometer with an ultracompact sensor head, and develop a series of technologies to comprehensively evaluate the systematic errors. This work will have an impact on the calibration of gravimetry instruments, correction of inertial navigation errors, and direct onboard high-precision mapping.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 054091] Published Wed Nov 30, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wei Lyu, Jia-Qi Zhong, Xiao-Wei Zhang, Wu Liu, Lei Zhu, Wei-Hao Xu, Xi Chen, Biao Tang, Jin Wang, and Ming-Sheng Zhan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conformally Mapped Black Hole Effect in Elastic Curved Continuum]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.054092</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.18.054092"/>
        <updated>2022-11-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dongwoo Lee, Yiran Hao, Jeonghoon Park, Yaxi Shen, Jensen Li, and Junsuk Rho
What if we could manipulate and study a black hole in the laboratory? Here the authors employ the elastic curved framework to mimic the black hole effect and achieve a singularity, which has an infinite refractive index in the classical regime and has proven challenging to navigate so far. In particular, they adopt a conformal mapping-based strategy that leads to wave localization and time lags. This work would have an impact on finding solutions to wave propagation in the presence of singularity, and have potential applications in sensing, imaging, vibration isolation, and energy harvesting.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 18, 054092] Published Wed Nov 30, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dongwoo Lee, Yiran Hao, Jeonghoon Park, Yaxi Shen, Jensen Li, and Junsuk Rho</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of Rb-Rb van der Waals coefficient via quantum diffractive universality]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.052812</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.052812"/>
        <updated>2022-11-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Riley A. Stewart, Pinrui Shen, James L. Booth, and Kirk W. Madison
The authors demonstrate a new method for measuring the C6 van der Waals coefficient of the Rb-Rb interaction potential from the loss rate of atoms confined in a shallow atom trap of tunable depth. The technique is based on the universal nature of the room-temperature collisions, which depends only on the long-range potential between the collision partners.

[Phys. Rev. A 106, 052812] Published Wed Nov 30, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Riley A. Stewart, Pinrui Shen, James L. Booth, and Kirk W. Madison</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cosmic Optical Background Excess, Dark Matter, and Line-Intensity Mapping]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.231301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.231301"/>
        <updated>2022-11-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): José Luis Bernal, Gabriela Sato-Polito, and Marc Kamionkowski
Axions that decay into photons could account for visible light that exceeds what’s expected to come from all known galaxies.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 231301] Published Tue Nov 29, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>José Luis Bernal, Gabriela Sato-Polito, and Marc Kamionkowski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Augmenting the residue theorem with boundary terms in finite-density calculations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.105026</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.105026"/>
        <updated>2022-11-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tyler Gorda, Juuso Österman, and Saga Säppi
Within the framework of the imaginary time formalism applied to systems at zero temperature but finite density, the authors investigate whether the order of integration, namely the spatial momentum integration is performed before that of the temporal momentum or vice versa, matters. They show that the former yields results consistent with those for nonzero but very low values of the temperature whilst the latter does not. They attribute this to the way the limit of the Fermi-Dirac distribution is taken as the temperature goes to zero.

[Phys. Rev. D 106, 105026] Published Tue Nov 29, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tyler Gorda, Juuso Österman, and Saga Säppi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Superconductivity and bosonic fluid emerging from moiré flat bands]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.184517</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.184517"/>
        <updated>2022-11-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xu Zhang, Kai Sun, Heqiu Li, Gaopei Pan, and Zi Yang Meng
Here, the authors find a phenomenological theory of superconductivity in moiré flat band systems. With decreasing temperature, charge excitations are gapped, while charge excitations exist within the gap, shaping a bosonic fluid. Finite band width breaks the symmetry in these two-dimensional systems, making the bosonic fluid coherent and condense.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 184517] Published Tue Nov 29, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xu Zhang, Kai Sun, Heqiu Li, Gaopei Pan, and Zi Yang Meng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Standard Model Prediction for Paramagnetic Electric Dipole Moments]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.231801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.231801"/>
        <updated>2022-11-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yohei Ema, Ting Gao, and Maxim Pospelov
CP-violating contributions from the standard-model quark-mixing phase to electric dipole moments are shown to be three orders of magnitude larger than previously thought, possibly putting them in reach of future experiments.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 231801] Published Mon Nov 28, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yohei Ema, Ting Gao, and Maxim Pospelov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[State-of-the-Art Estimation of Protein Model Accuracy Using AlphaFold]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.238101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.238101"/>
        <updated>2022-11-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): James P. Roney and Sergey Ovchinnikov
An algorithm that already predicts how proteins fold might also shed light on the physical principles that dictate this folding.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 238101] Published Mon Nov 28, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>James P. Roney and Sergey Ovchinnikov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tunneling spectroscopy of few-monolayer ${\mathrm{NbSe}}_{2}$ in high magnetic fields: Triplet superconductivity and Ising protection]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.184514</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.184514"/>
        <updated>2022-11-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Kuzmanović, T. Dvir, D. LeBoeuf, S. Ilić, M. Haim, D. Möckli, S. Kramer, M. Khodas, M. Houzet, J. S. Meyer, M. Aprili, H. Steinberg, and C. H. L. Quay
Equal spin triplet pairs (ESTPs) of nuclei form the ground state of superfluid 3He. ESTPs of electrons have long been sought in superconducting systems. In layered transition metal dichalcogenides with 2H structure, such as NbSe2, ESTP correlations have been predicted to arise from the interaction of the Ising spin-orbit field, which pins the internal spin axis of conventional singlet pairs out-of-plane, and an applied in-plane magnetic field. The tunneling spectroscopy study done here of bilayer NbSe2 shows experimental signatures of these ESTPs.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 184514] Published Mon Nov 28, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Kuzmanović, T. Dvir, D. LeBoeuf, S. Ilić, M. Haim, D. Möckli, S. Kramer, M. Khodas, M. Houzet, J. S. Meyer, M. Aprili, H. Steinberg, and C. H. L. Quay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coupled Cluster Molecular Dynamics of Condensed Phase Systems Enabled by Machine Learning Potentials: Liquid Water Benchmark]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.226001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.226001"/>
        <updated>2022-11-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): János Daru, Harald Forbert, Jörg Behler, and Dominik Marx
A novel method offers a general and systematic approach to transfer the accuracy and versatility of coupled cluster theory from finite gas phase systems to the condensed phase.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 226001] Published Wed Nov 23, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>János Daru, Harald Forbert, Jörg Behler, and Dominik Marx</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manipulating Non-Abelian Anyons in a Chiral Multichannel Kondo Model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.227703</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.227703"/>
        <updated>2022-11-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Matan Lotem, Eran Sela, and Moshe Goldstein
Numerical evidence shows that non-Abelian anyons, fractional excitations that describe topological superconductors and quantum Hall states, appear in gapless electronic models in addition to gapped ones.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 227703] Published Wed Nov 23, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matan Lotem, Eran Sela, and Moshe Goldstein</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Complete characterization of non-Abelian topological phase transitions and detection of anyon splitting with projected entangled pair states]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.205139</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.205139"/>
        <updated>2022-11-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wen-Tao Xu, Jose Garre-Rubio, and Norbert Schuch
Topological phases - systems with a global ordering in the entanglement - exhibit exotic excitations known as anyons which can display highly nontrivial (non-Abelian) statistics. Through transitions between such phases, these anyons can undergo rather surprising changes. Perhaps most surprisingly, one anyon can split into two or more anyons, some of which might condense or become confined. The authors propose here a complete set of order parameters which allow one to extract the full information about how the properties of anyons change through phase transitions, and to apply them to a range of topological phase transitions.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 205139] Published Wed Nov 23, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wen-Tao Xu, Jose Garre-Rubio, and Norbert Schuch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bell-state generation for spin qubits via dissipative coupling]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L180406</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L180406"/>
        <updated>2022-11-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ji Zou, Shu Zhang, and Yaroslav Tserkovnyak
Magnet-mediated dissipative coupling between spin qubits can be exploited to imprint long-lived quantum entanglement. This work points to a new direction for the application of spintronic schemes in future quantum information technologies, with an eye on the dynamical phase transitions associated with non-Hermitian dynamics of the reduced density matrix.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L180406] Published Wed Nov 23, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ji Zou, Shu Zhang, and Yaroslav Tserkovnyak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intrinsic radio-frequency gradiometer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.053113</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.106.053113"/>
        <updated>2022-11-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Robert J. Cooper, David W. Prescott, Karen L. Sauer, Nezih Dural, and Michael V. Romalis
The authors develop two optically pumped atomic magnetometers with sub-fT sensitivity operating at radio frequencies and compare their magnetic-field sensitivity and interference rejection. They identify ways to improve the sensitivity of unshielded magnetic detectors, which could advance the development of portable magnetometers for field uses.

[Phys. Rev. A 106, 053113] Published Wed Nov 23, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert J. Cooper, David W. Prescott, Karen L. Sauer, Nezih Dural, and Michael V. Romalis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bose-Einstein Condensation of Europium]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.223401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.223401"/>
        <updated>2022-11-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuki Miyazawa, Ryotaro Inoue, Hiroki Matsui, Gyohei Nomura, and Mikio Kozuma
A Bose-Einstein condensate of europium atoms provides a new experimental platform for studying quantum spin interactions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 223401] Published Tue Nov 22, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuki Miyazawa, Ryotaro Inoue, Hiroki Matsui, Gyohei Nomura, and Mikio Kozuma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sublattice Ferrimagnetism in Quasifreestanding Graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.226401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.226401"/>
        <updated>2022-11-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Artem G. Rybkin, Artem V. Tarasov, Anna A. Rybkina, Dmitry Yu. Usachov, Anatoly E. Petukhov, Alexander V. Eryzhenkov, Dmitrii A. Pudikov, Alevtina A. Gogina, Ilya I. Klimovskikh, Giovanni Di Santo, Luca Petaccia, Andrei Varykhalov, and Alexander M. Shikin
Ferrimagnetic ordering is demonstrated in graphene at a Au/Co interface with dislocation loops that are responsible for the uniform magnetizations on the graphene sublattices.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 226401] Published Tue Nov 22, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Artem G. Rybkin, Artem V. Tarasov, Anna A. Rybkina, Dmitry Yu. Usachov, Anatoly E. Petukhov, Alexander V. Eryzhenkov, Dmitrii A. Pudikov, Alevtina A. Gogina, Ilya I. Klimovskikh, Giovanni Di Santo, Luca Petaccia, Andrei Varykhalov, and Alexander M. Shikin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kibble-Zurek Mechanism for Dynamical Ordering in a Driven Vortex System]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.227001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.227001"/>
        <updated>2022-11-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Maegochi, K. Ienaga, and S. Okuma
First experimental evidence for the applicability of the well known Kibble-Zurek mechanism to the nonequilibrium regime of electrically driven magnetic vortices in a superconducting Mo-Ge thin film.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 227001] Published Tue Nov 22, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Maegochi, K. Ienaga, and S. Okuma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Equivalence of Fluctuation-Dissipation and Edwards’ Temperature in Cyclically Sheared Granular Systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.228004</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.228004"/>
        <updated>2022-11-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zhikun Zeng, Shuyang Zhang, Xu Zheng, Chengjie Xia, Walter Kob, Ye Yuan, and Yujie Wang
X-ray tomography of cyclically sheared granular systems shows that the effective temperatures associated with the fluctuation-dissipation relation and the Edwards volume ensemble are equivalent, independent of shear amplitude and particle friction.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 228004] Published Tue Nov 22, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhikun Zeng, Shuyang Zhang, Xu Zheng, Chengjie Xia, Walter Kob, Ye Yuan, and Yujie Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fitting an active Brownian particle's mean-squared displacement with improved parameter estimation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.L052602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.106.L052602"/>
        <updated>2022-11-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maximilian R. Bailey, Alexander R. Sprenger, Fabio Grillo, Hartmut Löwen, and Lucio Isa
Active matter experiments are often analyzed in terms of the active Brownian particle model. In this paper the authors show that a commonly used approximation to estimate model parameters can lead to erroneous results, and they propose an improved procedure.

[Phys. Rev. E 106, L052602] Published Tue Nov 22, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maximilian R. Bailey, Alexander R. Sprenger, Fabio Grillo, Hartmut Löwen, and Lucio Isa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Critical phenomena in a gravitational collapse with a competing scalar field and gravitational waves in $4+1$ dimensions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.104044</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.104044"/>
        <updated>2022-11-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bernardo Porto Veronese and Carsten Gundlach
The authors numerically study the interactions between scalar fields and gravitational waves in the context of gravitational collapse at the threshold of black hole formation in 4+1 dimensions. They find evidence for the existence of a co-dimension two attractor in the dynamical systems picture.

[Phys. Rev. D 106, 104044] Published Tue Nov 22, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bernardo Porto Veronese and Carsten Gundlach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Many-body localization and the area law in two dimensions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L180201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.L180201"/>
        <updated>2022-11-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): K. S. C. Decker, D. M. Kennes, and C. Karrasch
Quantum systems are typically ergodic and can be described by a thermal ensemble. In this work, the authors use large-scale tensor network numerics to investigate if a generic two-dimensional disordered Heisenberg model of quantum spins exhibits a nonergodic phase. They provide evidence for the existence of a many-body localized regime at sufficiently strong disorder. They also estimate the critical disorder strength where a crossover into an ergodic regime occurs and address finite-size effects.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, L180201] Published Tue Nov 22, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>K. S. C. Decker, D. M. Kennes, and C. Karrasch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Model-Free Measurement of Local Entropy Production and Extractable Work in Active Matter]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.220601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.220601"/>
        <updated>2022-11-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sunghan Ro, Buming Guo, Aaron Shih, Trung V. Phan, Robert H. Austin, Dov Levine, Paul M. Chaikin, and Stefano Martiniani
A tool for estimating the local entropy production rate of a system enables the visualization and quantification of the out-of-equilibrium regions of an active-matter system.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 220601] Published Mon Nov 21, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sunghan Ro, Buming Guo, Aaron Shih, Trung V. Phan, Robert H. Austin, Dov Levine, Paul M. Chaikin, and Stefano Martiniani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microwave Susceptibility Observation of Interacting Many-Body Andreev States]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.227701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.129.227701"/>
        <updated>2022-11-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): V. Fatemi, P. D. Kurilovich, M. Hays, D. Bouman, T. Connolly, S. Diamond, N. E. Frattini, V. D. Kurilovich, P. Krogstrup, J. Nygård, A. Geresdi, L. I. Glazman, and M. H. Devoret
Measurements of the state-dependent microwave susceptibility of Andreev bound states in a superconductor-semiconductor weak link show that the susceptibility does not exhibit particle-hole symmetry due to the influence of the Coulomb interaction.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 129, 227701] Published Mon Nov 21, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>V. Fatemi, P. D. Kurilovich, M. Hays, D. Bouman, T. Connolly, S. Diamond, N. E. Frattini, V. D. Kurilovich, P. Krogstrup, J. Nygård, A. Geresdi, L. I. Glazman, and M. H. Devoret</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theory of QED radiative corrections to neutrino scattering at accelerator energies]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.093006</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.106.093006"/>
        <updated>2022-11-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Oleksandr Tomalak, Qing Chen, Richard J. Hill, Kevin S. McFarland, and Clarence Wret
Neutrino beam experiments to measure neutrino cross sections on nuclear targets are part of a major experimental program. In this paper, the authors compute radiative QED corrections to neutrino-nucleus scattering using effective field theory methods that separate perturbative QED soft and collinear contributions from hard nuclear ones. Applications of this framework are promising because theoretical control of neutrino-nucleus scattering is crucial to making sense of experimental data.

[Phys. Rev. D 106, 093006] Published Mon Nov 21, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oleksandr Tomalak, Qing Chen, Richard J. Hill, Kevin S. McFarland, and Clarence Wret</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wire construction of class DIII topological crystalline superconductors in two dimensions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.174512</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.174512"/>
        <updated>2022-11-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bingrui Peng, Hongming Weng, and Chen Fang
Topological superconductors have drawn wide interest as they host Majorana zero modes potentially useful in quantum computation. The crystalline symmetries remarkably enrich the family of topological superconductors. Here, the authors present a real-space method, called the “wire construction”, to construct two-dimensional topological superconductors. A complete classification of 2D topological crystalline superconductors in class DIII is obtained, with anomalous boundary states enumerated. The new method provides a real-space picture for understanding topological superconductors, and should guide the discovery of realistic topological superconducting materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 174512] Published Mon Nov 21, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bingrui Peng, Hongming Weng, and Chen Fang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Insulating phase in two-dimensional Josephson junction arrays investigated by nonlinear transport]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.184511</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.184511"/>
        <updated>2022-11-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hiroki Ikegami and Yasunobu Nakamura
Understanding the properties of the insulating phase is key to uncovering the nature of the superconductor-insulator quantum phase transition. Here, the authors study two-dimensional Josephson junction arrays, a canonical model system of the superconductor-insulator transition, to clarify how the insulating phase develops. By systematic studies of nonlinear transport properties, they show that the formation of the insulating phase upon decreasing temperature is understood as the localization of Cooper pairs caused by the Berezinskii-Kosterlitz-Thouless mechanism under the influence of a finite-range screening of the interaction between Cooper pairs.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 184511] Published Mon Nov 21, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hiroki Ikegami and Yasunobu Nakamura</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Combination of ultrafast time-resolved spectroscopy techniques for the analysis of electron dynamics of heliumlike impurity centers in silicon]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.195205</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.106.195205"/>
        <updated>2022-11-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. Dessmann, S. G. Pavlov, A. Pohl, V. B. Shuman, L. M. Portsel, A. N. Lodygin, Yu. A. Astrov, N. V. Abrosimov, B. Redlich, and H.-W. Hübers
Helium-like interstitial donors in silicon have larger binding energies compared to their hydrogen-like counterparts. Long lifetimes of the excited states are expected since one-phonon transitions are not available. Here, the authors study their relaxation dynamics at two different free electron laser facilities using photon echo, transient grating, and pump-probe spectroscopy. In contrast to the theoretical predictions and previous experimental studies, it is found that the relaxation rates are extremely high. These results shed new light on the electron-lattice interaction and open the possibility for further studies of similar materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 106, 195205] Published Mon Nov 21, 2022]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Dessmann, S. G. Pavlov, A. Pohl, V. B. Shuman, L. M. Portsel, A. N. Lodygin, Yu. A. Astrov, N. V. Abrosimov, B. Redlich, and H.-W. Hübers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>