<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-07-30T00:54:27.459Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-07-30T00:54:27.459Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Dark Matter Search Results from the LUX-ZEPLIN (LZ) Experiment]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.041002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.041002"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Aalbers et al. (LUX-ZEPLIN Collaboration)
Two mammoth underground detectors have delivered more stringent upper limits on how strongly a putative dark matter candidate interacts with normal matter.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 041002] Published Fri Jul 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Aalbers &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LUX-ZEPLIN Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Dark Matter Search with Nuclear Recoils from the XENONnT Experiment]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.041003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.041003"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): E. Aprile et al. (XENON Collaboration)
Two mammoth underground detectors have delivered more stringent upper limits on how strongly a putative dark matter candidate interacts with normal matter.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 041003] Published Fri Jul 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>E. Aprile &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (XENON Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phonon Laser in the Quantum Regime]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.043605</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.043605"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Behrle, T. L. Nguyen, F. Reiter, D. Baur, B. de Neeve, M. Stadler, M. Marinelli, F. Lancellotti, S. F. Yelin, and J. P. Home
A laser for vibrational energy, rather than for light, operating in the quantum regime could teach researchers about the interplay between spin, vibration, and dissipation in quantum mechanics.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 043605] Published Fri Jul 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Behrle, T. L. Nguyen, F. Reiter, D. Baur, B. de Neeve, M. Stadler, M. Marinelli, F. Lancellotti, S. F. Yelin, and J. P. Home</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis of Metallic Space-Time Gratings Using Lorentz Transformations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014063</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014063"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Antonio Alex-Amor, Carlos Molero, and Mário G. Silveirinha
Research on space-time-modulated systems has recently attracted interest due to their fascinating properties, such as nonreciprocity and frequency mixing. However, the scarcity of commercial full-wave solutions limits their study at present. Here mathematical tools are presented to shed light on the physics of moving and space-time metallic gratings, for direct application in engineering.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 014063] Published Fri Jul 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Antonio Alex-Amor, Carlos Molero, and Mário G. Silveirinha</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Observation of a Doubly Charged Tetraquark and Its Neutral Partner]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.041902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.041902"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Aaij et al. (LHCb Collaboration)
CERN’s Large Hadron Collider has detected the signals of two new four-quark states that are unusual because of their charges and their quark compositions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 041902] Published Thu Jul 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Aaij &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHCb Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetic Susceptibility of Andreev Bound States in Superfluid $^{3}\mathrm{He}\text{−}\mathrm{B}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.046001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.046001"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. W. Scott, M. D. Nguyen, D. Park, and W. P. Halperin
The magnetic susceptibility of superfluid Helium-3 in an anisotropic stretched aerogel exhibits behavior indicative of surface Andreev bound states within the planar aerogel structure.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 046001] Published Thu Jul 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. W. Scott, M. D. Nguyen, D. Park, and W. P. Halperin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonmonotonous Translocation Time of Polymers across Pores]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.048101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.048101"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Emanuele Locatelli, Valentino Bianco, Chantal Valeriani, and Paolo Malgaretti
The translocation time of linear polymers across a varying-section channel shows a nonmonotonous dependence on the polymer size, that may be a useful tool to design channels for polymer sorting.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 048101] Published Thu Jul 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emanuele Locatelli, Valentino Bianco, Chantal Valeriani, and Paolo Malgaretti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bag-mediated film atomization in a cough machine]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.074802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.074802"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pallav Kant, Cesar Pairetti, Youssef Saade, Stéphane Popinet, Stéphane Zaleski, and Detlef Lohse
Studying the fluid dynamics of exhalations, from droplet formation to turbulent cloud transport, is vital for understanding respiratory disease transmission. Our research combines experiments and numerical modeling to uncover the interfacial phenomena involved in bioaerosol generation during forceful breathing actions like coughing or sneezing. By investigating these fluid-mechanical processes, we aim to establish a foundation for optimizing mitigation strategies and promoting public health and well-being.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 074802] Published Thu Jul 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pallav Kant, Cesar Pairetti, Youssef Saade, Stéphane Popinet, Stéphane Zaleski, and Detlef Lohse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amplitude analysis of ${B}^{0}→{\overline{D}}^{0}{D}_{s}^{+}{π}^{−}$ and ${B}^{+}→{D}^{−}{D}_{s}^{+}{π}^{+}$ decays]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.012017</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.012017"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Aaij et al. (LHCb Collaboration)
CERN’s Large Hadron Collider has detected the signals of two new four-quark states that are unusual because of their charges and their quark compositions.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 012017] Published Thu Jul 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Aaij &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHCb Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Control of Four-Magnon Scattering by Pure Spin Current in a Magnonic Waveguide]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014062</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014062"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Hache, L. Körber, T. Hula, K. Lenz, A. Kákay, O. Hellwig, J. Lindner, J. Fassbender, and H. Schultheiss
Spintronic devices have attracted strong interest in neuromorphic computing, because of their inherent nonlinear behavior and synchronization capabilities. To build magnon-based networks between spintronic oscillators acting as neurons, control mechanisms are the key to adjusting their interactions. This study uses spin-orbit torque to reduce damping and enable magnon scattering in ultrathin waveguides. Microwave power and frequency, as well as spin-current magnitude, can be used as control parameters for nonlinear generation of additional magnon modes at distinct frequencies. Field-dependent time- and space-resolved measurements expose the underlying physical process.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 014062] Published Thu Jul 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Hache, L. Körber, T. Hula, K. Lenz, A. Kákay, O. Hellwig, J. Lindner, J. Fassbender, and H. Schultheiss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Control over epitaxy and the role of the InAs/Al interface in hybrid two-dimensional electron gas systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.073403</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.073403"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Erik Cheah, Daniel Z. Haxell, Rüdiger Schott, Peng Zeng, Ekaterina Paysen, Sofieke C. ten Kate, Marco Coraiola, Max Landstetter, Ali B. Zadeh, Achim Trampert, Marilyne Sousa, Heike Riel, Fabrizio Nichele, Werner Wegscheider, and Filip Krizek
The interface quality in semiconductor/superconductor (SE/SC) platforms plays a crucial role for the superconducting coupling strength. In this work, a novel growth approach to grow grain-boundary-free Al on a lattice-mismatched InAs quantum well is introduced. More specifically, a monocrystalline Al phase is achieved by intentional roughening of the semiconductor surface. This approach can in general be applied to other mismatched material systems where a high degree of crystallinity is essential. Furthermore, the authors investigate the altered interfaces in transport measurements, hoping to shed more light upon the pressing question: “What is the role of the detailed crystallography of the SC for the performance of SE/SC hybrid devices?”

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 073403] Published Wed Jul 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erik Cheah, Daniel Z. Haxell, Rüdiger Schott, Peng Zeng, Ekaterina Paysen, Sofieke C. ten Kate, Marco Coraiola, Max Landstetter, Ali B. Zadeh, Achim Trampert, Marilyne Sousa, Heike Riel, Fabrizio Nichele, Werner Wegscheider, and Filip Krizek</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symmetry-enforced Fermi degeneracy in topological semimetal $\mathrm{Rh}{\mathrm{Sb}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.074205</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.074205"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): K. Wang, L. Wang, I-L. Liu, F. Boschini, M. Zonno, M. Michiardi, E. Rotenberg, A. Bostwick, D. Graf, B. J. Ramshaw, A. Damascelli, and J. Paglione
Following the discovery of topological insulators, new classes of topological materials such as Dirac, Weyl, and “nodal” semimetals have attracted considerable interest. This work reports an experimental exploration of RhSb3, a symmorphic cubic unfilled skutterudite compound that was predicted to host a quasi-linear electronic band dispersion long before the topological revolution. Angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy, magnetotransport, and quantum oscillation measurements are used to confirm this material family to host a symmetry-enforced Fermi degeneracy, complete with nonzero Berry phase and location of the Fermi energy in the linear regime of the system’s valence band.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 074205] Published Wed Jul 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>K. Wang, L. Wang, I-L. Liu, F. Boschini, M. Zonno, M. Michiardi, E. Rotenberg, A. Bostwick, D. Graf, B. J. Ramshaw, A. Damascelli, and J. Paglione</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anisotropic magnetism of the Shastry-Sutherland lattice material $\mathrm{Ba}{\mathrm{Nd}}_{2}\mathrm{Pt}{\mathrm{O}}_{5}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.074407</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.074407"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christopher M. Pasco, Binod K. Rai, Matthias Frontzek, Gabriele Sala, Matthew B. Stone, Bryan C. Chakoumakos, V. Ovidiu Garlea, Andrew D. Christianson, and Andrew F. May
The Shastry-Sutherland (SS) model is one of the few solvable models for emergent properties of frustrated spin systems. However, relatively few materials realize an interacting spin network that is topologically equivalent to the SS model. In this work, researchers have expanded the material space with a foundational study of single crystalline BaNd2PtO5, which contains an effective SS lattice of Nd moments. A complex three-dimensional magnetic structure was observed via neutron single crystal diffraction. This spin structure is associated with a large magnetic anisotropy and a particularly strong sensitivity of the magnetization to the crystal orientation. These results offer an interesting new candidate for studying the physics associated with the SS model and establish a high sensitivity to crystal orientation as a guide when studying related materials.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 074407] Published Wed Jul 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher M. Pasco, Binod K. Rai, Matthias Frontzek, Gabriele Sala, Matthew B. Stone, Bryan C. Chakoumakos, V. Ovidiu Garlea, Andrew D. Christianson, and Andrew F. May</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hindered segmental dynamics in associative protein hydrogels studied by neutron spin-echo spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.075602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.075602"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ameya Rao, Brian R. Carrick, Helen Yao, and Bradley D. Olsen
In this study, associative polymer hydrogels formed by well-defined artificial proteins are found to exhibit unexpected submolecular dynamics, including a suppression of segmental diffusion with junction density and self-similar diffusive behavior in gels of different strand lengths and numbers of stickers per chain. These properties are in contrast to conventional polymer gels, demonstrating the rich physics of transient bonds in physically associating systems on molecular-scale dynamics.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 075602] Published Wed Jul 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ameya Rao, Brian R. Carrick, Helen Yao, and Bradley D. Olsen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stability and magnetic behavior of exfoliable nanowire one-dimensional materials]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.076002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.076002"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Joshua T. Paul, Janet Lu, Sohum Shah, Stephen R. Xie, and Richard G. Hennig
Researchers have demonstrated a way to sift a database of crystalline compounds for structures that can be separated into useful one-dimensional materials.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 076002] Published Wed Jul 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joshua T. Paul, Janet Lu, Sohum Shah, Stephen R. Xie, and Richard G. Hennig</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electroassociation of Ultracold Dipolar Molecules into Tetramer Field-Linked States]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.043402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.043402"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Goulven Quéméner, John L. Bohn, and James F. E. Croft
A proposed method uses electric fields to form tetramers from two ultracold dipolar molecules, analogous to the magnetic field association between two atoms to form molecules.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 043402] Published Wed Jul 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Goulven Quéméner, John L. Bohn, and James F. E. Croft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information-field-based global Bayesian inference of the jet transport coefficient]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.L011901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.L011901"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Man Xie, Weiyao Ke, Hanzhong Zhang, and Xin-Nian Wang
All recent analyses of heavy-ion data that extract information about the transport properties of excited strongly interacting matter use Bayesian techniques to fit parameters of functional forms motivated by physical insight. These explicit parameterizations may introduce undesired long-range correlations between different regions of parameter space. This paper develops an information field approach to avoid an explicit functional parameterization and obtain a global Bayesian inference of the jet transport coefficient q̂ as a function of the temperature.

[Phys. Rev. C 108, L011901] Published Wed Jul 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Man Xie, Weiyao Ke, Hanzhong Zhang, and Xin-Nian Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revealing temperature evolution of the Dirac band in ${\mathrm{ZrTe}}_{5}$ via magnetoinfrared spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L041202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L041202"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuxuan Jiang, Tianhao Zhao, Luojia Zhang, Qiang Chen, Haidong Zhou, Mykhaylo Ozerov, Dmitry Smirnov, and Zhigang Jiang
The topological phases and their dependence on the lattice constant in zirconium pentatelluride ZrTe5 have been under heated debate. Here, the authors study the temperature evolution of the Dirac band in ZrTe5 and find no indication of band-gap closure as temperature changes. They show that a weak topological insulator phase across the temperature range may not be the only explanation. A topological phase transition is still possible if the band mixing and inversion are considered.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L041202] Published Wed Jul 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuxuan Jiang, Tianhao Zhao, Luojia Zhang, Qiang Chen, Haidong Zhou, Mykhaylo Ozerov, Dmitry Smirnov, and Zhigang Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tissue Flows Are Tuned by Actomyosin-Dependent Mechanics in Developing Embryos]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.1.013004</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.1.013004"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Marisol Herrera-Perez, Christian Cupo, Cole Allan, Alicia B. Dagle, and Karen E. Kasza
In this study, the authors utilize optogenetic tools to achieve precise in vivo manipulation of actomyosin, allowing them to investigate the effects of its activation and deactivation on tissue behavior during early development in Drosophila.

[PRX Life 1, 013004] Published Tue Jul 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Marisol Herrera-Perez, Christian Cupo, Cole Allan, Alicia B. Dagle, and Karen E. Kasza</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flat $\mathrm{Γ}$ Moiré Bands in Twisted Bilayer ${\mathrm{WSe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.046401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.046401"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): G. Gatti, J. Issing, L. Rademaker, F. Margot, T. A. de Jong, S. J. van der Molen, J. Teyssier, T. K. Kim, M. D. Watson, C. Cacho, P. Dudin, J. Avila, K. Cordero Edwards, P. Paruch, N. Ubrig, I. Gutiérrez-Lezama, A. F. Morpurgo, A. Tamai, and F. Baumberger
Combined real- and momentum-space mapping of moire superlattices reveals intriguing flat-band physics of certain van der Waals materials.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 046401] Published Tue Jul 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>G. Gatti, J. Issing, L. Rademaker, F. Margot, T. A. de Jong, S. J. van der Molen, J. Teyssier, T. K. Kim, M. D. Watson, C. Cacho, P. Dudin, J. Avila, K. Cordero Edwards, P. Paruch, N. Ubrig, I. Gutiérrez-Lezama, A. F. Morpurgo, A. Tamai, and F. Baumberger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two-Dimensional Crystals far from Equilibrium]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.047101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.047101"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Leonardo Galliano, Michael E. Cates, and Ludovic Berthier
Crystals cannot form in two-dimensional particle systems at equilibrium. A new study has found a regime where a crystal can form if the system is driven out of equilibrium.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 047101] Published Tue Jul 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leonardo Galliano, Michael E. Cates, and Ludovic Berthier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robust wall modes and their interplay with bulk turbulence in confined rotating Rayleigh-Bénard convection]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.073501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.073501"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xander M. de Wit, Wouter J. M. Boot, Matteo Madonia, Andrés J. Aguirre Guzmán, and Rudie P. J. Kunnen
Rotating Rayleigh-Benard convection is the fundamental flow system to understand many geophysical and astrophysical flows. Typically studied in a confined cylindrical geometry, it was found in recent years that in such confined set-ups, a strong flow structure can develop near the side wall, obscuring observations of the bulk dynamics that we are interested in. Here we study different properties of this wall bounded flow, focussing on the interaction between the bulk and side wall region, to advance our understanding of how to disentangle the two.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 073501] Published Tue Jul 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xander M. de Wit, Wouter J. M. Boot, Matteo Madonia, Andrés J. Aguirre Guzmán, and Rudie P. J. Kunnen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Substrate-mediated leg interactions play a key role in insect stability on granular slopes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.014903</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.014903"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Miguel Piñeirua, Anna Verbe, and Jérôme Casas
Experiments show that an optimal distance between points of contact helps insects and other multilegged creatures avoid slipping down a steep granular slope.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 014903] Published Tue Jul 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miguel Piñeirua, Anna Verbe, and Jérôme Casas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anharmonicity of the antiferrodistortive soft mode in barium zirconate ${\mathrm{BaZrO}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014309</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014309"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Petter Rosander, Erik Fransson, Cosme Milesi-Brault, Constance Toulouse, Frédéric Bourdarot, Andrea Piovano, Alexei Bossak, Mael Guennou, and Göran Wahnström
BaZrO3 is one of the very few perovskites that is claimed to remain cubic down to 0 K, but its tendency towards an antiferrodistortive (AFD) instability has fueled a lot of debates. Here, the AFD phonon mode is studied using inelastic neutron scattering (INS) and inelastic x-ray scattering (IXS), combined with a computational approach including anharmonicity. Both classical molecular dynamics (MD) and a self-consistent phonon approach are used, the latter including quantum fluctuations of the atomic motion. This robust description of the AFD mode clarifies that BaZrO3 stays cubic down to 0 K.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 014309] Published Tue Jul 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Petter Rosander, Erik Fransson, Cosme Milesi-Brault, Constance Toulouse, Frédéric Bourdarot, Andrea Piovano, Alexei Bossak, Mael Guennou, and Göran Wahnström</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Single Flux Quantum-Based Digital Control of Superconducting Qubits in a Multichip Module]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.030310</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.030310"/>
        <updated>2023-07-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C.H. Liu, A. Ballard, D. Olaya, D.R. Schmidt, J. Biesecker, T. Lucas, J. Ullom, S. Patel, O. Rafferty, A. Opremcak, K. Dodge, V. Iaia, T. McBroom, J.L. DuBois, P.F. Hopkins, S.P. Benz, B.L.T. Plourde, and R. McDermott
Integration of quantum bits and single flux quantum control elements in a multichip module provides a path to scaling, and an understanding of error mechanisms will guide future improvements in control fidelity.

[PRX Quantum 4, 030310] Published Mon Jul 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C.H. Liu, A. Ballard, D. Olaya, D.R. Schmidt, J. Biesecker, T. Lucas, J. Ullom, S. Patel, O. Rafferty, A. Opremcak, K. Dodge, V. Iaia, T. McBroom, J.L. DuBois, P.F. Hopkins, S.P. Benz, B.L.T. Plourde, and R. McDermott</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Femtosecond Polarization Shaping of Free-Electron Laser Pulses]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.045001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.045001"/>
        <updated>2023-07-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Giovanni Perosa et al.
A new method can generate intense, extreme-ultraviolet (XUV) pulses with time-dependent polarization using a free-electron laser, which may lead to new coherent control schemes for probing and manipulating core electrons in matter.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 045001] Published Mon Jul 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giovanni Perosa &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coupling of Ferromagnetic and Antiferromagnetic Spin Dynamics in ${\mathrm{Mn}}_{2}\mathrm{Au}/\mathrm{NiFe}$ Thin Film Bilayers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.046701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.046701"/>
        <updated>2023-07-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hassan Al-Hamdo, Tobias Wagner, Yaryna Lytvynenko, Gutenberg Kendzo, Sonka Reimers, Moritz Ruhwedel, Misbah Yaqoob, Vitaliy I. Vasyuchka, Philipp Pirro, Jairo Sinova, Mathias Kläui, Martin Jourdan, Olena Gomonay, and Mathias Weiler
By coupling antiferromagnetic and ferromagnetic modes in a ferromagnet-antiferromagnet bilayer, the antiferromagnetic dynamics can be made visible in the GHz range

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 046701] Published Mon Jul 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hassan Al-Hamdo, Tobias Wagner, Yaryna Lytvynenko, Gutenberg Kendzo, Sonka Reimers, Moritz Ruhwedel, Misbah Yaqoob, Vitaliy I. Vasyuchka, Philipp Pirro, Jairo Sinova, Mathias Kläui, Martin Jourdan, Olena Gomonay, and Mathias Weiler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drag resistance mediated by quantum spin liquids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014425</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014425"/>
        <updated>2023-07-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Raffaele Mazzilli, Alex Levchenko, and Elio J. König
Probing quantum spin liquid behavior in atomically thin materials is a challenging task. The authors propose here an experimental setup consisting of two metallic layers separated by a thin quantum spin liquid. The voltage induced in one of the metals by injecting a current in the other metal probes the nontrivial dynamics of gapless excitations in the quantum spin liquid. This analysis captures U(1) and ℤ2 quantum spin liquids and may find realizations in materials such as α-RuCl3, 1T-TaSe2, and 1T-TaS2.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 014425] Published Mon Jul 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Raffaele Mazzilli, Alex Levchenko, and Elio J. König</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetocaloric-Effect-Enhanced Near-Field Magneto-optical Thermal Switch]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014053</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014053"/>
        <updated>2023-07-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Simo Pajovic and Svetlana V. Boriskina
Magnetism has played an increasingly important role in thermal technologies over the past century, including solid-state magnetic refrigerators and magneto-optical thermal switches. In this study, modeling shows that a two-pronged approach enables a thermal switch with two tuning “knobs”: a magnetocaloric knob to tune the temperature gradient, and a magneto-optical knob to fine-tune the effective thermal resistance. This enables additional modes of operation, such as reversing the flow of heat. This work highlights the utility of combining various “-caloric” effects with complementary modes of heat transfer for fresh ways of controlling thermal energy.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 014053] Published Mon Jul 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simo Pajovic and Svetlana V. Boriskina</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prediction of a roton-type feature in warm dense hydrogen]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033039</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033039"/>
        <updated>2023-07-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Paul Hamann, Linda Kordts, Alexey Filinov, Michael Bonitz, Tobias Dornheim, and Jan Vorberger
This paper provides confirmation that a roton-type correlation effect manifest itself in warm dense hydrogen.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 033039] Published Fri Jul 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Hamann, Linda Kordts, Alexey Filinov, Michael Bonitz, Tobias Dornheim, and Jan Vorberger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Operator Product Expansion Coefficients of the 3D Ising Criticality via Quantum Fuzzy Spheres]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.031601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.031601"/>
        <updated>2023-07-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Liangdong Hu, Yin-Chen He, and W. Zhu
A new numerical technique leads to the precise determination of conformal data in the 3D Ising model, including some previously unknown expansion coefficients.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 031601] Published Fri Jul 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liangdong Hu, Yin-Chen He, and W. Zhu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vortex dynamics and fin-fin interactions resulting in performance enhancement in fish-like propulsion]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.073101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.073101"/>
        <updated>2023-07-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jiacheng Guo (郭佳诚), Pan Han (韩攀), Wei Zhang (张伟), Junshi Wang (王君实), George V. Lauder, Valentina Di Santo, and Haibo Dong (董海波)
The generation of leading-edge vortices (LEV) by the caudal fin (CF) has long been recognized as playing a key role in efficient propulsion in fish-like swimming. This study focuses on LEV enhancement due to vortex shedding of the median anal fin (AF), utilizing trout’s unique morphology and fin configurations. The shed anal-fin vortex (AFV) is found to stabilize and strengthen the LEV of the CF through its shearing with the CF leading edge, creating stronger leading-edge suction, resulting in stronger thrust production and increased propulsive efficiency in trout-like swimming.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 073101] Published Fri Jul 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jiacheng Guo (郭佳诚), Pan Han (韩攀), Wei Zhang (张伟), Junshi Wang (王君实), George V. Lauder, Valentina Di Santo, and Haibo Dong (董海波)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mass Partitioning in Fragmenting Tin Sheets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014048</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014048"/>
        <updated>2023-07-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bo Liu, Randy A. Meijer, Wei Li, Javier Hernandez-Rueda, Hanneke Gelderblom, and Oscar O. Versolato
This article reports experiments on the mass partitioning of a fragmenting liquid sheet, formed after the impact of a nanosecond laser pulse on a tin microdroplet, to help in optimizing mass utilization of the liquid tin that is key to extreme-ultraviolet nanolithography. The authors apply machine learning to analyze subresolution fragments in the temporal evolution of the sheet and its bounding rim, ligaments protruding from the rim, and droplets shed by the ligaments. A full accounting includes the further contributions unique to laser-droplet impact: the mass ablated by the laser, and a surprising, centrally located mass remnant.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 014048] Published Fri Jul 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bo Liu, Randy A. Meijer, Wei Li, Javier Hernandez-Rueda, Hanneke Gelderblom, and Oscar O. Versolato</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thermodynamic Limits of Sperm Swimming Precision]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.1.013003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.1.013003"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. Maggi, F. Saglimbeni, V. Carmona Sosa, R. Di Leonardo, B. Nath, and A. Puglisi
This study employs the thermodynamic uncertainty relation to explore the connection between energy dissipation and mesoscopic fluctuations in sperm beating, elucidating the role of the coupling among molecular motors that actuate the flagellar movement.

[PRX Life 1, 013003] Published Thu Jul 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. Maggi, F. Saglimbeni, V. Carmona Sosa, R. Di Leonardo, B. Nath, and A. Puglisi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exciton superfluidity in two-dimensional heterostructures from first principles: Importance of material-specific screening]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014506</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014506"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rune Højlund, Emil Grovn, Sahar Pakdel, Kristian S. Thygesen, and Fredrik Nilsson
van der Waal heterostructures can host long-lived excitons that can condense and exhibit superfluidity at low temperatures. In this paper, Højlund, Grovn and coworkers derive a first-principles framework, based on existing open-source codes, that can be used to model these systems. This framework is then used to evaluate the exciton binding energies and superfluid properties of hundreds of different heterostructures. Based on these calculations, the authors propose optimized materials with superior properties compared to the standard platforms.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 014506] Published Thu Jul 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rune Højlund, Emil Grovn, Sahar Pakdel, Kristian S. Thygesen, and Fredrik Nilsson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamics of orbital degrees of freedom probed via isotope $^{121,123}\mathrm{Sb}$ nuclear quadrupole moments in Sb-substituted iron pnictide superconductors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014507</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014507"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Kouchi, K. Yoshinaga, T. Asano, S. Nishioka, M. Yashima, H. Mukuda, A. Iyo, T. Kawashima, and S. Miyasaka
Since the discovery of the iron-based high-temperature superconductors, the superconductivity mechanism related to spin fluctuations and nematic (orbital) fluctuations has been much discussed, but it is remains unclear. Here, the authors reveal that the isotope 121,123Sb nuclei with large quadrupole moments are a sensitive local probe to observe the dynamics of orbital degrees of freedom. This provides us with a new approach to investigate systematically the correlation between the superconductivity and both the nematic and spin fluctuations, even in polycrystalline samples.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 014507] Published Thu Jul 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Kouchi, K. Yoshinaga, T. Asano, S. Nishioka, M. Yashima, H. Mukuda, A. Iyo, T. Kawashima, and S. Miyasaka</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optical magnetoelectric effects resonantly enhanced via electromagnons in cycloidal helimagnets ${\mathrm{Eu}}_{1−x}{\mathrm{Y}}_{x}{\mathrm{MnO}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.024418</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.024418"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Ogino, Y. Kaneko, Y. Tokura, and Y. Takahashi
Dynamical magnetoelectric coupling gives rise to nonreciprocal phenomena for light such as the optical diode effect and the nonreciprocity of light polarization. Here, the authors comprehensively study these nonreciprocal optical effects resonantly enhanced by electromagnons for multiferroic spin spiral states of perovskite manganites. The giant nonreciprocity observed near the phase boundary demonstrates an important role of anharmonicity of spin excitations for these nonreciprocal effects. Furthermore, they find one of the largest values for the dynamical magnetoelectric coupling on the resonance of electromagnons.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 024418] Published Thu Jul 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Ogino, Y. Kaneko, Y. Tokura, and Y. Takahashi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Obstructions to gapped phases from noninvertible symmetries]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.045134</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.045134"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anuj Apte, Clay Córdova, and Ho Tat Lam
Our understanding of quantum symmetry of systems has considerably broadened over the last decade. The idea of symmetry has become intrinsically linked with topology described and algebraically characterized by higher categories. Studying three-dimensional systems with noninvertible symmetries, the authors show here that these symmetries are in general incompatible with a unique gapped ground state. Their results extend the ideas behind the Lieb-Shultz-Mattis theorem to the arena of higher-dimensional field theories invariant under a novel class of symmetries.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 045134] Published Thu Jul 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anuj Apte, Clay Córdova, and Ho Tat Lam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strain control of exciton and trion spin-valley dynamics in monolayer transition metal dichalcogenides]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L041404</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L041404"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Z. An, P. Soubelet, Y. Zhumagulov, M. Zopf, A. Delhomme, C. Qian, P. E. Faria Junior, J. Fabian, X. Cao, J. Yang, A. V. Stier, F. Ding, and J. J. Finley
The spin-valley physics of monolayer transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) remains one of the main interests in the class of van der Waals materials. At low temperature, it is mainly driven by the electron-hole exchange interaction (EHEI) that describes the annihilation of an exciton in one valley and the creation of an exciton in the time-reversal equivalent valley. Here, the authors show that the EHEI in monolayer TMDs is biaxial strain dependent and, surprisingly, it is an order of magnitude more strain dependent than expected from these first principles calculations. This points to a valley scattering channel that has not been considered in the literature so far.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L041404] Published Thu Jul 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Z. An, P. Soubelet, Y. Zhumagulov, M. Zopf, A. Delhomme, C. Qian, P. E. Faria Junior, J. Fabian, X. Cao, J. Yang, A. V. Stier, F. Ding, and J. J. Finley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Direct Observation of Collider Neutrinos with FASER at the LHC]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.031801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.031801"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Henso Abreu et al. (FASER Collaboration)
The first observation of neutrinos produced at a particle collider opens a new field of study and offers ways to test the limits of the standard model.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 031801] Published Wed Jul 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Henso Abreu &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (FASER Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of Collider Muon Neutrinos with the SND@LHC Experiment]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.031802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.031802"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Albanese et al. (SND@LHC Collaboration)
The first observation of neutrinos produced at a particle collider opens a new field of study and offers ways to test the limits of the standard model.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 031802] Published Wed Jul 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Albanese &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (SND@LHC Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Large-Momentum-Transfer Atom Interferometers with $\mathrm{μ}\mathrm{rad}$-Accuracy Using Bragg Diffraction]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.033602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.033602"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J.-N. Kirsten-Siemß, F. Fitzek, C. Schubert, E. M. Rasel, N. Gaaloul, and K. Hammerer
A new method using atoms on optical gratings significantly improves the precision of the Bragg atom interferometers by reducing some of the detrimental systematic effects.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 033602] Published Wed Jul 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J.-N. Kirsten-Siemß, F. Fitzek, C. Schubert, E. M. Rasel, N. Gaaloul, and K. Hammerer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extended Spatial Coherence of Interlayer Excitons in ${\mathrm{MoSe}}_{2}/{\mathrm{WSe}}_{2}$ Heterobilayers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.036902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.036902"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mirco Troue, Johannes Figueiredo, Lukas Sigl, Christos Paspalides, Manuel Katzer, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Malte Selig, Andreas Knorr, Ursula Wurstbauer, and Alexander W. Holleitner
Evidence of coherent light emission from excitons in a 2D-material structure could inspire new quantum-technology applications.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 036902] Published Wed Jul 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mirco Troue, Johannes Figueiredo, Lukas Sigl, Christos Paspalides, Manuel Katzer, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Malte Selig, Andreas Knorr, Ursula Wurstbauer, and Alexander W. Holleitner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Compensation of seeding bias for particle tracking velocimetry in turbulent flows]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.074603</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.074603"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Thomas Barois, Bianca Viggiano, Thomas Basset, Raúl Bayoán Cal, Romain Volk, Mathieu Gibert, and Mickaël Bourgoin
For small particles locally injected in a turbulent flow and used as fluid tracers, the reconstruction of the mean flow is biased by the particle dispersion caused by turbulence. For example, in a turbulent jet with nozzle injection, the entrained flow is inaccurately measured because all the tracked particles come from the jet source. In this work, we present a compensation method that provides the accurate mean velocity for turbulent flows in non-homogeneous seeding conditions.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 074603] Published Wed Jul 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Barois, Bianca Viggiano, Thomas Basset, Raúl Bayoán Cal, Romain Volk, Mathieu Gibert, and Mickaël Bourgoin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stability of the modulator in a plasma-modulated plasma accelerator]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.015204</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.015204"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. J. van de Wetering, S. M. Hooker, and R. Walczak
Laser-plasma accelerators can provide a compact method for acceleration of particles. The authors of this paper derive a three-dimensional analytic theory for a laser-plasma accelerator that some of the authors introduced earlier. Using theory and simulations, they evaluate the influence of various parameters on the stability of the accelerator and conclude that higher energies can be achieved than those demonstrated in the original proposal.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 015204] Published Wed Jul 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. J. van de Wetering, S. M. Hooker, and R. Walczak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interplay between magnetism and band topology in the kagome magnets $R{\mathrm{Mn}}_{6}{\mathrm{Sn}}_{6}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.045132</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.045132"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Y. Lee, R. Skomski, X. Wang, P. P. Orth, Y. Ren, Byungkyun Kang, A. K. Pathak, A. Kutepov, B. N. Harmon, R. J. McQueeney, I. I. Mazin, and Liqin Ke
The kagome magnets RMn6Sn6 have recently emerged as a new topological materials platform. By elucidating the topological nature of the band structure, the authors conclude that the observed anomalous Hall conductivity is unrelated to the previously speculated quasi-two-dimensional Dirac points. The microscopic origin of magnetocrystalline anisotropy is explored at various levels: phenomenological, analytical, and ab initio. The authors discovered how the special Mn coordination of the rare-earth atoms results in significant high-order anisotropy.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 045132] Published Wed Jul 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Y. Lee, R. Skomski, X. Wang, P. P. Orth, Y. Ren, Byungkyun Kang, A. K. Pathak, A. Kutepov, B. N. Harmon, R. J. McQueeney, I. I. Mazin, and Liqin Ke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Single-Photon Synchronization with a Room-Temperature Atomic Quantum Memory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.033601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.033601"/>
        <updated>2023-07-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Omri Davidson, Ohad Yogev, Eilon Poem, and Ofer Firstenberg
Researchers use two clouds of rubidium vapor to generate, store, and simultaneously release two photons.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 033601] Published Tue Jul 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Omri Davidson, Ohad Yogev, Eilon Poem, and Ofer Firstenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voltage X-Ray Reflectometry: A Method to Study Electric-Field-Induced Changes in Interfacial Electronic Structures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.036201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.036201"/>
        <updated>2023-07-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sven Erik Ilse, Gisela Schütz, and Eberhard Goering
A new method enables element-specific measurements of electric-field-induced changes to electronic structures at buried interfaces.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 036201] Published Tue Jul 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sven Erik Ilse, Gisela Schütz, and Eberhard Goering</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comprehensive <i>Ab Initio</i> Investigation of the Phase Diagram of Quasi-One-Dimensional Molecular Solids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.036401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.036401"/>
        <updated>2023-07-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kazuyoshi Yoshimi, Takahiro Misawa, Takao Tsumuraya, and Hitoshi Seo
By deriving the \textit{ab initio} effective low-energy Hamiltonians of complex materials and analyzing them with a highly accurate numerical solver, a crucial parameter which determines physical properties has been identified, providing guidelines for designing functional organic materials.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 036401] Published Tue Jul 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kazuyoshi Yoshimi, Takahiro Misawa, Takao Tsumuraya, and Hitoshi Seo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kinematic Sunyaev-Zel’dovich effect with ACT, DES, and BOSS: A novel hybrid estimator]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.023516</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.023516"/>
        <updated>2023-07-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Mallaby-Kay et al.
This paper introduces a novel, “hybrid” (optical+spectroscopic) estimator for kinematic Sunyaev-Zel’dovich (kSZ) studies. It is expected to be most useful for increasing the SZ signal when results from upcoming data surveys become available.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 023516] Published Tue Jul 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Mallaby-Kay &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Partial fillings of the bosonic ${E}_{8}$ quantum Hall state]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.035136</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.035136"/>
        <updated>2023-07-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pak Kau Lim, Michael Mulligan, and Jeffrey C. Y. Teo
Interactions are crucial in driving topological phenomena in bosonic systems. Here, the authors construct exactly solvable models of topological phases of interacting bosons that preserve electric charge. They focus on the E8 bosonic integer quantum Hall state and show how its intrinsic E8 symmetry allows for the emergence of fractional topological phases of bosons. They detail the charge and statistics of the quasiparticle excitations of the resulting fractional quantum Hall states.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 035136] Published Tue Jul 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pak Kau Lim, Michael Mulligan, and Jeffrey C. Y. Teo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin-statistics relation for quantum Hall states]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L041105</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L041105"/>
        <updated>2023-07-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alberto Nardin, Eddy Ardonne, and Leonardo Mazza
Forty years ago, Laughlin explained the newly discovered fractional quantum Hall effect by proposing his famous wave function. He predicted the existence of anyons, particles with fractional charge, obeying fractional statistics. The fractional charge was confirmed almost thirty years ago, while the fractional statistics was observed only a few years back. In this paper, the authors focus on yet another fundamental property of the anyons, namely their spin. They derive a “spin-statistics relation” for anyons in fractional quantum Hall states, directly from the microscopic theory. This relation is a generalization of the fundamental “spin-statistics relation” that all ordinary particles obey.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L041105] Published Tue Jul 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alberto Nardin, Eddy Ardonne, and Leonardo Mazza</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of a $J/ψ\mathrm{Λ}$ Resonance Consistent with a Strange Pentaquark Candidate in ${B}^{−}→J/ψ\mathrm{Λ}\overline{p}$ Decays]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.031901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.031901"/>
        <updated>2023-07-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Aaij et al. (LHCb Collaboration)
A pentaquark candidate that has strange quark content, seen as a resonant structure in B−→JψΛp¯ decay, is observed for the first time.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 031901] Published Mon Jul 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Aaij &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHCb Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synthesis of Single Crystals of $ε$-Iron and Direct Measurements of Its Elastic Constants]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.034101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.034101"/>
        <updated>2023-07-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Agnès Dewaele, Bernard Amadon, Alexei Bosak, Volodymyr Svitlyk, and Florent Occelli
Laboratory experiments elucidate the directions and speeds at which acoustic waves propagate in the type of iron that likely makes up Earth’s core.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 034101] Published Mon Jul 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agnès Dewaele, Bernard Amadon, Alexei Bosak, Volodymyr Svitlyk, and Florent Occelli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coupled instabilities drive quasiperiodic order-disorder transitions in Faraday waves]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.L012601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.L012601"/>
        <updated>2023-07-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Valeri Frumkin and Shreyas Gokhale
A vibrated layer of fluid can form an ordered pattern of standing waves known as Faraday waves, or a disordered state full of defects. The authors experimentally study the transitions between these two states and find an explanation for their quasiperiodicity in time.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, L012601] Published Mon Jul 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Valeri Frumkin and Shreyas Gokhale</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magic-angle twisted symmetric trilayer graphene as a topological heavy-fermion problem]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.035129</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.035129"/>
        <updated>2023-07-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jiabin Yu, Ming Xie, B. Andrei Bernevig, and Sankar Das Sarma
A topological heavy-fermion (THF) model is formulated for magical-angle twisted symmetric trilayer graphene (MATSTG), where “symmetric” means that the top and bottom layers are rotated equally with respect to the middle layer. In addition to the localized f modes and itinerant c modes (which serve as the basis of the THF model for twisted bilayer graphene), the THF model of MATSTG consists of extra Dirac (d) modes. The newly proposed f−c−d THF model can well reproduce previous numerical results on the correlated phases at integer fillings, and can provide a new analytical understanding of them at charge neutrality.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 035129] Published Mon Jul 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jiabin Yu, Ming Xie, B. Andrei Bernevig, and Sankar Das Sarma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steady-State Microwave Mode Cooling with a Diamond N-$V$ Ensemble]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014033</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014033"/>
        <updated>2023-07-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Donald P. Fahey, Kurt Jacobs, Matthew J. Turner, Hyeongrak Choi, Jonathan E. Hoffman, Dirk Englund, and Matthew E. Trusheim
All electronics are subject to thermal noise, which sets a minimum power to distinguish a signal from ambient background. Here quantum systems—in particular the nitrogen-vacancy center in diamond—show a path forward, as they can be laser-cooled to a quantum mechanical ground state while a device remains at ambient conditions. By placing an ensemble of N-V centers inside a low-loss microwave cavity in which their spins strongly interact with gigahertz magnetic fields, the cold spins extract more energy than can leak in from the hot environment. The output voltage shows vastly reduced fluctuations at the cavity frequency; the effective temperature is lowered by 150 K.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 014033] Published Mon Jul 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Donald P. Fahey, Kurt Jacobs, Matthew J. Turner, Hyeongrak Choi, Jonathan E. Hoffman, Dirk Englund, and Matthew E. Trusheim</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Negative vacuum friction in terahertz gain systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.045406</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.045406"/>
        <updated>2023-07-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lixin Ge
A friction-like quantum force could accelerate the motion of a rotating nanometer-diameter sphere when the sphere sits next to a graphene-coated surface.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 045406] Published Fri Jul 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lixin Ge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Equivalence of Active and Passive Gravitational Mass Tested with Lunar Laser Ranging]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.021401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.021401"/>
        <updated>2023-07-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vishwa Vijay Singh, Jürgen Müller, Liliane Biskupek, Eva Hackmann, and Claus Lämmerzahl
High-precision measurements of the Moon’s orbit show that iron and aluminum feel and exert gravitational forces equally.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 021401] Published Thu Jul 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vishwa Vijay Singh, Jürgen Müller, Liliane Biskupek, Eva Hackmann, and Claus Lämmerzahl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubiquitous Superconducting Diode Effect in Superconductor Thin Films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.027001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.027001"/>
        <updated>2023-07-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yasen Hou, Fabrizio Nichele, Hang Chi, Alessandro Lodesani, Yingying Wu, Markus F. Ritter, Daniel Z. Haxell, Margarita Davydova, Stefan Ilić, Ourania Glezakou-Elbert, Amith Varambally, F. Sebastian Bergeret, Akashdeep Kamra, Liang Fu, Patrick A. Lee, and Jagadeesh S. Moodera
A superconducting strip allows more superconducting current to flow in one direction than in the other—achieving a stronger diode effect than previous devices.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 027001] Published Thu Jul 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yasen Hou, Fabrizio Nichele, Hang Chi, Alessandro Lodesani, Yingying Wu, Markus F. Ritter, Daniel Z. Haxell, Margarita Davydova, Stefan Ilić, Ourania Glezakou-Elbert, Amith Varambally, F. Sebastian Bergeret, Akashdeep Kamra, Liang Fu, Patrick A. Lee, and Jagadeesh S. Moodera</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ionic liquid drop impact onto heated surfaces]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.073602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.073602"/>
        <updated>2023-07-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lihui Liu, Bijiao He, Weizong Wang, Guobiao Cai, and Peichun Amy Tsai
The Leidenfrost effect causes liquid droplets, like water or ethanol, to levitate over hot surfaces due to an insulating vapor layer. This process limits heat transfer, leading researchers to find ways to suppress it. Remarkably, our experimental findings show that ionic liquids do not exhibit the Leidenfrost phenomena, despite similar impact speed and surface temperature. Their superior thermal stability prevents the Leidenfrost effect, opening exciting possibilities for enhancing a variety of thermal processes, including cooling and coating applications.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 073602] Published Thu Jul 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lihui Liu, Bijiao He, Weizong Wang, Guobiao Cai, and Peichun Amy Tsai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drag, lift, and buoyancy forces on a single large particle in dense granular flows]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.074301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.074301"/>
        <updated>2023-07-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Arjun V. Yennemadi and Devang V. Khakhar
Large particles migrate upward in gravity-driven granular shear flows, which results in size segregation, a phenomenon of considerable practical importance. In this study, we show using extensive discrete element method (DEM) computations that this effect is not caused by a granular lift force or Archimedean buoyancy, rather it stems from a buoyancy force that exceeds the weight of the large particle, which is a result of patches of high-stress concentration on the surface of the large particle caused by strong flow-induced layering.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 074301] Published Thu Jul 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Arjun V. Yennemadi and Devang V. Khakhar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cavity Nano-Optomechanics with Suspended Subwavelength-Sized Nanowires]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014025</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014025"/>
        <updated>2023-07-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Antoine Reigue, Francesco Fogliano, Philip Heringlake, Laure Mercier de Lépinay, Benjamin Besga, Jakob Reichel, Benjamin Pigeau, and Olivier Arcizet
An ongoing line of inquiry in cavity optomechanics consists of increasing the strength of the light-oscillator interaction to explore various dynamical regimes. By combining a high-finesse microcavity with an ultrasensitive force sensor (a suspended SiC nanowire), one can reach the regime where a single photon in the cavity has a measurable impact on the nanoresonator. The internal optical resonances of the nanowire strongly structure and possibly enhance the light-nanowire interaction, which can be fine-tuned through careful positioning of the subwavelength-sized nanowire within the standing wave inside the cavity.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 014025] Published Thu Jul 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Antoine Reigue, Francesco Fogliano, Philip Heringlake, Laure Mercier de Lépinay, Benjamin Besga, Jakob Reichel, Benjamin Pigeau, and Olivier Arcizet</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tilt-driven antiferroelectricity in ${\mathrm{PbZrO}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.L071401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.L071401"/>
        <updated>2023-07-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Konstantin Shapovalov and Massimiliano Stengel
Though antiferroelectricity in PbZrO3 was discovered over 70 years ago, there is still no consensus on the exact physical mechanism behind its formation. In this study, the authors rationalize the antiferroelectric Pbam state of PbZrO3 as a modulated phase, where polarization and antiphase O6 octahedra tilts are coupled via a trilinear gradient term – the so-called rotopolar coupling. A Landau-like continuum Hamiltonian, with gradient terms calculated directly from first principles, gives an accurate description of the energetics and structure of the Pbam phase. Besides reconciling the existing theories on PbZrO3, this study may facilitate the understanding of other modulated structures in perovskites, including ferrielectric and incommensurate phases.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, L071401] Published Wed Jul 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Konstantin Shapovalov and Massimiliano Stengel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linear Classification of Neural Manifolds with Correlated Variability]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.027301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.027301"/>
        <updated>2023-07-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Albert J. Wakhloo, Tamara J. Sussman, and SueYeon Chung
A new theory allows researchers to determine the ability of arbitrarily complex neural networks to perform recognition tasks on data with intricate structure.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 027301] Published Wed Jul 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Albert J. Wakhloo, Tamara J. Sussman, and SueYeon Chung</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental verification of the reflection matrix description in linear magneto-optics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014415</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014415"/>
        <updated>2023-07-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Carmen Martín Valderrama, Mikel Quintana, and Andreas Berger
The magneto-optical Kerr effect (MOKE) is described by a dielectric tensor ϵ that contains magnetization dependent terms, whose impact on reflected light is solved as an electromagnetic boundary problem. Corresponding solutions for the Jones-type reflection matrix R have been known for decades, but have not been rigorously confirmed in experiments. Here, the authors have verified that the MOKE coefficients of R describe an ellipsoid (ellipse) for a random three-dimensional (two-dimensional) magnetization vector as predicted. The experiments accomplish the simultaneous measurements of all R components through generalized magneto-optical ellipsometry.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 014415] Published Wed Jul 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carmen Martín Valderrama, Mikel Quintana, and Andreas Berger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Digitized Counterdiabatic Quantum Algorithm for Protein Folding]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014024</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014024"/>
        <updated>2023-07-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pranav Chandarana, Narendra N. Hegade, Iraitz Montalban, Enrique Solano, and Xi Chen
The challenge of predicting protein folding—a pivotal task in biology, chemistry, and drug design—has yet to be fully surmounted, due to the complexity of finding the lowest-energy configuration of the constituent amino acids. The current study provides a hybrid classical-quantum digitized counterdiabatic approach that enhances the performance of existing quantum algorithms, producing remarkable results even in the NISQ era. This innovative solution opens up possibilities for tackling complex problems in biology and chemistry, pushing the boundaries of what is achievable with quantum computing.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 014024] Published Wed Jul 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pranav Chandarana, Narendra N. Hegade, Iraitz Montalban, Enrique Solano, and Xi Chen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final Measurement of the $^{235}\mathrm{U}$ Antineutrino Energy Spectrum with the PROSPECT-I Detector at HFIR]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.021802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.021802"/>
        <updated>2023-07-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Andriamirado et al. (PROSPECT Collaboration)
The most precise measurement of the antineutrino spectrum of Uranium-235 using the PROSPECT-I detector at the High Flux Isotope Reactor.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 021802] Published Tue Jul 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Andriamirado &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (PROSPECT Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Driving Alkali Rydberg Transitions with a Phase-Modulated Optical Lattice]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.023201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.023201"/>
        <updated>2023-07-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Cardman and G. Raithel
Oscillating an optical lattice of Rydberg atoms at the right frequency causes the atoms to make electronic transitions, which can be useful for quantum processing techniques.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 023201] Published Tue Jul 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Cardman and G. Raithel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Difference between fixed-order and contour-improved perturbation theory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.014007</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.014007"/>
        <updated>2023-07-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maarten Golterman, Kim Maltman, and Santiago Peris
Contour-Improved Perturbation Theory and Fixed-Order Perturbation Theory are two methods used to approach the poorly converging QCD calculations involved in extracting the strong coupling constant from tau decays. However, they give somewhat differing results. Here, the authors introduce a new measure of the distance between the FOPT Borel sum and the CIPT series which clarifies the differences, and confirms that CIPT is inconsistent with the Operator Product Expansion.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 014007] Published Tue Jul 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maarten Golterman, Kim Maltman, and Santiago Peris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Viscosity of pure-glue QCD from the lattice]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.014503</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.014503"/>
        <updated>2023-07-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Luis Altenkort, Alexander M. Eller, Anthony Francis, Olaf Kaczmarek, Lukas Mazur, Guy D. Moore, and Hai-Tao Shu
The shear and bulk viscosities in the Quark-Gluon Plasma are quantities of enormous interest for the collisions of heavy ions at RHIC and the LHC. Using lattices up to 1443 x 36 in size, and applying gradient flow and blocking methods with high precision, the authors compute these viscosities at 1.5 times the deconfining transition temperature in the pure glue theory. This shows that obtaining values with dynamical quarks, which can be compared directly to experiment, is feasible in the near future.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 014503] Published Tue Jul 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luis Altenkort, Alexander M. Eller, Anthony Francis, Olaf Kaczmarek, Lukas Mazur, Guy D. Moore, and Hai-Tao Shu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Direct Measurement of Inverse Piezoelectric Effects in Thin Films Using Laser Doppler Vibrometry]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014017</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014017"/>
        <updated>2023-07-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Megha Acharya, Djamila Lou, Abel Fernandez, Jieun Kim, Zishen Tian, and Lane W. Martin
This study highlights efforts to develop an accurate, simple methodology to assess the electromechanical response in thin-film heterostructures, using laser Doppler vibrometry to measuring surface displacements smaller than 1 nm. The work demonstrates how to use the measured values to extract the piezoelectric coefficient d33 for a generic thin-film system by means of finite-element modeling. Finally, the work shows how to assess the electromechanical figure of merit for thin films, and offers a procedure for how to compare them to their bulk counterparts via the electromechanical coupling coefficient k33.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 014017] Published Tue Jul 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Megha Acharya, Djamila Lou, Abel Fernandez, Jieun Kim, Zishen Tian, and Lane W. Martin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Acoustic Radiation From a Superconducting Qubit: From Spontaneous Emission to Rabi Oscillations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014018</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014018"/>
        <updated>2023-07-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vijay Jain, Vladislav D. Kurilovich, Yanni D. Dahmani, Chan U Lei, David Mason, Taekwan Yoon, Peter T. Rakich, Leonid I. Glazman, and Robert J. Schoelkopf
A phonon (quantized vibration of a crystalline medium) is much shorter in wavelength than a photon of the same frequency. This length-scale reduction offers an opportunity to achieve higher density of quantum information storage, and may open a path to scalable implementations of superconducting quantum processors. However, the smallness of the acoustic wavelength also poses a challenge: It may result in fast qubit decoherence via an unintentional emission of phonons. The authors demonstrate how to circumvent such spontaneous emission and attain quantum coherent coupling of a qubit to an isolated phonon mode.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 014018] Published Tue Jul 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vijay Jain, Vladislav D. Kurilovich, Yanni D. Dahmani, Chan U Lei, David Mason, Taekwan Yoon, Peter T. Rakich, Leonid I. Glazman, and Robert J. Schoelkopf</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Classical Analogue to the Kitaev Model and Majoranalike Topological Bound States]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014019</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014019"/>
        <updated>2023-07-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ting-Wei Liu and Fabio Semperlotti
Despite the fundamental differences between quantum and classical topological material systems, recent studies have shown remarkable similarities in their underlying mathematical structure. This study discusses the classical analogue of the well-known second-quantization formalism, and uses it to analyze a dimerized mechanical chain. The formalism reveals a striking resemblance between the Hamiltonians of the classical dimerized chain and the Kitaev chain, a toy model renowned for bound-state solutions akin to Majorana zero modes. This formulation provides a powerful tool to discover and design classical mechanical mimics of topological quantum systems.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 014019] Published Tue Jul 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ting-Wei Liu and Fabio Semperlotti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interaction of Domain Walls with Grain Boundaries in Uniaxial Insulating Antiferromagnets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014020</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014020"/>
        <updated>2023-07-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Oleksandr V. Pylypovskyi, Natascha Hedrich, Artem V. Tomilo, Tobias Kosub, Kai Wagner, René Hübner, Brendan Shields, Denis D. Sheka, Jürgen Fassbender, Patrick Maletinsky, and Denys Makarov
Antiferromagnetic (AFM) spin-orbitronics and data storage rely on the motion of AFM solitons (domain walls and skyrmions) in thin films consisting of nanocrystalline grains. The design of high-performance antiferromagnet-based memory and logic devices has been limited by a lack of knowledge about the interaction of AFM solitons with grain boundaries. The authors develop a model of a nanocrystalline AFM material (e.g. magnetoelectric Cr2O3), including proper intergrain exchange. Their approach provides design rules for granular AFM memory devices, and should stimulate further research on ultrafast magnetization dynamics of the order parameter in insulating granular AFM thin films.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 014020] Published Tue Jul 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oleksandr V. Pylypovskyi, Natascha Hedrich, Artem V. Tomilo, Tobias Kosub, Kai Wagner, René Hübner, Brendan Shields, Denis D. Sheka, Jürgen Fassbender, Patrick Maletinsky, and Denys Makarov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[State of Cell Unjamming Correlates with Distant Metastasis in Cancer Patients]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.031003"/>
        <updated>2023-07-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pablo Gottheil, Jürgen Lippoldt, Steffen Grosser, Frédéric Renner, Mohamad Saibah, Dimitrij Tschodu, Anne-Kathrin Poßögel, Anne-Sophie Wegscheider, Bernhard Ulm, Kay Friedrichs, Christoph Lindner, Christoph Engel, Markus Löffler, Benjamin Wolf, Michael Höckel, Bahriye Aktas, Hans Kubitschke, Axel Niendorf, and Josef A. Käs
A concept in condensed-matter physics called jamming provides a possible prognostic tool for cancer.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 031003] Published Mon Jul 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pablo Gottheil, Jürgen Lippoldt, Steffen Grosser, Frédéric Renner, Mohamad Saibah, Dimitrij Tschodu, Anne-Kathrin Poßögel, Anne-Sophie Wegscheider, Bernhard Ulm, Kay Friedrichs, Christoph Lindner, Christoph Engel, Markus Löffler, Benjamin Wolf, Michael Höckel, Bahriye Aktas, Hans Kubitschke, Axel Niendorf, and Josef A. Käs</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal Velocity Statistics in Decaying Turbulence]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.024001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.024001"/>
        <updated>2023-07-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christian Küchler, Gregory P. Bewley, and Eberhard Bodenschatz
Measurements conducted over an unprecedented span of conditions uncover universal behavior, but not the kind that theorists expected.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 024001] Published Mon Jul 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christian Küchler, Gregory P. Bewley, and Eberhard Bodenschatz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Superconductivity beyond the Conventional Pauli Limit in High-Pressure ${\mathrm{CeSb}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.026001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.026001"/>
        <updated>2023-07-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Oliver P. Squire, Stephen A. Hodgson, Jiasheng Chen, Vitaly Fedoseev, Christian K. de Podesta, Theodore I. Weinberger, Patricia L. Alireza, and F. Malte Grosche
The upper critical field of CeSb2 exceeds the conventional Pauli limit, an observation generally associated with spin-triplet superconductivity, especially in strongly correlated materials where the orbital-limit is high.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 026001] Published Mon Jul 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver P. Squire, Stephen A. Hodgson, Jiasheng Chen, Vitaly Fedoseev, Christian K. de Podesta, Theodore I. Weinberger, Patricia L. Alireza, and F. Malte Grosche</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marangoni-driven spreading and receding of a volatile droplet on a liquid layer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.073601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.073601"/>
        <updated>2023-07-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Amin Jaberi, Gérald Debenest, and Franck Plouraboué
When gently putting down a volatile immiscible drop of low viscous liquid onto a small more viscous liquid layer, it spreads under the layer for favorable positive spreading coefficient from the action of Marangoni forces. In this work however, the opposite is observed after a finite receding time: a reversed flow associated with the volatile droplet recession. This paper precisely analyzes this phenomenon both experimentally and theoretically and the physics behind it.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 073601] Published Mon Jul 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amin Jaberi, Gérald Debenest, and Franck Plouraboué</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effect of nitrogen doping and pressure on the stability of $\mathrm{Lu}{\mathrm{H}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L020101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L020101"/>
        <updated>2023-07-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yang Sun, Feng Zhang, Shunqing Wu, Vladimir Antropov, and Kai-Ming Ho
The near-ambient superconductivity of nitrogen-doped lutetium hydride remains a contentious topic. This paper discusses how pressure and nitrogen doping affect the stability of lutetium trihydride. The authors propose a structural model that illustrates improved stability by substituting hydrogen atoms with nitrogen and introducing vacancies. However, the study uncovers no theoretical evidence for strong electron-phonon coupling in these phases. These findings provide a possible way to understand the experimental structure and offer insights for future superconductivity investigations into this intriguing compound.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L020101] Published Mon Jul 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yang Sun, Feng Zhang, Shunqing Wu, Vladimir Antropov, and Kai-Ming Ho</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of Rydberg Blockade Due to the Charge-Dipole Interaction between an Atom and a Polar Molecule]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.013401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.013401"/>
        <updated>2023-07-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexander Guttridge, Daniel K. Ruttley, Archie C. Baldock, Rosario González-Férez, H. R. Sadeghpour, C. S. Adams, and Simon L. Cornish
Researchers take a step toward a new form of quantum computation by demonstrating a state-controlling interaction called Rydberg blockade between an atom and a molecule.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 013401] Published Fri Jul 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexander Guttridge, Daniel K. Ruttley, Archie C. Baldock, Rosario González-Férez, H. R. Sadeghpour, C. S. Adams, and Simon L. Cornish</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Proof-of-Principle Experiment on the Dynamic Shell Formation for Inertial Confinement Fusion]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.015102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.015102"/>
        <updated>2023-07-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): I. V. Igumenshchev et al.
A laser experiment provides a proof-of-principle test for an alternative fusion concept that uses targets made with liquid fuel rather than conventional frozen fuel.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 015102] Published Fri Jul 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>I. V. Igumenshchev &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measuring Topological Entanglement Entropy Using Maxwell Relations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.016601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.016601"/>
        <updated>2023-07-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sarath Sankar, Eran Sela, and Cheolhee Han
A new scheme that combines a quantum point contact with a quantum dot may enable the elusive measurement of topological entanglement entropy in systems such the fractional quantum Hall state.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 016601] Published Fri Jul 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarath Sankar, Eran Sela, and Cheolhee Han</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Current fluctuations in stochastically resetting particle systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.014112</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.014112"/>
        <updated>2023-07-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Costantino Di Bello, Alexander K. Hartmann, Satya N. Majumdar, Francesco Mori, Alberto Rosso, and Grégory Schehr
The authors investigate the effects of stochastic resetting on current fluctuations for two different models for particle motion: Brownian motion and run-and-tumble motion. Using analytical and numerical methods, they find large differences in how the two models approach the steady state in the annealed and the quenched cases.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 014112] Published Fri Jul 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Costantino Di Bello, Alexander K. Hartmann, Satya N. Majumdar, Francesco Mori, Alberto Rosso, and Grégory Schehr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing Heavy Majorana Neutrinos and the Weinberg Operator through Vector Boson Fusion Processes in Proton-Proton Collisions at $\sqrt{s}=13\text{ }\text{ }\mathrm{TeV}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.011803</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.011803"/>
        <updated>2023-07-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Tumasyan et al. (CMS Collaboration)
Collider experiments have set new direct limits on the existence of hypothetical heavy neutrinos, helping to constrain how ordinary neutrinos get their mass.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 011803] Published Thu Jul 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Tumasyan &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (CMS Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General Bound States in the Continuum in Momentum Space]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.013801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.013801"/>
        <updated>2023-07-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Qiao Jiang, Peng Hu, Jun Wang, Dezhuan Han, and Jian Zi
A graph-theory-based approach reveals a new kind of bound state in the continuum at an arbitrary point in momentum space, useful for the classification and evolution of polarization singularities in the whole momentum space.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 013801] Published Thu Jul 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qiao Jiang, Peng Hu, Jun Wang, Dezhuan Han, and Jian Zi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photonic Realization of a Generic Type of Graphene Edge States Exhibiting Topological Flat Band]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.013804</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.013804"/>
        <updated>2023-07-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shiqi Xia, Yongsheng Liang, Liqin Tang, Daohong Song, Jingjun Xu, and Zhigang Chen
A photonic version of graphene hosts never-before-seen “twig” edge states—which could provide new avenues for realizing topological phases in graphene-like materials.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 013804] Published Thu Jul 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shiqi Xia, Yongsheng Liang, Liqin Tang, Daohong Song, Jingjun Xu, and Zhigang Chen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forecasting landslides using community detection on geophysical satellite data]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.014901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.014901"/>
        <updated>2023-07-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vrinda D. Desai, Farnaz Fazelpour, Alexander L. Handwerger, and Karen E. Daniels
A new method based on satellite data and network models can identify hillsides that may be at risk of catastrophic landslides.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 014901] Published Thu Jul 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vrinda D. Desai, Farnaz Fazelpour, Alexander L. Handwerger, and Karen E. Daniels</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orbital Fulde-Ferrell Pairing State in Moiré Ising Superconductors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.016001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.016001"/>
        <updated>2023-07-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ying-Ming Xie and K. T. Law
An orbital field-driven Fulde–Ferrell (FF) pairing state can be driven by the orbital effects of in-plane magnetic fields (different from the conventional Zeeman effects-driven FF state), such a pairing makes possible a giant and gate-tunable superconducting diode effect.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 016001] Published Wed Jul 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ying-Ming Xie and K. T. Law</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Renormalization group flow as optimal transport]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.025003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.025003"/>
        <updated>2023-07-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jordan Cotler and Semon Rezchikov
This highly original paper relates the exact renormalization group (ERG) flow to optimal gradient flow which naturally leads to the (previously known) interpretation of the ERG as a flow that minimizes the relative entropy of a probability distribution. This provides an elegant explanation of otherwise opaque features of ERG schemes and establishes a clear and intriguing link to information theory. The intuitive picture that emerges is that the coarse-graining of the RG flow produces entropy and this entropy production determines the flow itself. All these basic relations are established nonperturbatively.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 025003] Published Wed Jul 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Cotler and Semon Rezchikov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetic anisotropy, magnetoelastic coupling, and the magnetic phase diagram of ${\mathrm{Ni}}_{0.25}{\mathrm{Mn}}_{0.75}{\mathrm{TiO}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014406</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014406"/>
        <updated>2023-07-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Elghandour, L. Gries, L. Singer, M. Hoffmann, S. Spachmann, M. Uhlarz, K. Dey, and R. Klingeler
Magnetic anisotropy describes the tendency of a material to exhibit different magnetic behavior along different crystallographic directions. Here, the authors mix two antiferromagnets, namely MnTiO3 and NiTiO3, to form Ni0.25Mn0.75TiO3. The parent magnets are of competing anisotropy. The former has an easy magnetic axis along the c axis, whereas the latter has an easy magnetic plane within the ab plane. The authors also shed light on the doping effect upon the long-range magnetic order, emergent magnetic phases, and the magnetic entropy consumption in comparison to the parent magnets. Finally, they employ different thermodynamic probes to build a complex and rich anisotropic magnetic phase diagram of Ni0.25Mn0.75TiO3.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 014406] Published Wed Jul 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Elghandour, L. Gries, L. Singer, M. Hoffmann, S. Spachmann, M. Uhlarz, K. Dey, and R. Klingeler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Van Roosbroeck's equations with topological terms: The case of Weyl semimetals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.024301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.024301"/>
        <updated>2023-07-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pierre-Antoine Graham, Simon Bertrand, Michaël Bédard, Robin Durand, and Ion Garate
For decades, van Roosbroeck’s (VR) equations have been used to model microelectronic devices made from ordinary semiconductors. The advent of topological materials raises a largely unexplored question: how are VR equations and their solutions modified when electronic bands are topological? Here, the authors solve VR equations analytically in a Weyl semimetal placed under a magnetic field and subjected to a spatially inhomogeneous light pulse. They predict photoinduced plasma oscillations, which originate from a topological term in VR equations.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 024301] Published Wed Jul 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pierre-Antoine Graham, Simon Bertrand, Michaël Bédard, Robin Durand, and Ion Garate</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ultrafast relaxation dynamics of spin density wave order in ${\mathrm{BaFe}}_{2}{\mathrm{As}}_{2}$ under high pressures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.035101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.035101"/>
        <updated>2023-07-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ivan Fotev, Stephan Winnerl, Saicharan Aswartham, Sabine Wurmehl, Bernd Büchner, Harald Schneider, Manfred Helm, and Alexej Pashkin
Application of pressure offers a way to continuously tune the ground state of a system across different phases realizing so-called quantum phase transitions. However, studying the order parameter is challenging because some established experimental techniques are not compatible with diamond anvil pressure cells. Here, the authors show that ultrafast pump-probe spectroscopy is an efficient method to accomplish this task. Using this approach, they succeed in mapping the spin density wave order parameter in iron-based superconductor BaFe2As2 over a broad range of pressures and temperatures.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 035101] Published Wed Jul 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ivan Fotev, Stephan Winnerl, Saicharan Aswartham, Sabine Wurmehl, Bernd Büchner, Harald Schneider, Manfred Helm, and Alexej Pashkin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>