<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-04-06T00:47:51.698Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-04-06T00:47:51.699Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Highly Efficient Single-Exciton Strong Coupling with Plasmons by Lowering Critical Interaction Strength at an Exceptional Point]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.143601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.143601"/>
        <updated>2023-04-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wei Li, Renming Liu, Junyu Li, Jie Zhong, Yu-Wei Lu, Huanjun Chen, and Xue-Hua Wang
A strategy for achieving the plasmon-single exciton strong coupling by simultaneously lowering the plasmonic decay and critical interaction strength at an exceptional point of a coupled system largely relaxes the severe requirements of realizing the single exciton strong coupling for both the ultrasmall mode volume and direction aligning of emitter’s dipole moment with the mode field.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 143601] Published Wed Apr 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wei Li, Renming Liu, Junyu Li, Jie Zhong, Yu-Wei Lu, Huanjun Chen, and Xue-Hua Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Geometry-Induced Spin Filtering in Photoemission Maps from ${\mathrm{WTe}}_{2}$ Surface States]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.146401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.146401"/>
        <updated>2023-04-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tristan Heider, Gustav Bihlmayer, Jakub Schusser, Friedrich Reinert, Jan Minár, Stefan Blügel, Claus M. Schneider, and Lukasz Plucinski
A new spin behavior has been found in the light-induced electron emission of tungsten ditelluride.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 146401] Published Wed Apr 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tristan Heider, Gustav Bihlmayer, Jakub Schusser, Friedrich Reinert, Jan Minár, Stefan Blügel, Claus M. Schneider, and Lukasz Plucinski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Testing hadronic and photohadronic interactions as responsible for ultrahigh energy cosmic rays and neutrino fluxes from starburst galaxies]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.083009</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.083009"/>
        <updated>2023-04-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Antonio Condorelli, Denise Boncioli, Enrico Peretti, and Sergio Petrera
The sources and acceleration mechanisms for observed ultra-high energy cosmic rays (UHECRs) are abiding problems still needing definitive resolution. The authors of the present study investigate the potential of starburst galaxies (SBGs) - so named for being particularly active environments for formation of new stars - to be the sources of UHECRs. Using Monte Carlo simulations of the extremely dense and turbulent environment in the most active region of SBGs, the authors show by a highly suggestive comparison to data obtained by the Pierre Auger Observatory that SBGs can be sources of UHECRs.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 083009] Published Wed Apr 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Antonio Condorelli, Denise Boncioli, Enrico Peretti, and Sergio Petrera</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dark Energy Survey Year 3 results: Constraints on extensions to $\mathrm{Λ}\mathrm{CDM}$ with weak lensing and galaxy clustering]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.083504</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.083504"/>
        <updated>2023-04-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. M. C. Abbott et al. (DES Collaboration)
The authors use Dark Energy Survey data on galaxy clustering and lensing from the first three years of observations combined with five prominent external datasets. They robustly constrain six potential extensions to the currently prevalent cosmological paradigm of ΛCDM (Cold Dark Matter with a cosmological constant). All extensions would add significant new physics, such as deviations from General Relativity or non-zero spatial curvature, but no significant evidence for new physics is found.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 083504] Published Wed Apr 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. M. C. Abbott &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (DES Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Relativistic approach to the nuclear breathing mode]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.L041302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.L041302"/>
        <updated>2023-04-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Elena Litvinova
Nuclear compressibility governs fluctuations around the saturation density of nuclear matter, and is therefore crucial for understanding the structure of nuclei as well as of neutron stars. QRPA calculations using a nuclear compression modulus that reproduces the position of the isoscalar giant monopole resonance in 208Pb predict too high an energy for the same excitation in the Sn isotopes. The author shows that the self-consistent inclusion of quasiparticle-vibration coupling beyond QRPA in a relativistic framework can solve the problem. This indicates that a consensus between a softer equation of state extracted from the compressibility of finite nuclei and a stiffer one required by recent analyses of neutron star data can be achieved by systematic incorporation of beyond-QRPA many-body correlations in the theory.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, L041302] Published Wed Apr 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elena Litvinova</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reanalysis of experimental determinations of polariton-polariton interactions in microcavities]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.165302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.165302"/>
        <updated>2023-04-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. W. Snoke, V. Hartwell, J. Beaumariage, S. Mukherjee, Y. Yoon, D. M. Myers, M. Steger, Z. Sun, K. A. Nelson, and L. N. Pfeiffer
Inside solids, photons can become strongly interacting, which allows the possibility of optical transistors, in a which one light beam controls the transmission of another light beam. The strength of this interaction can be greatly increased in specially designed structures in which the photon frequency is near an electronic resonance known as an exciton. The exact value of this interaction strength has been much debated, ranging over orders of magnitude. This paper reviews a set of experiments and argues for a number well below some earlier estimates, but still large compared to the predictions of standard theory calculations.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 165302] Published Wed Apr 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. W. Snoke, V. Hartwell, J. Beaumariage, S. Mukherjee, Y. Yoon, D. M. Myers, M. Steger, Z. Sun, K. A. Nelson, and L. N. Pfeiffer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Characteristic nanoscale deformation on a large-area coherent graphite moiré pattern]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L161402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L161402"/>
        <updated>2023-04-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. Sarkar, P. R. Bandaru, and R. C. Dynes
Highly oriented pyrolytic graphite (HoPG) is the only monoatomic crystal found to host naturally formed moiré patterns on its cleaved exfoliated surfaces, which are coherent over micrometers with fixed periodicities. The authors merge the idea of STM tip-induced deformation to probe in situ the gradual nanoscale structural changes on moiré patterns with strain. They show the first experimental proof that one-dimensional domain walls of moiré patterns can laterally split into two similar to the triangular networks of one-dimensional electronic channels in domain walls, topologically protected around AA nodes. Further, domain-wall edge states are also possibly probed with spectroscopy.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L161402] Published Wed Apr 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Sarkar, P. R. Bandaru, and R. C. Dynes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chip-Scale Packages for a Tunable Wavelength Reference and Laser Cooling Platform]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.044015</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.044015"/>
        <updated>2023-04-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Dyer, K. Gallacher, U. Hawley, A. Bregazzi, P.F. Griffin, A.S. Arnold, D.J. Paul, E. Riis, and J.P. McGilligan
The miniaturization of cold-atom systems brings high accuracy into portable atomic metrology. However, the impact of cold-atom sensors in real-world applications has been limited by the overall laser cooling package. This study amalgamates a chip-scale optics setup with a microfabricated laser cooling system to dramatically reduce device size, weight, and power usage. The authors use an on-chip Zeeman offset lock for laser cooling, and demonstrate improved atom number afforded by new techniques in silicon cell fabrication. The simplicity, scalability, and utility demonstrated in this cold-atom platform will enable exciting opportunities in portable cold-atom clocks and interferometers.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 044015] Published Wed Apr 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Dyer, K. Gallacher, U. Hawley, A. Bregazzi, P.F. Griffin, A.S. Arnold, D.J. Paul, E. Riis, and J.P. McGilligan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[General Theory for Bilayer Stacking Ferroelectricity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.146801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.146801"/>
        <updated>2023-04-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Junyi Ji, Guoliang Yu, Changsong Xu, and H. J. Xiang
Two atom-thick layers of the same crystalline material can be stacked on top of each other in ways that yield ferroelectricity.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 146801] Published Tue Apr 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Junyi Ji, Guoliang Yu, Changsong Xu, and H. J. Xiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entanglement wedges for gravitating regions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.086002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.086002"/>
        <updated>2023-04-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Raphael Bousso and Geoff Penington
As part of the AdS/CFT dictionary, the entanglement wedge reconstruction identifies the spacetime region in AdS that is dual to a given CFT subregion on the boundary. In this paper, the authors make an important step forward by extending the entanglement wedge reconstruction to arbitrary spacetimes, which can reveal aspects of the full quantum theory of gravity.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 086002] Published Tue Apr 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Raphael Bousso and Geoff Penington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Self-Ordering of Buckling, Bending, and Bumping Beams]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.148201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.148201"/>
        <updated>2023-04-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Arman Guerra, Anja C. Slim, Douglas P. Holmes, and Ousmane Kodio
The behavior of a collection of squeezed elastic beams is determined by geometry, not by complex forces.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 148201] Published Mon Apr 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Arman Guerra, Anja C. Slim, Douglas P. Holmes, and Ousmane Kodio</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological defect coarsening in quenched smectic-$\phantom{\rule{0.16em}{0ex}}C$ films analyzed using artificial neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.044701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.044701"/>
        <updated>2023-04-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ravin A. Chowdhury, Adam A. S. Green, Cheol S. Park, Joseph E. Maclennan, and Noel A. Clark
After quenching, a liquid crystal film might contain thousands of topological defects which annihilate during coarsening. The authors analyze high-speed video of the coarsening process using neural networks, and find agreement with theoretical predictions and simulations.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, 044701] Published Mon Apr 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ravin A. Chowdhury, Adam A. S. Green, Cheol S. Park, Joseph E. Maclennan, and Noel A. Clark</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photoinduced charge dynamics in $1T\text{−}{\mathrm{TaS}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.165102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.165102"/>
        <updated>2023-04-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Francesco Petocchi, Jiyu Chen, Jiajun Li, Martin Eckstein, and Philipp Werner
Nonequilibrium cluster dynamical mean-field theory simulations of a realistic multilayer structure are used to study the charge carrier dynamics induced by a laser pulse in 1T-TaS2. The solution is propagated up to picosecond timescales and shows that long-lived charge excitations only exist in the surface state of a specific structure, while the disturbance of bonding states in the bilayers that make up the bulk of the structure explain the almost instantaneous appearance of in-gap states reported in recent experiments.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 165102] Published Mon Apr 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Francesco Petocchi, Jiyu Chen, Jiajun Li, Martin Eckstein, and Philipp Werner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Engineering Dynamically Decoupled Quantum Simulations with Trapped Ions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.010334</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.010334"/>
        <updated>2023-03-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): W. Morong, K.S. Collins, A. De, E. Stavropoulos, T. You, and C. Monroe
A new method based on dynamical decoupling is shown to significantly enhance the coherence of quantum simulations.

[PRX Quantum 4, 010334] Published Fri Mar 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>W. Morong, K.S. Collins, A. De, E. Stavropoulos, T. You, and C. Monroe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discovery of New Isotope $^{241}\mathrm{U}$ and Systematic High-Precision Atomic Mass Measurements of Neutron-Rich Pa-Pu Nuclei Produced via Multinucleon Transfer Reactions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.132502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.132502"/>
        <updated>2023-03-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Niwase, Y. X. Watanabe, Y. Hirayama, M. Mukai, P. Schury, A. N. Andreyev, T. Hashimoto, S. Iimura, H. Ishiyama, Y. Ito, S. C. Jeong, D. Kaji, S. Kimura, H. Miyatake, K. Morimoto, J.-Y. Moon, M. Oyaizu, M. Rosenbusch, A. Taniguchi, and M. Wada
Scientists have precisely measured the masses of 19 neutron-rich nuclei, discovering a new isotope of uranium in the process.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 132502] Published Fri Mar 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Niwase, Y. X. Watanabe, Y. Hirayama, M. Mukai, P. Schury, A. N. Andreyev, T. Hashimoto, S. Iimura, H. Ishiyama, Y. Ito, S. C. Jeong, D. Kaji, S. Kimura, H. Miyatake, K. Morimoto, J.-Y. Moon, M. Oyaizu, M. Rosenbusch, A. Taniguchi, and M. Wada</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downslope granular flow through a forest of obstacles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.034303</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.034303"/>
        <updated>2023-03-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Baptiste Darbois Texier, Yann Bertho, and Philippe Gondret
This work investigates the role played by a forest of pillars on the steady flow of a granular layer down an inclined plane. We realized experiments for different inter-pillar distances to observe how the forest density slows down the granular flow. These observations are rationalized by an average approach that considers a granular rheology for the flow and includes the additional force exerted by the pillars on the granular layer.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 034303] Published Fri Mar 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Baptiste Darbois Texier, Yann Bertho, and Philippe Gondret</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Persistent homology of quantum entanglement]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115174</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115174"/>
        <updated>2023-03-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bart Olsthoorn
What shapes of entanglement are present in quantum states? Persistent homology provides an answer that contains both topological and geometrical information. This is a relatively new method from the field of topological data analysis, where shapes in discrete data are captured at varying length scales. In this case, the length scale is based on quantum mutual information, and the method is used to detect quantum phase transitions.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 115174] Published Fri Mar 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bart Olsthoorn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Limits to the Energy-Conversion Efficiency of Air-Bridge Thermophotovoltaics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034099</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034099"/>
        <updated>2023-03-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jihun Lim and Stephen R. Forrest
As the energy economy becomes increasingly decarbonized, low-cost energy storage grows ever more important. Thermal batteries in combination with thermophotovoltaic (TPV) cells are one major source of storage. The lowest-loss TPV cells utilize an air bridge (AB) with a gold back reflector. In this work, the authors determine a 55.5% thermodynamic efficiency limit for AB-TPVs at an emitter temperature of 1400 K, based on detailed balance. Including losses from nonradiative recombination, finite resistance, and free-carrier absorption, the practical efficiency limit is 48.6%. This work provides a road map for evaluating and limiting losses, leading to even higher AB-TPV efficiencies.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 034099] Published Fri Mar 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jihun Lim and Stephen R. Forrest</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Control of the Radiative Heat Transfer in a Pair of Rotating Nanostructures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.133605</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.133605"/>
        <updated>2023-03-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Juan R. Deop-Ruano and Alejandro Manjavacas
When spun fast enough, a cold object can transfer heat to a nearby hot object.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 133605] Published Thu Mar 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Juan R. Deop-Ruano and Alejandro Manjavacas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum Phase Diagram and Spontaneously Emergent Topological Chiral Superconductivity in Doped Triangular-Lattice Mott Insulators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.136003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.136003"/>
        <updated>2023-03-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yixuan Huang, Shou-Shu Gong, and D. N. Sheng
Tuning hopping and spin interaction parameters in a t−J model provide a new route for discovering topological superconductivity in certain moiré superlattices.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 136003] Published Thu Mar 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yixuan Huang, Shou-Shu Gong, and D. N. Sheng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giant Magnetochiral Anisotropy in Weyl Semimetal ${\mathrm{WTe}}_{2}$ Induced by Diverging Berry Curvature]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.136301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.136301"/>
        <updated>2023-03-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tomoyuki Yokouchi, Yuya Ikeda, Takahiro Morimoto, and Yuki Shiomi
Berry curvature induces giant magnetochiral anisotropy.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 136301] Published Thu Mar 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tomoyuki Yokouchi, Yuya Ikeda, Takahiro Morimoto, and Yuki Shiomi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gauge-invariant and anyonic-symmetric autoregressive neural network for quantum lattice models]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.013216</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.013216"/>
        <updated>2023-03-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Di Luo, Zhuo Chen, Kaiwen Hu, Zhizhen Zhao, Vera Mikyoung Hur, and Bryan K. Clark
Development of gauge-invariant and anyonic-symmetric autoregressive neural networks for quantum many-body physics simulations.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 013216] Published Wed Mar 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Di Luo, Zhuo Chen, Kaiwen Hu, Zhizhen Zhao, Vera Mikyoung Hur, and Bryan K. Clark</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Macroscopic Quantum Test with Bulk Acoustic Wave Resonators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.133604</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.133604"/>
        <updated>2023-03-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Björn Schrinski, Yu Yang, Uwe von Lüpke, Marius Bild, Yiwen Chu, Klaus Hornberger, Stefan Nimmrichter, and Matteo Fadel
An experiment with an acoustic resonator demonstrates the quantum superposition of 1016 atoms—nearly matching the ability of matter interferometers to test quantumness on macroscopic scales.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 133604] Published Wed Mar 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Björn Schrinski, Yu Yang, Uwe von Lüpke, Marius Bild, Yiwen Chu, Klaus Hornberger, Stefan Nimmrichter, and Matteo Fadel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cross-section measurement of the $^{82}\mathrm{Kr}(p,γ)^{83}\mathrm{Rb}$ reaction in inverse kinematics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.035808</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.035808"/>
        <updated>2023-03-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Tsantiri, A. Palmisano-Kyle, A. Spyrou, P. Mohr, H. C. Berg, P. A. DeYoung, A. C. Dombos, P. Gastis, E. C. Good, C. M. Harris, S. N. Liddick, S. M. Lyons, O. Olivas-Gomez, G. Owens-Fryar, J. Pereira, A. L. Richard, A. Simon, M. K. Smith, and R. G. T. Zegers
Although most nuclei heavier than Fe are likely produced by the slow and the rapid neutron-capture (s and r) processes, a number of medium-mass, proton-rich nuclei are thought to be produced via photo-disintegration (γ process). To confirm this, one needs detailed statistical model calculations that are constrained by experimental input. In this work, the authors measured the (γ,p) reaction on the unstable 83Rb nucleus, via detailed balance, using the 82Kr(p,γ)83Rb reaction with a 82Kr beam and detecting the produced γ rays. The results put important constraints on the parameters of the statistical model calculations, allowing improved tests of the γ process in hot stellar environments.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, 035808] Published Wed Mar 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Tsantiri, A. Palmisano-Kyle, A. Spyrou, P. Mohr, H. C. Berg, P. A. DeYoung, A. C. Dombos, P. Gastis, E. C. Good, C. M. Harris, S. N. Liddick, S. M. Lyons, O. Olivas-Gomez, G. Owens-Fryar, J. Pereira, A. L. Richard, A. Simon, M. K. Smith, and R. G. T. Zegers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orbital selective coupling in ${\mathrm{CeRh}}_{3}{\mathrm{B}}_{2}$: Coexistence of high Curie and high Kondo temperatures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115164</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115164"/>
        <updated>2023-03-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Andrea Amorese, Philipp Hansmann, Andrea Marino, Peter Körner, Thomas Willers, Andrew Walters, Ke-Jin Zhou, Kurt Kummer, Nicholas B. Brookes, Hong-Ji Lin, Chien-Te Chen, Pascal Lejay, Maurits W. Haverkort, Liu Hao Tjeng, and Andrea Severing
Orbital selective coupling explains the exotic ferromagnetism in CeRh3B2, which combines a high Curie temperature, a strongly reduced ordered moment, strong intermediate valence, and a high Kondo temperature. The cigar-shaped Ce 4f |Jz = ½⟩ states couples with the Ce 5d states setting up the ferromagnetism, while the in-plane Ce 4f |Jz =⁵⁄₂⟩ hybridizes with the surrounding B states, forming the Kondo state. The image shows the crystal field potential of the Ce 4f states; the preferred directions of interaction are shown in blue, while the least favored ones are marked in red.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 115164] Published Wed Mar 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrea Amorese, Philipp Hansmann, Andrea Marino, Peter Körner, Thomas Willers, Andrew Walters, Ke-Jin Zhou, Kurt Kummer, Nicholas B. Brookes, Hong-Ji Lin, Chien-Te Chen, Pascal Lejay, Maurits W. Haverkort, Liu Hao Tjeng, and Andrea Severing</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Supermoiré low-energy effective theory of twisted trilayer graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125423</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125423"/>
        <updated>2023-03-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuncheng Mao, Daniele Guerci, and Christophe Mora
Twisted trilayer graphene features a supermoiré pattern on top of two moiré patterns between adjacent layers. Here, the authors have devised a supermoiré effective model for the staircase twisted trilayer graphene, manifesting a gauge field originating from non-Abelian Berry connection acting as a pseudo magnetic field, and a space-dependent anisotropic velocity for the low-energy Dirac electrons. The supermoiré low-energy band structures and profiles of density of states can therefore be accessed by solving the effective model numerically.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 125423] Published Wed Mar 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuncheng Mao, Daniele Guerci, and Christophe Mora</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Terahertz Vibrational Molecular Clock with Systematic Uncertainty at the ${10}^{−14}$ Level]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011047</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011047"/>
        <updated>2023-03-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): K. H. Leung, B. Iritani, E. Tiberi, I. Majewska, M. Borkowski, R. Moszynski, and T. Zelevinsky
Researchers have attained a 100-fold increase in the accuracy of a molecular clock that could serve as a terahertz-frequency standard and as a platform for investigating new physics.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 011047] Published Tue Mar 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>K. H. Leung, B. Iritani, E. Tiberi, I. Majewska, M. Borkowski, R. Moszynski, and T. Zelevinsky</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unraveling the role of Sm $4f$ electrons in the magnetism of ${\mathrm{SmFeO}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104427</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104427"/>
        <updated>2023-03-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Danila Amoroso, Bertrand Dupé, and Matthieu J. Verstraete
Magnetic rare-earth orthoferrite perovskites (RFeO3) host a variety of functional properties particularly suitable for next-generation, ultrafast spintronic devices. A key ingredient is the complex magnetic interaction at play between the two magnetic substructures. SmFeO3 has attracted particular interest because of its high-temperature spin reorientation transition and anomalous temperature-dependent lattice vibrational modes. Through first-principles calculations, the authors unveil here the interplay of the Sm-Fe exchange with the strong Sm f anisotropy as the dominant microscopic mechanism, and the nature of the anomalous vibrations.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 104427] Published Tue Mar 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Danila Amoroso, Bertrand Dupé, and Matthieu J. Verstraete</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[${\mathbb{Z}}_{2}$ spin Hopf insulator: Helical hinge states and returning Thouless pump]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115159</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115159"/>
        <updated>2023-03-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Penghao Zhu, A. Alexandradinata, and Taylor L. Hughes
The authors introduce here a time-reversal-symmetric analog of the Hopf insulator, dubbed as a spin Hopf insulator. The spin Hopf insulator harbors surface Kane-Mele ℤ2 order and gapless helical hinge modes. Remarkably, the spin Hopf insulator is the first example of a nonmagnetic delicate topological insulator with spin-orbital coupling. In the presence of fourfold rotational symmetry, the spin Hopf insulator also exhibits a returning Thouless pump. These studies of nonmagnetic spin Hopf insulators provide a pathway towards realizing a Hopf material in experiments.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 115159] Published Tue Mar 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Penghao Zhu, A. Alexandradinata, and Taylor L. Hughes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From spin liquid to magnetic ordering in the anisotropic kagome Y-kapellasite ${\mathrm{Y}}_{3}{\mathrm{Cu}}_{9}{(\mathrm{OH})}_{19}{\mathrm{Cl}}_{8}$: A single-crystal study]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125156</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125156"/>
        <updated>2023-03-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dipranjan Chatterjee, Pascal Puphal, Quentin Barthélemy, Jannis Willwater, Stefan Süllow, Christopher Baines, Sylvain Petit, Eric Ressouche, Jacques Ollivier, Katharina M. Zoch, Cornelius Krellner, Michael Parzer, Alexander Riss, Fabian Garmroudi, Andrej Pustogow, Philippe Mendels, Edwin Kermarrec, and Fabrice Bert
Y3Cu9(OH)19Cl8, also known as Y-kapellasite, realizes an original anisotropic frustrated kagome model. Here, the authors study large phase-pure single crystals, obtained via an external gradient method, by susceptibility, specific heat, thermal expansion, neutron scattering, and local μSR and NMR techniques. These find subtle structural changes along with long-range magnetic ordering (1/3,1/3). Large quantum fluctuations reduce the Cu2+ moments, likely as a result of the proximity to a phase boundary in the rich magnetic phase diagram of the model.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 125156] Published Tue Mar 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dipranjan Chatterjee, Pascal Puphal, Quentin Barthélemy, Jannis Willwater, Stefan Süllow, Christopher Baines, Sylvain Petit, Eric Ressouche, Jacques Ollivier, Katharina M. Zoch, Cornelius Krellner, Michael Parzer, Alexander Riss, Fabian Garmroudi, Andrej Pustogow, Philippe Mendels, Edwin Kermarrec, and Fabrice Bert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Collective density fluctuations of strange metals with critical Fermi surfaces]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125157</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125157"/>
        <updated>2023-03-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xuepeng Wang and Debanjan Chowdhury
A hallmark of a Fermi liquid is a collective excitation associated with fluctuations of the Fermi surface, which evolves into the well-known plasmon in the presence of Coulomb interactions. This paper addresses the fate of the plasmon excitation in non-Fermi liquid metals with a sharply defined Fermi surface, but where long-lived single-electron excitations are absent. The authors use two complementary theoretical techniques to analyze the collective density fluctuations and their decay into the two-particle continuum for three distinct solvable examples of non-Fermi liquids.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 125157] Published Tue Mar 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xuepeng Wang and Debanjan Chowdhury</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Direct Observation of Quantum Anomalous Vortex in Fe(Se,Te)]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011046</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011046"/>
        <updated>2023-03-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Y. S. Lin, S. Y. Wang, X. Zhang, Y. Feng, Y. P. Pan, H. Ru, J. J. Zhu, B. K. Xiang, K. Liu, C. L. Zheng, L. Y. Wei, M. X. Wang, Z. K. Liu, L. Chen, K. Jiang, Y. F. Guo, Ziqiang Wang, and Y. H. Wang
A quantum phase of matter detected in an iron-based superconductor could host Majorana zero modes—quasiparticles that may serve as building blocks for future quantum computers.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 011046] Published Mon Mar 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Y. S. Lin, S. Y. Wang, X. Zhang, Y. Feng, Y. P. Pan, H. Ru, J. J. Zhu, B. K. Xiang, K. Liu, C. L. Zheng, L. Y. Wei, M. X. Wang, Z. K. Liu, L. Chen, K. Jiang, Y. F. Guo, Ziqiang Wang, and Y. H. Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Adaptive power method for estimating large deviations in Markov chains]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.034137</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.034137"/>
        <updated>2023-03-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Francesco Coghi and Hugo Touchette
Large deviation functions can be used to describe fluctuations in model nonequilibrium systems. The authors study the properties of a numerical method for estimating these functions, and test it by applying it to a random walk on a random graph.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, 034137] Published Mon Mar 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Francesco Coghi and Hugo Touchette</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dispersive formalism for the nuclear structure correction ${δ}_{\text{NS}}$ to the $β$ decay rate]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.035503</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.035503"/>
        <updated>2023-03-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chien-Yeah Seng and Mikhail Gorchtein
Searches for new physics are often performed along the precision frontier, requiring more careful treatment of corrections previously treated approximately. For example, interpretation of high-precision measurements of β decay require the radiative correction arising from nuclear structure that was previously estimated using oversimplified nuclear models. In this paper, the authors carefully work out the formalism needed to use input from microscopic nuclear calculations, including a multipole expansion of the relevant matrix elements. This work prepares a path to a more rigorous theory framework and more precise limits on physics beyond the Standard Model.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, 035503] Published Mon Mar 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chien-Yeah Seng and Mikhail Gorchtein</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Berry-dipole photovoltaic demon and the thermodynamics of photocurrent generation within the optical gap of metals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125151</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125151"/>
        <updated>2023-03-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Li-kun Shi, Oles Matsyshyn, Justin C. W. Song, and Inti Sodemann Villadiego
Employing a detailed model of electrons coupled to a heat bath, this work demonstrates the generation of photocurrents when the frequency of light lies within the optical gap of a metal in the limit of small absorption. Such in-gap rectification is shown to be consistent with thermodynamic principles and is generally dissipative. The nonlinear Hall effect behaves, however, as a special dissipationless “demon” that can perform a highly efficient and reversible transfer of energy between the radiation and an external circuit.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 125151] Published Mon Mar 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Li-kun Shi, Oles Matsyshyn, Justin C. W. Song, and Inti Sodemann Villadiego</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Direct Measurement of Hexacontatetrapole, $E6$ $γ$ Decay from $^{53m}\mathrm{Fe}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.122503</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.122503"/>
        <updated>2023-03-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Palazzo, A. J. Mitchell, G. J. Lane, A. E. Stuchbery, B. A. Brown, M. W. Reed, A. Akber, B. J. Coombes, J. T. H. Dowie, T. K. Eriksen, M. S. M. Gerathy, T. Kibédi, T. Tornyi, and M. O. de Vries
Observations deliver evidence of an exotic “sixth-order” electromagnetic transition in the gamma-ray emission of an iron isotope, a finding that could provide new ways to test nuclear models.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 122503] Published Fri Mar 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Palazzo, A. J. Mitchell, G. J. Lane, A. E. Stuchbery, B. A. Brown, M. W. Reed, A. Akber, B. J. Coombes, J. T. H. Dowie, T. K. Eriksen, M. S. M. Gerathy, T. Kibédi, T. Tornyi, and M. O. de Vries</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generalizing Monin-Obukhov Similarity Theory (1954) for Complex Atmospheric Turbulence]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.124001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.124001"/>
        <updated>2023-03-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ivana Stiperski and Marc Calaf
The first generalization for all flow conditions of the 70-year old Monin-Obukhov similarity theory using an ensemble of atmospheric measurements covering the widest range of atmospheric complexity explains turbulence in complex atmospheric conditions

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 124001] Published Fri Mar 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ivana Stiperski and Marc Calaf</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Imprinting Spatial Helicity Structure of Vector Vortex Beam on Spin Texture in Semiconductors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.126701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.126701"/>
        <updated>2023-03-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jun Ishihara, Takachika Mori, Takuya Suzuki, Sota Sato, Ken Morita, Makoto Kohda, Yuzo Ohno, and Kensuke Miyajima
Researchers use an optical vortex beam to create a stable pattern of electron spins in a thin layer of semiconductor material.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 126701] Published Fri Mar 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jun Ishihara, Takachika Mori, Takuya Suzuki, Sota Sato, Ken Morita, Makoto Kohda, Yuzo Ohno, and Kensuke Miyajima</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thickness profiles of giant soap films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.034001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.034001"/>
        <updated>2023-03-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marina Pasquet, Frédéric Restagno, Isabelle Cantat, and Emmanuelle Rio
In this work, we measure and model the thickness profile of soap films in the regime of large extensions and large extension rates. For this purpose, we developed an experiment to generate soap films up to two meters high at velocities of the order of a meter per second. We show that the thickness profile in the central part of the film is exponential and described by a static model where the soap film is modeled by an elastic object stretched under gravity.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 034001] Published Fri Mar 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marina Pasquet, Frédéric Restagno, Isabelle Cantat, and Emmanuelle Rio</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anisotropic photon and electron scattering without ultrarelativistic approximation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.063026</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.063026"/>
        <updated>2023-03-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anderson C. M. Lai and Kenny C. Y. Ng
The authors present exact numerical computations leading to a general theoretical formalism of Compton and inverse Compton scattering in several key astrophysical processes, such as X- & γ-ray polarization and astrophysical jets. Their assumption of (1) anisotropic photons and electrons, and (2) no ultrarelativistic approximations, demonstrates major deviations in certain regimes compared to previous calculations.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 063026] Published Fri Mar 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anderson C. M. Lai and Kenny C. Y. Ng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perturbation theory with dispersion and higher cumulants: Framework and linear theory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.063539</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.063539"/>
        <updated>2023-03-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mathias Garny, Dominik Laxhuber, and Román Scoccimarro
The authors develop an alternative perturbative approach to gravitational clustering and the large-scale structure. This approach is complementary to the effective field theory approach while being much more predictive and providing a more detailed understanding of mechanisms like the decoupling of nonlinear small-scale modes into dark matter halos where standard perturbation theory completely fails. This is an exciting step into the future of making predictions, especially in light of upcoming Stage IV experiments.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 063539] Published Fri Mar 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mathias Garny, Dominik Laxhuber, and Román Scoccimarro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perturbation theory with dispersion and higher cumulants: Nonlinear regime]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.063540</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.063540"/>
        <updated>2023-03-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mathias Garny, Dominik Laxhuber, and Román Scoccimarro
The authors develop an alternative perturbative approach to gravitational clustering and the large-scale structure. This approach is complementary to the effective field theory approach while being much more predictive and providing a more detailed understanding of mechanisms like the decoupling of nonlinear small-scale modes into dark matter halos where standard perturbation theory completely fails. This is an exciting step into the future of making predictions, especially in light of upcoming Stage IV experiments.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 063540] Published Fri Mar 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mathias Garny, Dominik Laxhuber, and Román Scoccimarro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimizing the transport of Majorana zero modes in one-dimensional topological superconductors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104516</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104516"/>
        <updated>2023-03-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bill P. Truong, Kartiek Agarwal, and T. Pereg-Barnea
It is well known that Majorana zero modes can be harnessed for applications in topological quantum computation. Transitions away from the ground-state subspace, where computations are performed, are detrimental. The authors study the diabatic error which quantifies these transitions as Majorana zero modes are transported across a superconducting wire. Using the ‘piano key’ approach for transport, the authors find that there exists an optimal number of keys which reduces the diabatic error.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 104516] Published Fri Mar 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bill P. Truong, Kartiek Agarwal, and T. Pereg-Barnea</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mapping quantum Hall edge states in graphene by scanning tunneling microscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115426</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115426"/>
        <updated>2023-03-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Johnsen, C. Schattauer, S. Samaddar, A. Weston, M. J. Hamer, K. Watanabe, T. Taniguchi, R. Gorbachev, F. Libisch, and M. Morgenstern
Edge states are the fingerprint of topological materials, specifically of the quantum Hall effect. The authors map quantum Hall edge states along an electrostatically defined potential step in graphene using scanning tunneling microscopy. Tight-binding simulations reproduce the measurements and allow for identifying a parameter range that minimizes the influence of the tip. This enables investigating the edge states while avoiding tip-induced quantum dots within the sample. The image shows a measured edge state featuring the expected antinodal patterns as it meanders along the interface.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 115426] Published Fri Mar 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Johnsen, C. Schattauer, S. Samaddar, A. Weston, M. J. Hamer, K. Watanabe, T. Taniguchi, R. Gorbachev, F. Libisch, and M. Morgenstern</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Static and dynamic properties of self-bound droplets of light in hot vapors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.033519</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.033519"/>
        <updated>2023-03-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Heitor da Silva, Robin Kaiser, and Tommaso Macrì
The authors explore analogies between self-bound droplet states in Bose-Einstein condensates (BECs) and the propagation of light in nonlinear hot vapor mediums. They establish a mapping between the experimental parameters used in BEC experiments and those needed to observe the analogous phenomenon in hot atomic vapors.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 033519] Published Fri Mar 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Heitor da Silva, Robin Kaiser, and Tommaso Macrì</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dissipative Pairing Interactions: Quantum Instabilities, Topological Light, and Volume-Law Entanglement]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.123602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.123602"/>
        <updated>2023-03-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Andrew Pocklington, Yu-Xin Wang, and A. A. Clerk
A new class of dynamical instabilities generated by a stable photonic lattice Hamiltonian and stable dissipative pairing interaction is sensitive to wavefunction localization and allows selective excitation and entanglement of pure topological photonic edge states with minimal resources.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 123602] Published Thu Mar 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Pocklington, Yu-Xin Wang, and A. A. Clerk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Averages of $b$-hadron, $c$-hadron, and $τ$-lepton properties as of 2021]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.052008</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.052008"/>
        <updated>2023-03-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Y. Amhis et al. (Heavy Flavor Averaging Group Collaboration)
The Heavy Flavor Averaging Group has released new world averages for properties of “heavy-flavor” particle decays—an update aimed at improving our understanding of flavor physics.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 052008] Published Thu Mar 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Y. Amhis &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (Heavy Flavor Averaging Group Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lee-Yang theory of Bose-Einstein condensation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.033324</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.033324"/>
        <updated>2023-03-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fredrik Brange, Tuomas Pyhäranta, Eppu Heinonen, Kay Brandner, and Christian Flindt
Bose gases form into Bose-Einstein condensates at a certain transition temperature, at which a large fraction of bosons in the gas become cool enough to occupy the lowest quantum state together. Here, taking inspiration from recent advances in Lee-Yang theories of phase transitions, the authors demonstrate a method to predict this condensation temperature for an ideal gas of billions of bosons using the energy fluctuations of less than a hundred bosons.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 033324] Published Thu Mar 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fredrik Brange, Tuomas Pyhäranta, Eppu Heinonen, Kay Brandner, and Christian Flindt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coupling between vortex flow and whisker sensor in cylinder wakes with time-varying streamwise gaps]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.034701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.034701"/>
        <updated>2023-03-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pengyao Gong, Dhanush Bhamitipadi Suresh, and Yaqing Jin
The flow-induced vibration of a whisker in the wake of a movable circular cylinder with time-varying streamwise gaps is experimentally investigated to understand how whiskers detect variations in the swimming status of an upstream target. The results show that whisker sensitivity to gap growth rates gradually decreases when such growth rates become sufficiently high, regardless of initial gaps. From the integrated experimental measurements and theoretical model, the reduction of whisker sensitivity under high gap growth rates can be attributed to sufficiently strong vortices initiated by fast movement of the upstream cylinder, which compensate vortex strength decay due to the gap growth.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 034701] Published Wed Mar 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pengyao Gong, Dhanush Bhamitipadi Suresh, and Yaqing Jin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three-dimensional tomographic imaging of the magnetization vector field using Fourier transform holography]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.094425</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.094425"/>
        <updated>2023-03-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marisel Di Pietro Martínez, Alexis Wartelle, Carlos Herrero Martínez, Farid Fettar, Florent Blondelle, Jean-François Motte, Claire Donnelly, Luke Turnbull, Feodor Ogrin, Gerrit van der Laan, Horia Popescu, Nicolas Jaouen, Flora Yakhou-Harris, and Guillaume Beutier
The authors present a new tomographic technique, based on Fourier transform holography. It is a lensless imaging technique to retrieve the object of interest from its diffraction pattern in a single step of computation. A combination of dual-axis tomographic projections provides a 3D vectorial magnetic image of an 800-nm-thick Fe/Gd multilayer in a 5-μm-diameter field of view with a resolution of 80 nm. The reconstruction reveals not only wormlike domains with magnetization pointing mostly out of plane, but also the subtle features of magnetic flux closure around the domain walls.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 094425] Published Wed Mar 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marisel Di Pietro Martínez, Alexis Wartelle, Carlos Herrero Martínez, Farid Fettar, Florent Blondelle, Jean-François Motte, Claire Donnelly, Luke Turnbull, Feodor Ogrin, Gerrit van der Laan, Horia Popescu, Nicolas Jaouen, Flora Yakhou-Harris, and Guillaume Beutier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generalized multifractality in two-dimensional disordered systems of chiral symmetry classes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104202"/>
        <updated>2023-03-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jonas F. Karcher, Ilya A. Gruzberg, and Alexander D. Mirlin
Anderson transitions between metals and insulators exhibit fascinating spatial structure, fluctuations, and correlations of electronic wave functions. This structure has been properly characterized by the authors in terms of multifractals with continuous spectra of scaling exponents. In this paper, the authors focus on Anderson transitions in systems with a sublattice (chiral) symmetry. This particular class of Anderson transitions has not been well-studied in the past, and the authors fill this gap with a thorough analytical and numerical study of multifractal spectra in the metallic phase and at the critical point of the Anderson transition.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 104202] Published Wed Mar 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonas F. Karcher, Ilya A. Gruzberg, and Alexander D. Mirlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin-orbital order and excitons in magnetoresistive HoBi]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104423</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104423"/>
        <updated>2023-03-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Gaudet, H.-Y. Yang, E. M. Smith, T. Halloran, J. P. Clancy, J. A. Rodriguez-Rivera, Guangyong Xu, Y. Zhao, W. C. Chen, G. Sala, A. A. Aczel, B. D. Gaulin, F. Tafti, and C. Broholm
The rare-earth monopnictides RX have been found to exhibit exotic topological three-dimensional states, coupled to unique magnetotransport responses such as extreme magnetoresistance. These findings generated interest to understand the interplay between electronic band topology, transport, and magnetism in RX. While neutron scattering is indispensable to fully characterize magnetism, there is very little modern work on this family of compounds. Since the details of the magnetism have a profound impact on the electronic band topology and transport in materials, the authors present here a thorough characterization of the magnetism in HoBi, based on modern neutron scattering techniques.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 104423] Published Wed Mar 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Gaudet, H.-Y. Yang, E. M. Smith, T. Halloran, J. P. Clancy, J. A. Rodriguez-Rivera, Guangyong Xu, Y. Zhao, W. C. Chen, G. Sala, A. A. Aczel, B. D. Gaulin, F. Tafti, and C. Broholm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accuracy of quantum simulators with ultracold dipolar molecules: A quantitative comparison between continuum and lattice descriptions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.033323</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.033323"/>
        <updated>2023-03-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Michael Hughes, Axel U. J. Lode, Dieter Jaksch, and Paolo Molignini
The authors perform a quantitative comparison between the continuum description of a one-dimensional gas of dipolar bosons in an optical lattice and the single-band Bose-Hubbard lattice model that it simulates. Discrepancies are found in regimes with strong dipole-dipole interactions and high densities in the continuum system.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 033323] Published Wed Mar 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Hughes, Axel U. J. Lode, Dieter Jaksch, and Paolo Molignini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Many-Body Description of STM-Induced Fluorescence of Charged Molecules]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.126202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.126202"/>
        <updated>2023-03-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Song Jiang, Tomáš Neuman, Rémi Bretel, Alex Boeglin, Fabrice Scheurer, Eric Le Moal, and Guillaume Schull
Spatial maps of the light emitted by an excited molecule reveal how the emission depends on the molecule’s charge states.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 126202] Published Tue Mar 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Song Jiang, Tomáš Neuman, Rémi Bretel, Alex Boeglin, Fabrice Scheurer, Eric Le Moal, and Guillaume Schull</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum oscillations in the centrosymmetric skyrmion-hosting magnet ${\mathrm{GdRu}}_{2}{\mathrm{Si}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104421</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104421"/>
        <updated>2023-03-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. Matsuyama, T. Nomura, S. Imajo, T. Nomoto, R. Arita, K. Sudo, M. Kimata, N. D. Khanh, R. Takagi, Y. Tokura, S. Seki, K. Kindo, and Y. Kohama
The skyrmion formation mechanism in centrosymmetric systems remains to be understood, partially because of the lack of fundamental understanding of the electronic structure. The authors observe de Haas–van Alphen and Shubnikov–de Haas oscillations in high magnetic fields up to 58 T on GdRu2Si2, which is one of such centrosymmetric skyrmion-hosting magnets with the shortest skyrmion diameter ever found. Combined with first-principles calculations, the authors now reveal the electronic structure of GdRu2Si2 and its reconstruction at the magnetic phase boundary.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 104421] Published Tue Mar 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Matsuyama, T. Nomura, S. Imajo, T. Nomoto, R. Arita, K. Sudo, M. Kimata, N. D. Khanh, R. Takagi, Y. Tokura, S. Seki, K. Kindo, and Y. Kohama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First-principles theory of the pressure-induced invar effect in FeNi alloys]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104422</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104422"/>
        <updated>2023-03-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Amanda Ehn, Björn Alling, and Igor A. Abrikosov
Beside the classic Fe64Ni36 Invar alloy, which shows an anomalously low thermal expansion at ambient pressure, Fe-Ni alloys with a higher nickel composition can be driven to Invar behavior by pressure. The authors investigate the pressure induced Invar effect theoretically and demonstrate that it can be explained by a magnetic transition from a ferromagnetic state at high volume to a complex noncollinear state upon compression. They relate the Invar effect to the increasing contribution of magnetic entropy with pressure.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 104422] Published Tue Mar 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amanda Ehn, Björn Alling, and Igor A. Abrikosov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Valley-Tunable Even-Denominator Fractional Quantum Hall State in the Lowest Landau Level of an Anisotropic System]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.126301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.126301"/>
        <updated>2023-03-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Md. Shafayat Hossain, Meng K. Ma, Y. J. Chung, S. K. Singh, A. Gupta, K. W. West, K. W. Baldwin, L. N. Pfeiffer, R. Winkler, and M. Shayegan
An in-plane magnetic field and valley occupancy can tune phase transitions in an even-denominator quantum Hall regime.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 126301] Published Mon Mar 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Md. Shafayat Hossain, Meng K. Ma, Y. J. Chung, S. K. Singh, A. Gupta, K. W. West, K. W. Baldwin, L. N. Pfeiffer, R. Winkler, and M. Shayegan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enzyme-Enriched Condensates Show Self-Propulsion, Positioning, and Coexistence]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.128401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.128401"/>
        <updated>2023-03-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Leonardo Demarchi, Andriy Goychuk, Ivan Maryshev, and Erwin Frey
Phase separation within cells creates droplets whose chemical activity leads to surprising mobility that serves cellular function and hints at the origin of life.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 128401] Published Mon Mar 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leonardo Demarchi, Andriy Goychuk, Ivan Maryshev, and Erwin Frey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strong lateral exchange coupling and current-induced switching in single-layer ferrimagnetic films with patterned compensation temperature]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L100412</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L100412"/>
        <updated>2023-03-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zhentao Liu, Zhaochu Luo, Ivan Shorubalko, Christof Vockenhuber, Laura J. Heyderman, Pietro Gambardella, and Aleš Hrabec
Interlayer couplings are widely used in spintronic devices based on magnetic multilayers. Here, the authors demonstrate instead a strong tunable coupling between adjacent regions of a single ferrimagnetic layer, based on the exchange interaction. They unveil a large lateral exchange bias by spatially patterning the compensation temperature of the ferrimagnet. Furthermore, they show electrical switching of ferrimagnetic domains utilizing the lateral exchange coupling mechanism in combination with spin-orbit torques.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L100412] Published Mon Mar 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhentao Liu, Zhaochu Luo, Ivan Shorubalko, Christof Vockenhuber, Laura J. Heyderman, Pietro Gambardella, and Aleš Hrabec</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Precision Measurement of the Microwave Dielectric Loss of Sapphire in the Quantum Regime with Parts-per-Billion Sensitivity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034064</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034064"/>
        <updated>2023-03-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexander P. Read, Benjamin J. Chapman, Chan U Lei, Jacob C. Curtis, Suhas Ganjam, Lev Krayzman, Luigi Frunzio, and Robert J. Schoelkopf
To better understand decoherence in superconducting qubits, the authors develop a technique to measure the loss tangent of dielectric substrates and predict the impact of dielectric loss on qubit lifetimes. This is done with no need to fabricate planar devices; the technique is independent of material platform. Measurements of sapphire in a demonstration of the approach suggest that coherence of superconducting qubits on a common form of sapphire is limited significantly by bulk dielectric loss. The same technique also shows that another form of sapphire would substantially mitigate this bulk dielectric loss and prolong qubit coherence.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 034064] Published Mon Mar 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexander P. Read, Benjamin J. Chapman, Chan U Lei, Jacob C. Curtis, Suhas Ganjam, Lev Krayzman, Luigi Frunzio, and Robert J. Schoelkopf</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anisotropic acoustics in dipolar Fermi gases]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.033321</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.033321"/>
        <updated>2023-03-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Reuben R. W. Wang and John L. Bohn
The authors theoretically study the propagation of plane wave modes in ultracold dipolar Fermi gases in the hydrodynamic limit, including collisions and mean-field dipolar interactions. The authors find that longitudinal waves present anisotropies in both the speed of sound and damping. In addition, two types of shear waves are predicted, which could be used as an experimental means to measure the viscosity coefficients.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 033321] Published Mon Mar 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuben R. W. Wang and John L. Bohn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stacking domain morphology in epitaxial graphene on silicon carbide]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.034001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.034001"/>
        <updated>2023-03-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tobias A. de Jong, Luuk Visser, Johannes Jobst, Ruud M. Tromp, and Sense Jan van der Molen
Despite being considered homogeneous and uniform, graphene grown on silicon carbide has been found to contain a vast network of stacking domains and dislocations. These are formed due to the strain field between graphene and the substrate, and their spatial orientations and shapes arise from minute variations therein. In this work, the authors used low-energy electron microscopy and moire pattern analysis to map out local variations in orientation, strain, and dislocation distribution. This creates a better understanding of the growth process of graphene on silicon carbide (and similar two-dimensional materials) to enable their use in practical applications.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 034001] Published Fri Mar 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tobias A. de Jong, Luuk Visser, Johannes Jobst, Ruud M. Tromp, and Sense Jan van der Molen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Switchable Explosives: Performance Tuning of Fluid-Activated High Explosive Architectures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.116105</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.116105"/>
        <updated>2023-03-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Cameron B. Brown, Alexander H. Mueller, Seetharaman Sridhar, Joseph P. Lichthardt, Andrew M. Schmalzer, Bryce C. Tappan, Von H. Whitley, Larry G. Hill, Eduardo Lozano, and Tariq D. Aslam
An explosive material fabricated with a highly porous structure is inactive but is easily “switched on” when filled with water.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 116105] Published Fri Mar 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cameron B. Brown, Alexander H. Mueller, Seetharaman Sridhar, Joseph P. Lichthardt, Andrew M. Schmalzer, Bryce C. Tappan, Von H. Whitley, Larry G. Hill, Eduardo Lozano, and Tariq D. Aslam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Single-Molecule Force Spectroscopy Reveals Cation-$π$ Interactions in Aqueous Media Are Highly Affected by Cation Dehydration]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.118101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.118101"/>
        <updated>2023-03-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Weishuai Di, Kai Xue, Jun Cai, Zhenshu Zhu, Zihan Li, Hui Fu, Hai Lei, Wenbing Hu, Chun Tang, Wei Wang, and Yi Cao
Researchers have developed a method for measuring the strength of certain ion–electron interactions in water, with initial tests throwing up unexpected results.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 118101] Published Fri Mar 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weishuai Di, Kai Xue, Jun Cai, Zhenshu Zhu, Zihan Li, Hui Fu, Hai Lei, Wenbing Hu, Chun Tang, Wei Wang, and Yi Cao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Binary geometries, generalized particles and strings, and cluster algebras]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.066015</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.066015"/>
        <updated>2023-03-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nima Arkani-Hamed, Song He, Thomas Lam, and Hugh Thomas
The authors study the fundamental properties of scattering amplitudes of particles in any spacetime dimension. They introduce binary geometries, giving a completely rigid geometric realization of the combinatorics of generalized associahedra attached to any Dynkin diagram. Furthermore, they define open and closed “cluster string integrals”, which provide a generalization of particle and string scattering amplitudes, and enjoy remarkable factorization properties at finite α′.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 066015] Published Fri Mar 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nima Arkani-Hamed, Song He, Thomas Lam, and Hugh Thomas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Higher-order topological superconductivity in twisted bilayer graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.094512</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.094512"/>
        <updated>2023-03-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aaron Chew, Yijie Wang, B. Andrei Bernevig, and Zhi-Da Song
Twisted bilayer graphene, by nature of its symmetries (like the approximate particle-hole symmetry) and anomalous band structure, realizes a higher-order topological superconductor when s-wave pairing is introduced via proximity. Here, the authors demonstrate this exotic phase numerically and analytically, and illustrate a multitude of consequences: zero modes bound to Abrikosov vortices, the fractional Josephson effect, and much more.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 094512] Published Fri Mar 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aaron Chew, Yijie Wang, B. Andrei Bernevig, and Zhi-Da Song</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin and orbital metallic magnetism in rhombohedral trilayer graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L121405</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L121405"/>
        <updated>2023-03-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chunli Huang, Tobias M. R. Wolf, Wei Qin, Nemin Wei, Igor V. Blinov, and Allan H. MacDonald
Lightly doped multilayer graphene surprised researchers with the emergence of superconductivity and magnetism under strong electric displacement fields. The authors interpret the displacement field versus hole-density phase diagram using mean-field theory and experimentally informed band structure. They find that magnetism in these electronic systems is often intertwined with nematic order because of the noncompact Fermi sea topology and fourfold spin-valley degeneracy.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L121405] Published Fri Mar 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chunli Huang, Tobias M. R. Wolf, Wei Qin, Nemin Wei, Igor V. Blinov, and Allan H. MacDonald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robust quantum control with disorder-dressed evolution]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.032609</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.032609"/>
        <updated>2023-03-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tenzan Araki, Franco Nori, and Clemens Gneiting
Quantum control pulses, used to produce desired states in quantum technology applications, can be problematically sensitive to disorder. Here, the authors develop a systematic approach to finding quantum control pulses that are robust in realistic scenarios by translating disorder into a quantum master equation and maximizing the purity of the resulting density matrix.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 032609] Published Fri Mar 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tenzan Araki, Franco Nori, and Clemens Gneiting</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Helical Locomotion in Yield Stress Fluids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.114002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.114002"/>
        <updated>2023-03-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Farshad Nazari, Kourosh Shoele, and Hadi Mohammadigoushki
If a helical bacteria’s tail propulsion is strong enough to deform the yield-stress fluid ahead of the swimmer, locomotion proceeds.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 114002] Published Thu Mar 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Farshad Nazari, Kourosh Shoele, and Hadi Mohammadigoushki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lattice dynamics and in-plane antiferromagnetism in ${\mathrm{Mn}}_{x}{\mathrm{Zn}}_{1−x}{\mathrm{PS}}_{3}$ across the entire composition range]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104415</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.104415"/>
        <updated>2023-03-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Robert Oliva, Esther Ritov, Faris Horani, Iñigo Etxebarria, Adam K. Budniak, Yaron Amouyal, Efrat Lifshitz, and Mael Guennou
Antiferromagnetic MnPS3 and diamagnetic ZnPS3 belong to a family of two-dimensional compounds that exhibit a rich variety of magnetic ordering. Low-temperature Raman spectroscopy and SQUID magnetometer measurements are performed on both compounds and their alloy in order to evaluate a possible Jahn-Teller distortion as well as to reveal magnetic and alloy signatures. With the aid of first-principles calculations, a description of the lattice dynamics of the system is presented, together with the magnetic phase diagram across the entire compositional range.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 104415] Published Thu Mar 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Oliva, Esther Ritov, Faris Horani, Iñigo Etxebarria, Adam K. Budniak, Yaron Amouyal, Efrat Lifshitz, and Mael Guennou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interplay of structure and magnetism in ${\mathrm{LuFe}}_{4}{\mathrm{Ge}}_{2}$ tuned by hydrostatic pressure]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125136</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125136"/>
        <updated>2023-03-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. O. Ajeesh, P. Materne, R. D. dos Reis, K. Weber, S. Dengre, R. Sarkar, R. Khasanov, I. Kraft, A. M. León, W. Bi, J. Zhao, E. E. Alp, S. Medvedev, V. Ksenofontov, H. Rosner, H.-H. Klauss, C. Geibel, and M. Nicklas
Competing ground states often lead to the emergence of novel unconventional phases. The presence of magnetic frustration in such materials brings about additional complexity. Here, the authors present a comprehensive study on the ground-state properties of LuFe4Ge2, a ternary intermetallic compound with magnetic frustration and quasi-one-dimensional structure, elucidating the interplay of structure and magnetism. In contrast to the well-studied two-dimensional iron pnictides with competing exchange interactions, LuFe4Ge2 exhibits quasi-one-dimensional chains of geometrically frustrated Fe tetrahedra. It displays a magnetostructural transition at ambient pressure with a change in symmetry from tetragonal to orthorhombic, similar to that in the iron-pnictides, which evolves in an unexpected way under the application of hydrostatic pressure. In that way the intermetallic LuFe4Ge2 material family offers a new perspective on the entanglement of crystal structure and magnetism.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 125136] Published Thu Mar 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. O. Ajeesh, P. Materne, R. D. dos Reis, K. Weber, S. Dengre, R. Sarkar, R. Khasanov, I. Kraft, A. M. León, W. Bi, J. Zhao, E. E. Alp, S. Medvedev, V. Ksenofontov, H. Rosner, H.-H. Klauss, C. Geibel, and M. Nicklas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological nature of dislocation networks in two-dimensional moiré materials]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125413</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125413"/>
        <updated>2023-03-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rebecca Engelke, Hyobin Yoo, Stephen Carr, Kevin Xu, Paul Cazeaux, Richard Allen, Andres Mier Valdivia, Mitchell Luskin, Efthimios Kaxiras, Minhyong Kim, Jung Hoon Han, and Philip Kim
Twisted bilayers of two-dimensional materials contain a moiré superatomic lattice domain that can be bounded by a domain boundary network. The authors show here that the nodes of this network can be considered topological defects. While the nodes in previously studied twisted moiré materials are vortices, the authors discover antivortices formed in strained moiré systems using transmission electron micrographs. This work provides insight into the underlying rules governing moiré structures, inspiring the construction of new types of moiré interfaces.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 125413] Published Thu Mar 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca Engelke, Hyobin Yoo, Stephen Carr, Kevin Xu, Paul Cazeaux, Richard Allen, Andres Mier Valdivia, Mitchell Luskin, Efthimios Kaxiras, Minhyong Kim, Jung Hoon Han, and Philip Kim</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parallel Assembly of Arbitrary Defect-Free Atom Arrays with a Multitweezer Algorithm]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034048</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034048"/>
        <updated>2023-03-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Weikun Tian, Wen Jun Wee, An Qu, Billy Jun Ming Lim, Prithvi Raj Datla, Vanessa Pei Wen Koh, and Huanqian Loh
A new algorithm can organize hundreds of atoms into pristine patterns—including a honeycomb lattice, a fractal called a Sierpiński triangle, and a lion’s head.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 034048] Published Wed Mar 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Weikun Tian, Wen Jun Wee, An Qu, Billy Jun Ming Lim, Prithvi Raj Datla, Vanessa Pei Wen Koh, and Huanqian Loh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disordered Heterogeneous Universe: Galaxy Distribution and Clustering across Length Scales]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011038</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011038"/>
        <updated>2023-03-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Oliver H. E. Philcox and Salvatore Torquato
A new methodology for analyzing the 3D distribution of galaxies borrows techniques from the study of colloids and other disordered materials.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 011038] Published Tue Mar 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver H. E. Philcox and Salvatore Torquato</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal Quantum Rewinding Protocol with an Arbitrarily High Probability of Success]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.110201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.110201"/>
        <updated>2023-03-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. Trillo, B. Dive, and M. Navascués
A new technique for reversing the evolution of a quantum system could become a key tool in quantum information technology.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 110201] Published Tue Mar 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. Trillo, B. Dive, and M. Navascués</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological band inversion in HgTe(001): Surface and bulk signatures from photoemission]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L121102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L121102"/>
        <updated>2023-03-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Raphael C. Vidal, Giovanni Marini, Lukas Lunczer, Simon Moser, Lena Fürst, Julia Issing, Chris Jozwiak, Aaron Bostwick, Eli Rotenberg, Charles Gould, Hartmut Buhmann, Wouter Beugeling, Giorgio Sangiovanni, Domenico Di Sante, Gianni Profeta, Laurens W. Molenkamp, Hendrik Bentmann, and Friedrich Reinert
HgTe is a prime example of a topological material that exhibits a range of topological phases based on its dimensionality and lattice strain. The key to its topological properties lies in the band inversion between the Hg 6s and Te 5p valence levels, leading to the emergence of surface states. In this study, the authors present an in-depth examination of the electronic structure of strained HgTe films using angle-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy and density functional theory. The results offer a direct visualization of the topological band inversion and surface states present in HgTe.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L121102] Published Tue Mar 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Raphael C. Vidal, Giovanni Marini, Lukas Lunczer, Simon Moser, Lena Fürst, Julia Issing, Chris Jozwiak, Aaron Bostwick, Eli Rotenberg, Charles Gould, Hartmut Buhmann, Wouter Beugeling, Giorgio Sangiovanni, Domenico Di Sante, Gianni Profeta, Laurens W. Molenkamp, Hendrik Bentmann, and Friedrich Reinert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic Excitation Response of DNA to High-Energy Proton Radiation in Water]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.118401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.118401"/>
        <updated>2023-03-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christopher Shepard, Dillon C. Yost, and Yosuke Kanai
A study of the electron excitation response of DNA to proton radiation has elucidated mechanisms of damage incurred during proton radiotherapy.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 118401] Published Mon Mar 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher Shepard, Dillon C. Yost, and Yosuke Kanai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conserved currents for a Kerr black hole and orthogonality of quasinormal modes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.064030</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.064030"/>
        <updated>2023-03-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Stephen R. Green, Stefan Hollands, Laura Sberna, Vahid Toomani, and Peter Zimmerman
Using a symmetry of the Kerr spacetime, the authors determine an original bilinear form for perturbations of the Weyl scalars. They show that upon choosing appropriate integration contours, this form can also be used on quasi-normal mode data. This manuscript provides a formalism for studying ringdown beyond the leading order, with potential application to numerical relativity and gravitational wave observation.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 064030] Published Mon Mar 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen R. Green, Stefan Hollands, Laura Sberna, Vahid Toomani, and Peter Zimmerman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theoretical investigation of charge transfer between two defects in a wide band gap semiconductor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125305</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125305"/>
        <updated>2023-03-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rodrick Kuate Defo, Alejandro W. Rodriguez, Efthimios Kaxiras, and Steven L. Richardson
In calculating the concentrations of the charge states of various defects, the Fermi level is generally assumed to be uniform throughout a semiconductor. The authors establish the timescales involved in thermally driven charge transfer, ultimately refuting the assumption of Fermi-level uniformity on the timescales over which optically detected magnetic resonance (ODMR) spectroscopy experiments are typically performed for NV centers in diamond. Their results reveal the potential for noninvasive determination of defect distances and average defect concentrations through ODMR spectroscopy.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 125305] Published Mon Mar 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rodrick Kuate Defo, Alejandro W. Rodriguez, Efthimios Kaxiras, and Steven L. Richardson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Appropriate Mechanical Confinement Inhibits Multipolar Cell Division via Pole-Cortex Interaction]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011036</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.011036"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Longcan Cheng, Jingchen Li, Houbo Sun, and Hongyuan Jiang
Segregation of chromosomes in dividing cells can be disrupted if the cells are constrained by their surroundings.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 011036] Published Fri Mar 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Longcan Cheng, Jingchen Li, Houbo Sun, and Hongyuan Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin, Charge, and $η$-Spin Separation in One-Dimensional Photodoped Mott Insulators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.106501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.106501"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuta Murakami, Shintaro Takayoshi, Tatsuya Kaneko, Andreas M. Läuchli, and Philipp Werner
A derivation of the exact expression for the wave function of photodoped metastable states in one-dimensional Mott insulators shows that these systems host a number of correlations among the active degrees freedom, such as spin, charge and η-spin separation.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 106501] Published Fri Mar 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuta Murakami, Shintaro Takayoshi, Tatsuya Kaneko, Andreas M. Läuchli, and Philipp Werner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statistical analysis of initial-state and final-state response in heavy-ion collisions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.034905</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.034905"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nicolas Borghini, Marc Borrell, Nina Feld, Hendrik Roch, Sören Schlichting, and Clemens Werthmann
High-energy nuclear collisions are analyzed theoretically using multistage models assembled to simulate the different stages of the reaction. This paper presents a new method for systematically characterizing the early-time density of a heavy-ion collision system. It is then used to analyze events from different models as well as the system response to these initial conditions. This method will help distinguish between different approaches to describing the dynamics of relativistic heavy-ion collisions at very early times.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, 034905] Published Fri Mar 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicolas Borghini, Marc Borrell, Nina Feld, Hendrik Roch, Sören Schlichting, and Clemens Werthmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Structure of charge density waves in ${\mathrm{La}}_{1.875}{\mathrm{Ba}}_{0.125}{\mathrm{CuO}}_{4}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115125</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115125"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Sears, Y. Shen, M. J. Krogstad, H. Miao, E. S. Bozin, I. K. Robinson, G. D. Gu, R. Osborn, S. Rosenkranz, J. M. Tranquada, and M. P. M. Dean
The cuprate superconductors exhibit periodic modulations of their charge density and crystal structure. Using x-ray diffraction, the authors identify the subtle structural displacements associated with this ordering. The displacements are not confined to a single copper-oxygen layer but rather propagate over a surprisingly large distance through the crystal. The authors attribute this effect to the weak c-axis charge screening in cuprates and suggest that this effect could help couple the charge-density wave between adjacent planes in the crystal.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 115125] Published Fri Mar 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Sears, Y. Shen, M. J. Krogstad, H. Miao, E. S. Bozin, I. K. Robinson, G. D. Gu, R. Osborn, S. Rosenkranz, J. M. Tranquada, and M. P. M. Dean</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin polarization of exciton-polariton condensate in a photonic synthetic effective magnetic field]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125303</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.125303"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Mirek, M. Furman, M. Król, B. Seredyński, K. Łempicka-Mirek, K. Tyszka, W. Pacuski, M. Matuszewski, J. Szczytko, and B. Piętka
The authors investigate here the spin polarization of localized exciton-polariton condensates in CdTe-based microcavities doped with magnetic ions. They demonstrate that an effective magnetic field originating from the photonic potential landscape leads to the formation of elliptically polarized condensate. The degree of spin polarization of the condensate depends on the excitation power and polarization of the laser. Based on the magnetic field behavior of the condensate in the presence of magnetic ions, they estimate the polariton-polariton interaction strength in a CdTe system.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 125303] Published Fri Mar 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Mirek, M. Furman, M. Król, B. Seredyński, K. Łempicka-Mirek, K. Tyszka, W. Pacuski, M. Matuszewski, J. Szczytko, and B. Piętka</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minimal one-dimensional model of bad metal behavior from fast particle-hole scattering]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L100301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L100301"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yan-Qi Wang, Roman Rausch, Christoph Karrasch, and Joel E. Moore
The authors propose here a mechanism and an explicit one-dimensional model to realize the linear-in-temperature resistivity that is the hallmark of bad metals. They then verify the behavior with advanced DMRG-type simulations. These results open a new approach to understanding the limits of relaxation generated by local interactions in extended many-body systems. This work should push forward research into understanding some of the most basic questions about transport for 1D and critical systems, which bridge quantum matter and quantum chaos.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L100301] Published Fri Mar 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yan-Qi Wang, Roman Rausch, Christoph Karrasch, and Joel E. Moore</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electron-Beam Source with a Superconducting Niobium Tip]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034036</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034036"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C.W. Johnson, A.K. Schmid, M. Mankos, R. Röpke, N. Kerker, I.S. Hwang, E.K. Wong, D.F. Ogletree, A.M. Minor, and A. Stibor
Electron-beam sources are foundational in high-resolution electron microscopy and spectroscopy, but applications have been limited due to their relatively large energy spread. The authors fabricate a monocrystalline niobium nanotip electron field emitter and characterize it in superconducting and normal-conducting regimes. This bright, stable, coherent electron beam source features an exceptionally narrow energy spread. The authors also study the role of xenon adsorption and two-electron correlations. This work may improve aberration-corrected microscopy and electron energy-loss spectroscopy and enable high-resolution vibrational spectroscopy or quantum electron microscopy.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 034036] Published Fri Mar 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C.W. Johnson, A.K. Schmid, M. Mankos, R. Röpke, N. Kerker, I.S. Hwang, E.K. Wong, D.F. Ogletree, A.M. Minor, and A. Stibor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Macroscopic quantum electrodynamics theory of resonance energy transfer involving chiral molecules]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.032809</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.032809"/>
        <updated>2023-03-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Janine Christine Franz, Stefan Yoshi Buhmann, and A. Salam
The authors develop an approach for studying resonant energy transfer between two chiral molecules embedded in a homogeneous medium as a means for chiral discrimination. They find that the degree of discrimination is usually larger for large intermolecular distances, and can be modified by modifying the surrounding medium.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 032809] Published Fri Mar 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Janine Christine Franz, Stefan Yoshi Buhmann, and A. Salam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Role of geometry and adhesion in droplet freezing dynamics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.033601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.033601"/>
        <updated>2023-03-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lila Seguy, Suzie Protiere, and Axel Huerre
We propose a thermal and geometrical analytical model for the freezing front dynamics of a spherical drop. The growth is characterized by an effective diffusion coefficient that increases as the substrate temperature decreases and a spherical front that meets the edges of the drop perpendicularly. We compare our model with experimental data for substrate temperature ranging from -9 to -80 °C. We highlight the importance of heat diffusion in the liquid and the adhesion of drops to the substrate that decreases at low temperature.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 033601] Published Thu Mar 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lila Seguy, Suzie Protiere, and Axel Huerre</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Assignment of excitonic insulators in <i>ab initio</i> theories: The case of ${\mathrm{NiBr}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115121</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.115121"/>
        <updated>2023-03-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Stefano Di Sabatino, Alejandro Molina-Sánchez, Pina Romaniello, and Davide Sangalli
The determination of an excitonic insulator phase relies on the relative value of the excitonic binding energy and the fundamental band gap. With the quite unique case of NiBr2, the authors warn about the risk of running into false positives when using the GW+BSE scheme to determine if a system displays negative excitonic energies, which are a signature of an excitonic insulator phase. They show that consistency between approximations used in the ground-state and excited-state calculations as well as independence from the starting point are essential features for a proper description of excitonic insulators.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 115121] Published Thu Mar 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stefano Di Sabatino, Alejandro Molina-Sánchez, Pina Romaniello, and Davide Sangalli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linear Regression and Machine Learning for Nuclear Forensics of Spent Fuel from Six Types of Nuclear Reactors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034028</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034028"/>
        <updated>2023-03-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shengli Chen, Tianxiang Wang, Zhong Zhang, Runfeng Li, Su Yuan, Ruiyi Zhang, Cenxi Yuan, Chunyu Zhang, and Jianyu Zhu
A new set of diagnostic techniques developed from experimental data will improve authorities’ ability to determine the provenance of spent fuel.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 034028] Published Thu Mar 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shengli Chen, Tianxiang Wang, Zhong Zhang, Runfeng Li, Su Yuan, Ruiyi Zhang, Cenxi Yuan, Chunyu Zhang, and Jianyu Zhu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time-Dependent Magnetic Flux in Devices for Circuit Quantum Electrodynamics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034031</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034031"/>
        <updated>2023-03-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jacob Bryon, D.K. Weiss, Xinyuan You, Sara Sussman, Xanthe Croot, Ziwen Huang, Jens Koch, and Andrew A. Houck
Time-dependent external flux is ubiquitous across circuit quantum electrodynamics and calls for accurate modeling. Contrary to long-held belief, it is recently predicted—but not yet verified—that the allocation of time-dependent flux cannot be arbitrary in the Hamiltonian. This study provides an experimental verification of this prediction by applying fast flux pulses to a fluxonium qubit and taking measurements of the quantum state following the pulses. Given the widespread use of time-dependent flux in experiments with superconducting qubits, verification of this theory is critical to our understanding of circuit quantum electrodynamics.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 034031] Published Thu Mar 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jacob Bryon, D.K. Weiss, Xinyuan You, Sara Sussman, Xanthe Croot, Ziwen Huang, Jens Koch, and Andrew A. Houck</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Light-Induced Subnanometric Modulation of a Single-Molecule Electron Source]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.106204</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.106204"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hirofumi Yanagisawa, Markus Bohn, Hirotaka Kitoh-Nishioka, Florian Goschin, and Matthias F. Kling
The molecular orbitals of a single C60 molecule on a tungsten tip can be used to shape the emission pattern of electrons.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 106204] Published Wed Mar 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hirofumi Yanagisawa, Markus Bohn, Hirotaka Kitoh-Nishioka, Florian Goschin, and Matthias F. Kling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic Excited States in Extreme Limits via Ensemble Density Functionals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.106401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.106401"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tim Gould, Derk P. Kooi, Paola Gori-Giorgi, and Stefano Pittalis
A venerable strategy for approximating a system’s ground states has now been extended to accommodate its excited states.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 106401] Published Wed Mar 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tim Gould, Derk P. Kooi, Paola Gori-Giorgi, and Stefano Pittalis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Performance Boost of a Collective Qutrit Refrigerator]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034023</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034023"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dmytro Kolisnyk and Gernot Schaller
One of the world’s tiniest autonomous refrigerators can be realized by a single qutrit coupled to three thermal reservoirs. The authors analyze the performance of multiple collectively coupled qutrits, and observe a quantum boost in the steady-state cooling current with a quadratic scaling in the working fluid size. With additional interqutrit interactions, the quantum boost can be maintained also for larger systems and not perfectly collective scenarios, enabling efficient quantum cooling.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 034023] Published Wed Mar 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dmytro Kolisnyk and Gernot Schaller</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scalable Quantum Memory Nodes Using Nuclear Spins in Silicon Carbide]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034026</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.034026"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shravan Kumar Parthasarathy, Birgit Kallinger, Florian Kaiser, Patrick Berwian, Durga B.R. Dasari, Jochen Friedrich, and Roland Nagy
A distributed quantum network requires versatile and high-fidelity quantum memory nodes, but it remains challenging to make them scalable. This study investigates the use of multiple controllable quantum memories in silicon carbide—an established semiconductor material platform for various quantum technology applications—and provides a viable solution. The authors show that solid-state spins in silicon carbide are ideal quantum memories in a distributed quantum computing network, wherein a controlled generation of highly coherent qubit registers using nuclear spins is possible. This study will impact the future development of quantum networks with solid states spins as quantum memories.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 034026] Published Wed Mar 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shravan Kumar Parthasarathy, Birgit Kallinger, Florian Kaiser, Patrick Berwian, Durga B.R. Dasari, Jochen Friedrich, and Roland Nagy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Position measurement and the Huygens-Fresnel principle: A quantum model of Fraunhofer diffraction for polarized pure states]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.033706</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.033706"/>
        <updated>2023-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bernard Fabbro
Starting only from the postulates of quantum mechanics, the author presents a model of Fraunhofer diffraction by an aperture by treating the diaphragm as a position-measurement device, and explains how this model leads to experimentally testable consequences for large diffraction angles and polarization of the diffracted light.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 033706] Published Wed Mar 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bernard Fabbro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>