<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-12-03T00:50:59.868Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-12-03T00:50:59.868Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlocal Intrinsic Fracture Energy of Polymerlike Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.228102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.228102"/>
        <updated>2023-12-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bolei Deng, Shu Wang, Chase Hartquist, and Xuanhe Zhao
The crack resistance of polymer materials is explained by a new model that incorporates a network of stretchable polymer chains.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 228102] Published Fri Dec 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bolei Deng, Shu Wang, Chase Hartquist, and Xuanhe Zhao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ergodic properties of Brownian motion under stochastic resetting]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.064102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.064102"/>
        <updated>2023-12-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): E. Barkai, R. Flaquer-Galmés, and V. Méndez
Stochastic processes with resetting can exhibit different ergodic behaviors depending on the distribution of resetting times. For one-dimensional Brownian motion with resetting, the authors find two ergodic transitions, one of which is related to a competition between returns to the origin by resetting and returns by the diffusion process itself.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 064102] Published Fri Dec 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>E. Barkai, R. Flaquer-Galmés, and V. Méndez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thermo-osmotic slip flows around a thermophoretic microparticle characterized by optical trapping of tracers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.054061</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.054061"/>
        <updated>2023-11-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tetsuro Tsuji, Satoshi Mei, and Satoshi Taguchi
Using fluorescent tracers, researchers visualize the forces that move micrometer-diameter particles through a liquid subjected to a temperature gradient.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 054061] Published Thu Nov 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tetsuro Tsuji, Satoshi Mei, and Satoshi Taguchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vacancy-tuned magnetism in ${\mathrm{LaMn}}_{x}{\mathrm{Sb}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.114203</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.114203"/>
        <updated>2023-11-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tyler J. Slade, Aashish Sapkota, John M. Wilde, Qiang Zhang, Lin-Lin Wang, Saul H. Lapidus, Juan Schmidt, Thomas Heitmann, Sergey L. Bud'ko, and Paul C. Canfield
The AMnPn2 (A = Alkali earth, Pn = Sb, Bi) materials are widely explored as candidate magnetic topological semimetals. Replacing A with a rare-earth atom (R) produces a comparably underinvestigated family, RMnxPn2, in which charge balance favors Mn vacancies (x 2 as a function of the Mn vacancy concentration. They grow single crystals with x = 0.74-0.97 and find that LaMnxSb2 has an exceptionally rich magnetic phase diagram, with six different antiferromagnetic phases and two different crystal structures, depending on T and x. The highly tunable nature of LaMnxSb2 suggests this material may be a good model system for understanding the effects of disorder on magnetic intermetallic compounds.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 114203] Published Wed Nov 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tyler J. Slade, Aashish Sapkota, John M. Wilde, Qiang Zhang, Lin-Lin Wang, Saul H. Lapidus, Juan Schmidt, Thomas Heitmann, Sergey L. Bud'ko, and Paul C. Canfield</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gas Compression Systematically Delays the Onset of Viscous Fingering]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.224002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.224002"/>
        <updated>2023-11-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Liam C. Morrow, Callum Cuttle, and Christopher W. MacMinn
The onset time for “viscous fingering”—an instability that can occur at a gas–liquid boundary—depends on the compressibility of the gas, offering a way to control the behavior.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 224002] Published Wed Nov 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liam C. Morrow, Callum Cuttle, and Christopher W. MacMinn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Longitudinal Spin Fluctuations Driving Field-Reinforced Superconductivity in ${\mathrm{UTe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.226503</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.226503"/>
        <updated>2023-11-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Y. Tokunaga, H. Sakai, S. Kambe, P. Opletal, Y. Tokiwa, Y. Haga, S. Kitagawa, K. Ishida, D. Aoki, G. Knebel, G. Lapertot, S. Krämer, and M. Horvatić
High-field NMR measurements on single crystals of UTe2 show an enhancement of longitudinal spin fluctuations above 15 Tesla, exhibiting a divergence near the field-induced metamagnetic transition at 35 Tesla.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 226503] Published Wed Nov 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Y. Tokunaga, H. Sakai, S. Kambe, P. Opletal, Y. Tokiwa, Y. Haga, S. Kitagawa, K. Ishida, D. Aoki, G. Knebel, G. Lapertot, S. Krämer, and M. Horvatić</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Absence of Spontaneous Magnetic Fields due to Time-Reversal Symmetry Breaking in Bulk Superconducting ${\mathrm{UTe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.226504</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.226504"/>
        <updated>2023-11-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. Azari, M. Yakovlev, N. Rye, S. R. Dunsiger, S. Sundar, M. M. Bordelon, S. M. Thomas, J. D. Thompson, P. F. S. Rosa, and J. E. Sonier
Muon spin relaxation measurements on a new generation of high-quality flux-grown single crystals show that UTe2 does not break time-reversal symmetry.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 226504] Published Wed Nov 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Azari, M. Yakovlev, N. Rye, S. R. Dunsiger, S. Sundar, M. M. Bordelon, S. M. Thomas, J. D. Thompson, P. F. S. Rosa, and J. E. Sonier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Star-Shaped Space of Solutions of the Spherical Negative Perceptron]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.227301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.227301"/>
        <updated>2023-11-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Brandon Livio Annesi, Clarissa Lauditi, Carlo Lucibello, Enrico M. Malatesta, Gabriele Perugini, Fabrizio Pittorino, and Luca Saglietti
The solutions of a nonconvex over-parametrized neural network model are geodesically connected in a star-shaped geometry.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 227301] Published Wed Nov 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brandon Livio Annesi, Clarissa Lauditi, Carlo Lucibello, Enrico M. Malatesta, Gabriele Perugini, Fabrizio Pittorino, and Luca Saglietti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Compression-driven viscous fingering in a radial Hele-Shaw cell]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.113904</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.113904"/>
        <updated>2023-11-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Callum Cuttle, Liam C. Morrow, and Christopher W. MacMinn
The viscous-fingering instability that emerges when gas is injected into a liquid-filled Hele-Shaw cell is a paradigm of pattern formation that has been extensively studied. Here, we examine a previously neglected aspect of the problem: The compressibility of the injected gas. We use experiments, numerical simulations, and an axisymmetric model to show that gas compression controls the time-dependent injection rate and systematically delays the onset of viscous fingering at high capillary number. We quantify the importance of gas compression with a single dimensionless compressibility number.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 113904] Published Wed Nov 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Callum Cuttle, Liam C. Morrow, and Christopher W. MacMinn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beam longitudinal dynamics simulation studies]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.114602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.114602"/>
        <updated>2023-11-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): H. Timko, S. Albright, T. Argyropoulos, H. Damerau, K. Iliakis, L. Intelisano, B. E. Karlsen-Baeck, I. Karpov, A. Lasheen, L. Medina, D. Quartullo, J. Repond, A. L. Vanel, J. Esteban Müller, M. Schwarz, P. Tsapatsaris, and G. Typaldos
A simulation suite that covers a range of applications from low to high energy synchrotrons, from electrons over protons to ions, and from space-charge to synchrotron-radiation dominated regimes.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 26, 114602] Published Wed Nov 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>H. Timko, S. Albright, T. Argyropoulos, H. Damerau, K. Iliakis, L. Intelisano, B. E. Karlsen-Baeck, I. Karpov, A. Lasheen, L. Medina, D. Quartullo, J. Repond, A. L. Vanel, J. Esteban Müller, M. Schwarz, P. Tsapatsaris, and G. Typaldos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deuterium spectroscopy for enhanced bounds on physics beyond the standard model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.052825</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.052825"/>
        <updated>2023-11-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Robert M. Potvliege, Adair Nicolson, Matthew P. A. Jones, and Michael Spannowsky
The authors discuss the use of precise spectroscopic data on hydrogenic atoms in order to obtain new, more stringent bounds on new physics beyond the Standard Model. Assuming a certain “reasonable” flavor dependence the authors obtain constraints that are orders of magnitude more stringent than constraints from hydrogen alone.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 052825] Published Wed Nov 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert M. Potvliege, Adair Nicolson, Matthew P. A. Jones, and Michael Spannowsky</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Superconductivity Studied by Solving <i>Ab Initio</i> Low-Energy Effective Hamiltonians for Carrier Doped ${\mathrm{CaCuO}}_{2}$, ${\mathrm{Bi}}_{2}{\mathrm{Sr}}_{2}{\mathrm{CuO}}_{6}$, ${\mathrm{Bi}}_{2}{\mathrm{Sr}}_{2}{\mathrm{CaCu}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{8}$, and ${\mathrm{HgBa}}_{2}{\mathrm{CuO}}_{4}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041036</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041036"/>
        <updated>2023-11-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Michael Thobias Schmid, Jean-Baptiste Morée, Ryui Kaneko, Youhei Yamaji, and Masatoshi Imada
A first-principles model accounts for the wide range of critical temperatures (Tc’s) for four materials and suggests a parameter that determines Tc in any high-temperature superconductor.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 041036] Published Tue Nov 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael Thobias Schmid, Jean-Baptiste Morée, Ryui Kaneko, Youhei Yamaji, and Masatoshi Imada</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Single-Shot Measurements of Phonon Number States Using the Autler-Townes Effect]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.223603</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.223603"/>
        <updated>2023-11-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marion Mallweger, Murilo Henrique de Oliveira, Robin Thomm, Harry Parke, Natalia Kuk, Gerard Higgins, Romain Bachelard, Celso Jorge Villas-Boas, and Markus Hennrich
A new method based on the Autler-Townes effect can be used to measure the motional states of trapped ions in the number basis.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 223603] Published Tue Nov 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marion Mallweger, Murilo Henrique de Oliveira, Robin Thomm, Harry Parke, Natalia Kuk, Gerard Higgins, Romain Bachelard, Celso Jorge Villas-Boas, and Markus Hennrich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Model for Nonrelativistic Topological Multiferroic Matter]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.226801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.226801"/>
        <updated>2023-11-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Guidobeth Saez, Mario A. Castro, Sebastian Allende, and Alvaro S. Nunez
A minimal model shows that different magnetic configurations give rise to electric polarization stemming from a nontrivial Berry phase of the system without spin-orbit coupling.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 226801] Published Tue Nov 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guidobeth Saez, Mario A. Castro, Sebastian Allende, and Alvaro S. Nunez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic structure, dimer physics, orbital-selective behavior, and magnetic tendencies in the bilayer nickelate superconductor ${\mathrm{La}}_{3}{\mathrm{Ni}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{7}$ under pressure]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L180510</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L180510"/>
        <updated>2023-11-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yang Zhang, Ling-Fang Lin, Adriana Moreo, and Elbio Dagotto
The recently discovered high-temperature superconductor La3Ni2O7 with Tc ~ 80 K under pressure has revolutionized the field of correlated electrons. The authors find here that an orbital-selective spin-singlet “dimer” linking the two planes of this bilayer via the d3z2−r2 orbital provides the primary building block to study its electronic properties. Furthermore, an in-plane robust interorbital hopping between eg states, competes with the more natural intraorbital hopping, leading to a dominant spin stripe (π, 0) order, as well as a rich phase diagram.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L180510] Published Tue Nov 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yang Zhang, Ling-Fang Lin, Adriana Moreo, and Elbio Dagotto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Single-spin spectroscopy of spontaneous and phase-locked spin-torque-oscillator dynamics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.054055</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.054055"/>
        <updated>2023-11-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Adrian Solyom, Michael Caouette-Mansour, Brandon Ruffolo, Patrick Braganca, Lilian Childress, and Jack C. Sankey
Nanoscale magnetic circuits provide an alternate paradigm for computation and signal processing, but characterizing the GHz-frequency magnetic dynamics in these systems has been challenging. The authors use the single spin of a nitrogen-vacancy (N-V) center in diamond to probe nanoscale magnetic fields in the GHz regime, identifying signatures of a free-running and phase-locked spin-torque oscillator in the fluorescence spectrum of a proximal N-V, and measure how the dynamics impact the N-V’s spin relaxation. This technique could enable new sensing modalities for revealing the nanoscale structure of GHz-frequency dynamics in emerging magnetic nanotechnologies.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 054055] Published Tue Nov 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrian Solyom, Michael Caouette-Mansour, Brandon Ruffolo, Patrick Braganca, Lilian Childress, and Jack C. Sankey</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Propagating-spin-wave spectroscopy using inductive antennas: Conditions for unidirectional energy flow]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.054057</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.054057"/>
        <updated>2023-11-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Thibaut Devolder
Spin waves are of central importance in spintronic as they determine the rate at which the magnetization can vary. They can be better studied by using propagating-spin-wave spectroscopy with a physically transparent model. This study of spin-wave transduction focuses on the interaction between spin waves and microwaves, and the impact of the spin-wave dispersion relation. The authors choose specific magnetization orientations so that the magnons and microwave photons do not couple, and show that line-shaped dispersion relations can be harnessed to engineer reconfigurable, nonreciprocal frequency filters transferring spin wave energy in a unidirectional manner.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 054057] Published Tue Nov 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thibaut Devolder</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tension Remodeling Regulates Topological Transitions in Epithelial Tissues]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.1.023006</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.1.023006"/>
        <updated>2023-11-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fernanda Pérez-Verdugo and Shiladitya Banerjee
In this work, authors introduce a dynamic vertex model incorporating strain-induced tension remodeling and mechanical memory dissipation to explain topological transitions commonly observed in epithelial tissues.

[PRX Life 1, 023006] Published Mon Nov 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fernanda Pérez-Verdugo and Shiladitya Banerjee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kerr Black Holes from Massive Higher-Spin Gauge Symmetry]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.221401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.221401"/>
        <updated>2023-11-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lucile Cangemi, Marco Chiodaroli, Henrik Johansson, Alexander Ochirov, Paolo Pichini, and Evgeny Skvortsov
Spinning black holes may have a hidden higher-spin gauge symmetry.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 221401] Published Mon Nov 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucile Cangemi, Marco Chiodaroli, Henrik Johansson, Alexander Ochirov, Paolo Pichini, and Evgeny Skvortsov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nuclear Charge Radius of $^{26m}\mathrm{Al}$ and Its Implication for ${\mathrm{V}}_{ud}$ in the Quark Mixing Matrix]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.222502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.222502"/>
        <updated>2023-11-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): P. Plattner et al.
A measurement of the charge radius of an aluminum nucleus probes the assumption that there are only three families of quarks.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 222502] Published Mon Nov 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>P. Plattner &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cascade of Multielectron Bubble Phases in Monolayer Graphene at High Landau Level Filling]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.226501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.226501"/>
        <updated>2023-11-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fangyuan Yang, Ruiheng Bai, Alexander A. Zibrov, Sandeep Joy, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Brian Skinner, Mark O. Goerbig, and Andrea F. Young
Chemical potential measurements, in concert with theoretical calculations, reveal density-tuned phase transitions between multielectron bubble states in monolayer graphene.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 226501] Published Mon Nov 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fangyuan Yang, Ruiheng Bai, Alexander A. Zibrov, Sandeep Joy, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Brian Skinner, Mark O. Goerbig, and Andrea F. Young</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hunt for magnetic signatures of hidden-photon and axion dark matter in the wilderness]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.096026</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.096026"/>
        <updated>2023-11-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ibrahim A. Sulai, Saarik Kalia, Ariel Arza, Itay M. Bloch, Eduardo Castro Muñoz, Christopher Fabian, Michael A. Fedderke, Madison Forseth, Brian Garthwaite, Peter W. Graham, Will Griffith, Erik Helgren, Katie Hermanson, Andres Interiano-Alvarado, Brittany Karki, Abaz Kryemadhi, Andre Li, Ehsanullah Nikfar, Jason E. Stalnaker, Yicheng Wang, and Derek F. Jackson Kimball
This paper reports on the search for ultralight dark matter in the form of axions and dark photons using an innovative experimental design in which the earth serves as a transducer converting ultralight dark matter into a characteristic magnetic field signal. The magnetometers used to detect the expected magnetic field patterns are placed in areas in which magnetic noise sources, such as anthropogenic ones, are minimal. Although no conclusive detection is reported, limits are set for models in various parameter ranges and the prospects for refining the detection methodology are presented.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 096026] Published Mon Nov 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ibrahim A. Sulai, Saarik Kalia, Ariel Arza, Itay M. Bloch, Eduardo Castro Muñoz, Christopher Fabian, Michael A. Fedderke, Madison Forseth, Brian Garthwaite, Peter W. Graham, Will Griffith, Erik Helgren, Katie Hermanson, Andres Interiano-Alvarado, Brittany Karki, Abaz Kryemadhi, Andre Li, Ehsanullah Nikfar, Jason E. Stalnaker, Yicheng Wang, and Derek F. Jackson Kimball</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comprehensive revision of the summation method for the prediction of reactor ${\overline{ν}}_{e}$ fluxes and spectra]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.055501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.055501"/>
        <updated>2023-11-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lorenzo Périssé, Anthony Onillon, Xavier Mougeot, Matthieu Vivier, Thierry Lasserre, Alain Letourneau, David Lhuillier, and Guillaume Mention
Nuclear reactors are the most copious human-made source of electron antineutrinos (ν¯e) on Earth; yet, determining their flux and spectrum with accuracy remains a considerable challenge. In fact, measurements of the antineutrino flux from reactors have shown a deficit with respect to predictions, which has become known as the reactor antineutrino anomaly. This work combines a careful analysis of up-to-date nuclear decay data with advanced theoretical corrections to the V-A theory of β decay to produce, for the first time, a flux prediction with a comprehensive uncertainty budget. This new prediction achieves a better agreement with existing experimental neutrino data and methodically pins down points for improvements. It will likely stimulate targeted research to check and improve the experimental inputs, with potentially wide-ranging impact, from weak-interaction physics to many aspects of nuclear reactor science and technology.

[Phys. Rev. C 108, 055501] Published Mon Nov 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lorenzo Périssé, Anthony Onillon, Xavier Mougeot, Matthieu Vivier, Thierry Lasserre, Alain Letourneau, David Lhuillier, and Guillaume Mention</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-resolution acoustic field mapping of gigahertz phononic crystals with atomic force microscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.054054</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.054054"/>
        <updated>2023-11-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alessandro Pitanti, Mingyun Yuan, Simone Zanotto, and Paulo Ventura Santos
Manipulating mechanical waves at gigahertz frequencies can lead to next-generation communication technologies, but designing wave-controlling devices requires high-resolution and fast-scanning mapping of acoustic fields. The authors introduce the use of acoustic atomic force microscopy to characterize phononic crystals at gigahertz frequency, showing mechanical vibration mapping with tens-of-nanometer resolution and symmetry-dependent scattering. This study sets the baseline for advanced operations like hyperspectral filtering, beam steering, or spatial-division multiplexing, and will have an impact on the development of acoustic-based microwave technologies.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 054054] Published Mon Nov 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alessandro Pitanti, Mingyun Yuan, Simone Zanotto, and Paulo Ventura Santos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Midcircuit Qubit Measurement and Rearrangement in a $^{171}\mathrm{Yb}$ Atomic Array]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041034</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041034"/>
        <updated>2023-11-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. A. Norcia et al.
Three research groups have exploited the nuclear spins of ytterbium-171 to manipulate qubits before they are read out—an approach that could lead to efficient error-correction schemes for trapped-atom computing platforms.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 041034] Published Wed Nov 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. A. Norcia &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Midcircuit Operations Using the <i>omg</i> Architecture in Neutral Atom Arrays]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041035</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041035"/>
        <updated>2023-11-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Joanna W. Lis, Aruku Senoo, William F. McGrew, Felix Rönchen, Alec Jenkins, and Adam M. Kaufman
Three research groups have exploited the nuclear spins of ytterbium-171 to manipulate qubits before they are read out—an approach that could lead to efficient error-correction schemes for trapped-atom computing platforms.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 041035] Published Wed Nov 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joanna W. Lis, Aruku Senoo, William F. McGrew, Felix Rönchen, Alec Jenkins, and Adam M. Kaufman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ferroic Order for Anisotropic Magnetic Dipole Term in Collinear Antiferromagnets of $({t}_{2g}{)}^{4}$ System]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.216501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.216501"/>
        <updated>2023-11-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Norimasa Sasabe, Masaichiro Mizumaki, Takayuki Uozumi, and Yuichi Yamasaki
A theoretical study on the feasibility of observing x-ray magnetic circular dichroism on a compound with collinear antiferromagnetism reveals two possible magnetic phases, excitonic antiferromagnetism and van Vleck type paramagnetism.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 216501] Published Wed Nov 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Norimasa Sasabe, Masaichiro Mizumaki, Takayuki Uozumi, and Yuichi Yamasaki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Metastability of Discrete-Symmetry Flocks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.218301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.218301"/>
        <updated>2023-11-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Brieuc Benvegnen, Omer Granek, Sunghan Ro, Ran Yaacoby, Hugues Chaté, Yariv Kafri, David Mukamel, Alexandre Solon, and Julien Tailleur
Droplets of active particles moving in a direction opposite that of an ordered flocking phase nucleate and grow and spread ballistically in all directions, implying that discrete-symmetry flocks are metastable in all dimensions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 218301] Published Wed Nov 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brieuc Benvegnen, Omer Granek, Sunghan Ro, Ran Yaacoby, Hugues Chaté, Yariv Kafri, David Mukamel, Alexandre Solon, and Julien Tailleur</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impact craters formed by spinning granular projectiles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.054904</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.054904"/>
        <updated>2023-11-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Douglas D. Carvalho, Nicolao C. Lima, and Erick M. Franklin
Numerical simulations reveal that an impact crater’s shape can depend on the impactor’s spin and its degree of cohesion.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 054904] Published Wed Nov 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Douglas D. Carvalho, Nicolao C. Lima, and Erick M. Franklin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Branes and bundles through conifold transitions and dualities in heterotic string theory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.106018</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.106018"/>
        <updated>2023-11-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lara B. Anderson, Callum R. Brodie, and James Gray
The authors study transitions of particular string compactifications (heterotic theories with N=1 supersymmetry in four dimensions) that change the topology and other nonpertubative properties of the internal manifold. This is part of trying to understand the string landscape, here the moduli space of heterotic compactifications, and string effective field theories. The authors provide geometric analyses, which are an important foundations for the physical understanding of these transitions.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 106018] Published Wed Nov 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lara B. Anderson, Callum R. Brodie, and James Gray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building entanglement entropy out of correlation functions for interacting fermions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.174309</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.174309"/>
        <updated>2023-11-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Saranyo Moitra and Rajdeep Sensarma
There are very few analytical methods to calculate entanglement entropy (EE) of large quantum many-body states. Here, the authors show how to construct EE of generic interacting fermions in arbitrary spatial dimensions in terms of measurable correlation functions. They provide approximate answers for EE when only few-particle correlations are known. The field theory they construct is applicable to systems both in and out of thermal equilibrium.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 174309] Published Wed Nov 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Saranyo Moitra and Rajdeep Sensarma</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strong magnetic proximity effect in van der Waals heterostructures driven by direct hybridization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.184423</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.184423"/>
        <updated>2023-11-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. Cardoso, A. T. Costa, A. H. MacDonald, and J. Fernández-Rossier
The conventional spin proximity effect is normally pictured in terms of a small spin splitting of the bands of a nonmagnetic material, due to exchange coupling to a ferromagnet. In this work, the authors show a different type of proximity mechanism, where only one spin channel in the nonmagnetic material becomes strongly hybridized with the ferromagnet, whereas the other remains unaffected. In the case of graphene coupled to CrI3, a ferromagnetic insulator, the authors show that the hybridization proximity is both strong and electrically tunable.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 184423] Published Wed Nov 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. Cardoso, A. T. Costa, A. H. MacDonald, and J. Fernández-Rossier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transport anomalies in multiband superconductors near the quantum critical point]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.184513</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.184513"/>
        <updated>2023-11-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maxim Dzero, Maxim Khodas, and Alex Levchenko
Exploring quantum superconductor-metal transitions in correlated electron systems reveals intriguing phenomena under diverse nonthermal influences like pressure, chemical substitution, or magnetic field. This study delves into the impact of thermal and quantum fluctuations on transport properties as the system nears the superconducting state from the metallic phase. The focus is on multiband superconductors, unraveling the nuanced role of superconducting fluctuations. Interestingly, depending on the trajectory towards the quantum critical point, these fluctuations may induce localizing corrections to the normal-state conductivity.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 184513] Published Wed Nov 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maxim Dzero, Maxim Khodas, and Alex Levchenko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wigner-Araki-Yanase Theorem for Continuous and Unbounded Conserved Observables]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.210201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.210201"/>
        <updated>2023-11-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yui Kuramochi and Hiroyasu Tajima
According to a new extension to an old theory, a particle’s position cannot be measured precisely even if its momentum is not measured simultaneously.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 210201] Published Tue Nov 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yui Kuramochi and Hiroyasu Tajima</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Logical Magic State Preparation with Fidelity beyond the Distillation Threshold on a Superconducting Quantum Processor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.210603</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.210603"/>
        <updated>2023-11-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yangsen Ye et al.
An efficient and scalable protocol to prepare arbitrary logical states for the distance-3 surface code is demonstrated using 17 out of the 66 qubits on the Zuchongzhi 2.1 superconducting quantum processor.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 210603] Published Tue Nov 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yangsen Ye &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Validation of the $^{10}\mathrm{Be}$ Ground-State Molecular Structure Using $^{10}\mathrm{Be}(p,pα)^{6}\mathrm{He}$ Triple Differential Reaction Cross-Section Measurements]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.212501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.212501"/>
        <updated>2023-11-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): P. J. Li et al.
The protons and neutrons in a nucleus can form clusters analogous to atoms in a molecule, even in the nuclear ground state.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 212501] Published Tue Nov 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>P. J. Li &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charge Asymmetry Suppresses Coarsening Dynamics in Polyelectrolyte Complex Coacervation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.218201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.218201"/>
        <updated>2023-11-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shensheng Chen and Zhen-Gang Wang
Charge asymmetry in mixtures of polyelectrolytes can slow down coarsening dynamics during liquid-liquid phase separation.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 218201] Published Tue Nov 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shensheng Chen and Zhen-Gang Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rayleigh-number dependence of the critical vibration frequency in vibrating thermal turbulence]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.113501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.113501"/>
        <updated>2023-11-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ze-Lin Huang, Xi-Li Guo, Jian-Zhao Wu, Bo-Fu Wang, Kai Leong Chong, and Quan Zhou
Vibration has the ability to control the convective heat transport depending on the relative direction of vibration to the gravitation. We show that horizontal vibration (perpendicular to gravitation) enhances heat transport while vertical vibration (parallel to gravitation) suppresses heat transport. The observed heat transport enhancement or suppression is indicated by the critical vibration frequency. We theoretically and numerically reveal the scaling law between the critical vibration frequency and the Rayleigh number.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 113501] Published Tue Nov 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ze-Lin Huang, Xi-Li Guo, Jian-Zhao Wu, Bo-Fu Wang, Kai Leong Chong, and Quan Zhou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Geometric frustration of hard-disk packings on cones]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.054608</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.054608"/>
        <updated>2023-11-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jessica H. Sun, Abigail Plummer, Grace H. Zhang, David R. Nelson, and Vinothan N. Manoharan
This work models slow reaction-limited growth of crystals on a conical surface. Frustration arises from closure constraints when the crystal wraps around the cone. Defects form a seam running along the axial direction of the cone; a disordered region forms near the tip. The authors study how various parameters affect details.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 054608] Published Tue Nov 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica H. Sun, Abigail Plummer, Grace H. Zhang, David R. Nelson, and Vinothan N. Manoharan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modeling backward-angle $(u\text{−}\text{channel})$ virtual Compton scattering at the future Electron-Ion Collider]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.055205</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.055205"/>
        <updated>2023-11-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zachary Sweger, Saeahram Yoo, Ziyuan Zeng, Daniel Cebra, Spencer R. Klein, Yuanjing Ji, Xin Dong, and Minjung Kim
High-energy backward scattering of photons can involve very large momentum transfers to the target baryons. This is in stark contrast to the more common forward scattering process which dominates the Compton scattering cross section and is widely recognized as one of the most important measurements in the quest to understand and image the proton and nuclei. The authors present a detailed study of such high-energy virtual Compton back scattering at the future Electron-Ion Collider (EIC). The paper describes new opportunities for obtaining relevant physics information from this particular scattering scenario and highlights the physics potential at the EIC.

[Phys. Rev. C 108, 055205] Published Tue Nov 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zachary Sweger, Saeahram Yoo, Ziyuan Zeng, Daniel Cebra, Spencer R. Klein, Yuanjing Ji, Xin Dong, and Minjung Kim</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Type-II $t−J$ model and shared superexchange coupling from Hund's rule in superconducting ${\mathrm{La}}_{3}{\mathrm{Ni}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{7}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.174511</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.174511"/>
        <updated>2023-11-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hanbit Oh and Ya-Hui Zhang
80 K superconductivity was recently observed in a La3Ni2O7 under pressure. A pressing challenge is to unravel the intriguing pairing mechanism within these materials. Here, the authors point out a novel role of Hund’s rule to transmit the superexchange coupling of the dz2 orbital to the dx2−y2 orbital, which is a key factor for understanding the remarkably high Tc. The transmitted Hund coupling makes the dx2−y2 orbital feel a large interlayer spin coupling but no interlayer hopping, a situation not explored before. Within one-orbital mean-field theory, the authors find robust s-wave pairing even at 50% hole doping. Moreover, they propose a new analytical framework, the so-called type-II t-J model, which they argue is the minimal model to incorporate all essential ingredients, including large Hund’s coupling and two orbital effects. This work offers a new model, develops a pioneering method, and identifies intriguing pairing mechanisms in the emerging nickelate field.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 174511] Published Tue Nov 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hanbit Oh and Ya-Hui Zhang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vortexability: A unifying criterion for ideal fractional Chern insulators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205144</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205144"/>
        <updated>2023-11-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Patrick J. Ledwith, Ashvin Vishwanath, and Daniel E. Parker
Fractional Chern insulators exhibit the fractional quantum Hall effect (FQHE) in crystalline systems, without the need for strong magnetic fields, resulting in charge fractionalization, long-range entanglement, and anyonic statistics, potentially at elevated energy scales. The lowest Landau level (LLL) hosts the FQHE, but high Landau levels and many Chern bands do not. Vortexable bands capture the essential physics of the LLL that leads to the FQHE without requiring its more fine-tuned properties, such as uniformity of Berry curvature and of charge density.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 205144] Published Tue Nov 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick J. Ledwith, Ashvin Vishwanath, and Daniel E. Parker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kondo temperature evaluated from linear conductance in magnetic fields]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205147</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205147"/>
        <updated>2023-11-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rui Sakano, Tokuro Hata, Kaiji Motoyama, Yoshimichi Teratani, Kazuhiko Tsutsumi, Akira Oguri, Tomonori Arakawa, Meydi Ferrier, Richard Deblock, Mikio Eto, and Kensuke Kobayashi
The authors develop here an efficient and reliable method to estimate the Kondo temperature by exploiting the universal scaling property inherent in the Kondo effect, observed in the magnetic field dependent conductance in quantum dots. By applying this method to experiments conducted on a carbon nanotube quantum dot, they obtain successfully a quantitatively reliable estimate of the Kondo temperature. The method holds great promise for advancing the exploration of local Fermi liquid properties within various modern systems.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 205147] Published Tue Nov 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rui Sakano, Tokuro Hata, Kaiji Motoyama, Yoshimichi Teratani, Kazuhiko Tsutsumi, Akira Oguri, Tomonori Arakawa, Meydi Ferrier, Richard Deblock, Mikio Eto, and Kensuke Kobayashi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Critical issues in statistical causal inference for observational physics education research]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.020160</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.020160"/>
        <updated>2023-11-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vidushi Adlakha and Eric Kuo
A starting point for researchers to learn more about the causal inference methods and analysis techniques that have been developed outside the field of PER.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 19, 020160] Published Mon Nov 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vidushi Adlakha and Eric Kuo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AlphaFold2 Can Predict Single-Mutation Effects]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.218401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.218401"/>
        <updated>2023-11-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): John M. McBride, Konstantin Polev, Amirbek Abdirasulov, Vladimir Reinharz, Bartosz A. Grzybowski, and Tsvi Tlusty
A new method based on AlphaFold2 improves the precision of single-mutation predictions for protein folding.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 218401] Published Mon Nov 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John M. McBride, Konstantin Polev, Amirbek Abdirasulov, Vladimir Reinharz, Bartosz A. Grzybowski, and Tsvi Tlusty</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[${\mathrm{K}}_{2}{\mathrm{Co}}_{2}{\mathrm{TeO}}_{6}$: A layered magnet with a $S=\frac{1}{2}\phantom{\rule{0.16em}{0ex}}{\mathrm{Co}}^{2+}$ honeycomb lattice]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.174432</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.174432"/>
        <updated>2023-11-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xianghan Xu, Lijun Wu, Yimei Zhu, and R. J. Cava
As a Kramers ion, Co2+ can function as an effective spin-half ion, exhibiting large quantum fluctuations that give rise to rich and intriguing magnetic behaviors. Here, the authors present the synthesis of sizable single crystals of K2Co2TeO6. The structural characterization reveals a layered structure with an undistorted Co2+ honeycomb lattice stacking together. Magnetization and thermodynamics data unveil intricate magnetic phases and competing interactions. These results establish a promising platform for exploring Kitaev interactions and discovering exotic quantum phases.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 174432] Published Mon Nov 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xianghan Xu, Lijun Wu, Yimei Zhu, and R. J. Cava</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shaking photons out of a topological material]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205142</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205142"/>
        <updated>2023-11-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mário G. Silveirinha
Nontrivial topological phases in electronic materials are often associated with the quantization of the Hall conductivity. Here, the author introduces a photonic analogue of this phenomenon. It is shown that the physical acceleration of a material can induce a photon flow in a direction perpendicular to the acceleration, analogous to the electronic Hall effect. For nonreciprocal materials, the response function linking the induced energy flow with the acceleration is quantized and is determined by the photonic gap Chern number.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 205142] Published Mon Nov 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mário G. Silveirinha</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep-learning-based radio-frequency side-channel attack on quantum key distribution]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.054040</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.054040"/>
        <updated>2023-11-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Adomas Baliuka, Markus Stöcker, Michael Auer, Peter Freiwang, Harald Weinfurter, and Lukas Knips
Quantum key distribution (QKD) is a technique that allows two distant parties to distribute and share a common secret, which then can be used as a cryptographic key. While mathematical proofs verify the security of perfectly implemented systems, imperfections in real devices allow attackers to retrieve information. This study uses machine-learning techniques to investigate information leakage via radio-frequency emissions of QKD device electronics. The approach allows researchers and engineers to harden devices against attacks.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 054040] Published Mon Nov 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adomas Baliuka, Markus Stöcker, Michael Auer, Peter Freiwang, Harald Weinfurter, and Lukas Knips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental analysis of image resolution of quantum imaging with undetected light through position correlations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.052610</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.052610"/>
        <updated>2023-11-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marta Gilaberte Basset, René Sondenheimer, Jorge Fuenzalida, Andres Vega, Sebastian Töpfer, Elkin A. Santos, Sina Saravi, Frank Setzpfandt, Fabian Steinlechner, and Markus Gräfe
The authors explore the resolution dependency of imaging with undetected light, specifically the connection between spatial resolution and the strength of position correlations of SPDC-generated photons. Their results show a discrepancy from theoretical models, so they introduce an extended model that better takes image resolution into account.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 052610] Published Mon Nov 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marta Gilaberte Basset, René Sondenheimer, Jorge Fuenzalida, Andres Vega, Sebastian Töpfer, Elkin A. Santos, Sina Saravi, Frank Setzpfandt, Fabian Steinlechner, and Markus Gräfe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canonical Hubble-Tension-Resolving Early Dark Energy Cosmologies Are Inconsistent with the Lyman-$α$ Forest]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.201001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.201001"/>
        <updated>2023-11-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Samuel Goldstein, J. Colin Hill, Vid Iršič, and Blake D. Sherwin
An early-Universe spike in dark energy could resolve a disagreement between two cosmic-expansion-rate measurements, but such a spike may conflict with observations of quasar spectra.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 201001] Published Fri Nov 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Goldstein, J. Colin Hill, Vid Iršič, and Blake D. Sherwin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perfect Resonant Absorption of Guided Water Waves by Autler-Townes Splitting]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.204002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.204002"/>
        <updated>2023-11-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): L.-P. Euvé, K. Pham, R. Porter, P. Petitjeans, V. Pagneux, and A. Maurel
Cavities at the sides of a water channel can cause waves to be completely absorbed, suggesting new techniques for protecting coastlines.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 204002] Published Fri Nov 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L.-P. Euvé, K. Pham, R. Porter, P. Petitjeans, V. Pagneux, and A. Maurel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hydrodynamical constraints on the bubble wall velocity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.103523</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.103523"/>
        <updated>2023-11-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tomasz Krajewski, Marek Lewicki, and Mateusz Zych
The authors use numerical lattice simulations to study bubble nucleation in cosmological phase transitions. The terminal bubble velocity is an important parameter for the primordial gravitational wave spectrum as well as for electroweak (EW) baryogenesis. They are able to study an extreme parameter space that is the most promising for these phenomena. However, they find a hydrodynamical obstruction that creates a velocity gap that excludes the most promising models for EW baryogenesis, making it improbable to contribute to the solution of the baryon asymmetry problem.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 103523] Published Fri Nov 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tomasz Krajewski, Marek Lewicki, and Mateusz Zych</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plasmon thermal conductivity of thin Au and Ag films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205418</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205418"/>
        <updated>2023-11-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dong-min Kim, Jeongmin Nam, and Bong Jae Lee
Recently, the thermal energy carried by surface waves along the boundaries of a thin film has drawn much attention. This work reports the measured plasmon thermal conductivity of novel metal films on a glass substrate with a Ti adhesive layer. When considering the size effect of the metal permittivity, a decrease of approximately 30% in plasmon thermal conductivity is observed. The authors demonstrate that the plasmon thermal conductivity of Au and Ag films can reach about 20% of their electron contribution.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 205418] Published Fri Nov 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dong-min Kim, Jeongmin Nam, and Bong Jae Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ultracold molecular collisions in magnetic fields: Efficient incorporation of hyperfine structure in the total rotational angular momentum representation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.053317</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.053317"/>
        <updated>2023-11-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Timur V. Tscherbul and Jose P. D'Incao
The authors explore an alternative basis set for incorporating the effects of hyperfine structure and external magnetic fields in quantum scattering calculations on ultracold molecular collisions. The basis set combines the computational efficiency of the total-angular-momentum basis with the ease of evaluating matrix elements pertinent to the fully uncoupled basis.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 053317] Published Fri Nov 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Timur V. Tscherbul and Jose P. D'Incao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[QCD Equation of State of Dense Nuclear Matter from a Bayesian Analysis of Heavy-Ion Collision Data]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.202303</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.202303"/>
        <updated>2023-11-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Manjunath Omana Kuttan, Jan Steinheimer, Kai Zhou, and Horst Stoecker
A Bayesian analysis of heavy-ion collisions at intermediate collision energies puts strong constraints on the equation of state at large chemical potential and zero temperature.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 202303] Published Thu Nov 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Manjunath Omana Kuttan, Jan Steinheimer, Kai Zhou, and Horst Stoecker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photon Pathways and the Nonperturbative Scaling Law of High Harmonic Generation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.203402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.203402"/>
        <updated>2023-11-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mekha Vimal, Martin Luttmann, Titouan Gadeyne, Matthieu Guer, Romain Cazali, David Bresteau, Fabien Lepetit, Olivier Tcherbakoff, Jean-François Hergott, Thierry Auguste, and Thierry Ruchon
A new interpretation of high-harmonic generation—the cornerstone of attosecond physics—paves the way for quantum applications of this process.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 203402] Published Thu Nov 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mekha Vimal, Martin Luttmann, Titouan Gadeyne, Matthieu Guer, Romain Cazali, David Bresteau, Fabien Lepetit, Olivier Tcherbakoff, Jean-François Hergott, Thierry Auguste, and Thierry Ruchon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Polycrystallinity Enhances Stress Buildup around Ice]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.208201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.208201"/>
        <updated>2023-11-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dominic Gerber, Lawrence A. Wilen, Eric R. Dufresne, and Robert W. Style
The unfrozen water-filled channels that crisscross multicrystal ice help feed ice growth, which can lead to fractures in materials such as asphalt and cement.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 208201] Published Thu Nov 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dominic Gerber, Lawrence A. Wilen, Eric R. Dufresne, and Robert W. Style</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Logarithmic profiles of velocity in stably stratified atmospheric boundary layers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.114602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.114602"/>
        <updated>2023-11-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yu Cheng, Andrey Grachev, and Chiel van Heerwaarden
In global weather and climate models, the turbulent exchange of momentum, heat, moisture and carbon dioxide between the Earth’s surface and the atmosphere is described by Monin-Obukhov similarity theory (MOST) since 1954. A fundamental assumption of MOST is that velocity near the surface does not follow a logarithmic profile due to buoyancy effects driven by stratification. In contrast to MOST, we find that buoyancy does not change the logarithmic nature of velocity profiles but instead modifies the slope of the log law. The proposed logarithmic profile can serve as an alternative to MOST, possibly leading to more realistic predictions of weather and climate, especially in polar regions.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 114602] Published Thu Nov 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yu Cheng, Andrey Grachev, and Chiel van Heerwaarden</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Single-file diffusion in spatially inhomogeneous systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.054125</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.054125"/>
        <updated>2023-11-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Benjamin Sorkin and David S. Dean
In single-file diffusion, particles in one dimension cannot cross each other due to a hard-core repulsion. For such a system with a periodically varying potential and diffusivity, the authors show that it has the same long-time behavior as Brownian particles in a spatially homogeneous system characterized by a known effective diffusion constant.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 054125] Published Thu Nov 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin Sorkin and David S. Dean</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Persistent Josephson tunneling between ${\mathrm{Bi}}_{2}{\mathrm{Sr}}_{2}{\mathrm{CaCu}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{8+x}$ flakes twisted by ${45}^{∘}$ across the superconducting dome]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.174508</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.174508"/>
        <updated>2023-11-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuying Zhu, Heng Wang, Zechao Wang, Shuxu Hu, Genda Gu, Jing Zhu, Ding Zhang, and Qi-Kun Xue
There is an on-going debate on the pairing symmetry – whether it is s-, d-, or d+id-wave – in twisted cuprates. Here, the authors obtain strong Josephson tunneling in 45∘-twisted cuprates with ultrahigh interfacial quality and precisely calibrated twist angles. The results firmly establish the existence of isotropic pairing in twisted cuprates, posing strong constraints on the theory considering a pure d wave or d+id wave. They also extend the study to the overdoped regime and observe the Josephson diode effect, promising next-generation high-temperature superconducting devices.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 174508] Published Thu Nov 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuying Zhu, Heng Wang, Zechao Wang, Shuxu Hu, Genda Gu, Jing Zhu, Ding Zhang, and Qi-Kun Xue</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tuning the confinement potential between spinons in the Ising chain compound ${\mathrm{CoNb}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{6}$ using longitudinal fields and quantitative determination of the microscopic Hamiltonian]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.184416</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.184416"/>
        <updated>2023-11-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Leonie Woodland, David Macdougal, Ivelisse M. Cabrera, Jordan D. Thompson, D. Prabhakaran, Robert I. Bewley, and Radu Coldea
The excitations on an Ising chain are domain walls (spinons), which can be confined into a Zeeman ladder of bound states by an applied magnetic field. Here, the authors report inelastic neutron scattering measurements of a quasi-one-dimensional Ising-like ferromagnet to probe the evolution of the spectrum with field, from weak confinement, where there are many closely spaced bound states, to strong confinement, where only two bound states remain. They also propose a model Hamiltonian that quantitatively reproduces all observed spectra.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 184416] Published Thu Nov 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leonie Woodland, David Macdougal, Ivelisse M. Cabrera, Jordan D. Thompson, D. Prabhakaran, Robert I. Bewley, and Radu Coldea</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tailoring hierarchical nanoporous gold on dual length scales]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.116001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.116001"/>
        <updated>2023-11-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lukas Riedel, Jürgen Markmann, Jörg Weissmüller, and Shan Shi
Researchers can fabricate gold foams that feature small and large pores with specific sizes.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 116001] Published Wed Nov 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lukas Riedel, Jürgen Markmann, Jörg Weissmüller, and Shan Shi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chemomechanical model of sperm locomotion reveals two modes of swimming]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.113102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.113102"/>
        <updated>2023-11-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chenji Li, Brato Chakrabarti, Pedro Castilla, Achal Mahajan, and David Saintillan
We present a chemomechanical model to analyze the propulsion of mammalian spermatozoa. The model accounts for motor kinetics, flagellar deformations, and the hydrodynamics of the suspending fluid. Simulations demonstrate spontaneous oscillations leading to realistic swimming patterns. Notably, the swimming velocity exhibits two distinct peaks as a function of the activity of the molecular motors. These peaks are characterized by distinct waveforms and trajectories. Our findings contribute to a deeper understanding of the biophysical mechanisms involved in sperm locomotion.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 113102] Published Wed Nov 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chenji Li, Brato Chakrabarti, Pedro Castilla, Achal Mahajan, and David Saintillan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deformation versus Sphericity in the Ground States of the Lightest Gold Isotopes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.202501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.202501"/>
        <updated>2023-11-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. G. Cubiss et al.
Charge radii of neutron-deficient gold isotopes measured with resonance-ionization laser spectroscopy display a unique pattern that has not been observed elsewhere in the nuclear chart.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 202501] Published Tue Nov 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. G. Cubiss &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trapping and Imaging Single Dysprosium Atoms in Optical Tweezer Arrays]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.203401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.203401"/>
        <updated>2023-11-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Damien Bloch, Britton Hofer, Sam R. Cohen, Antoine Browaeys, and Igor Ferrier-Barbut
Trapping and imaging single dysprosium atoms extends the utility of optical tweezer arrays to electronically complex species, opening the door to new quantum physics studies.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 203401] Published Tue Nov 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damien Bloch, Britton Hofer, Sam R. Cohen, Antoine Browaeys, and Igor Ferrier-Barbut</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Final results of Borexino on CNO solar neutrinos]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.102005</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.102005"/>
        <updated>2023-11-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. Basilico et al. (Borexino Collaboration)
Although only one percent or so of the sun’s luminosity comes from the Carbon-Nitrogen-Oxygen (CNO) reaction cycle, the Borexino Collaboration has managed to discriminate neutrinos arising from this process from the dominant pp cycle. In this new study, the collaboration uses a recently developed technique called the “correlated integrated directionality” (CID) method. This is an efficient way to separate solar neutrinos from background sources and further refine the detection of CNO cycle neutrinos through spectral analysis.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 102005] Published Tue Nov 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. Basilico &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (Borexino Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Role of isospin composition in low-energy nuclear fusion]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.L051602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.L051602"/>
        <updated>2023-11-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Richard Gumbel, Christian Ross, and A. S. Umar
Heavy-ion fusion is a major research area, and practical approaches to describe the evolution of the nucleon movement across the barrier between the two nuclei are highly relevant for elucidating the essential dynamics of the fusion process. When two nuclei approach each other to distances where the nuclear force becomes active, neutrons and protons could move from one nucleus to the other. This movement could open and facilitate the pathway to fusion. The authors employ a microscopic many-body approach based on the density-constrained time-dependent Hartree-Fock calculations to study the impact of isospin (i.e., proton versus neutron) dynamics on low-energy nuclear fusion along an isotope chain and its dependence on the deformation of the colliding nuclei. In asymmetric systems, iso-vector dynamics plays a significant role. Its typical effect is a reduction in the potential barrier, which turns into enhancement for neutron-rich systems. These effects could be studied at facilities that provide beams of exotic, unstable nuclei.

[Phys. Rev. C 108, L051602] Published Tue Nov 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Richard Gumbel, Christian Ross, and A. S. Umar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recent Gravitational Wave Observation by Pulsar Timing Arrays and Primordial Black Holes: The Importance of Non-Gaussianities]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.201401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.201401"/>
        <updated>2023-11-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gabriele Franciolini, Antonio Junior Iovino, Ville Vaskonen, and Hardi Veermäe
The balance between the abundance of primordial black holes and non-Gaussianities is reanalyzed in light of the recent NANOGrav data.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 201401] Published Mon Nov 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gabriele Franciolini, Antonio Junior Iovino, Ville Vaskonen, and Hardi Veermäe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generalized ray tracing for axions in astrophysical plasmas]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.103021</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.103021"/>
        <updated>2023-11-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. I. McDonald and S. J. Witte
The authors present a “ray-tracing” framework to compute radio emission associated with axion-photon conversion in the vicinity of magnetars. They show that future radio telescopes should be able to explore QCD axion parameter space, independently from a magnetar’s astrophysical model.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 103021] Published Mon Nov 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. I. McDonald and S. J. Witte</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[$X$-cube Floquet code: A dynamical quantum error correcting code with a subextensive number of logical qubits]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205116</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205116"/>
        <updated>2023-11-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zhehao Zhang, David Aasen, and Sagar Vijay
Using experimentally accessible two-body measurements, this work provides unique insights into constructing dynamical quantum error correcting codes with a subextensive number of qubits, and a nonzero error threshold.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 205116] Published Mon Nov 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhehao Zhang, David Aasen, and Sagar Vijay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Structure of quasiparticles in a local Fermi liquid]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205120</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205120"/>
        <updated>2023-11-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Izak Snyman
There are two distinct single-particle-like structures associated with dynamic fermionic quantum impurity systems. There are the quasiparticles that provide a description of low-energy excitations in terms of independent effective degrees of freedom. Then there is also the natural orbital basis, associated with the bare electronic degrees of freedom, which provides an economical description of ground-state correlations. This study employs natural orbitals to describe explicitly how bare electrons are dressed to form local Fermi liquid quasiparticles.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 205120] Published Mon Nov 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Izak Snyman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enhancing high harmonic generation in GaAs by elliptically polarized light excitation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205201"/>
        <updated>2023-11-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fumiya Sekiguchi, Minoru Sakamoto, Kotaro Nakagawa, Hirokazu Tahara, Shunsuke A. Sato, Hideki Hirori, and Yoshihiko Kanemitsu
High harmonic generation (HHG) in solids shows interesting behavior owing to their crystal structures. Here, the authors investigate a prominent example: HHG in GaAs can be enhanced by elliptically polarized light excitation. Remarkably, the enhancement is accompanied by emergent nonlinear optical activity, and it become salient only at particular “intermediate” excitation strengths. These results indicate that the key for HHG enhancement lies in the interference among nonlinear emission processes, revealing that not only material properties but optimal-strength excitations are important for controlling HHG properties via fine-tuning of the nonlinear dynamics.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 205201] Published Mon Nov 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fumiya Sekiguchi, Minoru Sakamoto, Kotaro Nakagawa, Hirokazu Tahara, Shunsuke A. Sato, Hideki Hirori, and Yoshihiko Kanemitsu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interplay between relaxational atomic fluctuations and charge density waves in ${\mathrm{La}}_{2−x}{\mathrm{Sr}}_{x}{\mathrm{CuO}}_{4}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L201111</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L201111"/>
        <updated>2023-11-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): L. Shen, V. Esposito, N. G. Burdet, M. Zhu, A. N. Petsch, T. P. Croft, S. P. Collins, Z. Ren, F. Westermeier, M. Sprung, S. M. Hayden, J. J. Turner, and E. Blackburn
The charge density wave (CDW) state is crucial for understanding high-temperature superconductivity in cuprates. How the CDW forms, however, is still debated. It does not have a well-defined thermodynamic phase transition, but is typically characterized by a temperature TCDW, below which spatial coherence begins to grow. Using x-ray photon correlation spectroscopy to study an archetypal cuprate, the authors show here that the atomic relaxation dynamics – an inherent, yet hardly explored property in the doped cuprates – is coupled to this change at TCDW.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L201111] Published Mon Nov 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L. Shen, V. Esposito, N. G. Burdet, M. Zhu, A. N. Petsch, T. P. Croft, S. P. Collins, Z. Ren, F. Westermeier, M. Sprung, S. M. Hayden, J. J. Turner, and E. Blackburn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Incorporating intrinsic compressibility effects in velocity transformations for wall-bounded turbulent flows]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L112601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L112601"/>
        <updated>2023-11-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Asif Manzoor Hasan, Johan Larsson, Sergio Pirozzoli, and Rene Pecnik
The law of the wall states that, after appropriate scaling, the mean velocity of incompressible turbulent flows near flat solid walls is a universal function of the wall-normal distance. An analogous law does not exist for compressible flows due to complexities arising from mean property variations and intrinsic compressibility effects, which occur when pressure directly changes the density of fluid elements. By accounting for both these effects, we propose a new velocity scaling that transforms the mean velocity of compressible flows to the incompressible law of the wall. This transformation is more accurate than the state-of-the-art, and is applicable to a wider range of flows.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, L112601] Published Thu Nov 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Asif Manzoor Hasan, Johan Larsson, Sergio Pirozzoli, and Rene Pecnik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Contribution of negative-energy states to the $E2\text{−}M1$ polarizability of optical clocks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.L051101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.L051101"/>
        <updated>2023-11-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fang-Fei Wu, Ting-Yun Shi, Wei-Tou Ni, and Li-Yan Tang
The authors theoretically investigate the impact of Dirac negative-energy states on the E2 and M1 polarizabilities in optical clocks. They demonstrate the importance of negative-energy states for the M1 polarizability and resolve the sign inconsistency between the theoretical calculations and experimental measurements in the E2-M1 polarizability difference of the Sr clock.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, L051101] Published Thu Nov 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fang-Fei Wu, Ting-Yun Shi, Wei-Tou Ni, and Li-Yan Tang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Contribution of negative-energy states to multipolar polarizabilities of the Sr optical lattice clock]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.L051102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.L051102"/>
        <updated>2023-11-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. G. Porsev, M. G. Kozlov, and M. S. Safronova
An accurate formula for the magnetic-dipole polarizability that takes into account both the positive- and negative-energy-state contributions is presented. The major discrepancy between the theory and experiment is explained.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, L051102] Published Thu Nov 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. G. Porsev, M. G. Kozlov, and M. S. Safronova</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantitative statistical analysis of order-splitting behavior of individual trading accounts in the Japanese stock market over nine years]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043131</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043131"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuki Sato and Kiyoshi Kanazawa
An analysis of data from the Tokyo Stock Exchange provides the first quantitative evidence for the Lillo-Mike-Farmer model—a long-standing theory in economics.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 043131] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuki Sato and Kiyoshi Kanazawa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oscillations and Cavity Modes in the Circular Hydraulic Jump]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.194001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.194001"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aurélien Goerlinger, Michael Baudoin, Farzam Zoueshtiagh, and Alexis Duchesne
A fluid phenomenon seen daily in kitchens has been found to exhibit unexpected behavior.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 194001] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aurélien Goerlinger, Michael Baudoin, Farzam Zoueshtiagh, and Alexis Duchesne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Acoustically Driven Magnon-Phonon Coupling in a Layered Antiferromagnet]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.196701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.196701"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Thomas P. Lyons, Jorge Puebla, Kei Yamamoto, Russell S. Deacon, Yunyoung Hwang, Koji Ishibashi, Sadamichi Maekawa, and Yoshichika Otani
The low oscillation frequency of spin waves in chromium trichloride enables researchers to explore this antiferromagnet’s rich properties with standard laboratory equipment.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 196701] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas P. Lyons, Jorge Puebla, Kei Yamamoto, Russell S. Deacon, Yunyoung Hwang, Koji Ishibashi, Sadamichi Maekawa, and Yoshichika Otani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inferring Microscopic Financial Information from the Long Memory in Market-Order Flow: A Quantitative Test of the Lillo-Mike-Farmer Model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.197401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.197401"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuki Sato and Kiyoshi Kanazawa
An analysis of data from the Tokyo Stock Exchange provides the first quantitative evidence for the Lillo-Mike-Farmer model—a long-standing theory in economics.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 197401] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuki Sato and Kiyoshi Kanazawa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crystal and magnetic structure of cesium superoxide]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.174412</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.174412"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. A. Ewings, M. Reehuis, F. Orlandi, P. Manuel, D. D. Khalyavin, A. S. Gibbs, A. D. Fortes, A. Hoser, A. J. Princep, and M. Jansen
Cesium superoxide is magnetic, due to the half-occupied π orbitals on its O2− molecules. Neutron diffraction experiments done here find that the crystal structure undergoes a sequence of transitions from tetragonal to incommensurate to orthorhombic, with the latter two exhibiting staggered displacements of the cesium ions. The symmetry of this structure permits antisymmetric exchange, which is consistent with a canted antiferromagnetic structure also observed, and a nice example of a structure-property relationship.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 174412] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. A. Ewings, M. Reehuis, F. Orlandi, P. Manuel, D. D. Khalyavin, A. S. Gibbs, A. D. Fortes, A. Hoser, A. J. Princep, and M. Jansen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kondo interaction of quantum spin Hall edge channels with charge puddles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205302"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christopher Fuchs, Saquib Shamim, Pragya Shekhar, Lena Fürst, Johannes Kleinlein, Jukka I. Väyrynen, Hartmut Buhmann, and Laurens W. Molenkamp
Since the first observation of the quantum spin Hall effect, it is known that the helical edge channel conductance exhibits fluctuations around the quantized value, in contrast to the (integer) quantum Hall effect. Here, the authors show, in a mechanistic study, that these fluctuations originate from spin-flip scattering mediated by charge puddles via a Kondo-type interaction, an effect which is expected to occur in any narrow-gap quantum spin Hall insulator.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 205302] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher Fuchs, Saquib Shamim, Pragya Shekhar, Lena Fürst, Johannes Kleinlein, Jukka I. Väyrynen, Hartmut Buhmann, and Laurens W. Molenkamp</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physically motivated analytical expression for the temperature dependence of the zero-field splitting of the nitrogen-vacancy center in diamond]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L180102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L180102"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. C. Cambria, G. Thiering, A. Norambuena, H. T. Dinani, A. Gardill, I. Kemeny, V. Lordi, Á. Gali, J. R. Maze, and S. Kolkowitz
The zero-field splitting (ZFS) of the nitrogen vacancy (NV) center in diamond’s ground-state electronic spin is temperature dependent, enabling nanoscale thermometry with NV centers. Here, the authors propose a simple, analytical expression that captures the measured ZFS over a wide range of temperatures. The authors explain the physical motivations for this expression and suggest that similar expressions may apply to other properties of the NV center, as well as to other solid-state spin systems.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L180102] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. C. Cambria, G. Thiering, A. Norambuena, H. T. Dinani, A. Gardill, I. Kemeny, V. Lordi, Á. Gali, J. R. Maze, and S. Kolkowitz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Structure and dynamics of a pinned vortex liquid in a superconducting $a\text{−}{\mathrm{Re}}_{6}\mathrm{Zr}$ thin film]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L180503</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L180503"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rishabh Duhan, Subhamita Sengupta, Ruchi Tomar, Somak Basistha, Vivas Bagwe, Chandan Dasgupta, and Pratap Raychaudhuri
Real space imaging using a scanning tunnelling microscope reveals the formation of an inhomogeneous vortex liquid state in few nanometer thick superconducting films that does not freeze into a crystal or a glass down to 0.41 K. Vortices in this two-dimensional liquid form a network of percolating paths, due to the combined effect of pinning and intervortex interaction. While some vortices remain static, others move on this network, with their relative fractions changing with magnetic field, temperature, and applied current.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L180503] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rishabh Duhan, Subhamita Sengupta, Ruchi Tomar, Somak Basistha, Vivas Bagwe, Chandan Dasgupta, and Pratap Raychaudhuri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimal qubit circuits for quantum-enhanced telescopes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.052408</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.052408"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Robert Czupryniak, John Steinmetz, Paul G. Kwiat, and Andrew N. Jordan
The authors propose two optimal phase-estimation schemes that can be used for quantum-enhanced long-baseline interferometry where distributed entanglement eliminates the loss of stellar photons during transmission over the baselines. The schemes can lead to a reduction of both the number of ancilla qubits and the number of gate operations by a factor of two.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 052408] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Czupryniak, John Steinmetz, Paul G. Kwiat, and Andrew N. Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phase-Driving Hole Spin Qubits]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.197001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.197001"/>
        <updated>2023-11-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Stefano Bosco, Simon Geyer, Leon C. Camenzind, Rafael S. Eggli, Andreas Fuhrer, Richard J. Warburton, Dominik M. Zumbühl, J. Carlos Egues, Andreas V. Kuhlmann, and Daniel Loss
A microwave pulse modulates the phase of a spin qubit, providing an alternative driving mechanism in quantum information processing.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 197001] Published Tue Nov 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stefano Bosco, Simon Geyer, Leon C. Camenzind, Rafael S. Eggli, Andreas Fuhrer, Richard J. Warburton, Dominik M. Zumbühl, J. Carlos Egues, Andreas V. Kuhlmann, and Daniel Loss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theoretical modeling of capillary surfer interactions on a vibrating fluid bath]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.114001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.114001"/>
        <updated>2023-11-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anand U. Oza, Giuseppe Pucci, Ian Ho, and Daniel M. Harris
“Capillary surfers” are small objects that self-propel while floating at the interface of a vibrating fluid bath. In this paper, we construct and analyze a theoretical model for the waves generated by such surfers and thus the hydrodynamic forces exerted by one surfer on another. Our model recovers the dynamical modes of surfer pairs found in experiments, and predicts that surfer collectives may lock into a variety of quantized bound states. Generally, our work shows that capillary surfers are a promising platform for studying wave-coupled active matter.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 114001] Published Tue Nov 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anand U. Oza, Giuseppe Pucci, Ian Ho, and Daniel M. Harris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capillary surfers: Wave-driven particles at a vibrating fluid interface]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L112001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L112001"/>
        <updated>2023-11-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ian Ho, Giuseppe Pucci, Anand U. Oza, and Daniel M. Harris
A small solid particle resting atop a vibrating fluid interface generates a field of outwardly propagating capillary waves due to its relative vertical motion. In this paper, we show that if the particle’s symmetry is broken, the resultant unbalanced wave stresses enable steady self-propulsion along the interface. Such “capillary surfers” interact with each other hydrodynamically at long range via their mutual wavefield and form a number of dynamic bound states. This new active system bridges the gap between dissipation- and inertia-dominated regimes and promises a number of novel collective behaviors.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, L112001] Published Tue Nov 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Ho, Giuseppe Pucci, Anand U. Oza, and Daniel M. Harris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flavored jets with exact anti-${k}_{t}$ kinematics and tests of infrared and collinear safety]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.094010</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.094010"/>
        <updated>2023-11-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fabrizio Caola, Radosław Grabarczyk, Maxwell L. Hutt, Gavin P. Salam, Ludovic Scyboz, and Jesse Thaler
A longstanding goal in collider analysis has been to assign flavor consistently to jets of final state particles which can then be associated with the initial partons coming from hard scattering processes. This paper presents “Interleaved Flavor Neutralization” to define jets with infrared- and collinear-safe (IRC safe) flavor and clustering properties similar to successful kinematic jet definitions. The authors carry out detailed checks to show the algorithm is IRC safe to at least sixth order in the strong coupling constant.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 094010] Published Mon Nov 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fabrizio Caola, Radosław Grabarczyk, Maxwell L. Hutt, Gavin P. Salam, Ludovic Scyboz, and Jesse Thaler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multipartite entanglement in the measurement-induced phase transition of the quantum Ising chain]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.184302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.184302"/>
        <updated>2023-11-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alessio Paviglianiti and Alessandro Silva
Quantum systems subject to external monitoring manifest a rich phenomenology in their entanglement properties. Here, the authors use quantum Fisher information to uncover a multipartite entanglement phase transition in the monitored quantum Ising chain. By changing the measurement rate, they observe a shift from bounded to long-range multipartiteness of quantum correlations. They show that the quantum Fisher information displays distinct behavior from the entanglement entropy, and the two outline different phase boundaries.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 184302] Published Mon Nov 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alessio Paviglianiti and Alessandro Silva</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>