<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-06-26T01:05:36.582Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-06-26T01:05:36.582Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of Nuclear Wave-Packet Interference in Ultrafast Interatomic Energy Transfer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.253202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.253202"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Meng Han, Jacqueline Fedyk, Jia-Bao Ji, Victor Despré, Alexander I. Kuleff, and Hans Jakob Wörner
Quantum interference in the nuclear dynamics driving interatomic excitation-energy transfer, also known as frustrated interatomic Coulombic decay, acts as an electronic-relaxation mechanism in many forms of matter, including clusters and liquids.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 253202] Published Fri Jun 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Meng Han, Jacqueline Fedyk, Jia-Bao Ji, Victor Despré, Alexander I. Kuleff, and Hans Jakob Wörner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interaction of a buoyant plume with a turbulent canopy mixing layer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.064501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.064501"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hayoon Chung and Jeffrey R. Koseff
Buoyant convective plumes have a strong impact on the behavior and spread of wildfires. This experimental study investigates the role of turbulent coherent structures rising from canopy mixing layers on the trajectory and behavior of buoyant plumes. The turbulent structures give rise to unsteady behavior of the buoyant plume that is observed as strong vertical oscillatory motions. This oscillatory motion is found to fluctuate at the dominant frequency of the canopy-induced instability. The analysis also looks at mixing and transport rates through the impacted plume.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 064501] Published Fri Jun 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hayoon Chung and Jeffrey R. Koseff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Infinite-randomness criticality in monitored quantum dynamics with static disorder]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L220204</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L220204"/>
        <updated>2023-06-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aidan Zabalo, Justin H. Wilson, Michael J. Gullans, Romain Vasseur, Sarang Gopalakrishnan, David A. Huse, and J. H. Pixley
The measurement-induced phase transition (MIPT) represents a critical point connected to quantum information and nonequilibrium statistical physics. However, any quantum code utilizing the MIPT can be affected by noise introduced in device fabrication, appearing as static disorder. Leveraging analytics and large-scale simulations, the authors show that this static noise destabilizes the MIPT towards an infinite-randomness critical point. Their findings reveal the Harris criterion’s applicability beyond equilibrium, indicating the relevance of perturbations at this phase transition.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L220204] Published Fri Jun 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aidan Zabalo, Justin H. Wilson, Michael J. Gullans, Romain Vasseur, Sarang Gopalakrishnan, David A. Huse, and J. H. Pixley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improved Limits on the Coupling of Ultralight Bosonic Dark Matter to Photons from Optical Atomic Clock Comparisons]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.253001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.253001"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Filzinger, S. Dörscher, R. Lange, J. Klose, M. Steinel, E. Benkler, E. Peik, C. Lisdat, and N. Huntemann
A search for oscillations in the frequencies of optical clocks has set new bounds on ultralight dark matter particles.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 253001] Published Thu Jun 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Filzinger, S. Dörscher, R. Lange, J. Klose, M. Steinel, E. Benkler, E. Peik, C. Lisdat, and N. Huntemann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multiversality and Unnecessary Criticality in One Dimension]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.256401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.256401"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Abhishodh Prakash, Michele Fava, and S. A. Parameswaran
Two new concepts, multiversality and unnecessary criticality, useful for the quantum field theoretic description of topological properties, have been demonstrated using one-dimensional quantum spin systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 256401] Published Thu Jun 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhishodh Prakash, Michele Fava, and S. A. Parameswaran</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin-Derived Electric Polarization and Chirality Density Inherent in Localized Electron Orbitals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.256801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.256801"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shintaro Hoshino, Michi-To Suzuki, and Hiroaki Ikeda
The relation between the spin current tensor, electric toroidal multipole, and chirality based on a relativistic quantum mechanical formalism, shows that the spin-derived polarization associated with the spin current tensor serves as a fundamental physical quantity that characterizes electric toroidal multipoles.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 256801] Published Thu Jun 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shintaro Hoshino, Michi-To Suzuki, and Hiroaki Ikeda</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giant Bulk Electrophotovoltaic Effect in Heteronodal-Line Systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.256902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.256902"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xiao Jiang, Lei Kang, Jianfeng Wang, and Bing Huang
First-principles model calculations predict a large tunable photovoltaic effect in electric-field-biased bilayers made of heteronodal-line systems, such as HSnN-MoS2 bilayers.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 256902] Published Thu Jun 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiao Jiang, Lei Kang, Jianfeng Wang, and Bing Huang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microscopic study of the hot-fusion reaction $^{48}\mathrm{Ca}+^{238}\mathrm{U}$ with the constraints from time-dependent Hartree-Fock theory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.064609</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.064609"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xiang-Xiang Sun (孙向向) and Lu Guo (郭璐)
The hot fusion reaction 48C + 238U is studied with time-dependent Hartree-Fock theory in combination with coupled-channels and fusion-by-diffusion models. The authors find that the fusion probability is strongly dependent on the orientation of the 238U nucleus, with the probability being greatest for the tip collision orientation. This understanding will be applied in the future to determine optimal target and projectile combinations for the synthesis of elements Z=119 and 120.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, 064609] Published Thu Jun 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiang-Xiang Sun (孙向向) and Lu Guo (郭璐)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Signatures of a topological phase transition in a planar Josephson junction]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.245304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.245304"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Banerjee, O. Lesser, M. A. Rahman, H.-R. Wang, M.-R. Li, A. Kringhøj, A. M. Whiticar, A. C. C. Drachmann, C. Thomas, T. Wang, M. J. Manfra, E. Berg, Y. Oreg, Ady Stern, and C. M. Marcus
Intense scrutiny over the last decade of experiments on a variety of platforms aiming to identify topological superconductivity has raised the stakes in this search. Because nontopological Andreev bound states at or near zero energy can resemble topological states, signatures beyond spectroscopy of zero-energy modes are called for. A key signature of a topological phase transition - namely, the closing and reopening of the superconducting gap - is mostly unobserved in previous experiments. Here, this phenomenon is reported in planar Josephson junction devices made from superconductor-semiconductor hybrid materials. Consistency between experiment and numerics, along with a number of other characteristic signatures, including dependence on phase, magnetic field, and chemical potential, support the conclusion that the observed gap closing and reopening, with associated appearance of a zero-bias conductance peaks upon reopening, are associated with topological transition.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 245304] Published Thu Jun 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Banerjee, O. Lesser, M. A. Rahman, H.-R. Wang, M.-R. Li, A. Kringhøj, A. M. Whiticar, A. C. C. Drachmann, C. Thomas, T. Wang, M. J. Manfra, E. Berg, Y. Oreg, Ady Stern, and C. M. Marcus</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[X-ray holography of skyrmionic cocoons in aperiodic magnetic multilayers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L220405</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L220405"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Grelier, F. Godel, A. Vecchiola, S. Collin, K. Bouzehouane, V. Cros, N. Reyren, R. Battistelli, H. Popescu, C. Léveillé, N. Jaouen, and F. Büttner
The development and characterization of three-dimensional topological magnetic textures has become an important topic in modern magnetism from both fundamental and technological perspectives. Here, the authors stabilize skyrmionic cocoons by engineering the properties of Pt/Co/Al based multilayers with variable Co thickness. These new textures can be observed in transmission with x-ray holography. Their coexistence with skyrmion tubes is particularly interesting as they can open new paths for three-dimensional spintronics.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L220405] Published Thu Jun 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Grelier, F. Godel, A. Vecchiola, S. Collin, K. Bouzehouane, V. Cros, N. Reyren, R. Battistelli, H. Popescu, C. Léveillé, N. Jaouen, and F. Büttner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thermal Hall conductivity near field-suppressed magnetic order in a Kitaev-Heisenberg model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L220406</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L220406"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aman Kumar and Vikram Tripathi
Historically, analytical treatments for the thermal Hall effect of many-body systems have been based around an underlying quasiparticle assumption. The authors introduce here a new purification-based tensor network method for the thermal Hall response of gapped systems, making no prior quasiparticle assumption. Motivated by reports of half-quantized thermal Hall response of Kitaev materials near field-suppressed magnetic order, the authors calculate the thermal Hall response in this parameter regime and find that it is large, but non-universal, ruling out the possibility of a revival of Ising topological order and a Majorana Hall state through this route.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L220406] Published Thu Jun 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aman Kumar and Vikram Tripathi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological Transformation with Emerging Zero Modes in Multistable Metamaterials for Reprogrammable Flexural Stiffness]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.L061001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.L061001"/>
        <updated>2023-06-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lei Wu and Damiano Pasini
In situ tuning of elastic stiffness enriches the range of functionalities of mechanical metamaterials for next-generation multifunctional devices. While stiffness tunability has been demonstrated under compression and tension, tuning flexural stiffness in multistable materials is now addressed in this work. Researchers leverage a multistable topological transformation induced by internal contact to activate zero-energy modes that yield both stiff and soft flexural modes. This remarkable tunability of flexural stiffness endows the architecture with a reversible rigid-flexible switch, which could support diverse applications from soft robotics to medical devices.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, L061001] Published Thu Jun 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lei Wu and Damiano Pasini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bounded-confidence model of opinion dynamics with heterogeneous node-activity levels]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.023179</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.023179"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Grace J. Li and Mason A. Porter
A bounded-confidence model of opinion dynamics on networks with node weights, which encode heterogeneous activity levels, is studied. The presence of heterogeneous node weights increases both opinion fragmentation and convergence times to steady state.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 023179] Published Wed Jun 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Grace J. Li and Mason A. Porter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hyperbolic Fringe Signal for Twin Impurity Quasiparticle Interference]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.256001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.256001"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Peize Ding, Tilman Schwemmer, Ching Hua Lee, Xianxin Wu, and Ronny Thomale
Depositing two adjacent atomic impurities on the surface of a superconductor produces hyperbolic interference fringes when probed with a scanning tunneling microscope that make it possible to extract previously inaccessible order parameter symmetry data.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 256001] Published Wed Jun 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peize Ding, Tilman Schwemmer, Ching Hua Lee, Xianxin Wu, and Ronny Thomale</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing Enhanced Electron-Phonon Coupling in Graphene by Infrared Resonance Raman Spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.256901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.256901"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tommaso Venanzi, Lorenzo Graziotto, Francesco Macheda, Simone Sotgiu, Taoufiq Ouaj, Elena Stellino, Claudia Fasolato, Paolo Postorino, Vaidotas Mišeikis, Marvin Metzelaars, Paul Kögerler, Bernd Beschoten, Camilla Coletti, Stefano Roddaro, Matteo Calandra, Michele Ortolani, Christoph Stampfer, Francesco Mauri, and Leonetta Baldassarre
A low-intensity Raman probe shows enhanced coupling between electrons and Brillouin zone boundary optical phonons in graphene near the Dirac point.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 256901] Published Wed Jun 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tommaso Venanzi, Lorenzo Graziotto, Francesco Macheda, Simone Sotgiu, Taoufiq Ouaj, Elena Stellino, Claudia Fasolato, Paolo Postorino, Vaidotas Mišeikis, Marvin Metzelaars, Paul Kögerler, Bernd Beschoten, Camilla Coletti, Stefano Roddaro, Matteo Calandra, Michele Ortolani, Christoph Stampfer, Francesco Mauri, and Leonetta Baldassarre</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bound for the moment generating function from the detailed fluctuation theorem]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.L062103</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.L062103"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Domingos S. P. Salazar
The author proves a theorem in nonequilibrium physics that is related to the second law of thermodynamics. The result is valid arbitrarily far from equilibrium and is quite general, with applications in stochastic and quantum thermodynamics.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, L062103] Published Wed Jun 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Domingos S. P. Salazar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Peculiar velocity effects on the Hubble constant from time-delay cosmography]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.123528</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.123528"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Charles Dalang, Martin Millon, and Tessa Baker
The paper studies the determination of the Hubble constant from time delays for a sample of strongly lensed quasars. It focuses on the impact of peculiar velocities and examines a possible relation between the tensions for Hubble constant and CMB dipole measurements.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 123528] Published Wed Jun 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charles Dalang, Martin Millon, and Tessa Baker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stochastic gravitational wave background reconstruction for a nonequilateral and unequal-noise LISA constellation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.123531</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.123531"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Olaf Hartwig, Marc Lilley, Martina Muratore, and Mauro Pieroni
This paper represents a major step in developing LISA Time Delay Interferometry (TDI) techniques to separate the Stochastic Gravitational Wave Signal from instrumental noise, and shows how different TDI variables can be critical in this respect.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 123531] Published Wed Jun 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Olaf Hartwig, Marc Lilley, Martina Muratore, and Mauro Pieroni</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neural network ansatz for periodic wave functions and the homogeneous electron gas]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.235139</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.235139"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Max Wilson, Saverio Moroni, Markus Holzmann, Nicholas Gao, Filip Wudarski, Tejs Vegge, and Arghya Bhowmik
The authors introduce here WAPNET, a periodic neural network (NN) variational ansatz for solving the ground state of a homogeneous electron gas with high accuracy over a broad range of the density coupling constant rs. Going beyond recent work for molecules, this contribution establishes NN models as flexible and powerful ansatz for electronic structure calculations in extended systems. In all density regimes, WAPNET-based variational Monte Carlo results are comparable to or better than state-of-the-art benchmarks obtained by diffusion Monte Carlo with iterative backflow.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 235139] Published Wed Jun 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Max Wilson, Saverio Moroni, Markus Holzmann, Nicholas Gao, Filip Wudarski, Tejs Vegge, and Arghya Bhowmik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[InAs-Al hybrid devices passing the topological gap protocol]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.245423</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.245423"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Morteza Aghaee et al. (Microsoft Quantum)
Topological phases of matter can enable highly stable qubits with small footprints, fast gate times, and digital control. These hardware-protected qubits must be fabricated with a material combination in which a topological phase can reliably be induced. The challenge: disorder can destroy the topological phase and obscure its detection. This paper reports on devices with low enough disorder to pass the topological gap protocol, thereby demonstrating gapped topological superconductivity and paving the way for a new stable qubit.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 245423] Published Wed Jun 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Morteza Aghaee &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (Microsoft Quantum)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blueprint for a Molecular-Spin Quantum Processor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.064060</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.064060"/>
        <updated>2023-06-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Chiesa, S. Roca, S. Chicco, M.C. de Ory, A. Gómez-León, A. Gomez, D. Zueco, F. Luis, and S. Carretta
The physical implementation of any quantum computer still faces important issues related to scalability and error correction. This study sets up the blueprint for a quantum processor based on molecular spins coupled to superconducting resonators, which control different qudits, read out their final states, and establish coherent communication channels between them. The feasibility of this route is demonstrated by an accurate design of the resonator to reach the strong-coupling regime between a single photon and a single molecule. Very good results for proof-of-principle quantum algorithms and quantum simulations are obtained by numerical simulations of a realistic experimental scenario.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 064060] Published Wed Jun 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Chiesa, S. Roca, S. Chicco, M.C. de Ory, A. Gómez-León, A. Gomez, D. Zueco, F. Luis, and S. Carretta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental Quantum Communication Overcomes the Rate-Loss Limit without Global Phase Tracking]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.250801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.250801"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lai Zhou, Jinping Lin, Yuan-Mei Xie, Yu-Shuo Lu, Yumang Jing, Hua-Lei Yin, and Zhiliang Yuan
A series of demonstrations considerably ease the requirements for implementing quantum cryptography protocols over large distances.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 250801] Published Tue Jun 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lai Zhou, Jinping Lin, Yuan-Mei Xie, Yu-Shuo Lu, Yumang Jing, Hua-Lei Yin, and Zhiliang Yuan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twin-Field Quantum Key Distribution without Phase Locking]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.250802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.250802"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wei Li, Likang Zhang, Yichen Lu, Zheng-Ping Li, Cong Jiang, Yang Liu, Jia Huang, Hao Li, Zhen Wang, Xiang-Bin Wang, Qiang Zhang, Lixing You, Feihu Xu, and Jian-Wei Pan
A series of demonstrations considerably ease the requirements for implementing quantum cryptography protocols over large distances.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 250802] Published Tue Jun 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wei Li, Likang Zhang, Yichen Lu, Zheng-Ping Li, Cong Jiang, Yang Liu, Jia Huang, Hao Li, Zhen Wang, Xiang-Bin Wang, Qiang Zhang, Lixing You, Feihu Xu, and Jian-Wei Pan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mechanism for giant enhancement of transport induced by active fluctuations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.064120</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.064120"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): K. Białas and J. Spiechowicz
Transport of a particle diffusing in a periodic potential can be greatly enhanced by active fluctuations. In this paper, the authors investigate the effect of different kinds of active noise and construct a simple model that provides additional insight.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, 064120] Published Tue Jun 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>K. Białas and J. Spiechowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetic ground state and perturbations of the distorted kagome Ising metal TmAgGe]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.224419</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.224419"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. B. Larsen, D. G. Mazzone, N. Gauthier, H. D. Rosales, F. A. Gómez Albarracín, J. Lass, X. Boraley, S. L. Bud'ko, P. C. Canfield, and O. Zaharko
Magnetic order and excitations of the distorted kagome intermetallic magnet TmAgGe are explored using a variety of methods, including single-crystal neutron diffraction, inelastic neutron scattering, Monte Carlo simulations, and the random phase approximation. The magnetic properties are governed by strong, local single-ion anisotropy and geometrically frustrated magnetic exchanges. The authors establish multi-k structures at several different magnetic field configurations and model effective exchange parameters using field-dependencies of the magnetic neutron diffraction reflections and the weakly dispersive crystal electric field mode.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 224419] Published Tue Jun 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. B. Larsen, D. G. Mazzone, N. Gauthier, H. D. Rosales, F. A. Gómez Albarracín, J. Lass, X. Boraley, S. L. Bud'ko, P. C. Canfield, and O. Zaharko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symmetry-conserving maximally projected Wannier functions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.235135</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.235135"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): K. Koepernik, O. Janson, Yan Sun, and J. van den Brink
Wannier functions are a powerful tool for the determination of topological properties of solids based on band structure calculations. Here, the authors present a simple and efficient scheme to obtain symmetry-conserving Wannier functions especially suitable for local orbital codes. They analyze which approximation of the basis contribution to the Berry connection and curvature matrices preserves symmetry and argue which Bloch function gauge is best suited for model systems, where the basis is not explicitly known.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 235135] Published Tue Jun 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>K. Koepernik, O. Janson, Yan Sun, and J. van den Brink</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological Andreev rectification]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.245422</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.245422"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pok Man Tam, Christophe De Beule, and Charles L. Kane
Quantized transport is a powerful probe of topological phases, and metals are topologically classified by the Euler characteristic of the Fermi sea. Here, the authors demonstrate analytically and numerically that a 2D metal proximitized by a Josephson π junction exhibits rectification for current along the junction. They introduce the rectified nonlocal conductance and show it is quantized by the Fermi sea topology. InAs-based heterostructures, as well as monolayer and bilayer graphene, are identified as promising platforms for demonstrating this effect.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 245422] Published Tue Jun 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pok Man Tam, Christophe De Beule, and Charles L. Kane</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dispersion tuning of nonlinear optical pulse dynamics in gas-filled hollow capillary fibers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.063512</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.063512"/>
        <updated>2023-06-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Teodora Grigorova, Christian Brahms, Federico Belli, and John C. Travers
Gas-filled hollow capillary fibers can be used for continuum generation and pulse compression. Here, the authors change the gas pressure inside hollow capillary fibers and investigate how ultrashort laser pulses propagating through the fibers respond to these changes. The use of short pulses and a long capillary fiber enables the authors to survey a much wider range of dynamics than previously observed.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 063512] Published Tue Jun 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Teodora Grigorova, Christian Brahms, Federico Belli, and John C. Travers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Swirling Fluid Reduces the Bounce of Partially Filled Containers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.244001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.244001"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Klebbert Andrade, Javiera Catalán, Juan F. Marín, Vicente Salinas, Gustavo Castillo, Leonardo Gordillo, and Pablo Gutiérrez
Dropping a rotating plastic bottle containing water results in a bounce whose height depends on the rotation rate.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 244001] Published Fri Jun 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Klebbert Andrade, Javiera Catalán, Juan F. Marín, Vicente Salinas, Gustavo Castillo, Leonardo Gordillo, and Pablo Gutiérrez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reconnection-Powered Fast Radio Transients from Coalescing Neutron Star Binaries]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.245201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.245201"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Elias R. Most and Alexander A. Philippov
Warning of the catastrophic collapse of a neutron star could come in the form of potentially detectable radio bursts in the 10–20 gigahertz range.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 245201] Published Fri Jun 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elias R. Most and Alexander A. Philippov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exotic tetraquark states with two $\overline{b}$ quarks and ${J}^{P}={0}^{+}$ and ${1}^{+}$ ${B}_{s}$ states in a nonperturbatively tuned lattice NRQCD setup]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.114510</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.114510"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. J. Hudspith and D. Mohler
The authors use six splittings between bottomonium levels to nonperturbatively tune an NRQCD action on four gauge field ensembles. They then use the tuned action for the b antiquarks in their study of the binding energies of exotic tetraquark states with two b antiquarks, achieving a roughly 10% precision in the computed binding energies.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 114510] Published Fri Jun 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. J. Hudspith and D. Mohler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effect of the N3LO three-nucleon contact interaction on $p\text{−}d$ scattering observables]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.L061001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.L061001"/>
        <updated>2023-06-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): L. Girlanda, E. Filandri, A. Kievsky, L. E. Marcucci, and M. Viviani
Chiral effective field theory allows one to express nuclear physics observables in terms of low-energy constants (LECs), representing physics at unresolved scales. In this work the authors focus on the two-nucleon contact interaction at fourth order (N3LO) and use a unitary transformation to reduce the number of involved LECs. This procedure induces a three-nucleon (3N) interaction depending on five unconstrained LECs. Those can be used, in association with a two-nucleon (2N) interaction, to fit very accurate data on polarization observables at low energies, in particular the p-d Ay polarization asymmetry. Thereby, adjusting the induced 3N N3LO LECs can solve the long-standing Ay puzzle.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, L061001] Published Fri Jun 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L. Girlanda, E. Filandri, A. Kievsky, L. E. Marcucci, and M. Viviani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Culinary fluid mechanics and other currents in food science]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/RevModPhys.95.025004</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/RevModPhys.95.025004"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Arnold J. T. M. Mathijssen, Maciej Lisicki, Vivek N. Prakash, and Endre J. L. Mossige
This review describes recent scientific advances in the context of the culinary arts. It is written as a menu, starting with the physics of drinks, followed by the main course, and ending with complex desserts. Recent discoveries are reviewed, particularly in fluid mechanics and soft matter physics, and their relevance to food science is highlighted. Many phenomena like the Cheerios effect, coffee-ring effect, Brazil nut effect, Leidenfrost effect, and Marangoni effect are described and illustrated by epicurean examples.

[Rev. Mod. Phys. 95, 025004] Published Thu Jun 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Arnold J. T. M. Mathijssen, Maciej Lisicki, Vivek N. Prakash, and Endre J. L. Mossige</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing Accretion Physics with Gravitational Waves]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.021035</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.021035"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lorenzo Speri, Andrea Antonelli, Laura Sberna, Stanislav Babak, Enrico Barausse, Jonathan R. Gair, and Michael L. Katz
Future space-based gravitational-wave detectors could probe the physics of accretion disks surrounding massive black holes.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 021035] Published Thu Jun 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lorenzo Speri, Andrea Antonelli, Laura Sberna, Stanislav Babak, Enrico Barausse, Jonathan R. Gair, and Michael L. Katz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Control of Metastable States by Heat Flux in the Hamiltonian Potts Model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.247102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.247102"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Michikazu Kobayashi, Naoko Nakagawa, and Shin-ichi Sasa
Numerical simulations of the Hamiltonian Potts model show that metastable states in equilibrium are controlled by a weak heat flux.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 247102] Published Thu Jun 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michikazu Kobayashi, Naoko Nakagawa, and Shin-ichi Sasa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Role of alkaline metal in the rare-earth triangular antiferromagnet ${\mathrm{KYbO}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.224416</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.224416"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Franziska Grußler, Mamoun Hemmida, Sebastian Bachus, Yurii Skourski, Hans-Albrecht Krug von Nidda, Philipp Gegenwart, and Alexander A. Tsirlin
Spin-liquid materials can be tailored by chemical substitutions. Here, the authors use thermodynamic measurements and electron spin resonance to show that replacing Na by K in triangular magnets of the AYbO2 family weakens the magnetic couplings and renders the Yb3+ ion more isotropic. They map out the temperature-field phase diagram and demonstrate that the field-induced plateau phase corresponds to 1/2 of the saturated magnetization.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 224416] Published Thu Jun 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Franziska Grußler, Mamoun Hemmida, Sebastian Bachus, Yurii Skourski, Hans-Albrecht Krug von Nidda, Philipp Gegenwart, and Alexander A. Tsirlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Energy deposition studies for the LHCb insertion region of the CERN Large Hadron Collider]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.061002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.061002"/>
        <updated>2023-06-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alessia Ciccotelli, Robert B. Appleby, Francesco Cerutti, Kacper Bilko, Luigi Salvatore Esposito, Ruben Garcia Alia, Anton Lechner, and Andrea Tsinganis
A detailed model of an LHC experimental region predicts the energy deposition from proton-proton collisions.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 26, 061002] Published Thu Jun 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alessia Ciccotelli, Robert B. Appleby, Francesco Cerutti, Kacper Bilko, Luigi Salvatore Esposito, Ruben Garcia Alia, Anton Lechner, and Andrea Tsinganis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamics of all-optical single-shot switching of magnetization in Tb/Co multilayers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.023163</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.023163"/>
        <updated>2023-06-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): K. Mishra, T. G. H. Blank, C. S. Davies, L. Avilés-Félix, D. Salomoni, L. D. Buda-Prejbeanu, R. C. Sousa, I. L. Prejbeanu, B. Koopmans, Th. Rasing, A. V. Kimel, and A. Kirilyuk
The spatial and temporal dynamics of laser-induced single-shot magnetization switching are studied for various compositions of Tb/Co multilayers to understand the underlying mechanism. This is shown to be drastically different from the ones in Tb-Co alloys as well as in the previously studied toggle-switching Gd-containing ferrimagnets.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 023163] Published Wed Jun 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>K. Mishra, T. G. H. Blank, C. S. Davies, L. Avilés-Félix, D. Salomoni, L. D. Buda-Prejbeanu, R. C. Sousa, I. L. Prejbeanu, B. Koopmans, Th. Rasing, A. V. Kimel, and A. Kirilyuk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Structure and equation of state of ${\mathrm{Bi}}_{2}{\mathrm{Sr}}_{2}{\mathrm{Ca}}_{n−1}{\mathrm{Cu}}_{n}{\mathrm{O}}_{2n+4+δ}$ from x-ray diffraction to megabar pressures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.064803</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.064803"/>
        <updated>2023-06-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexander C. Mark, Muhtar Ahart, Ravhi Kumar, Changyong Park, Yue Meng, Dmitry Popov, Liangzi Deng, Ching-Wu Chu, Juan Carlos Campuzano, and Russell J. Hemley
Experiments on a family of cuprate superconductors resolve discrepancies in previous work and elucidate why the critical temperature varies with pressure.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 064803] Published Wed Jun 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexander C. Mark, Muhtar Ahart, Ravhi Kumar, Changyong Park, Yue Meng, Dmitry Popov, Liangzi Deng, Ching-Wu Chu, Juan Carlos Campuzano, and Russell J. Hemley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetism and quantum melting in moiré-material Wigner crystals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.235131</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.235131"/>
        <updated>2023-06-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nicolás Morales-Durán, Pawel Potasz, and Allan H. MacDonald
Semiconductor moiré materials host generalized Wigner crystal states at a series of fractional fillings, originating from localization of electrons in a subset of moiré sites in order to minimize long-range Coulomb interactions. Using exact diagonalization calculations, this paper studies the interplay between spin and charge degrees of freedom that gives rise to different magnetic orders within the crystalline states at fillings ν=1/3 and ν=2/3. The authors provide effective spin model descriptions of those phases, also addressing their Mott-Wigner melting transitions.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 235131] Published Wed Jun 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicolás Morales-Durán, Pawel Potasz, and Allan H. MacDonald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Significant phonon drag effect in wide band gap GaN and AlN]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.245202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.245202"/>
        <updated>2023-06-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yujie Quan, Yubi Chen, and Bolin Liao
Understanding the electrical and thermal transport properties of group-III nitride semiconductors is crucial for their electronic and thermoelectric applications. This study investigates the impact of the phonon drag effect, which refers to the momentum exchange between nonequilibrium phonons and electrons, on electronic transport in GaN and AlN. Results show that, even at room temperature, phonon drag significantly enhances mobility and the Seebeck coefficient. The study delves into the specific mechanisms for this.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 245202] Published Wed Jun 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yujie Quan, Yubi Chen, and Bolin Liao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electrically driven photon statistics engineering in quantum-dot circuit quantum electrodynamics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L241405</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L241405"/>
        <updated>2023-06-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lei-Lei Nian, Bo Zheng, and Jing-Tao Lü
Quantum-dot circuit quantum electrodynamics (QD-cQED) has enabled the probe and control of light-matter interaction at the elementary level, with the demonstration of nonclassical photon sources driven by inelastic electron tunneling. Due to the absence of the photon blockade mechanism, an general scheme for photon statistics engineering in QD-cQED is lacking. Based on current-driven joint interference effect, the authors propose here an all-electrical scheme to achieve arbitrary photon statistics with classical or quantum correlation by simply controlling bias voltage.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L241405] Published Wed Jun 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lei-Lei Nian, Bo Zheng, and Jing-Tao Lü</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How women physics teacher candidates utilize their double outsider identities to productively learn physics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.010140</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.010140"/>
        <updated>2023-06-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Johanna Larsson and Anna T. Danielsson
It is important for women physics teacher candidates to have the option to participate in physics without needing to adopt physics norms associated with nerdiness.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 19, 010140] Published Tue Jun 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Johanna Larsson and Anna T. Danielsson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsecond Isomer at the $N=20$ Island of Shape Inversion Observed at FRIB]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.242501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.242501"/>
        <updated>2023-06-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. J. Gray et al.
Researchers may have found an unstable sodium nucleus that has an excited state with a spherical wave function—an elusive prospect for the study of nuclear shapes.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 242501] Published Tue Jun 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. J. Gray &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interacting models for twisted bilayer graphene: A quantum chemistry approach]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.235123</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.235123"/>
        <updated>2023-06-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fabian M. Faulstich, Kevin D. Stubbs, Qinyi Zhu, Tomohiro Soejima, Rohit Dilip, Huanchen Zhai, Raehyun Kim, Michael P. Zaletel, Garnet Kin-Lic Chan, and Lin Lin
Twisted bilayer graphene (TBG) has garnered significant interest in condensed matter physics over the past few years. Here, the authors present numerical investigations of TBG implementing state-of-the-art quantum chemistry methods. Using a gauge-invariant order parameter, they show a C2z𝒯 phase transition at charge neutrality which persists at noninteger fillings near charge neutrality. The work is the first systematic study of TBG for noninteger fillings near charge neutrality.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 235123] Published Tue Jun 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fabian M. Faulstich, Kevin D. Stubbs, Qinyi Zhu, Tomohiro Soejima, Rohit Dilip, Huanchen Zhai, Raehyun Kim, Michael P. Zaletel, Garnet Kin-Lic Chan, and Lin Lin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Independent and coherent transitions between antiferromagnetic states of few-molecule systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.245414</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.245414"/>
        <updated>2023-06-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Claire Besson, Philipp Stegmann, Michael Schnee, Zeila Zanolli, Simona Achilli, Nils Wittemeier, Asmus Vierck, Robert Frielinghaus, Paul Kögerler, Janina Maultzsch, Pablo Ordejón, Claus M. Schneider, Alfred Hucht, Jürgen König, and Carola Meyer
Molecular spintronics is usually based on paramagnetic or ferromagnetic (S ≠ 0) species. Here, the authors study small ensembles of two molecular antiferromagnets, {Mn4} and {Co4}, bound to carbon nanotube quantum dots. The current through the quantum dots shows a random telegraph signal caused by transitions between nondegenerate Stot = 0 states of individual molecular antiferromagnets. Statistical analysis shows that transitions between those states are independent in the case of {Co4} ensembles, while {Mn4} ensembles display long-lived coherent superposition involving multiple complexes.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 245414] Published Tue Jun 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Besson, Philipp Stegmann, Michael Schnee, Zeila Zanolli, Simona Achilli, Nils Wittemeier, Asmus Vierck, Robert Frielinghaus, Paul Kögerler, Janina Maultzsch, Pablo Ordejón, Claus M. Schneider, Alfred Hucht, Jürgen König, and Carola Meyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum Oscillations in Graphene Using Surface Acoustic Wave Resonators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.246201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.246201"/>
        <updated>2023-06-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yawen Fang, Yang Xu, Kaifei Kang, Benyamin Davaji, Kenji Watanabe, Takashi Taniguchi, Amit Lal, Kin Fai Mak, Jie Shan, and B. J. Ramshaw
High quality factor surface acoustic wave resonators can be optimized to measure quantum transport in graphene at low temperatures and high magnetic fields.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 246201] Published Mon Jun 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yawen Fang, Yang Xu, Kaifei Kang, Benyamin Davaji, Kenji Watanabe, Takashi Taniguchi, Amit Lal, Kin Fai Mak, Jie Shan, and B. J. Ramshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biphasic Chemokinesis of Mammalian Sperm]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.248401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.248401"/>
        <updated>2023-06-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Meisam Zaferani and Alireza Abbaspourrad
Mammalian sperm adopt a complex stochastic navigation strategy that depends on the local environment’s chemical conditions and rheological properties.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 248401] Published Mon Jun 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Meisam Zaferani and Alireza Abbaspourrad</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Large upper critical fields and dimensionality crossover of superconductivity in the infinite-layer nickelate ${\mathrm{La}}_{0.8}{\mathrm{Sr}}_{0.2}{\mathrm{NiO}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L220503</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L220503"/>
        <updated>2023-06-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wei Wei, Wenjie Sun, Yue Sun, Yongqiang Pan, Gangjian Jin, Feng Yang, Yueying Li, Zengwei Zhu, Yuefeng Nie, and Zhixiang Shi
The recent discovery of superconductivity in nickelates, sharing structural and electronic similarities with cuprates, is crucial for understanding the high-Tc superconducting pairing mechanism. Here, the authors study the Hc2 of a high-quality La0.8Sr0.2NiO2 thin film. Significantly large Hc2 (∼ 40 T for H || c and ∼ 52 T for H || ab) are obtained. The anisotropy decreases from ∼10 near Tc to ∼1.5 at 2 K, which confirms a crossover from 2D to 3D superconductivity based on the angle dependence of Hc2.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L220503] Published Mon Jun 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wei Wei, Wenjie Sun, Yue Sun, Yongqiang Pan, Gangjian Jin, Feng Yang, Yueying Li, Zengwei Zhu, Yuefeng Nie, and Zhixiang Shi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phase transitions and spin state of iron in FeO under the conditions of Earth's deep interior]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L241103</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L241103"/>
        <updated>2023-06-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): E. Greenberg, R. Nazarov, A. Landa, J. Ying, R. Q. Hood, B. Hen, R. Jeanloz, V. B. Prakapenka, V. V. Struzhkin, G. Kh. Rozenberg, and I. V. Leonov
Iron oxide (FexO) serves as a model constituent of Earth-like planetary interiors, reflecting the distinctive high-pressure chemistry of their cores and rocky mantles. Under pressure it undergoes crystal structural transitions and metallization, accompanied by a local-moment collapse of Fe ions. Here, the experiments and theoretical calculations characterize the complex interplay between electron states and structural phases, resulting in a rich phase diagram and revealing the existence of a metallic high-spin state of iron at the conditions near those of Earth’s core-mantle boundary.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L241103] Published Mon Jun 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>E. Greenberg, R. Nazarov, A. Landa, J. Ying, R. Q. Hood, B. Hen, R. Jeanloz, V. B. Prakapenka, V. V. Struzhkin, G. Kh. Rozenberg, and I. V. Leonov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental Realization of a Three-Dimensional Dirac Semimetal Phase with a Tunable Lifshitz Transition in ${\mathrm{Au}}_{2}\mathrm{Pb}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.236402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.236402"/>
        <updated>2023-06-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Sánchez-Barriga, O. J. Clark, M. G. Vergniory, M. Krivenkov, A. Varykhalov, O. Rader, and L. M. Schoop
Experimental evidence for the existence of three-dimensional Dirac fermions in Au2Pb confirms a theoretically predicted Dirac semimetal phase with a fourfold degenerate Dirac crossing protected by rotational lattice symmetry.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 236402] Published Fri Jun 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Sánchez-Barriga, O. J. Clark, M. G. Vergniory, M. Krivenkov, A. Varykhalov, O. Rader, and L. M. Schoop</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Power-Law Density of States in Organic Solar Cells Revealed by the Open-Circuit Voltage Dependence of the Ideality Factor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.236403</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.236403"/>
        <updated>2023-06-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maria Saladina, Christopher Wöpke, Clemens Göhler, Ivan Ramirez, Olga Gerdes, Chao Liu, Ning Li, Thomas Heumüller, Christoph J. Brabec, Karsten Walzer, Martin Pfeiffer, and Carsten Deibel
The density of states in organic disordered semiconductors is shown to follow a power-law distribution over a broad range of energies.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 236403] Published Fri Jun 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maria Saladina, Christopher Wöpke, Clemens Göhler, Ivan Ramirez, Olga Gerdes, Chao Liu, Ning Li, Thomas Heumüller, Christoph J. Brabec, Karsten Walzer, Martin Pfeiffer, and Carsten Deibel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rectified Rotational Dynamics of Mobile Inclusions in Two-Dimensional Active Nematics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.238301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.238301"/>
        <updated>2023-06-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sattvic Ray, Jie Zhang, and Zvonimir Dogic
The chaotic motion in a fluid of microscopic, actively moving rods can be harnessed to drive the rotation of a small propeller-like object.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 238301] Published Fri Jun 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sattvic Ray, Jie Zhang, and Zvonimir Dogic</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin-motion coupling in a circular-Rydberg-state quantum simulator: Case of two atoms]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.063106</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.063106"/>
        <updated>2023-06-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Paul Méhaignerie, Clément Sayrin, Jean-Michel Raimond, Michel Brune, and Guillaume Roux
The authors study the interplay between the spin exchange and motional dynamics in the case of two interacting circular Rydberg atoms confined in harmonic traps. The results unveil new physics emerging from the long time scale in the proposal of an XXZ spin-array simulator based on chains of trapped circular atoms.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 063106] Published Fri Jun 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Méhaignerie, Clément Sayrin, Jean-Michel Raimond, Michel Brune, and Guillaume Roux</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elastic Snap-Through Instabilities Are Governed by Geometric Symmetries]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.236102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.236102"/>
        <updated>2023-06-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Basile Radisson and Eva Kanso
Elastic shape transitions can be predicted from geometric symmetries and symmetry-breaking mechanisms, providing universal design rules for these transitions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 236102] Published Thu Jun 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Basile Radisson and Eva Kanso</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental mitigation of large-amplitude transverse gusts via closed-loop pitch control]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.064701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.064701"/>
        <updated>2023-06-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Girguis Sedky, Antonios Gementzopoulos, Francis D. Lagor, and Anya R. Jones
In this work, we experimentally demonstrate the utility of unsteady potential flow models in developing closed-loop control strategies for mitigating the lift transients on a wing experiencing large-amplitude transverse gusts. The developed closed-loop controller mitigates lift for gusts of various strengths and directions and for wings with pre- and post-stall angles of attack. Time-resolved force and flow field measurements are used to discover the salient flow physics during these encounters and illustrate how closed-loop actuation mitigates their lift transients.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 064701] Published Thu Jun 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Girguis Sedky, Antonios Gementzopoulos, Francis D. Lagor, and Anya R. Jones</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How roughness and thermal properties of a solid substrate determine the Leidenfrost temperature: Experiments and a model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L061601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L061601"/>
        <updated>2023-06-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuki Wakata, Ning Zhu, Xiaoliang Chen, Sijia Lyu, Detlef Lohse, Xing Chao, and Chao Sun
Understanding and regulating the Leidenfrost temperature is of great importance for practical applications such as spray cooling. In this study, nonnegligible cooling effects of Leidenfrost drops on surfaces with small thermal diffusivities are observed with an IR camera. The influence of thermal properties and surface roughness on the Leidenfrost temperature is investigated experimentally and explained by a simple theoretical model.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, L061601] Published Thu Jun 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuki Wakata, Ning Zhu, Xiaoliang Chen, Sijia Lyu, Detlef Lohse, Xing Chao, and Chao Sun</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stochasticity of cosmic rays from supernova remnants and the ionization rates in molecular clouds]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.123006</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.123006"/>
        <updated>2023-06-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vo Hong Minh Phan, Sarah Recchia, Philipp Mertsch, and Stefano Gabici
This paper demonstrates that a stochastic, rather than uniform, injection rate of MeV cosmic rays from supernovae can successfully model the observed ionization rate distribution for Galactic molecular clouds.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 123006] Published Thu Jun 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vo Hong Minh Phan, Sarah Recchia, Philipp Mertsch, and Stefano Gabici</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rapidity and momentum distributions of one-dimensional dipolar quantum gases]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.L061302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.L061302"/>
        <updated>2023-06-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kuan-Yu Li, Yicheng Zhang, Kangning Yang, Kuan-Yu Lin, Sarang Gopalakrishnan, Marcos Rigol, and Benjamin L. Lev
The effects of integrability-breaking interactions on equilibrium states are explored using a one-dimensional Bose gas of highly magnetic atoms. A dressed-quasiparticle description is found to be necessary to predict equilibrium rapidity and momentum distributions as the strength of the integrability-breaking perturbation increases.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, L061302] Published Thu Jun 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kuan-Yu Li, Yicheng Zhang, Kangning Yang, Kuan-Yu Lin, Sarang Gopalakrishnan, Marcos Rigol, and Benjamin L. Lev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Locating the Source of Forced Oscillations in Transmission Power Grids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXEnergy.2.023009</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXEnergy.2.023009"/>
        <updated>2023-06-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Robin Delabays, Andrey Y. Lokhov, Melvyn Tyloo, and Marc Vuffray
A fully data-driven method solves an outstanding challenge in power grids, inferring the correct source and frequency of forced oscillations that pose significant risks to critical infrastructures.

[PRX Energy 2, 023009] Published Wed Jun 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robin Delabays, Andrey Y. Lokhov, Melvyn Tyloo, and Marc Vuffray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[${\mathrm{YbV}}_{3}{\mathrm{Sb}}_{4}$ and ${\mathrm{EuV}}_{3}{\mathrm{Sb}}_{4}$ vanadium-based kagome metals with ${\mathrm{Yb}}^{2+}$ and ${\mathrm{Eu}}^{2+}$ zigzag chains]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.064201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.064201"/>
        <updated>2023-06-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Brenden R. Ortiz, Ganesh Pokharel, Malia Gundayao, Hong Li, Farnaz Kaboudvand, Linus Kautzsch, Suchismita Sarker, Jacob P. C. Ruff, Tom Hogan, Steven J. Gomez Alvarado, Paul M. Sarte, Guang Wu, Tara Braden, Ram Seshadri, Eric S. Toberer, Ilija Zeljkovic, and Stephen D. Wilson
Motivated in part by the success of the AV3Sb5 kagome superconductors, ongoing efforts to explore new kagome metals have led to the discovery of a range of materials exhibiting unique magnetic and electronic properties. In this study, the authors present novel vanadium-based kagome antimonides that incorporate the chemical flexibility of a rare-earth site, allowing for the intertwining of magnetic and charge degrees of freedom. These new compounds, namely EuV3Sb4 and YbV3Sb4, provide valuable insights into the relatively small LnM3X4 family and open up potential avenues for the realization of additional rare-earth, antimonide-based kagome metals.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 064201] Published Wed Jun 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brenden R. Ortiz, Ganesh Pokharel, Malia Gundayao, Hong Li, Farnaz Kaboudvand, Linus Kautzsch, Suchismita Sarker, Jacob P. C. Ruff, Tom Hogan, Steven J. Gomez Alvarado, Paul M. Sarte, Guang Wu, Tara Braden, Ram Seshadri, Eric S. Toberer, Ilija Zeljkovic, and Stephen D. Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accuracy of DFT computed oxygen-vacancy formation energies and high-throughput search of solar thermochemical water-splitting compounds]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.065403</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.065403"/>
        <updated>2023-06-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bianca Baldassarri, Jiangang He, Xin Qian, Emanuela Mastronardo, Sean Griesemer, Sossina M. Haile, and Christopher Wolverton
The computation of the oxygen vacancy formation energy using density functional theory is a critical factor in applications like solar thermochemical hydrogen production. However, when we calculate it using structures that are dynamically unstable, results in artificially reduced values and lack of convergence with cell size. By comparing the calculated values with experimental data, the authors can clearly see the importance of using dynamically stable structures for accurate calculations. This comparison also validates the reliability of density functional theory calculations. Furthermore, using a high-throughput approach, the authors perform such calculations to identify new candidates for solar thermochemical hydrogen production among ABO3 perovskite materials, demonstrating the striong influence of B-site cations on the oxygen vacancy formation energy.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 065403] Published Wed Jun 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bianca Baldassarri, Jiangang He, Xin Qian, Emanuela Mastronardo, Sean Griesemer, Sossina M. Haile, and Christopher Wolverton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physical vapor deposition of Yb-doped $\mathrm{CsPb}{\mathrm{Cl}}_{3}$ thin films for quantum cutting]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.065404</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.065404"/>
        <updated>2023-06-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Iver J. Cleveland, Minh N. Tran, Suryansh Kabra, Kajini Sandrakumar, Haripriya Kannan, Ayaskanta Sahu, and Eray S. Aydil
Ytterbium-doped CsPbCl3 emerges as the primary contender for a quantum cutting coating on silicon solar cells, aiming to enhance both their efficiencies and durability. This is accomplished by converting each incident ultraviolet and blue photon with energies greater than 2.5 eV into two 1.25 eV near-infrared red photons. The potential of this approach lies in the possibility of surpassing the Quessier limit, thereby augmenting the efficiencies of silicon solar cells. While thin films produced through colloidal synthesis and nanocrystal dispersions have demonstrated photoluminescence quantum yields nearing 200%, there has been a growing interest in employing physical vapor deposition as a large-area scalable method due to sub-band gap absorption exhibited by colloidal films. In the present study, the authors made an intriguing discovery regarding the significant influence of post-deposition annealing environment and protocols on the near-infrared photoluminescence quantum yields in Yb-doped halide perovskite films that demonstrate the downconversion of ultraviolet and blue light through quantum cutting.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 065404] Published Wed Jun 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iver J. Cleveland, Minh N. Tran, Suryansh Kabra, Kajini Sandrakumar, Haripriya Kannan, Ayaskanta Sahu, and Eray S. Aydil</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[<i>Ab initio</i> Green-Kubo simulations of heat transport in solids: Method and implementation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.224304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.224304"/>
        <updated>2023-06-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Florian Knoop, Matthias Scheffler, and Christian Carbogno
Ab initio Green-Kubo simulations provide an accurate description of lattice thermal conductivities from first principles. This approach reliably describes the full range from harmonic to strongly anharmonic materials. The latter are not handled well by often employed, perturbed phonon models. Using challenging benchmark materials as examples, this paper discusses various physical and computational strategies that speed up the calculations. These advancements pave the way for efficiently exploring materials space in the search for thermal insulators, as demonstrated in the accompanying PRL.
Can we pls add a hyperlink to the word “PRL” to the published wrapper page for the PRL

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 224304] Published Wed Jun 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Florian Knoop, Matthias Scheffler, and Christian Carbogno</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inhomogeneous disordering at a photoinduced charge density wave transition]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.245112</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.245112"/>
        <updated>2023-06-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Antonio Picano, Francesco Grandi, and Martin Eckstein
Symmetry-breaking phase transitions are ubiquitous in nature. The study of their dynamics in solids has often been performed using homogeneous order parameter theories. By microscopically modeling the photoinduced melting and recovery of a charge density wave, the authors instead show here that the transient dynamics can lead to disordered state, where the average order parameter is not representative of the atomic-scale configuration. This provides a possible minimal model description of the experimentally proposed inhomogeneous disordering pathway in photoinduced phase transitions.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 245112] Published Wed Jun 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Antonio Picano, Francesco Grandi, and Martin Eckstein</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effect of a flight stream on subsonic turbulent jets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.063902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.063902"/>
        <updated>2023-06-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Igor A. Maia, Guillaume Brès, Lutz Lesshafft, and Peter Jordan
We study a turbulent jet in a uniform external flow stream. This flow configuration is of interest in aeroacoustics and aeronautics, as it mimics the effect of forward flight in real aircraft. We perform a thorough characterization of the effect of the flight stream, combining experimental and numerical data, signal processing, and linear modeling. We show that the flight stream reduces fluctuation energy in a broad region of the frequency-wavenumber space and stabilizes flow structures underpinned by modal and non-modal instability mechanisms. Streaky structures, associated with helical azimuthal wavenumbers and very slow timescales, are the most strongly affected by the flight stream.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 063902] Published Tue Jun 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Igor A. Maia, Guillaume Brès, Lutz Lesshafft, and Peter Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Role of herbivory in shaping the dryland vegetation ecosystem: Linking spiral vegetation patterns and nonlinear, nonlocal grazing]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.064403</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.064403"/>
        <updated>2023-06-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mrinal Kanti Pal and Swarup Poria
Model improvements uncover more information on the link between grazing animals and the formation of spiral vegetation patterns in arid climates.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, 064403] Published Tue Jun 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mrinal Kanti Pal and Swarup Poria</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Few-nucleon scattering in pionless effective field theory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.064001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.064001"/>
        <updated>2023-06-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Martin Schäfer and Betzalel Bazak
In nuclear physics, effective field theory is a low-energy manifestation of QCD with baryons and pions as its constituents, rather than quarks and gluons. At very low energies, even the pions can be integrated out, providing a simple yet thorough framework to study nuclear physics with controlled theoretical uncertainties. This work extends previous studies to A≤4 with accurate predictions for low-energy few-nucleon scattering, comparable to those from the best current analyses. The work confirms that a four-body force is needed at next-to-leading order to achieve cutoff-independent results.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, 064001] Published Tue Jun 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Schäfer and Betzalel Bazak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlocal optical potential in inelastic deuteron scattering off $^{24}\mathrm{Mg}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.064602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.107.064602"/>
        <updated>2023-06-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Deltuva and D. Jurčiukonis
Nuclear reactions are a powerful tool for obtaining information on yet unknown aspects of nuclear structure. This work combines an elaborate reaction framework, based on the Faddeev equations, with novel nonlocal nucleon-nucleus potentials including core excitations. The authors show that nonlocalities lead to an improved description of inelastic deuteron scattering data and may impact the extracted structure information. These results may serve as motivation for exploring a wider range of reaction frameworks.

[Phys. Rev. C 107, 064602] Published Tue Jun 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Deltuva and D. Jurčiukonis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of the conduction band spin-orbit splitting in ${\mathrm{WSe}}_{2}$ and ${\mathrm{WS}}_{2}$ monolayers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.245407</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.245407"/>
        <updated>2023-06-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lei Ren, Cedric Robert, Hanan Dery, Minhao He, Pengke Li, Dinh Van Tuan, Pierre Renucci, Delphine Lagarde, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Xiaodong Xu, and Xavier Marie
The conduction band spin-orbit splitting ∆c has a strong impact on optical, transport, and spin-valley properties of 2D materials based on transition metal dichalcogenide monolayers. Here, the authors study charge tunable devices based on WSe2 and WS2 monolayers. In addition to the well-known radiative recombination of neutral and charged excitons, photoluminescence measurements highlight a weaker intensity optical transition. This line is interpreted as an impurity-assisted recombination of the negatively charged exciton (triplet trion), whose radiative recombination energy differs by ∆c from that of the trion’s direct optically active recombination.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 245407] Published Tue Jun 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lei Ren, Cedric Robert, Hanan Dery, Minhao He, Pengke Li, Dinh Van Tuan, Pierre Renucci, Delphine Lagarde, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Xiaodong Xu, and Xavier Marie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Future quantum workforce: Competences, requirements, and forecasts]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.010137</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.010137"/>
        <updated>2023-06-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Franziska Greinert, Rainer Müller, Philipp Bitzenbauer, Malte S. Ubben, and Kim-Alessandro Weber
A survey of experts to map requirements and forecasts for the future quantum workforce.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 19, 010137] Published Mon Jun 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Franziska Greinert, Rainer Müller, Philipp Bitzenbauer, Malte S. Ubben, and Kim-Alessandro Weber</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shockwavelike Behavior across Social Media]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.237401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.237401"/>
        <updated>2023-06-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pedro D. Manrique, Frank Yingjie Huo, Sara El Oud, Minzhang Zheng, Lucia Illari, and Neil F. Johnson
A theory derived from nonlinear fluid dynamics is able to reproduce the formation dynamics of online hate communities—offering insights that could inform public policies.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 237401] Published Mon Jun 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pedro D. Manrique, Frank Yingjie Huo, Sara El Oud, Minzhang Zheng, Lucia Illari, and Neil F. Johnson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gravitational Pair Production and Black Hole Evaporation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.221502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.221502"/>
        <updated>2023-06-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Michael F. Wondrak, Walter D. van Suijlekom, and Heino Falcke
The gravitational fields of black holes and other compact objects are strong enough that they might wrest massless particles out of the vacuum and into existence, causing the objects to decay.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 221502] Published Fri Jun 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael F. Wondrak, Walter D. van Suijlekom, and Heino Falcke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Superfluid Fraction in an Interacting Spatially Modulated Bose-Einstein Condensate]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.226003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.226003"/>
        <updated>2023-06-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): G. Chauveau, C. Maury, F. Rabec, C. Heintze, G. Brochier, S. Nascimbene, J. Dalibard, J. Beugnon, S. M. Roccuzzo, and S. Stringari
Breaking Galilean invariance in a superfluid reduces the superfluid fraction while the system remains fully condensed.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 226003] Published Fri Jun 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>G. Chauveau, C. Maury, F. Rabec, C. Heintze, G. Brochier, S. Nascimbene, J. Dalibard, J. Beugnon, S. M. Roccuzzo, and S. Stringari</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stochastic Exceptional Points for Noise-Assisted Sensing]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.227201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.227201"/>
        <updated>2023-06-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zhipeng Li, Chenhui Li, Ze Xiong, Guoqiang Xu, Yongtai Raymond Wang, Xi Tian, Xin Yang, Zhu Liu, Qihang Zeng, Rongzhou Lin, Ying Li, Jason Kai Wei Lee, John S. Ho, and Cheng-Wei Qiu
By exploiting a phenomenon called stochastic resonance, sensors can perform better in a noisy environment than in a noise-free setting.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 227201] Published Fri Jun 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhipeng Li, Chenhui Li, Ze Xiong, Guoqiang Xu, Yongtai Raymond Wang, Xi Tian, Xin Yang, Zhu Liu, Qihang Zeng, Rongzhou Lin, Ying Li, Jason Kai Wei Lee, John S. Ho, and Cheng-Wei Qiu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orientation dynamics of two-dimensional concavo-convex bodies]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L062301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L062301"/>
        <updated>2023-06-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Ravichandran and J. S. Wettlaufer
We study the complex orientation dynamics of a settling body with concave and convex surfaces using particle-resolving direct numerical simulations, and find multiple bifurcations of the dynamics as the Reynolds number of the body is varied from O(1) to O(20). The dynamics of irregularly shaped solid bodies in this range of Reynolds numbers is relevant in such varied phenomena as the tumbling of ice particles in atmospheric clouds, and of plant and animal microorganisms in the ocean.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, L062301] Published Fri Jun 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Ravichandran and J. S. Wettlaufer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paramagnetic electronic structure of CrSBr: Comparison between <i>ab initio</i> $GW$ theory and angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.235107</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.235107"/>
        <updated>2023-06-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marco Bianchi, Swagata Acharya, Florian Dirnberger, Julian Klein, Dimitar Pashov, Kseniia Mosina, Zdenek Sofer, Alexander N. Rudenko, Mikhail I. Katsnelson, Mark van Schilfgaarde, Malte Rösner, and Philip Hofmann
Understanding the electronic structure of the layered magnetic semiconductor CrSBr is a formidable challenge for both experiment and theory. The material is highly insulating at low temperatures, preventing angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy investigations in the magnetically ordered phase. Theoretically, not only the non-local Coulomb interaction in the low-dimensional compound needs to be addressed properly, but a comparison to the experimental data also requires an approximate handling of the paramagnetic phase. Including these effects gives an excellent understanding of the experimentally observed band structure.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 235107] Published Fri Jun 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marco Bianchi, Swagata Acharya, Florian Dirnberger, Julian Klein, Dimitar Pashov, Kseniia Mosina, Zdenek Sofer, Alexander N. Rudenko, Mikhail I. Katsnelson, Mark van Schilfgaarde, Malte Rösner, and Philip Hofmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elastic scattering and rotational excitation of ${\mathrm{H}}_{2}$ by electron impact: Convergent close-coupling calculations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.062804</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.062804"/>
        <updated>2023-06-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Liam H. Scarlett, Una S. Rehill, Mark C. Zammit, Nicolas A. Mori, Igor Bray, and Dmitry V. Fursa
The authors report benchmark results for the rotational excitation of the hydrogen molecule at energies up to 20 eV obtained with the adiabatic-nuclei molecular convergent close-coupling method. The results are compared to available measurements and previous calculations. They contribute to the understanding of low-energy collision physics in a full quantum mechanical treatment.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 062804] Published Fri Jun 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liam H. Scarlett, Una S. Rehill, Mark C. Zammit, Nicolas A. Mori, Igor Bray, and Dmitry V. Fursa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Direct measurement of high-lying vibrational repumping transitions for molecular laser cooling]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.062805</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.062805"/>
        <updated>2023-06-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nickolas H. Pilgram, Arian Jadbabaie, Chandler J. Conn, and Nicholas R. Hutzler
The authors demonstrate a method for high-resolution spectroscopy of excited vibrational states of molecules without the need for optical cycling, and apply it to measure the A(100) - X(300) band in YbOH. The method, whose sensitivity could be further improved, should have broad utility for molecular laser cooling, and applications that make use of excited vibrational states such as searches for fundamental symmetry violations, searches for ultralight dark matter, etc.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 062805] Published Fri Jun 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nickolas H. Pilgram, Arian Jadbabaie, Chandler J. Conn, and Nicholas R. Hutzler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tangent Space Approach for Thermal Tensor Network Simulations of the 2D Hubbard Model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.226502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.226502"/>
        <updated>2023-06-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Qiaoyi Li, Yuan Gao, Yuan-Yao He, Yang Qi, Bin-Bin Chen, and Wei Li
A new tangent space tensor renormalization group method is well-controlled, highly efficient, and accurate for strongly correlated 2D lattice models at finite temperature.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 226502] Published Thu Jun 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qiaoyi Li, Yuan Gao, Yuan-Yao He, Yang Qi, Bin-Bin Chen, and Wei Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological invariants for symmetry-protected topological phase entanglers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.235104</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.235104"/>
        <updated>2023-06-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Carolyn Zhang
Broad classes of symmetry protected topological (SPT) phases can be prepared from a product state by locality preserving unitary operators that respect the symmetry as a whole, but cannot be written as symmetric finite depth quantum circuits. This work provides a framework for obtaining explicit topological invariants of such unitary operators, based on a special easily computable flux insertion operator. For unitary operators that are SPT entanglers, these invariants are related to the cocycle that labels the SPT phase.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 235104] Published Thu Jun 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carolyn Zhang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evidence for three-dimensional Dirac conical bands in TlBiSSe by optical and magneto-optical spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L241101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.L241101"/>
        <updated>2023-06-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): F. Le Mardelé, J. Wyzula, I. Mohelsky, S. Nasrallah, M. Loh, S. Ben David, O. Toledano, D. Tolj, M. Novak, G. Eguchi, S. Paschen, N. Barišić, J. Chen, A. Kimura, M. Orlita, Z. Rukelj, Ana Akrap, and D. Santos-Cottin
TlBiSSe is a 3D Dirac semimetal that exists at the interface between a topological insulator, TlBiS2, and a trivial insulator, TlBiSe2. It is one of the few systems with an ideal band structure, exhibiting only conical dispersive bands over almost half an electronvolt. Here, the authors find a rare unequivocal signature of a 3D Dirac cone in its optical and magneto-optical properties, achieved by carefully controlled synthesis that places the Fermi level very close to the Dirac point.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, L241101] Published Thu Jun 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>F. Le Mardelé, J. Wyzula, I. Mohelsky, S. Nasrallah, M. Loh, S. Ben David, O. Toledano, D. Tolj, M. Novak, G. Eguchi, S. Paschen, N. Barišić, J. Chen, A. Kimura, M. Orlita, Z. Rukelj, Ana Akrap, and D. Santos-Cottin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fundamental limits of pulsed quantum light spectroscopy: Dipole moment estimation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.062601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.062601"/>
        <updated>2023-06-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Francesco Albarelli, Evangelia Bisketzi, Aiman Khan, and Animesh Datta
In order to rigorously find the limit of estimation precision for an atom probed by a quantum light pulse, the authors incorporate tools from quantum metrology and atomic spectroscopy. Their methodology uses a Hamiltonian model of the light-matter interaction to compute the information in the quantum state of the light after interaction with the atom.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 062601] Published Thu Jun 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Francesco Albarelli, Evangelia Bisketzi, Aiman Khan, and Animesh Datta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Partition Function for a Volume of Space]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.221501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.221501"/>
        <updated>2023-05-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ted Jacobson and Manus R. Visser
A new calculation shows that any region of space with the topology of a ball has a standard Bekenstein-Hawking entropy.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 221501] Published Wed May 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ted Jacobson and Manus R. Visser</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Constraints on Heavy QCD Axions with a Liquid Argon Time Projection Chamber Using the ArgoNeuT Experiment]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.221802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.221802"/>
        <updated>2023-05-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Acciarri, C. Adams, B. Baller, V. Basque, F. Cavanna, R. T. Co, R. S. Fitzpatrick, B. Fleming, P. Green, R. Harnik, K. J. Kelly, S. Kumar, K. Lang, I. Lepetic, Z. Liu, X. Luo, K. F. Lyu, O. Palamara, G. Scanavini, M. Soderberg, J. Spitz, A. M. Szelc, W. Wu, and T. Yang (The ArgoNeuT Collaboration)
The first search for heavy QCD axions using a liquid argon detector bounds a previously unexplored region of axion parameter space between 0.2 and 0.9 GeV.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 221802] Published Wed May 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Acciarri, C. Adams, B. Baller, V. Basque, F. Cavanna, R. T. Co, R. S. Fitzpatrick, B. Fleming, P. Green, R. Harnik, K. J. Kelly, S. Kumar, K. Lang, I. Lepetic, Z. Liu, X. Luo, K. F. Lyu, O. Palamara, G. Scanavini, M. Soderberg, J. Spitz, A. M. Szelc, W. Wu, and T. Yang (The ArgoNeuT Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Formation of Ultracold Molecules by Merging Optical Tweezers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.223401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.223401"/>
        <updated>2023-05-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Daniel K. Ruttley, Alexander Guttridge, Stefan Spence, Robert C. Bird, C. Ruth Le Sueur, Jeremy M. Hutson, and Simon L. Cornish
By merging two optical tweezers containing a single atom each, an ultracold molecule is formed in the motional ground state.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 223401] Published Wed May 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel K. Ruttley, Alexander Guttridge, Stefan Spence, Robert C. Bird, C. Ruth Le Sueur, Jeremy M. Hutson, and Simon L. Cornish</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Specific Heat of Electron Plasma Waves]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.225101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.225101"/>
        <updated>2023-05-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. R. Rygg, P. M. Celliers, and G. W. Collins
Discrepancies between shock compression models and experiments may be explained by accounting for the contribution of collective plasma oscillations in the heat model for warm dense hydrogen.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 225101] Published Wed May 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. R. Rygg, P. M. Celliers, and G. W. Collins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamics of Associative Polymers with High Density of Reversible Bonds]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.228101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.228101"/>
        <updated>2023-05-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shifeng Nian, Shalin Patil, Siteng Zhang, Myoeum Kim, Quan Chen, Mikhail Zhernenkov, Ting Ge, Shiwang Cheng, and Li-Heng Cai (蔡历恒)
Experiments show that the sticky behavior of so-called associative polymers is controlled by the density of bonding structures, contradicting theoretical predictions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 228101] Published Wed May 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shifeng Nian, Shalin Patil, Siteng Zhang, Myoeum Kim, Quan Chen, Mikhail Zhernenkov, Ting Ge, Shiwang Cheng, and Li-Heng Cai (蔡历恒)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[$D$-meson semileptonic decays to pseudoscalars from four-flavor lattice QCD]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.094516</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.107.094516"/>
        <updated>2023-05-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexei Bazavov, Carleton DeTar, Aida X. El-Khadra, Elvira Gámiz, Zechariah Gelzer, Steven Gottlieb, William I. Jay, Hwancheol Jeong, Andreas S. Kronfeld, Ruizi Li, Andrew T. Lytle, Paul B. Mackenzie, Ethan T. Neil, Thomas Primer, James N. Simone, Robert L. Sugar, Doug Toussaint, Ruth S. Van de Water, and Alejandro Vaquero (Fermilab Lattice and MILC Collaborations)
New theoretical results give a stringent test of Standard Model and second-row CKM unitarity. Precise calculations using lattice QCD yield percent-level determinations of the CKM matrix elements |Vcd| and |Vcs| from the semileptonic decays D→πℓν and D→Kℓν, respectively, as well as the world’s first extraction of |Vcd| from the decay Ds→Kℓν.

[Phys. Rev. D 107, 094516] Published Wed May 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexei Bazavov, Carleton DeTar, Aida X. El-Khadra, Elvira Gámiz, Zechariah Gelzer, Steven Gottlieb, William I. Jay, Hwancheol Jeong, Andreas S. Kronfeld, Ruizi Li, Andrew T. Lytle, Paul B. Mackenzie, Ethan T. Neil, Thomas Primer, James N. Simone, Robert L. Sugar, Doug Toussaint, Ruth S. Van de Water, and Alejandro Vaquero (Fermilab Lattice and MILC Collaborations)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic density of states of a $U(1)$ quantum spin liquid with spinon Fermi surface. I. Orbital magnetic field effects]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.195155</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.195155"/>
        <updated>2023-05-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wen-Yu He and Patrick A. Lee
The authors study the orbital magnetic field induced Landau quantization of a quantum spin liquid with spinon Fermi surface. In the electronic density of states of the quantum spin liquid, the Landau quantization is found to induce a set of band-edge steps, band-edge resonance peaks, or in-gap bound states when the gauge-field fluctuations are negligible, weak, or strong, respectively. The results indicate that the Landau quantization of the spinon Fermi surface can be detected through scanning tunneling microscope measurements.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 195155] Published Wed May 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wen-Yu He and Patrick A. Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic density of states of a $U(1)$ quantum spin liquid with spinon Fermi surface. II. Zeeman magnetic field effects]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.195156</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.195156"/>
        <updated>2023-05-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wen-Yu He and Patrick A. Lee
This work studies the Zeeman magnetic field effect on a quantum spin liquid with a spinon Fermi surface. In the absence of gauge binding, the quantum spin liquid electronic density of states exhibits no Zeeman shift in the threshold energy. As the gauge binding increases, the band edge resonance peaks exhibit a reduced Zeeman shift and eventually have the Zeeman shift direction reversed for a sufficiently large gauge binding. The authors further suggest to use such anomalous Zeeman response to identify the gapless quantum spin liquid phase.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 195156] Published Wed May 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wen-Yu He and Patrick A. Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Solid-State Microwave Magnetometer with Picotesla-Level Sensitivity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.054095</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.054095"/>
        <updated>2023-05-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Scott T. Alsid, Jennifer M. Schloss, Matthew H. Steinecker, John F. Barry, Andrew C. Maccabe, Guoqing Wang (王国庆), Paola Cappellaro, and Danielle A. Braje
Magnetometry with diamond nitrogen-vacancy (NV) ensembles has enabled devices with picotesla sensitivity at static and low-frequency fields, but their performance at higher frequencies lags far behind. The authors solve the technical challenges and demonstrate a microwave-frequency NV magnetometer with picotesla sensitivity, by implementing a pulse scheme for noise cancellation and employing a custom-grown diamond. This sensitivity enhancement could be extended into a far broader range of frequencies using spin-locking and quantum frequency mixing. These results could lead to applications such as near-field antenna characterization and microwave circuitry imaging.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 054095] Published Wed May 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Scott T. Alsid, Jennifer M. Schloss, Matthew H. Steinecker, John F. Barry, Andrew C. Maccabe, Guoqing Wang (王国庆), Paola Cappellaro, and Danielle A. Braje</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Demonstration of a kicker impedance reduction scheme with diode stack and resistors by operating the 3-GeV rapid cycling synchrotron of the Japan Proton Accelerator Research Complex]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.053501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.053501"/>
        <updated>2023-05-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yoshihiro Shobuda, Hiroyuki Harada, Pranab Kumar Saha, Tomohiro Takayanagi, Fumihiko Tamura, Tomohito Togashi, Yasuhiro Watanabe, Kazami Yamamoto, and Masanobu Yamamoto
Extraction kicker impedance reduction suppresses beam instabilities and raises beam power in the 3-GeV rapid cycling synchrotron of the Japan Proton Accelerator Research Complex.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 26, 053501] Published Wed May 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yoshihiro Shobuda, Hiroyuki Harada, Pranab Kumar Saha, Tomohiro Takayanagi, Fumihiko Tamura, Tomohito Togashi, Yasuhiro Watanabe, Kazami Yamamoto, and Masanobu Yamamoto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Einstein-Podolsky-Rosen Experiment with Two Bose-Einstein Condensates]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.021031</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.021031"/>
        <updated>2023-05-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Paolo Colciaghi, Yifan Li, Philipp Treutlein, and Tilman Zibold
A new demonstration involving hundreds of entangled atoms tests Schrödinger’s interpretation of Einstein, Rosen, and Podolsky’s classic thought experiment.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 021031] Published Tue May 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paolo Colciaghi, Yifan Li, Philipp Treutlein, and Tilman Zibold</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetic Response of Nematic Superconductors: Skyrmion Stripes and Their Signatures in Muon Spin Relaxation Experiments]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.226002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.226002"/>
        <updated>2023-05-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Martin Speight, Thomas Winyard, and Egor Babaev
An unusual kind of superconductor harbors magnetic vortices that researchers predict should be readily observable thanks to the striped configurations they adopt.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 130, 226002] Published Tue May 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Speight, Thomas Winyard, and Egor Babaev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Models of vimentin organization under actin-driven transport]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.054408</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.107.054408"/>
        <updated>2023-05-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Youngmin Park, Cécile Leduc, Sandrine Etienne-Manneville, and Stéphanie Portet
Several processes interact in the formation of intermediate filament networks. This paper reports on a study of one of those processes, a continuous flow towards the cell center caused by movement of actin filaments. The authors use mathematical modeling to compare several biologically realistic scenarios to interpret their experimental data. They conclude that the data are best explained by some spatial variation of transport and trapping.

[Phys. Rev. E 107, 054408] Published Tue May 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Youngmin Park, Cécile Leduc, Sandrine Etienne-Manneville, and Stéphanie Portet</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symmetries, length scales, magnetic response, and skyrmion chains in nematic superconductors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.195204</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.195204"/>
        <updated>2023-05-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Martin Speight, Thomas Winyard, and Egor Babaev
The structure of vortex lattices for unconventional superconductors is mostly unknown and a mathematically challenging problem. The authors propose a general method to find vortex lattices for any superconducting system. They focus on the example of nematic superconductors, demonstrating that in an external magnetic field such superconductors form chains of fractional vortices. Their approach, by describing the geometry of the unit cell, directly maps to the signal such lattices exhibit in muon spin rotation experiments, producing a powerful tool to study the superconducting order parameter.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 195204] Published Tue May 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Speight, Thomas Winyard, and Egor Babaev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symmetry-resolved entanglement in critical non-Hermitian systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.205153</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.107.205153"/>
        <updated>2023-05-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Michele Fossati, Filiberto Ares, and Pasquale Calabrese
Non-Hermitian quantum systems display unusual features that set them apart from the Hermitian ones, yet their understanding is still very poor. Here, by studying how entanglement distributes in the symmetry sectors, the authors manage to explain one of these elusive features, namely, the origin of the nonpositiveness of the reduced density.

[Phys. Rev. B 107, 205153] Published Tue May 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michele Fossati, Filiberto Ares, and Pasquale Calabrese</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Properties of Donor Qubits in $\mathrm{Zn}\mathrm{O}$ Formed by Indium-Ion Implantation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.054090</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.19.054090"/>
        <updated>2023-05-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xingyi Wang, Christian Zimmermann, Michael Titze, Vasileios Niaouris, Ethan R. Hansen, Samuel H. D’Ambrosia, Lasse Vines, Edward S. Bielejec, and Kai-Mei C. Fu
Point-defect spin qubits with an optical interface may become the building blocks of future quantum networks. In this study, ion implantation at low fluences is used to create neutral In donors in ZnO that demonstrate desirable qubit properties. Notably, the authors also observe the signature of the indium electron-nuclear hyperfine interaction, which could enable access to a long-lived nuclear-spin memory. This result is an important step toward scalable formation of donor qubits in ZnO with optical access to a nuclear-spin memory.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 19, 054090] Published Tue May 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xingyi Wang, Christian Zimmermann, Michael Titze, Vasileios Niaouris, Ethan R. Hansen, Samuel H. D’Ambrosia, Lasse Vines, Edward S. Bielejec, and Kai-Mei C. Fu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multichannel hyperspherical model for Efimov physics with van der Waals interactions controlled by a Feshbach resonance]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.053319</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.107.053319"/>
        <updated>2023-05-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kajsa-My Tempest and Svante Jonsell
Because Feshbach resonances can be used to tune atom-atom scattering, they are used as a tool to study Efimov physics in three-body ultracold systems. Here the authors develop and test a model that explicitly includes the multichannel nature of the physics near a Feshbach resonance, and find that the model captures features that are missed by the typical single-channel model.

[Phys. Rev. A 107, 053319] Published Tue May 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kajsa-My Tempest and Svante Jonsell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>