<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-12-30T00:45:04.706Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T00:45:04.706Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing the edge states of Chern insulators using microwave impedance microscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235432</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235432"/>
        <updated>2023-12-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Taige Wang, Chen Wu, Masataka Mogi, Minoru Kawamura, Yoshinori Tokura, Zhi-Xun Shen, Yi–Zhuang You, and Monica T. Allen
Quantum anomalous Hall (QAH) insulators, known for their topological 1D conducting edge states, are a focus of many recent quantum material studies. Here, the authors overcome the challenges in direct imaging and analysis of edge states by exploiting the power of microwave impedance microscopy (MIM). By analyzing the resonance pattern of 1D edge plasmon excitations, MIM can discern true topological edge states from potential trivial ones. This approach significantly advances our understanding of QAH insulators and their topological edge states.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 235432] Published Fri Dec 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Taige Wang, Chen Wu, Masataka Mogi, Minoru Kawamura, Yoshinori Tokura, Zhi-Xun Shen, Yi–Zhuang You, and Monica T. Allen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Towards an experimental proof of the magnonic Aharonov-Casher effect]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L220404</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L220404"/>
        <updated>2023-12-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rostyslav O. Serha, Vitaliy I. Vasyuchka, Alexander A. Serga, and Burkard Hillebrands
The Aharonov-Casher effect is the accumulation of the wave function phase when a particle with magnetic moment passes through an electric field. This phenomenon is observed for real particles and predicted for quasiparticles such as magnons. Here, the authors investigate the impact of a strong electric field on the phase of dipolar spin waves exited in a ferromagnetic yttrium iron garnet (YIG) film and report the experimental results in favor of the magnonic Aharonov-Casher effect.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L220404] Published Fri Dec 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rostyslav O. Serha, Vitaliy I. Vasyuchka, Alexander A. Serga, and Burkard Hillebrands</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Possible explanation for the high superconducting ${T}_{c}$ in bcc Ti at high pressure]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.214523</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.214523"/>
        <updated>2023-12-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Antonio Sanna, Camilla Pellegrini, Simone di Cataldo, Gianni Profeta, and Lilia Boeri
By means of ab initio calculations, the authors show here that neither a conventional nor an unconventional pairing mechanism can justify the observed 26-K superconducting Tc in compressed bcc titanium. They reconcile experimental and theoretical results by assuming the presence of Ti vacancies. These induce a phonon softening that increases the electron-phonon coupling at high pressure, yielding an agreement with measurements over the full pressure range 150–300 GPa. The proposed mechanism applies to multiple types of defects and can occur in several simple metals.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 214523] Published Thu Dec 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Antonio Sanna, Camilla Pellegrini, Simone di Cataldo, Gianni Profeta, and Lilia Boeri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toward a global phase diagram of the fractional quantum anomalous Hall effect]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.245159</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.245159"/>
        <updated>2023-12-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aidan P. Reddy and Liang Fu
Recent experiments on tMoTe2 provide the first realization of the fractional quantum anomalous Hall effect. Synthesizing insights from an extensive exact diagonalization study, the authors present here a many-body phase diagram tMoTe2, in which lowest Landau level (LLL)-like features and non-LLL-like features coexist. The study highlights several guiding principles, including interaction-enhanced particle-hole asymmetry, that is expected to play an important role in general fractional quantum anomalous Hall systems.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 245159] Published Thu Dec 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aidan P. Reddy and Liang Fu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electron and hole doping of monolayer ${\mathrm{WSe}}_{2}$ induced by twisted ferroelectric hexagonal boron nitride]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.L121002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.L121002"/>
        <updated>2023-12-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Fraunié, R. Jamil, R. Kantelberg, S. Roux, L. Petit, E. Lepleux, L. Pacheco, K. Watanabe, T. Taniguchi, V. Jacques, L. Lombez, M. M. Glazov, B. Lassagne, X. Marie, and C. Robert
2D ferroelectric materials have attracted strong interest for their potential in future nanoelectronic devices. The recent discovery of 2D ferroelectricity in twisted layers of hexagonal boron nitride has opened the route to its integration into complex hybrid van der Waals heterostructures. Here the authors show that opposite polarizations in ferroelectric domains of a folded hBN layer imprint local n and p doping in a semiconducting WSe2 monolayer. They demonstrate that WSe2 can be used as an optical probe of ferroelectricity in hBN and show that doping can be controlled with the position of the semiconductor with respect to the ferroelectric interface.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, L121002] Published Wed Dec 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Fraunié, R. Jamil, R. Kantelberg, S. Roux, L. Petit, E. Lepleux, L. Pacheco, K. Watanabe, T. Taniguchi, V. Jacques, L. Lombez, M. M. Glazov, B. Lassagne, X. Marie, and C. Robert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Structures, charge density wave, and superconductivity of noncentrosymmetric $4{H}_{\mathrm{a}}\text{−}{\mathrm{NbSe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.224518</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.224518"/>
        <updated>2023-12-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Menghu Zhou, Yadong Gu, Shunli Ni, Binbin Ruan, Qiaoyu Liu, Qingsong Yang, Lewei Chen, Junkun Yi, Yunqing Shi, Genfu Chen, and Zhian Ren
Here, the authors report the charge density wave and superconductivity of noncentrosymmetric 4Ha-NbSe2. In particular, it exhibits a large upper critical field Hc2(0) well beyond the Pauli paramagnetic limit. Hc2(T) could be described by a two-band scenario that is also revealed via lower critical field and specific heat. The high Hc2 is expected to motivate the search of high-field superconductors in noncentrosymmetric materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 224518] Published Wed Dec 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Menghu Zhou, Yadong Gu, Shunli Ni, Binbin Ruan, Qiaoyu Liu, Qingsong Yang, Lewei Chen, Junkun Yi, Yunqing Shi, Genfu Chen, and Zhian Ren</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inhomogeneous excitation-regulated coherent strain wave in $2H\text{−}\mathrm{Mo}{\mathrm{Te}}_{2}$ revealed by ultrafast electron microscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.245426</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.245426"/>
        <updated>2023-12-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yongzhao Zhang, Shuaishuai Sun, Wentao Wang, Huanfang Tian, Jianqi Li, Jun Li, and Huaixin Yang
The potential to manipulate the coherent photoacoustic wave in 2H-MoTe2 is demonstrated here by adjusting the homogeneity of laser excitation. Homogeneous excitation results in out-of-phase intensity oscillations of the Friedel pairs, and only the fundamental frequency is detected. In contrast, inhomogeneous excitation leads to in-phase intensity oscillations and the emergence of a second harmonic component. These ultrafast electron diffraction results reveal that, as the flake thickness increases, the photoacoustic wave transforms from a standing wave with breathing motions to a soliton-like traveling wave.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 245426] Published Wed Dec 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yongzhao Zhang, Shuaishuai Sun, Wentao Wang, Huanfang Tian, Jianqi Li, Jun Li, and Huaixin Yang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hyperpolarization of nuclear spins: Polarization blockade]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043291</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043291"/>
        <updated>2023-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): O. T. Whaites, C. I. Ioannou, B. J. Pingault, G. L. van de Stolpe, T. H. Taminiau, and T. S. Monteiro
Sequences of periodic microwave pulses are used to efficiently transfer polarization from an NV defect electronic spin in diamond to surrounding nuclei, at specific resonant periods. It’s theoretically and experimentally demonstrated that the presence of a “blocking spin,” a nuclear spin with similar precession frequency but stronger coupling, leads to expulsion of polarization resonances of other nuclear spins from the central resonant period region, affecting the efficiency of the polarization protocol.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 043291] Published Tue Dec 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>O. T. Whaites, C. I. Ioannou, B. J. Pingault, G. L. van de Stolpe, T. H. Taminiau, and T. S. Monteiro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conformal Invariance and Multifractality at Anderson Transitions in Arbitrary Dimensions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.266401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.266401"/>
        <updated>2023-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jaychandran Padayasi and Ilya Gruzberg
Conformal invariance and Abelian fusion constrain the spectrum of multifractal exponents to be quadratic in its arguments in any dimension greater than two.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 266401] Published Tue Dec 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jaychandran Padayasi and Ilya Gruzberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Field theory of a superconductor with repulsion]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.214521</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.214521"/>
        <updated>2023-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Amir Dalal, Jonathan Ruhman, and Vladyslav Kozii
Superconductivity, the state of zero resistance in metals, involves electrons forming a quantum liquid of pairs. However, here lies a conundrum; electrons repel each other due to the electric force, so why should they bind? The answer to this question was provided a long time ago by Pierre Morel and Phillip Anderson. However, to date, there is no existing generalization of Morel-Anderson theory that gives a comprehensive understanding of the properties of real superconductors. This paper bridges the gap by outlining a path to generalize their theory into a “quantum field theory”. Surprisingly, this theory is controlled by a unique point in configuration space (“saddle point”). Utilizing mathematical techniques, the authors can exploit this saddle point to reveal insights into superconductor properties, such as the break point in a magnetic field.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 214521] Published Tue Dec 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amir Dalal, Jonathan Ruhman, and Vladyslav Kozii</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neutralization of impurities by continuous-wave excitation of high-$n$ Rydberg excitons]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235212</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235212"/>
        <updated>2023-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Heckötter, B. Panda, K. Brägelmann, M. Harati, and M. Aßmann
Rydberg excitons are electron-hole pairs excited to high principle quantum numbers (n), that can be addressed in the semiconductor Cu2O. Embedded in a crystalline environment, the highest Rydberg states typically suffer from the presence electric stray fields induced by charged impurities. Here, the authors show a technique to neutralize these impurities by the excitation of Rydberg excitons. The result is an overall improvement of the absorption spectrum’s quality in terms of increased oscillator strengths and narrower linewidths, approaching the Fourier limit.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 235212] Published Tue Dec 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Heckötter, B. Panda, K. Brägelmann, M. Harati, and M. Aßmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Injection mechanisms in a <i>III</i>-nitride light-emitting diode as seen by self-emissive electron microscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.064045</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.064045"/>
        <updated>2023-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tanay Tak, Cameron W. Johnson, Wan Ying Ho, Feng Wu, Mylène Sauty, Steve Rebollo, Andreas K. Schmid, Jacques Peretti, Yuh-Renn Wu, Claude Weisbuch, and James S. Speck
While charge carriers in electronics are fundamental to device operation, little is empirically known about their spatial distribution under standard operating conditions. The authors develop a technique for self-emissive electron microscopy that allows them to image electrons close to their point of generation in operando. Increased electron emission, and thus carrier density, is observed at the ridges of V-shaped defects in a green LED, confirming that the sidewalls of these defects allow lateral carrier injection⏤a necessity for increasing efficiency. Measuring the spatial distribution of carriers with this technique can inform the design of superior devices.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 064045] Published Tue Dec 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tanay Tak, Cameron W. Johnson, Wan Ying Ho, Feng Wu, Mylène Sauty, Steve Rebollo, Andreas K. Schmid, Jacques Peretti, Yuh-Renn Wu, Claude Weisbuch, and James S. Speck</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theory of hydrodynamic phenomena in optical mesh lattices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.063517</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.063517"/>
        <updated>2023-12-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hannah M. Price, Martin Wimmer, Monika Monika, Ulf Peschel, and Iacopo Carusotto
The authors develop a theoretical description of superfluidlike phenomena in an optical mesh lattice, a system composed of two fiber loops coupled via a beam splitter. The results provide analytical and numerical interpretation of previous experimental observations and predict physical effects stemming from the spatiotemporally periodic geometry.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 063517] Published Tue Dec 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah M. Price, Martin Wimmer, Monika Monika, Ulf Peschel, and Iacopo Carusotto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Relativistic two-body currents for one-nucleon knockout in electron-nucleus scattering]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.064608</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.064608"/>
        <updated>2023-12-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Franco-Munoz, J. García-Marcos, R. González-Jiménez, and J. M. Udías
Electron scattering is currently the subject of renewed interest, also by virtue of its connections with the neutrino-nucleus interaction. This work represents a step forward for the description of the quasielastic region, through the introduction of two-body meson-exchange currents in a fully relativistic approach. The good agreement with the experimental response of 12C opens up interesting perspectives of applications of the same model to neutrino scattering of heavier nuclei, of great interest for neutrino oscillation experiments, in particular for the new generation of experiments that require an unprecedented level of accuracy.

[Phys. Rev. C 108, 064608] Published Fri Dec 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Franco-Munoz, J. García-Marcos, R. González-Jiménez, and J. M. Udías</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twist- and gate-tunable proximity spin-orbit coupling, spin relaxation anisotropy, and charge-to-spin conversion in heterostructures of graphene and transition metal dichalcogenides]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235166</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235166"/>
        <updated>2023-12-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Klaus Zollner, Simão M. João, Branislav K. Nikolić, and Jaroslav Fabian
Proximity effects in van der Waals heterostructures offer controllable ways to tailor the electronic band structure of adjacent 2D materials. Here, the authors perform extensive first-principles calculations, to reveal the impact of twisting, gating, stacking, interlayer distance, and encapsulation, on the spin-orbit proximitized Dirac bands in graphene/transition metal dichalcogenide heterostructures. Furthermore, the authors make specific predictions for experimentally measurable quantities, such as charge-to-spin conversion efficiency. The results highlight the enormous tunability potential of proximity-induced phenomena in van der Waals heterostructures.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 235166] Published Fri Dec 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Klaus Zollner, Simão M. João, Branislav K. Nikolić, and Jaroslav Fabian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neural sensing and control in a kilometer-scale gravitational-wave observatory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.064041</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.064041"/>
        <updated>2023-12-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. Mukund, J. Lough, A. Bisht, H. Wittel, S. Nadji, C. Affeldt, F. Bergamin, M. Brinkmann, V. Kringel, H. Lück, M. Weinert, and K. Danzmann
Aligning suspended optics in gravitational-wave observatories is crucial for detecting astrophysical phenomena⏤and it is also challenging, due to several environmental factors. This research implements neural-network-based sensing and control deployed at the GEO600 detector, utilizing a sensor with a convolutional neural network and long- and short-term memory, plus a deep-reinforcement-learning-based agent for enhanced alignment. The method demonstrates sensitivity improvement over traditional schemes, thus offering a practical approach for AI-based real-time control of gravitational-wave interferometers, to aid the detection of cosmic events like merging compact neutron-star binaries.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 064041] Published Fri Dec 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Mukund, J. Lough, A. Bisht, H. Wittel, S. Nadji, C. Affeldt, F. Bergamin, M. Brinkmann, V. Kringel, H. Lück, M. Weinert, and K. Danzmann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Combined Measurement of the Higgs Boson Mass from the $H→γγ$ and $H→Z{Z}^{*}→4ℓ$ Decay Channels with the ATLAS Detector Using $\sqrt{s}=7$, 8, and 13 TeV $pp$ Collision Data]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.251802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.251802"/>
        <updated>2023-12-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): G. Aad et al. (ATLAS Collaboration)
The mass of the Higgs boson is measured with a precision of less than a tenth of a percent.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 251802] Published Thu Dec 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>G. Aad &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (ATLAS Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Continuous Phase Transitions between Fractional Quantum Hall States and Symmetry-Protected Topological States]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.256502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.256502"/>
        <updated>2023-12-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ying-Hai Wu, Hong-Hao Tu, and Meng Cheng
In Bose-Fermi mixtures under particular conditions, a symmetry-protected topological state goes through a continuous transition to two decoupled fractional quantum Hall states.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 256502] Published Thu Dec 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ying-Hai Wu, Hong-Hao Tu, and Meng Cheng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rationalizing Euclidean Assemblies of Hard Polyhedra from Tessellations in Curved Space]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.258201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.258201"/>
        <updated>2023-12-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Philipp W. A. Schönhöfer, Kai Sun, Xiaoming Mao, and Sharon C. Glotzer
Though geometrically forbidden from doing so in flat space, some hard Platonic solids can entropically self-assemble into space-filling crystals with sufficient spatial curvature.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 258201] Published Thu Dec 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Philipp W. A. Schönhöfer, Kai Sun, Xiaoming Mao, and Sharon C. Glotzer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amplitude of water pouring sound]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L122002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L122002"/>
        <updated>2023-12-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mouad Boudina, Joonoh Kim, and Ho-Young Kim
The familiar pouring sound we all hear when preparing tea or coffee has been a rare topic of study so far, despite its importance in several applications. We experimentally find that the sound amplitude increases with the jet corrugation, indicating that thin jets are louder than thick ones for the same given height. When pouring from a high distance, the jet breaks up into impacting drops, and the amplitude increases with the jet length and diameter. Results show that the jet corrugation relates to the volume of entrained air, hence the pouring sound can enter as a practical method to measure water aeration rates.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, L122002] Published Thu Dec 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mouad Boudina, Joonoh Kim, and Ho-Young Kim</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonequilibrium critical dynamics of the two-dimensional $±J$ Ising model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.064131</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.064131"/>
        <updated>2023-12-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ramgopal Agrawal, Leticia F. Cugliandolo, Lara Faoro, Lev B. Ioffe, and Marco Picco
Frustration has been shown to modify the critical properties of magnetic systems. By performing large-scale Monte Carlo simulations, the authors investigate the nonequilibrium critical dynamics and the geometrical features of the frustrated two-dimensional ±J Ising model after different temperature quenches.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 064131] Published Thu Dec 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ramgopal Agrawal, Leticia F. Cugliandolo, Lara Faoro, Lev B. Ioffe, and Marco Picco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Epidemic Spreading in Group-Structured Populations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041054</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041054"/>
        <updated>2023-12-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Siddharth Patwardhan, Varun K. Rao, Santo Fortunato, and Filippo Radicchi
Disease contagion is suppressed when different social groups have a large overlap in membership.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 041054] Published Wed Dec 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Siddharth Patwardhan, Varun K. Rao, Santo Fortunato, and Filippo Radicchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measuring Oscillations with a Million Atmospheric Neutrinos]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041055</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041055"/>
        <updated>2023-12-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. A. Argüelles, P. Fernández, I. Martínez-Soler, and M. Jin (靳淼辰)
The combined analysis of present and upcoming atmospheric-neutrino experiments may lead to the solution of outstanding puzzles in neutrino physics.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 041055] Published Wed Dec 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. A. Argüelles, P. Fernández, I. Martínez-Soler, and M. Jin (靳淼辰)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Neural-network force field backed nested sampling: Study of the silicon $p\text{−}T$ phase diagram]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.123804</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.123804"/>
        <updated>2023-12-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nico Unglert, Jesús Carrete, Livia B. Pártay, and Georg K. H. Madsen
Phase diagrams map out the thermodynamically stable conditions for different phases. Their predictive atomistic simulations demands integration of statistical mechanics and quantum mechanics, making computational cost a challenge. Our work successfully combines a neural-network model for silicon’s potential energy with nested-sampling to predict its low-pressure phase diagram accurately. Trained on diverse silicon structures, the model aligns remarkably well with experiments, accurately reproducing the melting line and identifying stable structures. The fusion of neural networks and nested sampling opens the door to not only predict phase diagrams but also assess the accuracy of the underlying exchange-correlation functionals.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 123804] Published Wed Dec 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nico Unglert, Jesús Carrete, Livia B. Pártay, and Georg K. H. Madsen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monte Carlo methods for stationary solutions of general-relativistic Vlasov systems: Collisionless accretion onto black holes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.124057</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.124057"/>
        <updated>2023-12-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Patryk Mach, Adam Cieślik, and Andrzej Odrzywołek
Understanding the phase space distribution of charge particles around compact object especially black holes are a central question in understanding the physics of collisionless accretion around these objects. Here, the authors compute this distribution by doing a clever Monte Carlo sampling of particles far away from the black hole and computing how they evolve. This can potentially lead to the development of steady state solutions that can augment time-dependent solutions that are computed using particle-in-cell simulations.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 124057] Published Wed Dec 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patryk Mach, Adam Cieślik, and Andrzej Odrzywołek</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fortifying gravitational-wave tests of general relativity against astrophysical assumptions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.124060</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.124060"/>
        <updated>2023-12-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ethan Payne, Maximiliano Isi, Katerina Chatziioannou, and Will M. Farr
Gravitational wave tests of general relativity (GR) can suffer from implicit population level biases that need to be addressed in order to accurately infer departures from GR. The authors show how modeling the astrophysical population simultaneously with the deviation from GR provides more trustworthy tests of GR.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 124060] Published Wed Dec 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan Payne, Maximiliano Isi, Katerina Chatziioannou, and Will M. Farr</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unconventional photoinduced charge density wave dynamics in $2H\text{−}{\mathrm{NbSe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235160</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235160"/>
        <updated>2023-12-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Venturini, A. Sarkar, P. Sutar, Z. Jagličić, Y. Vaskivskyi, E. Goreshnik, D. Mihailovic, and T. Mertelj
Using transient optical spectroscopy, the authors investigate ultrafast optical suppression and recovery of the charge density wave (CDW) in 2H-NbSe2, a layered material where CDW and superconductivity coexist. The suppression is marked by the absence of coherent amplitude mode oscillations and a relatively slow, picosecond timescale, different from most typical CDW materials. The suppression of the CDW is only weakly nonthermal and is characterized by an excitation of a large number of phonon degrees of freedom. The recovery of the CDW phase is dominated by slow phonon diffusion.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 235160] Published Wed Dec 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Venturini, A. Sarkar, P. Sutar, Z. Jagličić, Y. Vaskivskyi, E. Goreshnik, D. Mihailovic, and T. Mertelj</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generalized Glauber Dynamics for Inference in Biology]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041053</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041053"/>
        <updated>2023-12-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xiaowen Chen, Maciej Winiarski, Alicja Puścian, Ewelina Knapska, Aleksandra M. Walczak, and Thierry Mora
A new model reproduces both the dynamical and steady-state behavior of a group of living organisms, a first for such systems.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 041053] Published Tue Dec 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiaowen Chen, Maciej Winiarski, Alicja Puścian, Ewelina Knapska, Aleksandra M. Walczak, and Thierry Mora</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extreme Domain Wall Speeds under Ultrafast Optical Excitation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.256702</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.256702"/>
        <updated>2023-12-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rahul Jangid, Nanna Zhou Hagström, Meera Madhavi, Kyle Rockwell, Justin M. Shaw, Jeffrey A. Brock, Matteo Pancaldi, Dario De Angelis, Flavio Capotondi, Emanuele Pedersoli, Hans T. Nembach, Mark W. Keller, Stefano Bonetti, Eric E. Fullerton, Ezio Iacocca, Roopali Kukreja, and Thomas J. Silva
Experiments reveal that the boundaries between magnetic domains in a multilayered magnetic metal can move faster than sound, confirming a previous prediction.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 256702] Published Tue Dec 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rahul Jangid, Nanna Zhou Hagström, Meera Madhavi, Kyle Rockwell, Justin M. Shaw, Jeffrey A. Brock, Matteo Pancaldi, Dario De Angelis, Flavio Capotondi, Emanuele Pedersoli, Hans T. Nembach, Mark W. Keller, Stefano Bonetti, Eric E. Fullerton, Ezio Iacocca, Roopali Kukreja, and Thomas J. Silva</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dependence of scalar mixing on initial conditions in turbulent channel flow]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.124605</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.124605"/>
        <updated>2023-12-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Milind Singh, Emmanuel Germaine, Laurent Mydlarski, and Luca Cortelezzi
Scalar-field initial conditions can have a strong effect on the evolution(s) of scalar fields and the rate at which mixing occurs. The effects of the scalar field initial conditions are studied by analyzing the evolution of three scalar fields with interfaces oriented normal to the streamwise, wall-normal, and transverse directions. When the interface is aligned normal to the mean velocity vector, higher rates of production and destruction of the scalar dissipation, as well as strong advection and stretching of the interface by the mean flow are observed. It is therefore recommended that scalar interfaces be aligned normal to the mean velocity vector to promote mixing within internal flows.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 124605] Published Tue Dec 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Milind Singh, Emmanuel Germaine, Laurent Mydlarski, and Luca Cortelezzi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monte Carlo generation of localized particle trajectories]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.065306</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.065306"/>
        <updated>2023-12-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ivan Ahumada and James P. Edwards
Monte Carlo simulations of path integrals suffer from reduced precision at large times due to undersampling. To address this problem the authors propose a scheme where the sampling trajectories are concentrated in more important regions, and they show the effectiveness of their method with some simple test cases.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 065306] Published Tue Dec 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ivan Ahumada and James P. Edwards</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ionization clamping in ultrafast optical breakdown of transparent solids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.064035</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.064035"/>
        <updated>2023-12-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anton Rudenko, Jerome V. Moloney, and Pavel Polynkin
Internal modifications of transparent solid-state materials by intense, ultrashort laser pulses enable numerous applications in micromachining, photonics, and medicine. Understanding the highly nonlinear propagation of the laser beam through the interaction zone is important in developing these technologies. Here a comprehensive propagation model reveals that even under extremely tight focusing, the key physical quantities are rigidly clamped by plasma shielding, at values up to two orders of magnitude lower than those inferred from earlier studies. Potential routes to overcome the clamping limits are discussed.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 064035] Published Tue Dec 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anton Rudenko, Jerome V. Moloney, and Pavel Polynkin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monte Carlo graph search for quantum circuit optimization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.062615</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.062615"/>
        <updated>2023-12-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bodo Rosenhahn and Tobias J. Osborne
The authors introduce a search algorithm aimed at optimizing the arrangement of quantum gates, leveraging different sampling techniques to dynamically grow a graph that represents potential quantum circuits. They demonstrate efficacy in reducing the quantum gate count, both theoretically and numerically, albeit with acknowledged computational challenges as the graph expands.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 062615] Published Tue Dec 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bodo Rosenhahn and Tobias J. Osborne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Race-Track Trapped-Ion Quantum Processor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041052</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041052"/>
        <updated>2023-12-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. A. Moses et al.
Major technical improvements to a quantum computer based on trapped ions could bring a large-scale version closer to reality.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 041052] Published Mon Dec 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. A. Moses &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sampling Efficiency of Transverse Forces in Dense Liquids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.257101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.257101"/>
        <updated>2023-12-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Federico Ghimenti, Ludovic Berthier, Grzegorz Szamel, and Frédéric van Wijland
Transverse forces that break detailed balance accelerate the dynamics of an overdamped many-body system while preserving the Boltzmann distribution.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 257101] Published Mon Dec 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Federico Ghimenti, Ludovic Berthier, Grzegorz Szamel, and Frédéric van Wijland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[$O(N)$ smectic $σ$ model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.224423</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.224423"/>
        <updated>2023-12-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tzu-Chi Hsieh and Leo Radzihovsky
A smectic liquid crystal is known to display quasi-long-range positional order in three dimensions due to its “soft” elasticity and corresponding strong thermal fluctuations. This work extends such uniaxial scalar density-wave order to N-component magnetic spin-density wave orders, and thereby derives a new class of O(N) smectic sigma model. The model provides a unifying description of the universal low-energy properties of a variety of physical systems, ranging from quantum striped states to helimagnets in frustrated spin systems.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 224423] Published Mon Dec 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tzu-Chi Hsieh and Leo Radzihovsky</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spontaneous breaking of time-reversal symmetry and time-crystal states in chiral atomic systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235154</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235154"/>
        <updated>2023-12-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mário G. Silveirinha, Hugo Terças, and Mauro Antezza
Half-integer spin systems are characterized by a degenerate ground state. Here, the authors show that the chiral interactions of a spin-½ qubit with the vacuum fluctuations may spontaneously break both the time-reversal and the time-translation symmetries. In the former case, the electron spin becomes anchored along some particular direction of space determined by a geometrical symmetry. In contrast, the latter situation occurs when the intrinsic spin magnetic moment undergoes a cyclic oscillation in the ground state, realizing a time crystal.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 235154] Published Mon Dec 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mário G. Silveirinha, Hugo Terças, and Mauro Antezza</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evaporation of Concentrated Polymer Solutions Is Insensitive to Relative Humidity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.248102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.248102"/>
        <updated>2023-12-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Max Huisman, Paul Digard, Wilson C. K. Poon, and Simon Titmuss
Experiments verify a theory that explains why paint doesn’t dry any faster on a dry day than on a wet day.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 248102] Published Fri Dec 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Max Huisman, Paul Digard, Wilson C. K. Poon, and Simon Titmuss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Charge-carrier photogeneration in single-component organic carbazole-based semiconductors via low excitation power triplet-triplet annihilation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.064029</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.064029"/>
        <updated>2023-12-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Andrei Stankevych, Rishabh Saxena, Jeannine Grüne, Sebastian Lulei, Andreas Sperlich, Stavros Athanasopoulos, Alexander Vakhnin, Prakhar Sahay, Wolfgang Brütting, Vladimir Dyakonov, Heinz Bässler, Anna Köhler, and Andrey Kadashchuk
This work demonstrates that triplet-triplet annihilation (TTA) is the predominant mechanism of intrinsic photogeneration of charge-carrier pairs via autoionization, in a single-component disordered organic system with no heavy atoms. The findings challenge established beliefs by revealing efficient carrier generation via TTA upon excitation near the absorption edge. Photocurrent measurements, optical spectroscopy, and spin-sensitive techniques support this model of bimolecular charge generation. Such mechanisms in organic semiconductors are relevant not just for OLEDs, but also for long-persistent luminescence, photovoltaics, and potentially for photocatalytic water splitting.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 064029] Published Fri Dec 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andrei Stankevych, Rishabh Saxena, Jeannine Grüne, Sebastian Lulei, Andreas Sperlich, Stavros Athanasopoulos, Alexander Vakhnin, Prakhar Sahay, Wolfgang Brütting, Vladimir Dyakonov, Heinz Bässler, Anna Köhler, and Andrey Kadashchuk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Obtaining picosecond x-ray pulses from fourth generation synchrotron light sources]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.120701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.26.120701"/>
        <updated>2023-12-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xiaobiao Huang, James Safranek, and Alexander Zholents
A simple twist makes the two-frequency crab cavity scheme an ideal add-on option to produce picosecond level short pulses in fourth-generation storage rings.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 26, 120701] Published Fri Dec 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiaobiao Huang, James Safranek, and Alexander Zholents</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonideal measurement heat engines]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.062214</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.062214"/>
        <updated>2023-12-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Abhisek Panda, Felix C. Binder, and Sai Vinjanampathy
The authors introduce quantum thermal machines with feedback controlled by nonideal measurements. They shed light on overcoming a fundamental thermodynamic limitation against ideal projective measurements, by demonstrating that nonideal measurements can still drive engines consuming thermal or nonclassical correlations, albeit without additional thermodynamic benefit of quantum over classical correlations.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 062214] Published Fri Dec 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhisek Panda, Felix C. Binder, and Sai Vinjanampathy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Artificial Atoms, Wigner Molecules, and an Emergent Kagome Lattice in Semiconductor Moiré Superlattices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.246501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.246501"/>
        <updated>2023-12-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aidan P. Reddy, Trithep Devakul, and Liang Fu
The superlattice constant, the quantum confinement length, and the Wigner molecule size are three key length scales that control the properties of moiré materials at filling factors greater than one.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 246501] Published Thu Dec 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aidan P. Reddy, Trithep Devakul, and Liang Fu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Relativistic drag forces on black holes from scalar dark matter clouds of all sizes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.L121502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.L121502"/>
        <updated>2023-12-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dina Traykova, Rodrigo Vicente, Katy Clough, Thomas Helfer, Emanuele Berti, Pedro G. Ferreira, and Lam Hui
The authors compute the dynamical friction due to a scalar cloud on a moving, non-rotating black hole, offering for the first time a detailed comparison of analytical and numerical results, thereby putting both on firmer ground.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, L121502] Published Thu Dec 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dina Traykova, Rodrigo Vicente, Katy Clough, Thomas Helfer, Emanuele Berti, Pedro G. Ferreira, and Lam Hui</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impact of hyperfine contributions on the ground state of spin-ice compounds]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.214412</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.214412"/>
        <updated>2023-12-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Gronemann, S. Chattopadhyay, T. Gottschall, E. Osmic, A. T. M. N. Islam, V. K. Anand, B. Lake, H. Kaneko, H. Suzuki, J. Wosnitza, and T. Herrmannsdörfer
Here, the authors determine thermodynamic properties of pyrochlore spin-ice compounds at subkelvin temperatures. In particular, the magnetic field dependence of the heat capacity and magnetic entropy of Ho2Ti2O7 and Pr2Hf2O7 shows the existence of additional states beyond the electronic spin and orbital degrees of freedom. One can understand the data through the presence of hyperfine states and complex hyperfine-coupled term schemes.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 214412] Published Thu Dec 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Gronemann, S. Chattopadhyay, T. Gottschall, E. Osmic, A. T. M. N. Islam, V. K. Anand, B. Lake, H. Kaneko, H. Suzuki, J. Wosnitza, and T. Herrmannsdörfer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stabilization of collinear ferromagnetic order in Ir-doped triple-layer ruthenate ${\mathrm{Sr}}_{4}{\mathrm{Ru}}_{3}{\mathrm{O}}_{10}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L241109</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L241109"/>
        <updated>2023-12-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Feng Ye, Zachary Morgan, Yu Zhang, Yifei Ni, and G. Cao
The triple-layer, spin-orbit-coupled metal Sr4Ru3O10 features, peculiarly, a strong ferromagnetic state along the c axis but a contrasting metamagnetic state within the basal plane. Mere 4% Ir substitution for Ru readily alters the structural balance between the RuO6 layers, establishing a collinear ferromagnetic state with magnetic moments fully aligned along the c axis. The emerging perpendicular magnetic anisotropy increases the critical field for the metamagnetic transition, highlighting a critical coupling between the magnetic properties and the underlying lattice facilitated through orbital degrees of freedom and the enhanced spin-orbit interaction.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L241109] Published Thu Dec 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Feng Ye, Zachary Morgan, Yu Zhang, Yifei Ni, and G. Cao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of the Exotic ${0}_{2}^{+}$ Cluster State in $^{8}\mathrm{He}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.242501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.242501"/>
        <updated>2023-12-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Z. H. Yang et al.
Scattering experiments show that the four extra neutrons in helium-8 can pair up and form a nuclear analog of a Bose-Einstein condensate.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 242501] Published Wed Dec 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Z. H. Yang &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Description of the Proton-Decaying ${0}_{2}^{+}$ Resonance of the $α$ Particle]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.242502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.242502"/>
        <updated>2023-12-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): N. Michel, W. Nazarewicz, and M. Płoszajczak
Theoretical descriptions of the first excited state of helium-4 are now consistent with experimental data.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 242502] Published Wed Dec 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>N. Michel, W. Nazarewicz, and M. Płoszajczak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-Temperature Ferroic Glassy States in ${\mathrm{SrTiO}}_{3}$-Based Thin Films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.246801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.246801"/>
        <updated>2023-12-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tianyu Li, Shiqing Deng, He Qi, Tao Zhu, Yu Chen, Huanhua Wang, Fangyuan Zhu, Hui Liu, Jiaou Wang, Er-Jia Guo, Oswaldo Diéguez, and Jun Chen
A method of manipulating local symmetry to achieve a strong magnetic/electric moment along with high transition temperatures is proposed and experimentally demonstrated for the prototypical perovskite SrTiO3.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 246801] Published Wed Dec 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tianyu Li, Shiqing Deng, He Qi, Tao Zhu, Yu Chen, Huanhua Wang, Fangyuan Zhu, Hui Liu, Jiaou Wang, Er-Jia Guo, Oswaldo Diéguez, and Jun Chen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mott insulating low thermal expansion perovskite ${\mathrm{TiF}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235140</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235140"/>
        <updated>2023-12-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Donal Sheets, Kaitlin Lyszak, Menka Jain, Gayanath W. Fernando, Ilya Sochnikov, Jacob Franklin, Jason N. Hancock, and R. Matthias Geilhufe
A class of transition metal trifluorides harbors a structural quantum phase transition, above which extremely large negative thermal expansion (NTE) is shown in ScF3. A related material (TiF3) has reported a much weaker effect and attempts have been made to describe the differing thermal expansion behavior of this system using uncorrelated electronic structure calculations. Here, the authors use a combination of infrared reflectivity, ac magnetometry, and density functional theory calculations to demonstrate that in fact that TiF3 is a strongly correlated electron system, where uncorrelated approaches are ineffective. The work concludes that Mott physics is an important consideration in describing the evolution of the unusual NTE effect in these systems.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 235140] Published Wed Dec 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Donal Sheets, Kaitlin Lyszak, Menka Jain, Gayanath W. Fernando, Ilya Sochnikov, Jacob Franklin, Jason N. Hancock, and R. Matthias Geilhufe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flat bands and electronic localization in twisted bilayer graphene nanoribbons]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235418</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235418"/>
        <updated>2023-12-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Elias Andrade, Pierre A. Pantaleón, Francisco Guinea, and Gerardo G. Naumis
In an infinite twisted bilayer graphene lattice, flat bands emerge, representing electrons localized at the AA stacking regions. This study investigates the behavior of these bands when dealing with incomplete moiré supercells in twisted bilayer graphene nanoribbons. The findings reveal a transition from dispersive to flat bands near charge neutrality as the supercell completeness varies. Moreover, it is observed that the microscopic edges can influence the energy of states localized at the AA regions near the borders.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 235418] Published Wed Dec 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elias Andrade, Pierre A. Pantaleón, Francisco Guinea, and Gerardo G. Naumis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bipolaronic superconductivity out of a Coulomb gas]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L220502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L220502"/>
        <updated>2023-12-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Sous, C. Zhang, M. Berciu, D. R. Reichman, B. V. Svistunov, N. V. Prokof'ev, and A. J. Millis
Bipolaronic superconductivity induced by bond phonons survives even in the presence of very strong long-ranged Coulomb repulsion leading to transition temperatures in line with values found in 3D materials at low densities, providing a robust way to obtain superconductivity in the low-density limit.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L220502] Published Wed Dec 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Sous, C. Zhang, M. Berciu, D. R. Reichman, B. V. Svistunov, N. V. Prokof'ev, and A. J. Millis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum gas microscopy of fermionic triangular-lattice Mott insulators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.L061301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.L061301"/>
        <updated>2023-12-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jirayu Mongkolkiattichai, Liyu Liu, Davis Garwood, Jin Yang, and Peter Schauss
The authors probe fermionic Mott insulators in a geometrically frustrated symmetric triangular lattice using a quantum gas microscope with single-site resolution. They demonstrate the detection of antiferromagnetic spin-spin correlations and perform thermometry by comparison to numerical calculations.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, L061301] Published Wed Dec 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jirayu Mongkolkiattichai, Liyu Liu, Davis Garwood, Jin Yang, and Peter Schauss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Signatures of Prethermalization in a Quenched Cavity-Mediated Long-Range Interacting Fermi Gas]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.243401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.243401"/>
        <updated>2023-12-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zemao Wu, Jijie Fan, Xue Zhang, Jiansheng Qi, and Haibin Wu
Relaxation dynamics of an ultracold Fermi gas inside an optical resonator are observed experimentally by quenching the system across the Dicke phase transition to reveal a prethermalized quantum state.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 243401] Published Tue Dec 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zemao Wu, Jijie Fan, Xue Zhang, Jiansheng Qi, and Haibin Wu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All-Optical GeV Electron Bunch Generation in a Laser-Plasma Accelerator via Truncated-Channel Injection]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.245001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.245001"/>
        <updated>2023-12-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Picksley, J. Chappell, E. Archer, N. Bourgeois, J. Cowley, D. R. Emerson, L. Feder, X. J. Gu, O. Jakobsson, A. J. Ross, W. Wang, R. Walczak, and S. M. Hooker
The judicious shaping of a tube of plasma by one laser enhances the properties of electron bunches accelerated by another.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 245001] Published Tue Dec 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Picksley, J. Chappell, E. Archer, N. Bourgeois, J. Cowley, D. R. Emerson, L. Feder, X. J. Gu, O. Jakobsson, A. J. Ross, W. Wang, R. Walczak, and S. M. Hooker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of gravitational lensing of the cosmic microwave background using SPT-3G 2018 data]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.122005</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.122005"/>
        <updated>2023-12-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Z. Pan et al.
This work presents the first gravitational lensing measurements with the 3G camera on the South Pole Telescope (SPT). Notably, it places constraints on key cosmological parameters consistent with those from SPT-SZ, SPTpol, ACT, and Planck.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 122005] Published Tue Dec 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Z. Pan &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symmetry-enriched criticality in a coupled spin ladder]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.245135</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.245135"/>
        <updated>2023-12-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Suman Mondal, Adhip Agarwala, Tapan Mishra, and Abhishodh Prakash
This work investigates the interplay between microscopic symmetries and the effective degrees of freedom that define the macroscopic phase of matter. Considering a spin-ladder model and tuning the parameters, a myriad of distinct symmetry-enriched critical states is shown. Although the effective description in each of these phases is identical, i.e., the compact boson conformal field theory, symmetries act on the fields in subtly different ways leading to sharp distinctions in the nature of observables, including the presence of topological edge modes.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 245135] Published Tue Dec 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Suman Mondal, Adhip Agarwala, Tapan Mishra, and Abhishodh Prakash</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Loss-induced Floquet non-Hermitian skin effect]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L220301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L220301"/>
        <updated>2023-12-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yaohua Li, Cuicui Lu, Shuang Zhang, and Yong-Chun Liu
A mechanism for a loss-induced Floquet non-Hermitian skin effect (NHSE) is proposed, where gain/loss combined with Floquet engineering leads to the NHSE. This mechanism utilizes periodic coupling, which is a well-established experimental method, to realize the NHSE through loss instead of nonreciprocal coupling. The key to this mechanism is the Floquet-induced next-nearest neighbor coupling. This proposal is also applicable to high-dimensional systems and can be realized in photonic waveguides and other related systems.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L220301] Published Tue Dec 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yaohua Li, Cuicui Lu, Shuang Zhang, and Yong-Chun Liu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mass Difference of Tritium and Helium-3]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.243002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.243002"/>
        <updated>2023-12-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Moisés Medina Restrepo and Edmund G. Myers
Measurement of the mass difference between tritium and helium-3 achieves better precision by a factor of three for the Q-value of tritium beta-decay.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 243002] Published Mon Dec 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Moisés Medina Restrepo and Edmund G. Myers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hyper Suprime-Cam Year 3 results: Cosmology from galaxy clustering and weak lensing with HSC and SDSS using the emulator based halo model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.123517</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.123517"/>
        <updated>2023-12-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hironao Miyatake et al.
A new analysis of the distribution of matter in the Universe continues to find a discrepancy in the clumpiness of dark matter in the late and early Universe, suggesting a fundamental error in the standard cosmological model.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 123517] Published Mon Dec 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hironao Miyatake &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hyper Suprime-Cam Year 3 results: Cosmology from cosmic shear two-point correlation functions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.123518</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.123518"/>
        <updated>2023-12-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xiangchong Li et al.
A new analysis of the distribution of matter in the Universe continues to find a discrepancy in the clumpiness of dark matter in the late and early Universe, suggesting a fundamental error in the standard cosmological model.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 123518] Published Mon Dec 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiangchong Li &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hyper Suprime-Cam Year 3 results: Cosmology from cosmic shear power spectra]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.123519</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.123519"/>
        <updated>2023-12-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Roohi Dalal et al.
A new analysis of the distribution of matter in the Universe continues to find a discrepancy in the clumpiness of dark matter in the late and early Universe, suggesting a fundamental error in the standard cosmological model.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 123519] Published Mon Dec 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Roohi Dalal &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hyper Suprime-Cam Year 3 results: Measurements of clustering of SDSS-BOSS galaxies, galaxy-galaxy lensing, and cosmic shear]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.123520</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.123520"/>
        <updated>2023-12-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Surhud More et al.
A new analysis of the distribution of matter in the Universe continues to find a discrepancy in the clumpiness of dark matter in the late and early Universe, suggesting a fundamental error in the standard cosmological model.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 123520] Published Mon Dec 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Surhud More &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hyper Suprime-Cam Year 3 results: Cosmology from galaxy clustering and weak lensing with HSC and SDSS using the minimal bias model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.123521</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.123521"/>
        <updated>2023-12-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sunao Sugiyama et al.
A new analysis of the distribution of matter in the Universe continues to find a discrepancy in the clumpiness of dark matter in the late and early Universe, suggesting a fundamental error in the standard cosmological model.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 123521] Published Mon Dec 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sunao Sugiyama &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Local structure, bonding, and asymmetry of $({({\mathrm{NH}}_{2})}_{2}\mathrm{CH}){\mathrm{PbBr}}_{3}, {\mathrm{CsPbBr}}_{3}$, and $({\mathrm{CH}}_{3}{\mathrm{NH}}_{3}){\mathrm{PbBr}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.214102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.214102"/>
        <updated>2023-12-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): F. Bridges, J. Gruzdas, C. MacKeen, K. Mayford, N. J. Weadock, V. Urena Baltazar, Y. Rakita, Louis Waquier, Julian A. Vigil, Hemamala I. Karunadasa, and M. F. Toney
The local structure of hybrid organic-inorganic halide perovskites is of considerable interest due to the impact on optoelectronic and ion-conducting properties. Here, it is shown that the lead bromide perovskites are nearly perfect at low temperature, with negligible static disorder, through a temperature-dependent x-ray absorption spectroscopy study. As the crystal heats up, two things happen: the organic molecular-ion motion changes the Pb-Br bond strength at the orthorhombic-tetragonal transition, and anharmonicity (C3) contributes to a significant thermal disorder at room temperature.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 214102] Published Mon Dec 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>F. Bridges, J. Gruzdas, C. MacKeen, K. Mayford, N. J. Weadock, V. Urena Baltazar, Y. Rakita, Louis Waquier, Julian A. Vigil, Hemamala I. Karunadasa, and M. F. Toney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Engineering entangled coherent states of magnons and phonons via a transmon qubit]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.224416</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.224416"/>
        <updated>2023-12-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marios Kounalakis, Silvia Viola Kusminskiy, and Yaroslav M. Blanter
Entangled coherent states exhibit a special form of entanglement between two or more bosonic modes, which is useful for several tasks in quantum information and fundamental studies of quantum mechanics. Here, the authors propose a scheme for generating and controlling such states between distant magnets or mechanical resonators, using a superconducting qubit that couples via its inductance to the quanta of the collective magnetic excitations (magnons) or the vibrational excitations in mechanical beams (phonons). The results establish a promising platform for quantum information using magnonic and mechanical hybrid quantum devices.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 224416] Published Mon Dec 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marios Kounalakis, Silvia Viola Kusminskiy, and Yaroslav M. Blanter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Single-electron routing in a silicon quantum-dot array]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235308</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235308"/>
        <updated>2023-12-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Takeru Utsugi, Takuma Kuno, Noriyuki Lee, Ryuta Tsuchiya, Toshiyuki Mine, Digh Hisamoto, Shinichi Saito, and Hiroyuki Mizuno
Free electron transport on two-dimensional quantum dot arrays has the potential to dramatically improve the efficiency of quantum computing implemented on a solid-state device. Here, the authors have successfully controlled the paths of electrons on a silicon quantum dot array using a single-electron router. They perform proof-of-principle experiments for single-electron routing, which selectively transports individual electrons along a desired path, and develop the theory for estimating a minimum error rate of the routing.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 235308] Published Mon Dec 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Takeru Utsugi, Takuma Kuno, Noriyuki Lee, Ryuta Tsuchiya, Toshiyuki Mine, Digh Hisamoto, Shinichi Saito, and Hiroyuki Mizuno</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Localized $f$-electron magnetism in the semimetal ${\mathrm{Ce}}_{3}{\mathrm{Bi}}_{4}{\mathrm{Au}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.245125</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.245125"/>
        <updated>2023-12-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. O. Ajeesh, S. K. Kushwaha, S. M. Thomas, J. D. Thompson, M. K. Chan, N. Harrison, J. M. Tomczak, and P. F. S. Rosa
Cerium-based compounds crystallizing in the cubic Ce3X4T3 (X=Bi, Sb and T=transition metal) structure present a wide variety of semiconducting ground states ranging from a conventional band gap in Ce3Sb4Au3 to prototypical Kondo insulating behavior in Ce3Bi4Pt3. The variation in physical properties among members stems from the delicate interplay between the crystal lattice, electron filling, and the hybridization between f electrons and the conduction electron sea. Here, the authors show that the substitution of Pt by Au forces cerium moments into a localized state rendering Ce3Bi4Au3 a magnetically ordered semimetal. These experimental results combined with realistic many-body simulations enable a broader comparison between Ce3X4T3 compounds and shed light on the distinct ground states in this family.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 245125] Published Mon Dec 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. O. Ajeesh, S. K. Kushwaha, S. M. Thomas, J. D. Thompson, M. K. Chan, N. Harrison, J. M. Tomczak, and P. F. S. Rosa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fate of Quasiparticles at High Temperature in the Correlated Metal ${\mathrm{Sr}}_{2}{\mathrm{RuO}}_{4}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.236502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.236502"/>
        <updated>2023-12-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Hunter, S. Beck, E. Cappelli, F. Margot, M. Straub, Y. Alexanian, G. Gatti, M. D. Watson, T. K. Kim, C. Cacho, N. C. Plumb, M. Shi, M. Radović, D. A. Sokolov, A. P. Mackenzie, M. Zingl, J. Mravlje, A. Georges, F. Baumberger, and A. Tamai
An analysis of ARPES data from Sr2RuO4 shows that quasiparticles in a correlated metal vanish with increasing temperature by dissolving into the incoherent background because of excessive broadening arising from super-Planckian scattering.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 236502] Published Fri Dec 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Hunter, S. Beck, E. Cappelli, F. Margot, M. Straub, Y. Alexanian, G. Gatti, M. D. Watson, T. K. Kim, C. Cacho, N. C. Plumb, M. Shi, M. Radović, D. A. Sokolov, A. P. Mackenzie, M. Zingl, J. Mravlje, A. Georges, F. Baumberger, and A. Tamai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Excitonic Interactions and Mechanism for Ultrafast Interlayer Photoexcited Response in van der Waals Heterostructures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.236904</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.236904"/>
        <updated>2023-12-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chen Hu, Mit H. Naik, Yang-Hao Chan, and Steven G. Louie
An excitonic mechanism for ultrafast optical responses converts photoexcited intralayer to interlayer excitations in transition metal dichalcogenides.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 236904] Published Fri Dec 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chen Hu, Mit H. Naik, Yang-Hao Chan, and Steven G. Louie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fundamental Drivers of Electrochemical Barriers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.238003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.238003"/>
        <updated>2023-12-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xi Chen, Georg Kastlunger, and Andrew A. Peterson
The basic driving forces behind electrochemical reaction barriers are investigated using the solvated jellium method, uncovering their differences from conventional reactions at surfaces in nonelectrochemical systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 238003] Published Fri Dec 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xi Chen, Georg Kastlunger, and Andrew A. Peterson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bayesian and frequentist investigation of prior effects in EFT of LSS analyses of full-shape BOSS and eBOSS data]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.123514</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.123514"/>
        <updated>2023-12-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Emil Brinch Holm, Laura Herold, Théo Simon, Elisa G. M. Ferreira, Steen Hannestad, Vivian Poulin, and Thomas Tram
The authors employ a frequentist profile likelihood analysis, and confirm that Effective Field Theory of Large Scale Structure parameters are sensitive to the choice of priors in Bayesian analyses. They conclude that better data will be needed to constrain key cosmological parameters such as σ₈ .

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 123514] Published Fri Dec 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emil Brinch Holm, Laura Herold, Théo Simon, Elisa G. M. Ferreira, Steen Hannestad, Vivian Poulin, and Thomas Tram</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[${\mathrm{Pb}}_{9}\mathrm{Cu}{({\mathrm{PO}}_{4})}_{6}{(\mathrm{OH})}_{2}$: Phonon bands, localized flat-band magnetism, models, and chemical analysis]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235127</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235127"/>
        <updated>2023-12-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yi Jiang, Scott B. Lee, Jonah Herzog-Arbeitman, Jiabin Yu, Xiaolong Feng, Haoyu Hu, Dumitru Călugăru, Parker S. Brodale, Eoghan L. Gormley, Maia G. Vergniory, Claudia Felser, S. Blanco-Canosa, Christopher H. Hendon, Leslie M. Schoop, and B. Andrei Bernevig
Doped lead apatite (LK-99) has been proposed as a candidate ambient temperature and pressure superconductor, a dramatic claim requiring careful investigation from experiment and theory. Here, the authors synthesize an LK-99 sample and find a multiphase, transparent material that does not support high-temperature superconductivity. This is in agreement with ab initio calculations here that suggest the copper dopant does not meaningfully enter the structure and that the flat bands they generate at the Fermi level are largely unhybridized, with no quantum geometry to support a superfluid state.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 235127] Published Fri Dec 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yi Jiang, Scott B. Lee, Jonah Herzog-Arbeitman, Jiabin Yu, Xiaolong Feng, Haoyu Hu, Dumitru Călugăru, Parker S. Brodale, Eoghan L. Gormley, Maia G. Vergniory, Claudia Felser, S. Blanco-Canosa, Christopher H. Hendon, Leslie M. Schoop, and B. Andrei Bernevig</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Acoustic cloning]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.064014</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.064014"/>
        <updated>2023-12-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jonas Müller, Theodor S. Becker, Xun Li, Johannes Aichele, Marc Serra-Garcia, Johan O.A. Robertsson, and Dirk-Jan van Manen
You might hear an echo in the mountains, but can you hear your voice reflecting from the mug on your desk? Probably not: The intensity of that reflected sound is negligible, compared to the other reflections in your office…and what if we put out more mugs? Acoustic cloning, a form of holography, allows us to study acoustic wave propagation and reflection from a physical scatterer, even with modifications to that object. This study presents both theoretical framework and experimental implementation. The method is expected to be widely applicable in all domains of acoustic scattering, such as material characterization, active metamaterials, and virtual-acoustics applications.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 064014] Published Fri Dec 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonas Müller, Theodor S. Becker, Xun Li, Johannes Aichele, Marc Serra-Garcia, Johan O.A. Robertsson, and Dirk-Jan van Manen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Repeated Cyclogenesis on Hot-Exoplanet Atmospheres with Deep Heating]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.231201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.231201"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jack W. Skinner, Joonas Nättilä, and James Y-K. Cho
Supercomputer simulations of the weather on a hot Jupiter reveal a previously unseen storm pattern in which cyclones are repeatedly generated and destroyed.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 231201] Published Thu Dec 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jack W. Skinner, Joonas Nättilä, and James Y-K. Cho</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First-Principles Approach for Coupled Quantum Dynamics of Electrons and Protons in Heterogeneous Systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.238002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.238002"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jianhang Xu, Ruiyi Zhou, Volker Blum, Tao E. Li, Sharon Hammes-Schiffer, and Yosuke Kanai
Extension of the real-time NEO-DFT method to periodic systems can help simulate the coupled quantum dynamics of electrons and protons in complex heterogeneous systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 238002] Published Thu Dec 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jianhang Xu, Ruiyi Zhou, Volker Blum, Tao E. Li, Sharon Hammes-Schiffer, and Yosuke Kanai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic lift enhancement mechanism of dragonfly wing model by vortex-corrugation interaction]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.123101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.123101"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yusuke Fujita and Makoto Iima
Dragonfly wings, with their unique corrugated structure, may achieve superior aerodynamic performance in specific flight conditions, although these conditions are not yet fully understood. This led us to investigate the vortex dynamics and lift generation as a corrugated wing transitions from a stationary state to translational motion. The results reveal that suppression of secondary vortices generated on the wing significantly improves the overall performance of corrugated wings. This advances our understanding of flight dynamics and can also contribute to applications in engineering and biomimicry.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 123101] Published Thu Dec 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yusuke Fujita and Makoto Iima</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information content in continuous attractor neural networks is preserved in the presence of moderate disordered background connectivity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.064301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.064301"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tobias Kühn and Rémi Monasson
It is known that information such as the position of an animal can be represented in a recurrent attractor neural network by localized bumps of activity of neurons. This work addresses the question of how heterogeneities in the interactions of neurons affect the accuracy of information storage. The authors calculate the Fisher information as a function of the intensity of disordered interactions. They find that moderate disorder does not wipe out all information in their model.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 064301] Published Thu Dec 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tobias Kühn and Rémi Monasson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Possible large $CP$ violation in charmed ${\mathrm{Λ}}_{b}$ decays]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.L111901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.L111901"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yin-Fa Shen, Jian-Peng Wang, and Qin Qin
Researchers predict a large “CP” violation for the decay of a baryon that contains a bottom quark, a finding that has implications for how physicists understand the Universe.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, L111901] Published Thu Dec 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yin-Fa Shen, Jian-Peng Wang, and Qin Qin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetic-field periodic quantum Sondheimer oscillations in thin-film graphite]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235411</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235411"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Toshihiro Taen, Andhika Kiswandhi, and Toshihito Osada
Conventional quantum oscillations are periodic in an inverse of magnetic fields. Here, the authors observe magnetic-field periodic oscillations in a graphite thin film under magnetic fields where only two Landau levels remain. At this quasiquantum limit, they propose a new quantum oscillation mechanism: the quantum Sondheimer effect. The oscillations arise from the formation of the resonant modes periodically appearing in the magnetic fields. The period is inversely proportional to the film thickness, demonstrating its out-of-plane electron motion nature.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 235411] Published Thu Dec 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Toshihiro Taen, Andhika Kiswandhi, and Toshihito Osada</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Superresolution magnetic imaging by a Josephson junction via holographic reconstruction of ${I}_{c}(H)$ modulation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.064012</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.064012"/>
        <updated>2023-12-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Razmik A. Hovhannisyan, Taras Golod, and Vladimir M. Krasnov
Magnetic sensors generally exhibit a trade-off between spatial resolution and field sensitivity: As sensor size decreases, resolution improves but sensitivity deteriorates. This study reveals that the field distribution in a superconducting Josephson junction can be inferred by analyzing the diffractionlike magnetic field modulation of the critical current Ic. Here the spatial resolution is constrained solely by the field range of the Ic(H) pattern and is unrelated to the junction’s size. A remarkable feature of this detection method is that high spatial resolution accompanies high field sensitivity.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 064012] Published Thu Dec 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Razmik A. Hovhannisyan, Taras Golod, and Vladimir M. Krasnov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2D Helium Atom Diffraction from a Microscopic Spot]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.236202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.236202"/>
        <updated>2023-12-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nick A. von Jeinsen, Sam M. Lambrick, Matthew Bergin, Aleksandar Radić, Boyao Liu, Dan Seremet, Andrew P. Jardine, and David J. Ward
Researchers have developed an atom-diffraction imaging method with micrometer spatial resolution, which may allow new applications in material characterization.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 236202] Published Wed Dec 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nick A. von Jeinsen, Sam M. Lambrick, Matthew Bergin, Aleksandar Radić, Boyao Liu, Dan Seremet, Andrew P. Jardine, and David J. Ward</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mechanism of Ultraviolet-Induced CO Desorption from CO Ice: Role of Vibrational Relaxation Highlighted]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.238001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.238001"/>
        <updated>2023-12-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Samuel Del Fré, Alejandro Rivero Santamaría, Denis Duflot, Romain Basalgète, Géraldine Féraud, Mathieu Bertin, Jean-Hugues Fillion, and Maurice Monnerville
Molecular “kicks” induced by ultraviolet light are predicted to cause carbon monoxide molecules to be released from the icy layers that cover cosmic dust.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 238001] Published Wed Dec 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Del Fré, Alejandro Rivero Santamaría, Denis Duflot, Romain Basalgète, Géraldine Féraud, Mathieu Bertin, Jean-Hugues Fillion, and Maurice Monnerville</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Viscous free-surface cusps: Local solution]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.124001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.124001"/>
        <updated>2023-12-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Eggers
In the image, the free surface between a liquid and air is deformed into a sharp cusp by the rapid rotation of the cylinder on the left. We show that such a structure is a generic feature of viscous flow, and study its properties. This is important, since air can enter the fluid through the cusp’s tip, and thus become entrained into the interior of the fluid.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 124001] Published Wed Dec 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Eggers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visualizing the merger of tunably coupled graphene quantum dots]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235407</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235407"/>
        <updated>2023-12-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Daniel Walkup, Fereshte Ghahari, Steven R. Blankenship, Kenji Watanabe, Takashi Taniguchi, Nikolai B. Zhitenev, and Joseph A. Stroscio
The ability to pattern and simultaneously study a nanometer-scale potential landscape within hBN-based graphene devices using scanning tunneling microscopy (STM) opens a path for detailed investigation of model quantum systems. Here, the authors create a double-well potential and applied a strong magnetic field to induce Landau levels and the formation of quantum dots with single-electron charging characteristics. The system can be broadly tuned form weakly coupled dots to combined single dot while STM provides multiple measurement and manipulation modalities.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 235407] Published Wed Dec 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Daniel Walkup, Fereshte Ghahari, Steven R. Blankenship, Kenji Watanabe, Takashi Taniguchi, Nikolai B. Zhitenev, and Joseph A. Stroscio</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal productivity patterns in research careers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043203</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043203"/>
        <updated>2023-12-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Andre S. Sunahara, Matjaž Perc, and Haroldo V. Ribeiro
Methods from time series analysis, dimensionality reduction, and network science are combined to show evidence for the natural emergence of six universal patterns of productivity in scientific careers: constant, u-shaped, decreasing, periodic, increasing, and canonical curves. Canonical curves are the most prevalent pattern, but contrary to expectations, productivity peaks occur much more frequently around midcareer rather than early.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 043203] Published Tue Dec 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andre S. Sunahara, Matjaž Perc, and Haroldo V. Ribeiro</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Precise Predictions for the Associated Production of a $W$ Boson with a Top-Antitop Quark Pair at the LHC]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.231901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.231901"/>
        <updated>2023-12-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Luca Buonocore, Simone Devoto, Massimiliano Grazzini, Stefan Kallweit, Javier Mazzitelli, Luca Rottoli, and Chiara Savoini
Significant reduction in the perturbative uncertainty due to the first second-order QCD calculation of the hadroproduction of a W boson in association with a top-antitop quark pair could lead to stringent tests of the standard model.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 231901] Published Tue Dec 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luca Buonocore, Simone Devoto, Massimiliano Grazzini, Stefan Kallweit, Javier Mazzitelli, Luca Rottoli, and Chiara Savoini</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving Crystal Phases of a Quantum Wigner Solid in an Ultra-High-Quality 2D Electron System]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.236501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.236501"/>
        <updated>2023-12-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): P. T. Madathil, K. A. Villegas Rosales, Y. J. Chung, K. W. West, K. W. Baldwin, L. N. Pfeiffer, L. W. Engel, and M. Shayegan
Researchers have precisely measured the electrical-transport properties of a highly ordered Wigner solid—a crystalline state formed of electrons rather than atoms.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 236501] Published Tue Dec 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>P. T. Madathil, K. A. Villegas Rosales, Y. J. Chung, K. W. West, K. W. Baldwin, L. N. Pfeiffer, L. W. Engel, and M. Shayegan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Postquantum Theory of Classical Gravity?]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041040</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041040"/>
        <updated>2023-12-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jonathan Oppenheim
A proposed model unites quantum theory with classical gravity by assuming that states evolve in a probabilistic way, like a game of chance.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 041040] Published Mon Dec 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Oppenheim</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Connecting the Many-Body Chern Number to Luttinger’s Theorem through Středa’s Formula]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.236601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.236601"/>
        <updated>2023-12-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lucila Peralta Gavensky, Subir Sachdev, and Nathan Goldman
The many-body Chern number of a two-dimensional quantum anomalous Hall insulator can be decomposed as the sum of the Green-function-based invariant N3 and a correction that vanishes whenever the system satisfies Luttinger’s theorem.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 236601] Published Mon Dec 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lucila Peralta Gavensky, Subir Sachdev, and Nathan Goldman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remarks on boundaries, anomalies, and noninvertible symmetries]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.125005</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.125005"/>
        <updated>2023-12-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yichul Choi, Brandon C. Rayhaun, Yaman Sanghavi, and Shu-Heng Shao
The authors provide a comprehensive study of the role of boundary conditions in the presence of generalized non-invertible symmetries, beginning with the question of when boundary conditions are symmetric under those symmetries. They find different categories of symmetric boundary conditions (which would be identical under normal symmetries) and discuss their relation to ’t Hooft anomalies, gauging, and RG flows.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 125005] Published Mon Dec 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yichul Choi, Brandon C. Rayhaun, Yaman Sanghavi, and Shu-Heng Shao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black hole singularity resolution in $D=2$ via duality-invariant ${α}^{′}$ corrections]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.126006</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.126006"/>
        <updated>2023-12-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tomas Codina, Olaf Hohm, and Barton Zwiebach
The authors study the full α′ (higher derivative) corrections for a two-dimensional (non-critical) string theory and the associated black hole solutions. The exact form of these corrections is not known or analytically computable but the authors use an extremely skilled representation to parametrize all T-dually invariant higher derivative corrections. They find standard black holes with singularities as well as regular, nonsingular black hole solutions with a horizon. The latter do not seem to lie in the string theory set of this theory space.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 126006] Published Mon Dec 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tomas Codina, Olaf Hohm, and Barton Zwiebach</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Decodable hybrid dynamics of open quantum systems with ${\mathbb{Z}}_{2}$ symmetry]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.214302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.214302"/>
        <updated>2023-12-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yaodong Li and Matthew P. A. Fisher
Within a toy model of open quantum systems, this work discusses the relation between measurement-induced phase transitions (MIPTs) of quantum entanglement and quantum error correction (QEC), which also has a phase transition at an “error threshold”. In particular, the authors show how concepts from QEC can facilitate the observation of MIPTs and, conversely, how insights from MIPTs can inform the design of decoding algorithms.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 214302] Published Mon Dec 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yaodong Li and Matthew P. A. Fisher</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding muon diffusion in perovskite oxides below room temperature based on harmonic transition state theory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.224301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.224301"/>
        <updated>2023-12-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. U. Ito, W. Higemoto, and K. Shimomura
In certain perovskite oxides, positive muon (μ+) diffusion occurs with a small activation energy of ∼0.1 eV, contrary to the conventional assumption in μ+ spin spectroscopy for oxides that μ+ is tightly bound to an oxygen atom and immobile below room temperature. Here, the authors analyze the over-barrier diffusion of μ+ observed in KTaO3 using harmonic transition state theory and show that μ+ zero-point vibrations may significantly lower the activation barrier to facilitate fast μ+ diffusion below room temperature.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 224301] Published Mon Dec 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. U. Ito, W. Higemoto, and K. Shimomura</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Importance of nonuniform Brillouin zone sampling for <i>ab initio</i> Bethe-Salpeter equation calculations of exciton binding energies in crystalline solids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235117</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.235117"/>
        <updated>2023-12-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Antonios M. Alvertis, Aurélie Champagne, Mauro Del Ben, Felipe H. da Jornada, Diana Y. Qiu, Marina R. Filip, and Jeffrey B. Neaton
Excitons in solids often reside in a narrow region of reciprocal space. Yet, it is standard for first-principles exciton calculations to sample the entire Brillouin zone uniformly, at great computational cost and resulting in underconverged exciton binding energies. Here, the authors demonstrate that a straightforward-to-implement nonuniform sampling approach yields highly converged exciton binding energies, which can significantly differ from previous best theoretical estimates, at a fraction of the computational expense of uniform sampling approaches. This will enable the prediction of exciton binding energies of increasingly complex materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 235117] Published Mon Dec 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Antonios M. Alvertis, Aurélie Champagne, Mauro Del Ben, Felipe H. da Jornada, Diana Y. Qiu, Marina R. Filip, and Jeffrey B. Neaton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Longitudinal coupling between a ${\mathrm{Si}/\mathrm{Si}}_{1−x}{\mathrm{Ge}}_{x}$ double quantum dot and an off-chip $\mathrm{Ti}\mathrm{N}$ resonator]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.064005</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.064005"/>
        <updated>2023-12-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Corrigan, Benjamin Harpt, Nathan Holman, Rusko Ruskov, Piotr Marciniec, D. Rosenberg, D. Yost, R. Das, William D. Oliver, R. McDermott, Charles Tahan, Mark Friesen, and M.A. Eriksson
Far-off-resonant couplings are useful in quantum computing because they do not require special tunings of device components, but still await further exploration. The authors use a “flip-chip” coupling geometry to unequivocally demonstrate the presence of a far-off-resonant longitudinal coupling between a quantum-dot charge qubit and a microwave cavity, which can be turned on or off at will. This work provides a powerful and versatile tool for reading out and coupling quantum-dot qubits over large distances.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 064005] Published Mon Dec 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Corrigan, Benjamin Harpt, Nathan Holman, Rusko Ruskov, Piotr Marciniec, D. Rosenberg, D. Yost, R. Das, William D. Oliver, R. McDermott, Charles Tahan, Mark Friesen, and M.A. Eriksson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fault-tolerant qubit encoding using a spin-7/2 qudit]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.062403</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.062403"/>
        <updated>2023-12-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sumin Lim, Junjie Liu, and Arzhang Ardavan
The authors propose a quantum memory, implemented on a spin-7/2 nucleus coupled to an electron spin-1/2 qubit, which provides X, Y, and Z error correction using fewer quantum resources than the equivalently effective qubit-based protocols.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 062403] Published Mon Dec 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sumin Lim, Junjie Liu, and Arzhang Ardavan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlocal Intrinsic Fracture Energy of Polymerlike Networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.228102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.228102"/>
        <updated>2023-12-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bolei Deng, Shu Wang, Chase Hartquist, and Xuanhe Zhao
The crack resistance of polymer materials is explained by a new model that incorporates a network of stretchable polymer chains.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 228102] Published Fri Dec 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bolei Deng, Shu Wang, Chase Hartquist, and Xuanhe Zhao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ergodic properties of Brownian motion under stochastic resetting]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.064102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.064102"/>
        <updated>2023-12-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): E. Barkai, R. Flaquer-Galmés, and V. Méndez
Stochastic processes with resetting can exhibit different ergodic behaviors depending on the distribution of resetting times. For one-dimensional Brownian motion with resetting, the authors find two ergodic transitions, one of which is related to a competition between returns to the origin by resetting and returns by the diffusion process itself.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 064102] Published Fri Dec 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>E. Barkai, R. Flaquer-Galmés, and V. Méndez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>