<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-09-02T00:41:12.673Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-09-02T00:41:12.673Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entangling quantum memories via heralded photonic Bell measurement]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033149</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033149"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Prajit Dhara, Dirk Englund, and Saikat Guha
Analytical modeling of a quantum communication link is based on a photonic swap in the middle architecture. The effect of network and hardware nonidealities on the distributed entangled state is analyzed with the density operator formalism and with implications on the choice of distillation circuits of heralded states.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 033149] Published Fri Sep 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Prajit Dhara, Dirk Englund, and Saikat Guha</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Combining electron-phonon and dynamical mean-field theory calculations of correlated materials: Transport in the correlated metal ${\mathrm{Sr}}_{2}{\mathrm{RuO}}_{4}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.093801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.093801"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): David J. Abramovitch, Jin-Jian Zhou, Jernej Mravlje, Antoine Georges, and Marco Bernardi
In correlated quantum materials, strong electronic interactions lead to unconventional transport and exotic phases. Dynamical mean field theory (DMFT) calculations can describe the purely electronic dynamics in these materials. Here, the authors integrate into this framework the interactions between electrons and lattice vibrations (phonons). They apply this method to the correlated metal Sr2RuO4, elucidating the respective contributions of electron-electron and electron-phonon scattering to the resistivity and spectral functions. The method presented in this work enables future studies of electron-phonon physics in various classes of correlated materials, including Mott insulators, high-Tc superconductors and strange metals.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 093801] Published Fri Sep 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David J. Abramovitch, Jin-Jian Zhou, Jernej Mravlje, Antoine Georges, and Marco Bernardi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast Particle Acceleration in 3D Hybrid Simulations of Quasiperpendicular Shocks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.095201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.095201"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Luca Orusa and Damiano Caprioli
3D hybrid kinetic simulations show how ions can be spontaneously and efficiently accelerated by shock-drift acceleration at nonrelativistic quasiperpendicular shocks, ubiquitous in space and astrophysical environments.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 095201] Published Fri Sep 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luca Orusa and Damiano Caprioli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Structural Transformation between a Nematic Loose Packing and a Randomly Stacked Close Packing of Granular Disks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.098202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.098202"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yunhao Ding, Jing Yang, Chenyang Wang, Zhichao Wang, Jianqi Li, Bingwen Hu, and Chengjie Xia
Experiments with coin-sized plastic disks have uncovered an unexpected packing behavior in which the disks form randomly oriented stacks.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 098202] Published Fri Sep 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yunhao Ding, Jing Yang, Chenyang Wang, Zhichao Wang, Jianqi Li, Bingwen Hu, and Chengjie Xia</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Caterpillar like motion of droplet in a shear flow]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.093601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.093601"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Chahine, J. Sebilleau, R. Mathis, and D. Legendre
A special caterpillar like motion is reported for glycerin droplets sliding on a horizontal hydrophobic substrate under the influence of a shear flow. The droplet elongates in the flow direction adopting a rivulet shape with the development of waves resulting in a caterpillar like motion.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 093601] Published Fri Sep 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Chahine, J. Sebilleau, R. Mathis, and D. Legendre</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microtubule search-and-capture model evaluates the effect of chromosomal volume conservation on spindle assembly during mitosis]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.034401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.034401"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pinaki Nayak, Saptarshi Chatterjee, and Raja Paul
The authors study computationally how the speed and accuracy of mitotic spindle assembly depend on several parameters, such as chromosome number and volume and cell size and shape. This work is a step toward understanding the large variation in chromosome number found in some closely related species.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 034401] Published Fri Sep 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pinaki Nayak, Saptarshi Chatterjee, and Raja Paul</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin wave Hamiltonian and anomalous scattering in ${\mathrm{NiPS}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.104402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.104402"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Scheie, Pyeongjae Park, J. W. Villanova, G. E. Granroth, C. L. Sarkis, Hao Zhang, M. B. Stone, Je-Geun Park, S. Okamoto, T. Berlijn, and D. A. Tennant
Magnetic van der Waals materials have many proposed technological uses, but predicting their behavior requires understanding their magnetic interactions. Here, the authors present a comprehensive study of the spin exchange Hamiltonian of semiconducting magnet NiPS3. Using inelastic neutron scattering and first-principles density functional theory calculations, the authors derive a spin-exchange Hamiltonian able to explain spin excitations observed with other probes. Comparing semiclassical simulations against the experimental neutron spectrum reveals an anomalous suppression of low-energy magnetism in NiPS3, signaling nontrivial physics lurking in its ground state.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 104402] Published Fri Sep 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Scheie, Pyeongjae Park, J. W. Villanova, G. E. Granroth, C. L. Sarkis, Hao Zhang, M. B. Stone, Je-Geun Park, S. Okamoto, T. Berlijn, and D. A. Tennant</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Real Hopf insulator]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.125101"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hyeongmuk Lim, Sunje Kim, and Bohm-Jung Yang
While stable and fragile topological insulators (TIs) are blind to unoccupied states, defining a delicate TI depends critically on the conduction band. Here, the authors report a new delicate TI, dubbed a “real Hopf insulator” (RHI), in a spinless PT-symmetric fermion system in three dimensions. Having two topological invariants characterizing both conduction and valence bands, the RHI features a bulk-boundary correspondence and reverting Thouless pump that must be described by using both bands simultaneously. This sheds light on the generic properties of delicate TIs.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 125101] Published Fri Sep 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hyeongmuk Lim, Sunje Kim, and Bohm-Jung Yang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Heat Flow through Nonideal Contacts in Hot-Carrier Solar Cells]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.034001"/>
        <updated>2023-09-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Abhinav S. Sharma, Muhammad Hanif, Stephen P. Bremner, Michael P. Nielsen, Murad J. Y. Tayebjee, Fiacre E. Rougieux, Nicholas J. Ekins-Daukes, and Andreas Pusch
Hot-carrier solar cells (HCSCs) are one option for achieving solar-energy conversion more efficiently than conventional single-junction cells. Due to challenging material requirements, the development of HCSCs has been limited to proof-of-concept devices. By examining heat flow in HCSCs, this study suggests expanding their characterization to include the study of carrier temperatures for various contact configurations and biases. The authors show that hotter is not always better: High carrier temperatures may be a sign of excessively high barriers to extraction—an insight that could adjust expectations and interpretations of hot-carrier temperatures in devices.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 034001] Published Fri Sep 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhinav S. Sharma, Muhammad Hanif, Stephen P. Bremner, Michael P. Nielsen, Murad J. Y. Tayebjee, Fiacre E. Rougieux, Nicholas J. Ekins-Daukes, and Andreas Pusch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extremal Kerr Black Holes as Amplifiers of New Physics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.091402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.091402"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gary T. Horowitz, Maciej Kolanowski, Grant N. Remmen, and Jorge E. Santos
A theoretical analysis suggests that certain rotating black holes might be sensitive probes of quantum gravity.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 091402] Published Thu Aug 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gary T. Horowitz, Maciej Kolanowski, Grant N. Remmen, and Jorge E. Santos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anchoring Effect of an Obstacle in the Silo Unclogging Process]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.098201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.098201"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rodrigo Caitano, Angel Garcimartín, and Iker Zuriguel
A new experiment on granular discharge from a silo demonstrates that an obstacle near the outlet does not always reduce, and in some cases can increase, the likelihood of clogging.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 098201] Published Thu Aug 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rodrigo Caitano, Angel Garcimartín, and Iker Zuriguel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linear scaling relationship of Néel temperature and dominant magnons in pyrochlore ruthenates]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.054443</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.054443"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jae Hyuck Lee, Dirk Wulferding, Junkyoung Kim, Dongjoon Song, Seung Ryong Park, and Changyoung Kim
Transition metal pyrochlore oxides are prototypical platforms for exploring and engineering a plethora of magnetic phases based on the intimate interplay of charge, lattice, and spin degrees of freedom. Here, the authors conduct Raman spectroscopic experiments on a series of pyrochlore ruthenates and identify one-magnon modes. They find a remarkably simple proportional relation between the Néel temperature and magnon energy, inferring that the compounds host common spin structures. This work showcases the straightforward tunability of the magnon band structure based on the A-site ion in A2Ru2O7.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 054443] Published Thu Aug 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jae Hyuck Lee, Dirk Wulferding, Junkyoung Kim, Dongjoon Song, Seung Ryong Park, and Changyoung Kim</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[$2×{10}^{−13}$ Fractional Laser-Frequency Stability with a 7-cm Unequal-Arm Mach-Zehnder Interferometer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024078</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024078"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Victor Huarcaya, Miguel Dovale Álvarez, Daniel Penkert, Stefano Gozzo, Pablo Martínez Cano, Kohei Yamamoto, Juan José Esteban Delgado, Moritz Mehmet, Karsten Danzmann, and Gerhard Heinzel
To reach subpicometer sensitivities in the millihertz frequency range, inertial sensors based on laser interferometry must reduce laser-frequency noise, typically by using ultrastable optical reference cavities or atomic or molecular references. This study presents a simpler solution: a quasimonolithic Mach-Zehnder interferometer with intentionally mismatched arm lengths, plus two photodiodes at balanced output ports. Here structural stability is transferred to laser frequency via amplification, integration, and feedback of the balanced-detection signal. Improvements to the thermal design and isolation of a compact setup allow stabilities similar to those of reference systems.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 024078] Published Thu Aug 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor Huarcaya, Miguel Dovale Álvarez, Daniel Penkert, Stefano Gozzo, Pablo Martínez Cano, Kohei Yamamoto, Juan José Esteban Delgado, Moritz Mehmet, Karsten Danzmann, and Gerhard Heinzel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Piezostrain as a Local Handle to Control Gyrotropic Dynamics of Magnetic Vortices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024080</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024080"/>
        <updated>2023-08-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vadym Iurchuk, Serhii Sorokin, Jürgen Lindner, Jürgen Fassbender, and Attila Kákay
Power-saving solutions are sought for manipulating the dynamics of magnetic microelements in emerging spintronic rf devices. The authors show that local piezostrain is an efficient extrinsic means to control the gyrotropic motion of magnetic vortices, with low voltages and all-electrical operation. In addition, they find that the frequency-strain tuning ratio scales inversely with the size of the vortex-based microdevice. Their approach offers an extra dimension in the frequency tuning of vortex-based spintronic oscillators.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 024080] Published Thu Aug 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vadym Iurchuk, Serhii Sorokin, Jürgen Lindner, Jürgen Fassbender, and Attila Kákay</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Observation of Electron Scattering from Online-Produced Radioactive Target]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.092502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.092502"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): K. Tsukada, Y. Abe, A. Enokizono, T. Goke, M. Hara, Y. Honda, T. Hori, S. Ichikawa, Y. Ito, K. Kurita, C. Legris, Y. Maehara, T. Ohnishi, R. Ogawara, T. Suda, T. Tamae, M. Wakasugi, M. Watanabe, and H. Wauke
The first electron-scattering experiment off unstable radioisotopes marks a milestone for understanding the shape of exotic atomic nuclei.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 092502] Published Wed Aug 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>K. Tsukada, Y. Abe, A. Enokizono, T. Goke, M. Hara, Y. Honda, T. Hori, S. Ichikawa, Y. Ito, K. Kurita, C. Legris, Y. Maehara, T. Ohnishi, R. Ogawara, T. Suda, T. Tamae, M. Wakasugi, M. Watanabe, and H. Wauke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photocurrent Induced by a Bicircular Light Drive in Centrosymmetric Systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.096301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.096301"/>
        <updated>2023-08-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuya Ikeda, Sota Kitamura, and Takahiro Morimoto
A flower-petal pattern of light could induce electrical currents in a wider array of crystalline materials.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 096301] Published Wed Aug 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuya Ikeda, Sota Kitamura, and Takahiro Morimoto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symmetry of Open Quantum Systems: Classification of Dissipative Quantum Chaos]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.030328</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.030328"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kohei Kawabata, Anish Kulkarni, Jiachen Li, Tokiro Numasawa, and Shinsei Ryu
A novel method to classify open quantum systems in terms of non-Hermitian operators sheds light on the interplay between coherent and dissipative dynamics, with applications to quantum chaos.

[PRX Quantum 4, 030328] Published Tue Aug 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kohei Kawabata, Anish Kulkarni, Jiachen Li, Tokiro Numasawa, and Shinsei Ryu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of the Time-Integrated $CP$ Asymmetry in ${D}^{0}→{K}^{−}{K}^{+}$ Decays]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.091802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.091802"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Aaij et al. (LHCb Collaboration)
The measurement of time-integrated CP asymmetry in the Cabibbo-suppressed D0→K−K+ decay results in the first evidence for direct CP violation in a specific D0 decay mode.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 091802] Published Tue Aug 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Aaij &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHCb Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atypical Sliding and Moiré Ferroelectricity in Pure Multilayer Graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.096801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.096801"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Liu Yang, Shiping Ding, Jinhua Gao, and Menghao Wu
First-principles calculations show that pure graphene multilayers with more than three layers exhibit atypical sliding ferroelectricity.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 096801] Published Tue Aug 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liu Yang, Shiping Ding, Jinhua Gao, and Menghao Wu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interplay of self, epiphany, and positive actions in shaping individual careers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.024314</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.024314"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rafael A. Bittencourt, H. B. de B. Pereira, M. A. Moret, S. Galam, and I. C. da Cunha Lima
A new model could predict the impacts of policy changes on career progression prior to their implementation.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 024314] Published Tue Aug 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rafael A. Bittencourt, H. B. de B. Pereira, M. A. Moret, S. Galam, and I. C. da Cunha Lima</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum-Enhanced Pattern Recognition]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024072</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024072"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Giuseppe Ortolano, Carmine Napoli, Cillian Harney, Stefano Pirandola, Giuseppe Leonetti, Pauline Boucher, Elena Losero, Marco Genovese, and Ivano Ruo-Berchera
This work demonstrates experimentally that the advantage gained in sensing using quantum photonic resources can be sustained, and even amplified, through complex classical post-processing aimed at extracting relevant features. Despite the very different architectures of the classical algorithms tested here, the quantum advantage in classification performance appears to be robust and qualitatively very consistent. Thus the results argue for widespread use of quantum sensing technologies, in any field that deals with pattern recognition in large datasets.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 024072] Published Tue Aug 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giuseppe Ortolano, Carmine Napoli, Cillian Harney, Stefano Pirandola, Giuseppe Leonetti, Pauline Boucher, Elena Losero, Marco Genovese, and Ivano Ruo-Berchera</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum Hacking Against Discrete-Modulated Continuous-Variable Quantum Key Distribution Using Modified Local Oscillator Intensity Attack with Random Fluctuations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024073</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024073"/>
        <updated>2023-08-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lu Fan, Yiming Bian, Mingze Wu, Yichen Zhang, and Song Yu
Know your enemy: In practical inline systems for continuous-variable quantum key distribution, the local oscillator (LO) is particularly vulnerable to being controlled by hackers. The authors propose a modified LO intensity attack with random fluctuations, which has the advantage of evading the commonly used monitoring technologies. Moreover, similar quantum hacking could also target the pilot intensity in a LO system, which indicates the strong adaptability and practicability of the proposed attack. This work could be of great significance to the practical security of continuous-variable quantum key distribution.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 024073] Published Tue Aug 29, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lu Fan, Yiming Bian, Mingze Wu, Yichen Zhang, and Song Yu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bacterial Replication Initiation as Precision Control by Protein Counting]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.1.013011</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.1.013011"/>
        <updated>2023-08-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Haochen Fu, Fangzhou Xiao, and Suckjoon Jun
This study unveils a molecular model for DNA replication control in cells at different growth conditions. It tackles the long-standing challenge of how bacteria manage DNA initiation with constant protein concentrations, achieving very precise control of their size.

[PRX Life 1, 013011] Published Mon Aug 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haochen Fu, Fangzhou Xiao, and Suckjoon Jun</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Metastate analysis of the ground states of two-dimensional Ising spin glasses]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.024142</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.024142"/>
        <updated>2023-08-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. K. Hartmann and A. P. Young
The authors numerically investigate the Ising spin glass state at zero temperature in two dimensions. They find a single ground state, in accordance with the droplet model, and also show that a single power law describes corrections to this result down to the smallest sizes.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 024142] Published Mon Aug 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. K. Hartmann and A. P. Young</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phonon-induced collective modes in spin-orbit coupled polar metals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.075162</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.075162"/>
        <updated>2023-08-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Abhishek Kumar, Premala Chandra, and Pavel A. Volkov
In spin-orbit coupled metals, polar phonons couple to the spin of electrons by inducing a dynamical Rashba-type spin splitting. Here, the authors study the consequences of such coupling in polar metals, where one of the polar phonons has undergone a symmetry-breaking transition. They show that application of magnetic field reveals a spectrum of collective modes that can change their character (electronic vs. lattice) and energy as a function of field strength. Optical spectroscopy experiments are shown to have the capability to probe these modes.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 075162] Published Mon Aug 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Abhishek Kumar, Premala Chandra, and Pavel A. Volkov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microwave spectroscopy of low-$l$ singlet strontium Rydberg states at intermediate $n, 50≲n≲70$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.022815</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.022815"/>
        <updated>2023-08-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. A. Brienza, Y. Lu, C. Wang, S. K. Kanungo, T. C. Killian, F. B. Dunning, J. Burgdörfer, and S. Yoshida
The authors use microwave spectroscopy to measure the quantum defects for lower-l singlet strontium Rydberg states at intermediate n. The results are used to develop a revised set of Rydberg-Ritz quantum defect parameters that could help make accurate predictions of the energy intervals between other high-lying states.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 022815] Published Mon Aug 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. A. Brienza, Y. Lu, C. Wang, S. K. Kanungo, T. C. Killian, F. B. Dunning, J. Burgdörfer, and S. Yoshida</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of non-Abelian gauge fields using multiloop amplification]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.023316</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.023316"/>
        <updated>2023-08-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Qing-Xian Lv, Hong-Zhi Liu, Yan-Xiong Du, Lin-Qing Chen, Meng Wang, Jia-Hao Liang, Zhao-Xin Fu, Zi-Yuan Chen, Hui Yan, and Shi-Liang Zhu
The authors propose a scheme to measure the non-Abelian gauge field through multiloop evolution and robust holonomic quantum gates, and experimentally demonstrate it in the degenerate eigensubspace of a double-Λ four-level atomic system of 87Rb. The results could be useful for the development of high-resolution and high-precision measurements of the gauge fields.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 023316] Published Mon Aug 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qing-Xian Lv, Hong-Zhi Liu, Yan-Xiong Du, Lin-Qing Chen, Meng Wang, Jia-Hao Liang, Zhao-Xin Fu, Zi-Yuan Chen, Hui Yan, and Shi-Liang Zhu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effect of Pt vacancies on magnetotransport of Weyl semimetal candidate GdPtSb epitaxial films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.084204</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.084204"/>
        <updated>2023-08-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dongxue Du, Laxman Raju Thoutam, Konrad T. Genser, Chenyu Zhang, Karin M. Rabe, Tamalika Samanta, Taehwan Jung, Bharat Jalan, Paul M. Voyles, and Jason K. Kawasaki
Bismuth-containing half-Heusler compounds were among the first identified Weyl semimetals. However, it remains a question whether other half-Heuslers also exhibit Weyl physics. Additionally, the impacts of point defects on the transport properties of Weyl semimetals are often overlooked. One experimental signature of Weyl nodes is the chiral anomaly, which involves charge pumping between Weyl nodes in reciprocal space. In this study, the authors demonstrate that naturally occurring Pt vacancies in GdPtxSb epitaxial films complicate the identification of the chiral anomaly through magnetotransport measurements. On the other hand, they observe signatures of the topological Hall effect, indicating the presence of chiral spin textures in real space.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 084204] Published Fri Aug 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dongxue Du, Laxman Raju Thoutam, Konrad T. Genser, Chenyu Zhang, Karin M. Rabe, Tamalika Samanta, Taehwan Jung, Bharat Jalan, Paul M. Voyles, and Jason K. Kawasaki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shortcuts to Equilibrium with a Levitated Particle in the Underdamped Regime]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.087101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.087101"/>
        <updated>2023-08-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Damien Raynal, Timothée de Guillebon, David Guéry-Odelin, Emmanuel Trizac, Jean-Sébastien Lauret, and Loïc Rondin
An experiment using optically-levitated nanoparticles demonstrates a successful application of engineered swift equilibration in the underdamped regime.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 087101] Published Fri Aug 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damien Raynal, Timothée de Guillebon, David Guéry-Odelin, Emmanuel Trizac, Jean-Sébastien Lauret, and Loïc Rondin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search for magnetoelectric monopole response in ${\mathrm{Cr}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{3}$ powder]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.054437</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.054437"/>
        <updated>2023-08-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Syed Q. A. Shah, Ather Mahmood, Arun Parthasarathy, and Christian Binek
The discovery of a monopole contribution to the overall magnetoelectric susceptibility of Cr2O3 sparked the search for a material with pure monopole response. Magnetoelectric powder samples are alternatives to magnetic topological insulators which, in practice, are not suitable candidates. Here, the authors experimentally and theoretically investigate the magnetoelectric susceptibility of Cr2O3 powder. Although electric and magnetic field cooling tunes the susceptibility, there is no field-cooling protocol that leads to a pure monopole response. These insights provide alternatives to realize effective magnetoelectric monopole media.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 054437] Published Fri Aug 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Syed Q. A. Shah, Ather Mahmood, Arun Parthasarathy, and Christian Binek</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intercorrelated anomalous Hall and spin Hall effect in kagome-lattice ${\mathrm{Co}}_{3}{\mathrm{Sn}}_{2}{\mathrm{S}}_{2}$-based shandite films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.064429</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.064429"/>
        <updated>2023-08-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yong-Chang Lau, Junya Ikeda, Kohei Fujiwara, Akihiro Ozawa, Jiaxin Zheng, Takeshi Seki, Kentaro Nomura, Liang Du, Quansheng Wu, Atsushi Tsukazaki, and Koki Takanashi
This work establishes the pivotal role of topological bands in the magnetic Weyl semimetal prototype Co3Sn2S2 for efficient generation of spin current at room temperature via the spin Hall effect. Electron and hole-doped shandite films are systematically studied to map the evolution of Hall conductivities against Fermi level tuning. The authors demonstrate that the observed anomalous Hall conductivity and spin Hall conductivity maxima at distinct doping levels share the common origin in the band structure, suggesting such a correlation can be exploited for screening materials with large transverse magnetoelectric responses.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 064429] Published Fri Aug 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yong-Chang Lau, Junya Ikeda, Kohei Fujiwara, Akihiro Ozawa, Jiaxin Zheng, Takeshi Seki, Kentaro Nomura, Liang Du, Quansheng Wu, Atsushi Tsukazaki, and Koki Takanashi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum Time Transfer: A Practical Method for Lossy and Noisy Channels]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024064</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024064"/>
        <updated>2023-08-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Randy Lafler and R. Nicholas Lanning
Precise clock synchronization is important for quantum networking, enhanced position, navigation, timing, and other applications that require clock synchronization better than GPS, but remains an ongoing challenge. The authors propose a solution using hardware native to quantum networking. This quantum-time-transfer technique can quickly achieve picosecond-level clock synchronization despite relatively low-performance quantum-photon sources and detection equipment. Furthermore, it is robust against the high loss and high noise channel conditions representative of daytime space-Earth links, and could provide high-precision secure timing in GPS-denied environments.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 024064] Published Fri Aug 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Randy Lafler and R. Nicholas Lanning</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Variational Neural-Network Ansatz for Continuum Quantum Field Theory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.081601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.081601"/>
        <updated>2023-08-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): John M. Martyn, Khadijeh Najafi, and Di Luo
A variational ansatz based on deep-sets neural-network architecture enables the parametrization of all multiparticle wave functions in continuum nonrelativistic quantum field theories.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 081601] Published Thu Aug 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John M. Martyn, Khadijeh Najafi, and Di Luo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Temperature Dependence of Photoluminescence Intensity and Spin Contrast in Nitrogen-Vacancy Centers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.086903</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.086903"/>
        <updated>2023-08-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Ernst, P. J. Scheidegger, S. Diesch, L. Lorenzelli, and C. L. Degen
Two photoluminescence experiments and models of nitrogen-vacancy centers in diamond over broad temperature ranges improve our understanding of the photodynamics of vacancy centers and other spin defects.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 086903] Published Thu Aug 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Ernst, P. J. Scheidegger, S. Diesch, L. Lorenzelli, and C. L. Degen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Temperature-Dependent Photophysics of Single NV Centers in Diamond]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.086904</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.086904"/>
        <updated>2023-08-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jodok Happacher, Juanita Bocquel, Hossein T. Dinani, Märta A. Tschudin, Patrick Reiser, David A. Broadway, Jeronimo R. Maze, and Patrick Maletinsky
Two photoluminescence experiments and models of nitrogen-vacancy centers in diamond over broad temperature ranges improve our understanding of the photodynamics of vacancy centers and other spin defects.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 086904] Published Thu Aug 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jodok Happacher, Juanita Bocquel, Hossein T. Dinani, Märta A. Tschudin, Patrick Reiser, David A. Broadway, Jeronimo R. Maze, and Patrick Maletinsky</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wildebeest herds on rolling hills: Flocking on arbitrary curved surfaces]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.024610</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.024610"/>
        <updated>2023-08-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christina L. Hueschen, Alexander R. Dunn, and Rob Phillips
The collective motion of animal herds and other biological systems sometimes takes place in an environment with a complex geometrical structure. In this paper, the authors study such active matter systems on arbitrary curved surfaces and work towards a better understanding of various real-life systems.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 024610] Published Thu Aug 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christina L. Hueschen, Alexander R. Dunn, and Rob Phillips</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reference frames in general relativity and the galactic rotation curves]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.044056</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.044056"/>
        <updated>2023-08-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): L. Filipe O. Costa, José Natário, F. Frutos-Alfaro, and Michael Soffel
The authors extend the International Astronomical Union (IAU) reference system to a special class of spacetimes that admit non-shearing congruences of observers which, at infinity, have zero vorticity and acceleration. As an application, they analyze several known spacetimes and show that the galaxies’ rotation curves cannot be explained through gravitomagnetic effects without the need for dark matter.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 044056] Published Thu Aug 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L. Filipe O. Costa, José Natário, F. Frutos-Alfaro, and Michael Soffel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modeling temperature-dependent population dynamics in the excited state of the nitrogen-vacancy center in diamond]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.085203</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.085203"/>
        <updated>2023-08-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Ernst, P. J. Scheidegger, S. Diesch, and C. L. Degen
The nitrogen vacancy (NV) center in diamond is well known for its outstanding optical and spin properties, enabling various applications in quantum sensing and quantum information at both cryogenic and ambient temperatures. Despite a large body of work, however, the NV center’s dynamics at intermediate temperatures are incompletely understood. This paper describes a basic rate model able to explain the NV population dynamics over the full parameter space of temperature, crystallographic strain, and magnetic field. Numerical simulations of the model are in excellent agreement with experiments discussed in the accompanying PRL.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 085203] Published Thu Aug 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Ernst, P. J. Scheidegger, S. Diesch, and C. L. Degen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sub-$μ\mathrm{m}$ axial precision depth imaging with entangled two-color Hong-Ou-Mandel microscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.023726</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.023726"/>
        <updated>2023-08-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Cyril Torre, Alex McMillan, Jorge Monroy-Ruz, and Jonathan C. F. Matthews
Using two entangled photons of different colors in a Hong-Ou-Mandel interference scheme, the authors show that they can precisely measure the thickness of a semitransparent sample. The depth sensitivity is adjustable and the method is resilient against fluctuations commonly encountered in biological samples.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 023726] Published Thu Aug 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cyril Torre, Alex McMillan, Jorge Monroy-Ruz, and Jonathan C. F. Matthews</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Structural and optoelectronic properties of thin film ${\mathrm{LaWN}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.084411</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.084411"/>
        <updated>2023-08-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rebecca W. Smaha, John S. Mangum, Ian A. Leahy, Julian Calder, Matthew P. Hautzinger, Christopher P. Muzzillo, Craig L. Perkins, Kevin R. Talley, Serena Eley, Prashun Gorai, Sage R. Bauers, and Andriy Zakutayev
Perovskite and related materials exhibit a staggering array of interesting ground states and functional applications. Among these, nitride perovskites are predicted to possess intriguing physical properties, but they remain underexplored due to the challenges in synthesizing materials without unintentional oxygen incorporation. LaWN3, recently identified as the first fully nitrided perovskite, displays polar symmetry and a large piezoelectric coefficient. However, its predicted polarization switching (common for ferroelectrics) is hindered by a significant leakage current, necessitating a better understanding of its electronic structure and optical properties. This study delves into the structure and optoelectronic properties of thin film LaWN3 in greater detail, employing combinatorial techniques to establish correlations between properties and cation stoichiometry.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 084411] Published Wed Aug 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebecca W. Smaha, John S. Mangum, Ian A. Leahy, Julian Calder, Matthew P. Hautzinger, Christopher P. Muzzillo, Craig L. Perkins, Kevin R. Talley, Serena Eley, Prashun Gorai, Sage R. Bauers, and Andriy Zakutayev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Correlated anharmonicity and dynamic disorder control carrier transport in halide perovskites]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.L081601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.L081601"/>
        <updated>2023-08-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maximilian J. Schilcher, David J. Abramovitch, Matthew Z. Mayers, Liang Z. Tan, David R. Reichman, and David A. Egger
Charge transport characteristics in optoelectronic devices play a crucial role in their efficiency. Research over the past decades has established strategies to alter charge transport behavior through material design. However, when atomic motion becomes complex at elevated, application-relevant temperatures, the established structure-property relations are less predictive. In this work, the authors take a major step to solve this critical problem by quantitatively connecting vibrational anharmonicity and dynamic disorder in model anharmonic semiconductors. It is reported that the materials’ correlated behavior determine carrier mobilities and their temperature dependencies in halide perovskites, establishing these phenomena as knobs to tune key optoelectronic properties of important optoelectronic materials.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, L081601] Published Wed Aug 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maximilian J. Schilcher, David J. Abramovitch, Matthew Z. Mayers, Liang Z. Tan, David R. Reichman, and David A. Egger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes on conformal anomaly, nonlocal effective action, and the metamorphosis of the running scale]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.045014</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.045014"/>
        <updated>2023-08-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. O. Barvinsky and W. Wachowski
Explicit expressions for anomalies and associated effective actions may take many different forms. Here the authors discuss the conformal anomaly and solve in a clear and explicit manner long-standing confusions and controversies for several wildly different looking effective actions. They show how they are related by different choices of the conformal gauge, reflecting the ambiguity caused by Weyl-invariant pieces. They also discuss applications of these new results to anomaly-driven inflation and the “running” of gravitational and cosmological constants.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 045014] Published Wed Aug 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. O. Barvinsky and W. Wachowski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tests of $CP$ symmetry in entangled ${\mathrm{Ξ}}^{0}−{\overline{\mathrm{Ξ}}}^{0}$ pairs]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.L031106</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.L031106"/>
        <updated>2023-08-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Ablikim et al. (BESIII Collaboration)
The authors provide the most accurate up to date tests of CP symmetry for neutral hyperons in the decay of J/ψ.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, L031106] Published Wed Aug 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Ablikim &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (BESIII Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exchange-renormalized crystal field excitations in the quantum Ising magnet ${\mathrm{KTmSe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.054435</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.054435"/>
        <updated>2023-08-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shiyi Zheng, Hongliang Wo, Yiqing Gu, Rui Leonard Luo, Yimeng Gu, Yinghao Zhu, Paul Steffens, Martin Boehm, Qisi Wang, Gang Chen, and Jun Zhao
Emerging as a platform for novel quantum effects, triangular-lattice rare-earth delafossite compounds have attracted significant attention. This study investigates KTmSe2 using thermodynamic and neutron scattering methods, revealing highly dispersive crystal electric field excitations. From the transverse field Ising model and a full crystal field scheme, the findings uncover a strong interplay between spin exchange interactions and crystal field effects. These insights will provide a valuable framework for understanding low-temperature magnetism in materials of a similar type.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 054435] Published Wed Aug 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shiyi Zheng, Hongliang Wo, Yiqing Gu, Rui Leonard Luo, Yimeng Gu, Yinghao Zhu, Paul Steffens, Martin Boehm, Qisi Wang, Gang Chen, and Jun Zhao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum Mpemba Effect in a Quantum Dot with Reservoirs]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.080402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.080402"/>
        <updated>2023-08-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Amit Kumar Chatterjee, Satoshi Takada, and Hisao Hayakawa
The temperatures of two copies of a quantum dot, one initially hotter than the other, can cross each other at some finite time and reverse their identities, the first such prediction in a quantum regime.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 080402] Published Tue Aug 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amit Kumar Chatterjee, Satoshi Takada, and Hisao Hayakawa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Real-Space Imaging of Triplon Excitations in Engineered Quantum Magnets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.086701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.086701"/>
        <updated>2023-08-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Robert Drost, Shawulienu Kezilebieke, Jose L. Lado, and Peter Liljeroth
A minimal quantum magnet with triplon excitations has been engineered using molecular building blocks in the singlet ground state.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 086701] Published Tue Aug 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Drost, Shawulienu Kezilebieke, Jose L. Lado, and Peter Liljeroth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drag on a partially immersed sphere at the capillary scale]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.084003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.084003"/>
        <updated>2023-08-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Robert Hunt, Ze Zhao, Eli Silver, Jinhui Yan, Yuri Bazilevs, and Daniel M. Harris
Drag on a sphere in a steady flow is an important and thoroughly studied problem in fluid dynamics, yet relatively little work includes the effects of a free surface. Through experiments and simulations, we characterize the drag on a sphere partially immersed at an air-water interface as a function of submergence depth. The presence of the free surface can induce drag forces several times greater than the equivalent fully submerged case, with pronounced hysteretic effects strongly influenced by the sphere’s wettability. We ascribe the drag increase to an asymmetric pressure loading on the sphere that persists for flows both above and below the minimum capillary-gravity wave speed.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 084003] Published Tue Aug 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Hunt, Ze Zhao, Eli Silver, Jinhui Yan, Yuri Bazilevs, and Daniel M. Harris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sublattice interference promotes pair density wave order in kagome metals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L081117</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L081117"/>
        <updated>2023-08-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yi-Ming Wu, Ronny Thomale, and S. Raghu
Pair density wave superconductivity arises when the two paired fermions have finite center-of-mass momentum. It is usually not a weak coupling instability and requires stringent conditions, such as the pairing interaction remaining attractive at finite momentum, and the interaction strength has to be strong enough. Here, the authors find that the kagome lattice model, when doped to a particular Van Hove filling with both onsite and nearest neighbor repulsion, can serve as an ideal platform for realizing this novel superconducting state.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L081117] Published Tue Aug 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yi-Ming Wu, Ronny Thomale, and S. Raghu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crucial role of thermal fluctuations and vertex corrections for the magnetic pseudogap]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L081118</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L081118"/>
        <updated>2023-08-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mengxing Ye and Andrey V. Chubukov
It is known that thermal magnetic fluctuations can give rise to pseudogap behavior in a paramagnetic metal. However, the role of vertex corrections for the pseudogap formation is not well understood. The authors show here that without vertex corrections there is no pseudogap, but an inclusion of even infinitesimally small vertex corrections gives rise to pseudogap behavior. The authors further generalize this statement to a set of boundary models, in which the pseudogap develops upon inclusion of perturbations. This work provides an understanding of recent numerical studies of the pseudogap.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L081118] Published Tue Aug 22, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mengxing Ye and Andrey V. Chubukov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum Microwave Parametric Interferometer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024049</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024049"/>
        <updated>2023-08-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): F. Kronowetter, F. Fesquet, M. Renger, K. Honasoge, Y. Nojiri, K. Inomata, Y. Nakamura, A. Marx, R. Gross, and K.G. Fedorov
Interferometers are extremely powerful tools for precision measurements in a plethora of research fields and applications, such as the detection of gravitational waves. The authors present experimental realization of a nonlinear microwave interferometer based on superconducting quantum circuits. Useful properties of this device range from a signal-to-noise ratio that exceeds the shot-noise limit, to sub-Poissonian intensity fluctuations between its outputs. These intriguing findings will promote applications ranging from quantum illumination to the search for axionic dark matter.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 024049] Published Mon Aug 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>F. Kronowetter, F. Fesquet, M. Renger, K. Honasoge, Y. Nojiri, K. Inomata, Y. Nakamura, A. Marx, R. Gross, and K.G. Fedorov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sensing Rotations with Multiplane Light Conversion]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024052</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024052"/>
        <updated>2023-08-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Eriksson, A.Z. Goldberg, M. Hiekkamäki, F. Bouchard, J. Rehacek, Z. Hradil, G. Leuchs, R. Fickler, and L.L. Sánchez-Soto
Because any unitary operation is a rotation, in a sense measuring rotation is the most universal sort of measurement. In practice, precise rotation measurements are essential, from magnetometry to inertial navigation to fundamental tests of physics. The ultimate limits for simultaneously measuring all of the components of a rotation are dictated by quantum theory, and here are tested using light’s orbital angular momentum and multiplane light conversion. Rotated states are projected onto a set of coherent states to deduce the rotation parameters, using a method inspired by GPS. The results are near the ultimate limits of quantum precision.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 024052] Published Mon Aug 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Eriksson, A.Z. Goldberg, M. Hiekkamäki, F. Bouchard, J. Rehacek, Z. Hradil, G. Leuchs, R. Fickler, and L.L. Sánchez-Soto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optically trapped Feshbach molecules of fermionic $^{161}\mathrm{Dy}$ and $^{40}\mathrm{K}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033117</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033117"/>
        <updated>2023-08-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): E. Soave, A. Canali, Zhu-Xiong Ye, M. Kreyer, E. Kirilov, and R. Grimm
A pure sample of bosonic Feshbach molecules composed of fermionic Dy-161 and K-40 atoms has been prepared in an optical trap, with a phase-space density of about 0.1. Investigation of the molecular cloud decay in the presence of 1064-nm trapping light points to a one-photon coupling to electronically excited states as the main factor limiting the sample lifetime. This observation, together with a refined understanding of the molecule properties and behavior as a function of the magnetic field, offers crucial insights and experimental progress toward achieving quantum-degenerate samples of DyK molecules and novel superfluids based on mass-imbalanced fermion mixtures.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 033117] Published Fri Aug 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>E. Soave, A. Canali, Zhu-Xiong Ye, M. Kreyer, E. Kirilov, and R. Grimm</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effect of representation format on conceptual question performance and eye-tracking measures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.020114</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.020114"/>
        <updated>2023-08-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ana Susac, Maja Planinic, Andreja Bubic, Katarina Jelicic, and Marijan Palmovic
It takes students longer to extract relevant information from physics question presented using a verbal representation than from isomorphic questions using graphical or pictoral representations.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 19, 020114] Published Fri Aug 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ana Susac, Maja Planinic, Andreja Bubic, Katarina Jelicic, and Marijan Palmovic</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scalable Multipartite Entanglement Created by Spin Exchange in an Optical Lattice]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.073401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.073401"/>
        <updated>2023-08-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wei-Yong Zhang, Ming-Gen He, Hui Sun, Yong-Guang Zheng, Ying Liu, An Luo, Han-Yi Wang, Zi-Hang Zhu, Pei-Yue Qiu, Ying-Chao Shen, Xuan-Kai Wang, Wan Lin, Song-Tao Yu, Bin-Chen Li, Bo Xiao, Meng-Da Li, Yu-Meng Yang, Xiao Jiang, Han-Ning Dai, You Zhou, Xiongfeng Ma, Zhen-Sheng Yuan, and Jian-Wei Pan
Quantum mechanically entangled groups of eight and ten ultracold atoms provide a critical demonstration for optical-lattice-based quantum processing.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 073401] Published Fri Aug 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wei-Yong Zhang, Ming-Gen He, Hui Sun, Yong-Guang Zheng, Ying Liu, An Luo, Han-Yi Wang, Zi-Hang Zhu, Pei-Yue Qiu, Ying-Chao Shen, Xuan-Kai Wang, Wan Lin, Song-Tao Yu, Bin-Chen Li, Bo Xiao, Meng-Da Li, Yu-Meng Yang, Xiao Jiang, Han-Ning Dai, You Zhou, Xiongfeng Ma, Zhen-Sheng Yuan, and Jian-Wei Pan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coalescence of bubbles in a viscoelastic liquid]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.083603</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.083603"/>
        <updated>2023-08-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexandros T. Oratis, Vincent Bertin, and Jacco H. Snoeijer
The coalescence of bubbles dissolved in liquids occurs in systems like foams, magma, and various other bubbly flows. Here, we investigate the coalescence of two bubbles of identical size in semidilute aqueous polymer solutions. The rheological properties are very different from those of water; yet, the early-time dynamics of coalescence are not altered by the presence of polymers. Even though the polymers get highly stretched in the azimuthal direction, we find that the resulting hoop force is insufficient to modify the rate of coalescence or the shape of the growing neck.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 083603] Published Fri Aug 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandros T. Oratis, Vincent Bertin, and Jacco H. Snoeijer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Characterization of Microwave Loss Using Multimode Superconducting Resonators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024045</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024045"/>
        <updated>2023-08-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chan U Lei, Suhas Ganjam, Lev Krayzman, Archan Banerjee, Kim Kisslinger, Sooyeon Hwang, Luigi Frunzio, and Robert J. Schoelkopf
Understanding the loss mechanisms in materials is crucial to improving coherence in superconducting quantum circuits. The authors present a technique based on multimode superconducting resonators that distinguishes and quantifies all loss channels in relevant materials. Applying this technique reveals that both chemical etching and diamond turning reduce surface losses in high-purity aluminum, while coating diamond-turned surfaces with thin-film aluminum significantly improves joint quality. This method can be used to design on-chip superconducting devices to characterize microwave losses, as well as to quantify the effects of fabrication processes.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 024045] Published Fri Aug 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chan U Lei, Suhas Ganjam, Lev Krayzman, Archan Banerjee, Kim Kisslinger, Sooyeon Hwang, Luigi Frunzio, and Robert J. Schoelkopf</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Satellite-Relayed Global Quantum Communication without Quantum Memory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024048</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024048"/>
        <updated>2023-08-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sumit Goswami and Sayandip Dhara
Long-distance quantum communication can usher in hack-proof communication, enable precision quantum sensing technologies, and ultimately yield a quantum Internet. Existing protocols for global-scale quantum communication demand high-performance quantum memories, which have limited communication distance. This study proposes a chain of satellites in low Earth orbit to directly transmit photonic qubits through space, using the satellites like optical lenses to counter diffraction loss. Simulations and analysis of different quantum communication protocols using this relay system show the feasibility of building a global quantum network of only satellites, without requiring quantum memories.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 024048] Published Fri Aug 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sumit Goswami and Sayandip Dhara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pressure-enhanced fractional Chern insulators along a magic line in moiré transition metal dichalcogenides]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.L032022</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.L032022"/>
        <updated>2023-08-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nicolás Morales-Durán, Jie Wang, Gabriel R. Schleder, Mattia Angeli, Ziyan Zhu, Efthimios Kaxiras, Cécile Repellin, and Jennifer Cano
The effect of applied pressure on fractional Chern insulators (FCIs) in moiré TMDs is numerically studied, indicating that pressure can enhance the many-body gap of these topologically ordered phases. This is supported by showing that, within the region of stability of the FCI, the quantum geometry of the topmost moiré flat band almost satisfies the ideal condition.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, L032022] Published Thu Aug 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicolás Morales-Durán, Jie Wang, Gabriel R. Schleder, Mattia Angeli, Ziyan Zhu, Efthimios Kaxiras, Cécile Repellin, and Jennifer Cano</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Detecting partial synchrony in a complex oscillatory network using pseudovortices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.024307</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.024307"/>
        <updated>2023-08-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yasuhiro Yamada and Kensuke Inaba
The dynamics of a collection of coupled neurons resemble that of vortices in a commonly studied two-dimensional lattice model, a finding that could help in understanding brain function and dysfunction.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 024307] Published Thu Aug 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yasuhiro Yamada and Kensuke Inaba</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum Annealing Optimization Method for the Design of Barrier Materials in Magnetic Tunnel Junctions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024044</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024044"/>
        <updated>2023-08-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kenji Nawa, Tsuyoshi Suzuki, Keisuke Masuda, Shu Tanaka, and Yoshio Miura
Materials informatics has boosted materials design, but the search for optimal atomic configurations in spintronic devices is challenging, due to many degrees of freedom and the need to design at the atomic level. Quantum annealing offers a breakthrough for such challenges in huge search spaces. The authors propose a combination of quantum annealing, machine learning, and first-principles calculations that is computationally cheaper than ordinary machine learning in designing atomically disordered spinel oxides (promising materials for magnetoresistive devices). Furthermore, the origins of physical properties of interest can be interpreted from the obtained Ising model Hamiltonian.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 024044] Published Thu Aug 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kenji Nawa, Tsuyoshi Suzuki, Keisuke Masuda, Shu Tanaka, and Yoshio Miura</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generation of Large Vortex-Free Superfluid Helium Nanodroplets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.076002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.076002"/>
        <updated>2023-08-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anatoli Ulmer et al.
Researchers have created vortex-free helium nanodroplets that contain more helium atoms than previous droplets of this type, allowing the system to be used in a wider range of studies.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 076002] Published Wed Aug 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anatoli Ulmer &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thermodynamic Bound on the Asymmetry of Cross-Correlations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.077101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.077101"/>
        <updated>2023-08-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Naruo Ohga, Sosuke Ito, and Artemy Kolchinsky
Dissipation affects the time asymmetry of fluctuations in systems out of thermodynamic equilibrium. A newly discovered inequality elucidates that connection.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 077101] Published Wed Aug 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Naruo Ohga, Sosuke Ito, and Artemy Kolchinsky</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transport of inertial ellipsoidal particles in turbulent flow over rough walls]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.084303</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.084303"/>
        <updated>2023-08-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. Saccone, M. De Marchis, B. Milici, and C. Marchioli
This study examines combined effects of particle inertia, particle aspect ratio, and wall roughness on dynamics of prolate ellipsoidal particles dispersed in turbulent channel flow bounded by rough walls. We use direct numerical simulation of the turbulence and Lagrangian tracking of the particles. The particles spatial distribution within the flow domain and their translational statistics is shown to depend almost exclusively on the combined effect of inertia and wall roughness, with weak aspect ratio effects. These effects are observed in the particle orientation statistics: Longer particles exhibit a stronger tendency to align with the mean flow direction, especially at low inertia.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 084303] Published Wed Aug 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. Saccone, M. De Marchis, B. Milici, and C. Marchioli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Super-sample covariance of the power spectrum, bispectrum, halos, voids, and their cross covariances]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.043521</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.043521"/>
        <updated>2023-08-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Adrian E. Bayer, Jia Liu, Ryo Terasawa, Alexandre Barreira, Yici Zhong, and Yu Feng
The authors study the super-sample covariance (SSC) on higher-order statistics which are becoming standard tools for cosmological inferences from the non-linear small-scale regime of the cosmic structure. To this end, they compare small box sizes of simulations with those embedded in larger simulations that include SCC modes that are cut off by the small boxes. It is observed that these finite-size effects have to be taken into account in future cosmological analyses.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 043521] Published Wed Aug 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adrian E. Bayer, Jia Liu, Ryo Terasawa, Alexandre Barreira, Yici Zhong, and Yu Feng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Role of dimensionality and size in controlling the drag Seebeck coefficient of doped silicon nanostructures: A fundamental understanding]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L060301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L060301"/>
        <updated>2023-08-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Raja Sen, Nathalie Vast, and Jelena Sjakste
It is commonly believed that phonon drag, a phenomenon where electrons are dragged from the hot to the cold side of the sample by out-of-equilibrium phonons, does not play any significant role on the nanoscale. Here, the authors show that, even if the phonon-drag contribution is strongly reduced by nanostructuring, a silicon thin film of 100 nm thickness can still preserve more than 20% of the bulk phonon-drag contribution at 300 K along the in-plane direction of the thin film.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L060301] Published Wed Aug 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Raja Sen, Nathalie Vast, and Jelena Sjakste</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Carrier Mobility up to ${10}^{6}\phantom{\rule{0.2em}{0ex}}{\mathrm{cm}}^{2}\phantom{\rule{0.1em}{0ex}}{\mathrm{V}}^{−1}\phantom{\rule{0.1em}{0ex}}{\mathrm{s}}^{−1}$ Measured in Single-Crystal Diamond by the Time-of-Flight Electron-Beam-Induced-Current Technique]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024037</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024037"/>
        <updated>2023-08-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Portier, F. Donatini, D. Dauvergne, M.-L. Gallin-Martel, and J. Pernot
Diamond is hard: Carrier mobility in diamond is a key parameter for the development of future electronics and quantum devices, yet the low-field mobility of holes in ultrapure diamond is unknown, below 80 K or so. This study presents a time-of-flight technique using electron-beam-induced current to measure the velocities of electrons and holes as a function of temperature and electric field. A low-field mobility of (1.03±0.05)×106 cm2 V−1 s−1 is measured for holes at 13 K, demonstrating that diamond is a suitable material for ballistic transport of charge carriers at a length scale of greater than 10 μm.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 024037] Published Wed Aug 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Portier, F. Donatini, D. Dauvergne, M.-L. Gallin-Martel, and J. Pernot</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ultrastrong Magnon-Photon Coupling Achieved by Magnetic Films in Contact with Superconducting Resonators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024039</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.024039"/>
        <updated>2023-08-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alberto Ghirri, Claudio Bonizzoni, Maksut Maksutoglu, Alberto Mercurio, Omar Di Stefano, Salvatore Savasta, and Marco Affronte
Controlling magnon-photon coupling is one of the keys to enabling cavity magnonics in several emerging applications, where the realization of all-on-chip devices is crucial to integrating magnonic systems with microwave circuits. This study shows that ultrastrong coupling can be achieved with a ferrimagnetic film in direct contact with a superconducting resonator. Analysis shows that the diamagnetic coupling term is vanishingly small, suggesting a potential route to superradiant phase transitions. These results ought to be relevant for microwave technologies including memory devices, microwave-to-optical transducers, haloscopes for axion detection, and coherent microwave sources.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 024039] Published Wed Aug 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alberto Ghirri, Claudio Bonizzoni, Maksut Maksutoglu, Alberto Mercurio, Omar Di Stefano, Salvatore Savasta, and Marco Affronte</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toward Powerful Probes of Neutrino Self-Interactions in Supernovae]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.071002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.071002"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Po-Wen Chang, Ivan Esteban, John F. Beacom, Todd A. Thompson, and Christopher M. Hirata
A beyond-standard-model interaction between neutrinos could show up in future supernovae observations.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 071002] Published Tue Aug 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Po-Wen Chang, Ivan Esteban, John F. Beacom, Todd A. Thompson, and Christopher M. Hirata</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Geometric properties of the complete-graph Ising model in the loop representation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.024129</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.024129"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zhiyi Li, Zongzheng Zhou, Sheng Fang, and Youjin Deng
In this article, a worm algorithm is used to study the problem of the Ising model on a complete graph. The approach shows connections between different representations of the model and leads to a better understanding of its scaling properties and critical behavior.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 024129] Published Tue Aug 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhiyi Li, Zongzheng Zhou, Sheng Fang, and Youjin Deng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Easy-plane dominant stochastic magnetic tunnel junction with synthetic antiferromagnetic layers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.064418</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.064418"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jonathan Z. Sun, Christopher Safranski, Philip Trouilloud, Christopher D'Emic, Pouya Hashemi, and Guohan Hu
Superparamagnetic fluctuation of a nanomagnet, when confined by a strong easy-plane anisotropy, can yield a GHz-speed random signal. A magnetic tunnel junction converts such moment movement into conductance fluctuation and is useful as an entropy source for modern computing circuits. Here, the authors experimentally explore a magnetic tunnel junction with a synthetic antiferromagnetically coupled free layer and reference layer, in their superparamagnetic limit, to demonstrate hardware-based generation of a Gb/sec random bit stream, and to learn of factors in device materials and the fabrication process that are in need of future optimization.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 064418] Published Tue Aug 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan Z. Sun, Christopher Safranski, Philip Trouilloud, Christopher D'Emic, Pouya Hashemi, and Guohan Hu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fractional quantum anomalous Hall states in twisted bilayer ${\mathrm{MoTe}}_{2}$ and ${\mathrm{WSe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.085117</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.085117"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aidan P. Reddy, Faisal Alsallom, Yang Zhang, Trithep Devakul, and Liang Fu
The recent observation of the fractional quantum anomalous Hall effect opens a new frontier in topological phases and quantum materials. Here, the authors demonstrate that the strong interaction in partially filled topological moiré bands of twisted semiconductor bilayers induces a variety of phases, including ferromagnetic metals, charge density waves, and fractional quantum anomalous Hall states. This work reveals a remarkably rich phase diagram as a function of twist angle, awaiting further exploration.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 085117] Published Tue Aug 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aidan P. Reddy, Faisal Alsallom, Yang Zhang, Trithep Devakul, and Liang Fu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantized interband topological index in two-dimensional systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L081111</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L081111"/>
        <updated>2023-08-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tharindu Fernando and Ting Cao
Classifying the multiband topology of two-dimensional parameter space submanifolds, exemplified by electron valleys in a Brillouin zone, has historically been a complex endeavor. In response to these limitations, the authors unveil here a gauge-invariant, quantized interband topological index. This refined approach enhances the classification of valleys, and additionally sheds light on the nature of edge states resulting from band inversions in multiband systems. These findings deepen our grasp of valley physics and the intricacies of interband topology.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L081111] Published Tue Aug 15, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tharindu Fernando and Ting Cao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of a Resonant Structure near the ${D}_{s}^{+}{D}_{s}^{−}$ Threshold in the ${B}^{+}→{D}_{s}^{+}{D}_{s}^{−}{K}^{+}$ Decay]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.071901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.071901"/>
        <updated>2023-08-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Aaij et al. (LHCb Collaboration)
The LHCb collaboration reports the observation of a resonant structure around 3960 MeV that could be a 0++ cc¯ss¯ state.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 071901] Published Mon Aug 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Aaij &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHCb Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evidence of Electron Heating by Alpha Particles in JET Deuterium-Tritium Plasmas]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.075101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.075101"/>
        <updated>2023-08-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): V. G. Kiptily, R. Dumont, M. Fitzgerald, D. Keeling, S. E. Sharapov, M. Poradzinski, Ž. Štancar, P. J. Bonofiglo, E. Delabie, Z. Ghani, V. Goloborodko, S. Menmuir, E. Kowalska-Strzeciwilk, M. Podestà, H. Sun, D. M. Taylor, J. Bernardo, I. S. Carvalho, D. Douai, J. Garcia, M. Lennholm, C. F. Maggi, J. Mailloux, F. Rimini, and P. Siren
The observation of self-heating in magnetically confined plasmas represents a milestone on the road to fusion reactors based on such plasmas.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 075101] Published Mon Aug 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>V. G. Kiptily, R. Dumont, M. Fitzgerald, D. Keeling, S. E. Sharapov, M. Poradzinski, Ž. Štancar, P. J. Bonofiglo, E. Delabie, Z. Ghani, V. Goloborodko, S. Menmuir, E. Kowalska-Strzeciwilk, M. Podestà, H. Sun, D. M. Taylor, J. Bernardo, I. S. Carvalho, D. Douai, J. Garcia, M. Lennholm, C. F. Maggi, J. Mailloux, F. Rimini, and P. Siren</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First observation of the ${B}^{+}→{D}_{s}^{+}{D}_{s}^{−}{K}^{+}$ decay]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.034012</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.034012"/>
        <updated>2023-08-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Aaij et al. (LHCb Collaboration)
The LHCb collaboration reports the observation of a resonant structure around 3960 MeV that could be a 0++ cc¯ss¯ state.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 034012] Published Mon Aug 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Aaij &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHCb Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Propagation of a fast radio burst through a birefringent relativistic plasma]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.043009</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.043009"/>
        <updated>2023-08-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pravir Kumar, Ryan M. Shannon, Marcus E. Lower, Adam T. Deller, and J. Xavier Prochaska
The authors make a polarimetric study of a fast radio burst (FRB) from a particular source. The burst displays a considerable frequency-dependent circularly polarized component, which they analyze within a phenomenological generalized Faraday rotation framework. They find that initially linearly polarized radiation is transformed into circularly polarized radiation by a relativistic plasma located along the line of sight from the progenitor.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 043009] Published Mon Aug 14, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pravir Kumar, Ryan M. Shannon, Marcus E. Lower, Adam T. Deller, and J. Xavier Prochaska</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strain-coupling and relaxation dynamics in multicaloric ammonium sulphate ${({\mathrm{NH}}_{4})}_{2}{\mathrm{SO}}_{4}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.083601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.083601"/>
        <updated>2023-08-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Michael A. Carpenter, Miguel B. Costa, Guillaume F. Nataf, and Xavier Moya
The properties of materials that lay the groundwork for greenhouse gas-free solid-state cooling are intricately tied to their proximity to a phase transition—a phenomenon that unfolds reversibly in response to an externally applied field. Enter ammonium sulfate, a material that holds the promise of effectiveness and affordability within this remarkable realm. Its allure stems from a structural phase transition occurring at 225 K, which can be driven by changing hydrostatic pressure and electric fields. However, because of a large change in volume, cycling crystals through the transition typically results in mechanical failure. In this work, resonant ultrasound spectroscopy reveals the strain relaxation mechanisms responsible for this failure and a thermal pathway by which it can be avoided.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 083601] Published Fri Aug 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Michael A. Carpenter, Miguel B. Costa, Guillaume F. Nataf, and Xavier Moya</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intrinsic Nonlinear Hall Effect and Gate-Switchable Berry Curvature Sliding in Twisted Bilayer Graphene]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.066301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.066301"/>
        <updated>2023-08-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Meizhen Huang, Zefei Wu, Xu Zhang, Xuemeng Feng, Zishu Zhou, Shi Wang, Yong Chen, Chun Cheng, Kai Sun, Zi Yang Meng, and Ning Wang
An out-of-plane displacement field substantially affects the nonlinear Hall effect in high-mobility twisted bilayer graphene devices.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 066301] Published Fri Aug 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Meizhen Huang, Zefei Wu, Xu Zhang, Xuemeng Feng, Zishu Zhou, Shi Wang, Yong Chen, Chun Cheng, Kai Sun, Zi Yang Meng, and Ning Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Large Scale Zigzag Pattern Emerging from Circulating Active Shakers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.068301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.068301"/>
        <updated>2023-08-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gaspard Junot, Marco De Corato, and Pietro Tierno
A zigzag arrangement that appears spontaneously in a collection of magnetic particles and some other colloids is explained by the fluid flow around each particle.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 068301] Published Fri Aug 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gaspard Junot, Marco De Corato, and Pietro Tierno</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physics and modeling of liquid films in pulsating heat pipes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.084002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.084002"/>
        <updated>2023-08-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xiaolong Zhang (张晓龙) and Vadim S. Nikolayev
A pulsating heat pipe (PHP) is a capillary meandering between hot spot and cooled area filled with a two-phase fluid that oscillates inside it due to evaporation and condensation. We introduce a one-dimensional physical model, the Oscillating Film Thickness model, that incorporates previously overlooked physics related to liquid film deposition, evaporation, and contact line motion. The model more accurately represents the physics of the phenomena without loss of computational efficiency. Improvements in modeling accuracy and computational efficiency are demonstrated for the case of the simplest, single branch PHP.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 084002] Published Fri Aug 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiaolong Zhang (张晓龙) and Vadim S. Nikolayev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covalency, correlations, and interlayer interactions governing the magnetic and electronic structure of ${\mathrm{Mn}}_{3}{\mathrm{Si}}_{2}{\mathrm{Te}}_{6}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.054419</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.054419"/>
        <updated>2023-08-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chiara Bigi, Lei Qiao, Chao Liu, Paolo Barone, Monica Ciomaga Hatnean, Gesa-R. Siemann, Barat Achinuq, Daniel Alexander Mayoh, Giovanni Vinai, Vincent Polewczyk, Deepak Dagur, Federico Mazzola, Peter Bencok, Thorsten Hesjedal, Gerrit van der Laan, Wei Ren, Geetha Balakrishnan, Silvia Picozzi, and Phil D. C. King
This work establishes the spectroscopic fingerprints of ferrimagnetic Mn3Si2Te6, providing a comprehensive understanding of the electronic states underpinning its magnetic interactions. The authors show the pivotal role played by covalency, which weakens the electronic correlations and influences the magnetic frustrations and anisotropic exchange, leading to the onset of the long-range ferrimagnetic order in this compound. The approach of combining spectroscopic experiments with state-of-the-art first-principles theory will have widespread applicability across the families of layered and quasilayered magnetic materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 054419] Published Fri Aug 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chiara Bigi, Lei Qiao, Chao Liu, Paolo Barone, Monica Ciomaga Hatnean, Gesa-R. Siemann, Barat Achinuq, Daniel Alexander Mayoh, Giovanni Vinai, Vincent Polewczyk, Deepak Dagur, Federico Mazzola, Peter Bencok, Thorsten Hesjedal, Gerrit van der Laan, Wei Ren, Geetha Balakrishnan, Silvia Picozzi, and Phil D. C. King</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ultrafast Hidden Spin Polarization Dynamics of Bright and Dark Excitons in $2\mathrm{H}\text{−}{\mathrm{WSe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.066402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.066402"/>
        <updated>2023-08-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mauro Fanciulli, David Bresteau, Jérôme Gaudin, Shuo Dong, Romain Géneaux, Thierry Ruchon, Olivier Tcherbakoff, Ján Minár, Olivier Heckmann, Maria Christine Richter, Karol Hricovini, and Samuel Beaulieu
Multifaceted (spin-, time-, and angle-resolved) photoemission spectroscopy in transitional metal dichalcogenides provide optical control of excitons that could aid the study of spintronics in these systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 066402] Published Thu Aug 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mauro Fanciulli, David Bresteau, Jérôme Gaudin, Shuo Dong, Romain Géneaux, Thierry Ruchon, Olivier Tcherbakoff, Ján Minár, Olivier Heckmann, Maria Christine Richter, Karol Hricovini, and Samuel Beaulieu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Metalearning Generalizable Dynamics from Trajectories]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.067301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.067301"/>
        <updated>2023-08-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Qiaofeng Li, Tianyi Wang, Vwani Roychowdhury, and M. K. Jawed
A new artificial intelligence algorithm can model the behavior of a set of objects, such as helical springs or pendulums, using a method that can extrapolate to objects that the algorithm hasn’t previously analyzed.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 067301] Published Thu Aug 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qiaofeng Li, Tianyi Wang, Vwani Roychowdhury, and M. K. Jawed</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aspects of the phenomenology of interference that are genuinely nonclassical]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.022207</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.022207"/>
        <updated>2023-08-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lorenzo Catani, Matthew Leifer, Giovanni Scala, David Schmid, and Robert W. Spekkens
The authors show that a certain wave-particle duality relation is a type of uncertainty relation whose functional form is known to be able to witness the impossibility of a noncontextual model. In this way, they show that the quantum trade-off between path distinguishability and fringe visibility can witness contextuality and they discuss the requirements on an interferometric experiment necessary for achieving a noise-robust test.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 022207] Published Thu Aug 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lorenzo Catani, Matthew Leifer, Giovanni Scala, David Schmid, and Robert W. Spekkens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Cross an Energy Barrier at Zero Kelvin without Tunneling Effect]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.066701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.066701"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Seiji Miyashita and Bernard Barbara
Irradiating a uniaxial magnetic system with a specific sequence of microwave pulses can induce in the system quantum oscillations that cause the material’s spins to flip back and forth.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 066701] Published Wed Aug 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Seiji Miyashita and Bernard Barbara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Instability of Magnetic Skyrmion Strings Induced by Longitudinal Spin Currents]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.066702</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.066702"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shun Okumura, Volodymyr P. Kravchuk, and Markus Garst
A simple mechanism to topologically unwind magnetic textures uses currents flowing perpendicular to the skyrmion plane to trigger a Goldstone spin-wave instability that eventually destroys skyrmions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 066702] Published Wed Aug 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shun Okumura, Volodymyr P. Kravchuk, and Markus Garst</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Von Kármán vortex street past a permeable circular cylinder: Two-dimensional flow and dynamic-mode-decomposition-based secondary stability analysis]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.083901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.083901"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): F. Caruso Lombardi, A. Bongarzone, G. A. Zampogna, F. Gallaire, S. Camarri, and P. G. Ledda
We explore the role of permeability in modifying the vortex shedding past a permeable circular cylinder. The two-dimensional (2D) von Kármán vortex street sets at progressively larger distances from the body and is eventually suppressed, as permeability increases. Using Dynamic Mode Decomposition we perform a linear stability analysis with respect to three-dimensional perturbations of the 2D periodic vortex shedding. We identify a range of permeability in which the shedding remains 2D, at least for the values of Reynolds number considered here; for larger values of permeability, the wake remains steady and 2D.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 083901] Published Wed Aug 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>F. Caruso Lombardi, A. Bongarzone, G. A. Zampogna, F. Gallaire, S. Camarri, and P. G. Ledda</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Refined spin-wave model and multimagnon bound states in ${\mathrm{Li}}_{2}{\mathrm{CuO}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.064408</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.064408"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Eli Zoghlin, Matthew B. Stone, and Stephen D. Wilson
Quasi-one-dimensional materials serve as both testbeds for tractable magnetic models and as a perennial source of intriguing physics. An excellent example is the emergence of multimagnon bound states in ferromagnetic (FM) spin chains, which provide a platform for probing a few-body quantum phenomenon. Despite being studied for many years, the exchange anisotropy-driven bound state of a FM chain has yet to be observed by inelastic neutron scattering (INS). As INS provides a unique window into the nature of magnon-magnon interactions, this represents a substantive gap in the literature. Here, the authors rectify this gap by presenting detailed INS data on the S=½ spin chain Li2CuO2. Their data allows for determination of a refined spin Hamiltonian which fully describes the one-magnon dispersion. With these details in hand, they demonstrate the existence of two-magnon and, potentially, three-magnon bound states in Li2CuO2, with the potential three-magnon bound state showing anomalous behavior.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 064408] Published Wed Aug 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eli Zoghlin, Matthew B. Stone, and Stephen D. Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hybrid higher-order skin-topological effect in hyperbolic lattices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.075122</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.075122"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Junsong Sun, Chang-An Li, Shiping Feng, and Huaiming Guo
The hyperbolic lattice, existing in a space of constant negative curvature, displays unique physical properties compared to its Euclidean counterpart, and has garnered significant attention recently. Here, the authors have proposed the existence of a higher-order skin-topological effect in hyperbolic lattices. This result first introduces a non-Hermitian effect into hyperbolic lattices, which extends the regime of topological phases with hyperbolic geometry.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 075122] Published Wed Aug 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Junsong Sun, Chang-An Li, Shiping Feng, and Huaiming Guo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Low-dissipation data bus via coherent quantum dynamics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.075405</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.075405"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dylan Lewis, João P. Moutinho, Antonio T. Costa, Yasser Omar, and Sougato Bose
The transport of information is an essential component of both classical and quantum computers. Coherent quantum dynamics offers the potential for the transfer of information through a linear array of quantum dots almost without dissipation. Here, the authors describe a protocol and calculate the energetic cost of transferring quantum states as a quantum or classical data bus, showing its advantage over the shuttling of electrons and classical data buses.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 075405] Published Wed Aug 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dylan Lewis, João P. Moutinho, Antonio T. Costa, Yasser Omar, and Sougato Bose</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic nematic order in the normal state of strontium ruthenate]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L081105</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L081105"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ryan S. Russell, Hari P. Nair, Kyle M. Shen, Darrell G. Schlom, and John W. Harter
The nature of unconventional superconductivity in Sr2RuO4 remains stubbornly unresolved, and it is clear that a fundamental piece of the puzzle is still missing. Here, the authors use static and ultrafast optical dichroism measurements to uncover signatures of electronic nematic order in high quality epitaxially strained thin films of Sr2RuO4. Through the development of a simple Ising model of the nematic order, the authors show that optical pumping induces a coherent oscillation of its amplitude mode. Whether and how this nematic order ultimately influences the superconductivity in Sr2RuO4 remains a key open question.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L081105] Published Wed Aug 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ryan S. Russell, Hari P. Nair, Kyle M. Shen, Darrell G. Schlom, and John W. Harter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing Rydberg-state dc polarizability by microwave dressing]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.022805</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.022805"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. C. Bohorquez, R. Chinnarasu, J. Isaacs, D. Booth, M. Beck, R. McDermott, and M. Saffman
The authors demonstrate a reduction of the dc polarizability of cesium atom Rydberg states in a 77-K environment utilizing microwave field dressing. The results could be useful for stabilizing Rydberg resonances against varying dc fields present near surfaces and potentially enabling the development of hybrid Rydberg-atom–superconducting-resonator quantum gates.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 022805] Published Wed Aug 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. C. Bohorquez, R. Chinnarasu, J. Isaacs, D. Booth, M. Beck, R. McDermott, and M. Saffman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photon emission statistics of a driven microwave cavity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033091</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033091"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pedro Portugal, Fredrik Brange, Kalle S. U. Kansanen, Peter Samuelsson, and Christian Flindt
A theory that can predict the photon-emission statistics from driven microwave cavities is developed. Specifically, it’s shown how the photon-emission statistics is fully determined by a Riccati equation.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 033091] Published Tue Aug 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pedro Portugal, Fredrik Brange, Kalle S. U. Kansanen, Peter Samuelsson, and Christian Flindt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All-Order Coulomb Corrections to Delbrück Scattering above the Pair-Production Threshold]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.061601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.061601"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Sommerfeldt, V. A. Yerokhin, Th. Stöhlker, and A. Surzhykov
Improved calculations of a quantum phenomenon called Delbrück scattering resolve a long-standing discrepancy between theory and experiment.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 061601] Published Tue Aug 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Sommerfeldt, V. A. Yerokhin, Th. Stöhlker, and A. Surzhykov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-accuracy variational Monte Carlo for frustrated magnets with deep neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.054410</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.054410"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christopher Roth, Attila Szabó, and Allan H. MacDonald
Establishing quantum spin liquid physics in microscopic models is a daunting task due to a variety of competing low-energy states, requiring sophisticated computational approaches to find the true ground state. Here, the authors present such a technique, based on neural networks with space-group symmetry, to obtain significantly improved ground-state wave functions of frustrated Heisenberg models. The authors also use this approach to find excited states and provide a blueprint for testing analytical predictions from spin-liquid theories.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 054410] Published Tue Aug 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher Roth, Attila Szabó, and Allan H. MacDonald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phase transitions and bunching of correlated particles in a non-Hermitian quasicrystal]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.075121</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.075121"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Stefano Longhi
Strongly correlated systems in non-Hermitian models are an emergent area of research. Here, the author considers the correlated hopping dynamics of two fermions in a quasicrystal with a complex phase, unraveling non-Hermitian-induced mobility edges and the tendency of the fermions to stick together, forming a doublon state in the long time limit of evolution, a phenomenon that can be dubbed non-Hermitian particle bunching.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 075121] Published Tue Aug 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stefano Longhi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast Neutrino Flavor Conversions Can Help and Hinder Neutrino-Driven Explosions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.061401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.061401"/>
        <updated>2023-08-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jakob Ehring, Sajad Abbar, Hans-Thomas Janka, Georg Raffelt, and Irene Tamborra
We present the first simulations of core-collapse supernovae in axial symmetry with feedback from fast neutrino flavor conversion (FFC). Our schematic treatment of FFCs assumes instantaneous flavor equilibration under the constraint of lepton-number conservation individually for each flavor. Systema…
[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 061401] Published Mon Aug 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jakob Ehring, Sajad Abbar, Hans-Thomas Janka, Georg Raffelt, and Irene Tamborra</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search for Higgs Boson Decay to a Charm Quark-Antiquark Pair in Proton-Proton Collisions at $\sqrt{s}=13\text{ }\text{ }\mathrm{TeV}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.061801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.061801"/>
        <updated>2023-08-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Tumasyan et al. (CMS Collaboration)
Decays of Z bosons to charm quark-antiquark pairs have been observed for the first time at a hadron collider, as part of a search for decays of Higgs bosons to charm quark-antiquark pairs, which are bounded at 14 times the standard model value.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 061801] Published Mon Aug 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Tumasyan &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (CMS Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anti-Parity-Time Symmetry in a Su-Schrieffer-Heeger Sonic Lattice]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.066601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.066601"/>
        <updated>2023-08-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bolun Hu, Zhiwang Zhang, Zichong Yue, Danwei Liao, Yimin Liu, Haixiao Zhang, Ying Cheng, Xiaojun Liu, and Johan Christensen
A novel acoustic Su-Schrieffer-Heeger chain with non-Hermitian components displays a non-Hermitian phase transition and reveals new acoustic topological interface states with tunable robust confinement.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 066601] Published Mon Aug 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bolun Hu, Zhiwang Zhang, Zichong Yue, Danwei Liao, Yimin Liu, Haixiao Zhang, Ying Cheng, Xiaojun Liu, and Johan Christensen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physical Constraints in Intracellular Signaling: The Cost of Sending a Bit]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.068401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.068401"/>
        <updated>2023-08-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Samuel J. Bryant and Benjamin B. Machta
Calculations of the minimum energy a cell requires to transmit a signal between two internal components could help scientists understand how energy and information combine to produce living systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 068401] Published Mon Aug 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel J. Bryant and Benjamin B. Machta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>