<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-10-27T00:43:12.671Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-10-27T00:43:12.671Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emergence of a Spin Microemulsion in Spin-Orbit Coupled Bose-Einstein Condensates]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.173403</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.173403"/>
        <updated>2023-10-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ethan C. McGarrigle, Kris T. Delaney, Leon Balents, and Glenn H. Fredrickson
A phase that shares some properties with mayonnaise can form in a Bose-Einstein condensate.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 173403] Published Thu Oct 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan C. McGarrigle, Kris T. Delaney, Leon Balents, and Glenn H. Fredrickson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Internal clock of many-body delocalization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134204</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134204"/>
        <updated>2023-10-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ferdinand Evers, Ishita Modak, and Soumya Bera
For over two decades, researchers have investigated the effect of many-body interactions on Anderson localization. Early studies proposed many-body localization, i.e., strict particle confinement under strong disorder. Here, the authors challenge this notion by highlighting the prevalence of many-body delocalization in a fruit-fly model: the disordered Heisenberg chain. Its relaxation dynamics synchronize over various variables and parameters while adopting the entanglement entropy as an “internal clock”. These results suggest entanglement evolution as a novel temporal measure for a nuanced understanding of relaxation dynamics.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 134204] Published Thu Oct 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ferdinand Evers, Ishita Modak, and Soumya Bera</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Educational data augmentation in physics education research using ChatGPT]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.020150</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.020150"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fabian Kieser, Peter Wulff, Jochen Kuhn, and Stefan Küchemann
ChatGPT can be used to answer concept inventories and subsequently generate humanlike answers.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 19, 020150] Published Wed Oct 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fabian Kieser, Peter Wulff, Jochen Kuhn, and Stefan Küchemann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Second Data Release from the European Pulsar Timing Array: Challenging the Ultralight Dark Matter Paradigm]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.171001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.171001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Clemente Smarra et al. (European Pulsar Timing Array)
If ultralight dark matter particles exist, they can contribute no more than 70% of the dark matter between Earth and a set of monitored pulsars.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 171001] Published Wed Oct 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Clemente Smarra &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (European Pulsar Timing Array)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fluid-Glass-Jamming Rheology of Soft Active Brownian Particles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178302"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Roland Wiese, Klaus Kroy, and Demian Levis
With activity taking the place of temperature, a fluid-glass-jamming phase diagram is constructed for active Brownian particles under shear.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 178302] Published Wed Oct 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Roland Wiese, Klaus Kroy, and Demian Levis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lorentz Reciprocal Theorem in Fluids with Odd Viscosity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178303</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178303"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuto Hosaka, Ramin Golestanian, and Andrej Vilfan
The Lorentz reciprocal theorem, crucial for understanding microswimmer propulsion, is generalizable to fluids with odd viscosity.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 178303] Published Wed Oct 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuto Hosaka, Ramin Golestanian, and Andrej Vilfan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spontaneous Demixing of Binary Colloidal Flocks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178304"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Samadarshi Maity and Alexandre Morin
A homogenous mixture of two self-propelling species first forms a polar vortex and then spontaneously demixes, thanks to a difference in speeds and other competing effects.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 178304] Published Wed Oct 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samadarshi Maity and Alexandre Morin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of inertia-gravity wave attractors in an axisymmetric enclosed basin]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.104802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.104802"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Corentin Pacary, Thierry Dauxois, Evgeny Ermanyuk, Pascal Metz, Marc Moulin, and Sylvain Joubaud
The peculiar reflection of internal waves in rotating stratified fluids enables the concentration of energy on a limit cycle, called an attractor. In this work, the existence of internal gravity wave attractors for rotating stratified fluids is predicted in three-dimensional axisymmetric geometry. This information is used to design experiments using a truncated conical shaped tank in order to form an inertia-gravity waves attractor. We highlight an important difference in the nonlinear regime between the stratification-only and the rotation-only cases.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 104802] Published Wed Oct 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Corentin Pacary, Thierry Dauxois, Evgeny Ermanyuk, Pascal Metz, Marc Moulin, and Sylvain Joubaud</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Negative tripartite mutual information after quantum quenches in integrable systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134434</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134434"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fabio Caceffo and Vincenzo Alba
The tripartite information (TMI) has emerged as a tool to sieve quantum correlations in quantum many-body systems. A negative TMI is interpreted as evidence for quantum information delocalization in chaotic systems. Here, the authors show that a negative TMI can appear in out-of-equilibrium free-fermion models, and it is linked to the presence of entangled multiplets of excitations. Negative TMI signals a weakening of the relationship between entanglement and thermodynamics, which can be understood in a generalized quasiparticle picture framework.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 134434] Published Wed Oct 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fabio Caceffo and Vincenzo Alba</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perpendicular electronic transport and moiré-induced resonance in twisted interfaces of three-dimensional graphite]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165422</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165422"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tenta Tani, Takuto Kawakami, and Mikito Koshino
In moiré materials, the interference patterns give rise to flat bands and introduce novel physical properties. While previous work has mainly focused on two-dimensional systems, the authors theoretically investigate here emergent phenomena in twisted three-dimensional graphite composed of a misoriented pair of graphite pieces. Despite the twisted interface comprising only a small fraction of the entire structure, it is revealed that the moiré pattern produces interface localized bands, leading to a pronounced Fano resonance in electric conduction.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 165422] Published Wed Oct 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tenta Tani, Takuto Kawakami, and Mikito Koshino</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making context explicit in equation construction and interpretation: Symbolic blending]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.020149</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.020149"/>
        <updated>2023-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Benjamin P. Schermerhorn and John R. Thompson
The symbolic blending model can be used to analyze students’ mathematical sense-making when constructing equations in upper-division physics.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 19, 020149] Published Tue Oct 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin P. Schermerhorn and John R. Thompson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generation of High-Density High-Polarization Positrons via Single-Shot Strong Laser-Foil Interaction]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.175101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.175101"/>
        <updated>2023-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kun Xue, Ting Sun, Ke-Jia Wei, Zhong-Peng Li, Qian Zhao, Feng Wan, Chong Lv, Yong-Tao Zhao, Zhong-Feng Xu, and Jian-Xing Li
Numerical simulations show that highly-polarized dense positron beams can be generated during single-shot interaction of a strong laser with a tilted solid foil by carefully controlling the angle of incidence of the laser on the target.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 175101] Published Tue Oct 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kun Xue, Ting Sun, Ke-Jia Wei, Zhong-Peng Li, Qian Zhao, Feng Wan, Chong Lv, Yong-Tao Zhao, Zhong-Feng Xu, and Jian-Xing Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Traveling Perversion as Constant Torque Actuator]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.177201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.177201"/>
        <updated>2023-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Émilien Dilly, Sébastien Neukirch, Julien Derr, and Dražen Zanchi
Helical bacteria and corkscrew rods can both undergo handedness reversals that could be useful in future robotic systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 177201] Published Tue Oct 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Émilien Dilly, Sébastien Neukirch, Julien Derr, and Dražen Zanchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bend or Twist? What Plectonemes Reveal about the Mysterious Motility of <i>Spiroplasma</i>]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178401"/>
        <updated>2023-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Paul M. Ryan, Joshua W. Shaevitz, and Charles W. Wolgemuth
Helical bacteria and corkscrew rods can both undergo handedness reversals that could be useful in future robotic systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 178401] Published Tue Oct 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul M. Ryan, Joshua W. Shaevitz, and Charles W. Wolgemuth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to train your demon to do fast information erasure without heat production]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.044138</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.044138"/>
        <updated>2023-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Stephen Whitelam
Time-dependent protocols that perform irreversible logical operations, such as memory erasure, cost work and produce heat, placing bounds on the efficiency of computers. Using a model of a physical memory, the author shows that a neural-network demon can learn feedback-control protocols to do fast memory erasure without input of work or production of heat.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 044138] Published Tue Oct 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen Whitelam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Resonant x-ray diffraction study using circularly polarized x rays on antiferromagnetic ${\mathrm{TbB}}_{4}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134433</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134433"/>
        <updated>2023-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Misawa, K. Arakawa, T. Yoshioka, H. Ueda, F. Iga, K. Tamasaku, Y. Tanaka, and T. Kimura
The interference effect between the magnetic scattering and the charge scattering in resonant x-ray diffraction (RXD) leads to circular dichroism. The authors utilize this effect here to distinguish the antiferromagnetic (AFM) domain state in the noncollinear antiferromagnet TbB4, breaking both the space-inversion (P) and time-reversal (T) symmetries but preserving the combined PT symmetry. This result shows that circularly polarized RXD using the interference effect enables us to detect AFM order parameters and spatially resolve the domain state in PT-symmetric AFM materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 134433] Published Tue Oct 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Misawa, K. Arakawa, T. Yoshioka, H. Ueda, F. Iga, K. Tamasaku, Y. Tanaka, and T. Kimura</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gate-voltage switching of nonreciprocal transport in oxide-based Rashba interfaces]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044060</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044060"/>
        <updated>2023-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Julien Bréhin, Luis M. Vicente Arche, Sara Varotto, Srijani Mallik, Jean-Philippe Attané, Laurent Vila, Agnès Barthélémy, Nicolas Bergeal, and Manuel Bibes
Rashba interfaces enable spin-charge interconversion via the direct and inverse Edelstein effects, and so may be used to replace ferromagnets as efficient sources and detectors of spin. However, the direction of spins generated by a ferromagnet can be easily switched, while that of spins generated by a Rashba system is usually fixed, being set by its electronic structure. This study shows that in SrTiO3-based Rashba interfaces, where multiple electronic bands contribute differently to charge-spin conversion, the application of gate voltage enables a sign change of the charge-spin conversion effect. This offers possibilities for innovative spin-based logic devices.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 044060] Published Tue Oct 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julien Bréhin, Luis M. Vicente Arche, Sara Varotto, Srijani Mallik, Jean-Philippe Attané, Laurent Vila, Agnès Barthélémy, Nicolas Bergeal, and Manuel Bibes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multimode Brownian dynamics of a nanomechanical resonator in a viscous fluid]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044061</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044061"/>
        <updated>2023-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): H. Gress, J. Barbish, C. Yanik, I.I. Kaya, R.T. Erdogan, M.S. Hanay, M. González, O. Svitelskiy, M.R. Paul, and K.L. Ekinci
The ultimate precision attainable in a mechanical measurement can be determined from the random Brownian motion of the mechanical structure, if the nature of the fluctuations is well understood. To this end, the authors study the Brownian fluctuations of a nanomechanical beam in a viscous fluid. Their predictions based on elasticity theory, fluid dynamics, and statistical mechanics agree well with their experiments, indicating that the observed fluctuations come with “viscous memory”, but no spatial correlations. The insights from this work are expected to impact the design of nanoelectromechanical systems, cantilevers for atomic force microscopy, and other mechanical sensors.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 044061] Published Tue Oct 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>H. Gress, J. Barbish, C. Yanik, I.I. Kaya, R.T. Erdogan, M.S. Hanay, M. González, O. Svitelskiy, M.R. Paul, and K.L. Ekinci</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fabry-Pérot Interferometry at the $ν=2/5$ Fractional Quantum Hall State]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041012</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041012"/>
        <updated>2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Nakamura, S. Liang, G. C. Gardner, and M. J. Manfra
Fabry-Perot interferometry can observe anyon behavior at complex fractional states—a key requirement for analyzing non-abelian states that are sought after for intrinsically fault-tolerant qubits.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 041012] Published Mon Oct 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Nakamura, S. Liang, G. C. Gardner, and M. J. Manfra</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tuning the Curie temperature of a two-dimensional magnet/topological insulator heterostructure to above room temperature by epitaxial growth]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.104004</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.104004"/>
        <updated>2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wenyi Zhou, Alexander J. Bishop, Xiyue S. Zhang, Katherine Robinson, Igor Lyalin, Ziling Li, Ryan Bailey-Crandell, Thow Min Jerald Cham, Shuyu Cheng, Yunqiu Kelly Luo, Daniel C. Ralph, David A. Muller, and Roland K. Kawakami
The heterostructures of 2D magnets and topological insulators are attractive candidates for quantum anomalous hall effect and highly-efficient spin-orbit torque switching. To better study these phenomena, it will be crucial to synthesize epitaxial heterostructures for scalability while maintaining high-quality interfaces to preserve the topological surface states and having the Curie temperature (TC) above room temperature. Here, the authors utilize molecular beam epitaxy to tune the TC in heterostructures of van der Waals (vdW) magnet Fe3GeTe2 and topological insulator Bi2Te3 to above room temperature by varying growth conditions. Electron microscopy reveals the existence of thicker vdW compounds in the FemGenTe2 family, as well as some intercalants in between vdW gaps, which are possible origins for the enhanced TC.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 104004] Published Mon Oct 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wenyi Zhou, Alexander J. Bishop, Xiyue S. Zhang, Katherine Robinson, Igor Lyalin, Ziling Li, Ryan Bailey-Crandell, Thow Min Jerald Cham, Shuyu Cheng, Yunqiu Kelly Luo, Daniel C. Ralph, David A. Muller, and Roland K. Kawakami</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Construction of Coarse-Grained Molecular Dynamics with Many-Body Non-Markovian Memory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.177301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.177301"/>
        <updated>2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Liyao Lyu and Huan Lei
A machine-learning-based coarse-grained molecular dynamics (CGMD) model faithfully retains the many-body nature of the intermolecular dissipative interactions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 177301] Published Mon Oct 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liyao Lyu and Huan Lei</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electric Fields in Liquid Water Irradiated with Protons at Ultrahigh Dose Rates]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): F. Gobet, P. Barberet, M.-H. Delville, G. Devès, T. Guérin, R. Liénard, H. N. Tran, C. Vecco-Garda, A. Würger, S. Zein, and H. Seznec
Ultrahigh dose rates of proton irradiation induce electrokinetic effects in water that can perturb the dynamics of charged particles, such as macromolecules, in biological tissues and other aqueous systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 178001] Published Mon Oct 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>F. Gobet, P. Barberet, M.-H. Delville, G. Devès, T. Guérin, R. Liénard, H. N. Tran, C. Vecco-Garda, A. Würger, S. Zein, and H. Seznec</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple parameter estimation using observable features of gravitational-wave signals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.082006</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.082006"/>
        <updated>2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Stephen Fairhurst, Charlie Hoy, Rhys Green, Cameron Mills, and Samantha A. Usman
Rapid extraction of parameters to characterize sources of gravitational wave signals is vitally important to gravitational wave astronomy. This paper provides an intuitive method for extracting parameters more efficiently than existing full parameter estimation methods. Among other applications, these new methods appear to be promising ways of addressing real-time needs such as generating gravitational wave event alerts.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 082006] Published Mon Oct 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen Fairhurst, Charlie Hoy, Rhys Green, Cameron Mills, and Samantha A. Usman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Homotopic classification of band structures: Stable, fragile, delicate, and stable representation-protected topology]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155137</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155137"/>
        <updated>2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Piet W. Brouwer and Vatsal Dwivedi
Fragile and delicate topological phases of noninteracting fermions can be trivialized under addition of trivial bands, in contrast to strong topological phases. Here, the authors describe a classification procedure based on homotopy theory for topological insulators with a fixed number of bands. They thereby classify band structures symmetric under discrete rotations and time-reversal at the highest possible level of granularity and identify instances of “representation-protected stable topology”, which is robust to addition of trivial bands with a fixed orbital type.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 155137] Published Mon Oct 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Piet W. Brouwer and Vatsal Dwivedi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Range-separated hybrid functional pseudopotentials]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165142</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165142"/>
        <updated>2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yang Yang, Georgia Prokopiou, Tian Qiu, Aaron M. Schankler, Andrew M. Rappe, Leeor Kronik, and Robert A. DiStasio, Jr.
This work presents a general scheme for constructing pseudopotentials for advanced density functional theory (DFT) calculations employing range-separated hybrid (RSH) functionals. The authors demonstrate pseudopotential construction for several atoms and RSH functionals, and find that pseudopotential consistency errors tend to be systematic when computing solid-state properties and can exceed 0.1 eV for band gaps. This work removes the need to incur such unnecessary errors when performing state-of-the-art electronic structure calculations at the computationally demanding RSH-DFT level.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 165142] Published Mon Oct 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yang Yang, Georgia Prokopiou, Tian Qiu, Aaron M. Schankler, Andrew M. Rappe, Leeor Kronik, and Robert A. DiStasio, Jr.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum Thermometry with Single Molecules in Nanoprobes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.040314</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.040314"/>
        <updated>2023-10-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): V. Esteso, R. Duquennoy, R.C. Ng, M. Colautti, P. Lombardi, G. Arregui, E. Chavez-Angel, C.M. Sotomayor-Torres, P.D. Garcia, M. Hilke, and C. Toninelli
A single-molecule thermometer provides two-dimensional mapping with high spatial and temperature resolution under cryogenic conditions.

[PRX Quantum 4, 040314] Published Fri Oct 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>V. Esteso, R. Duquennoy, R.C. Ng, M. Colautti, P. Lombardi, G. Arregui, E. Chavez-Angel, C.M. Sotomayor-Torres, P.D. Garcia, M. Hilke, and C. Toninelli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple Reaction-Diffusion Modeling Predicts Inconspicuous Neighborhood-Dependent Color Subclustering of Lizard Scales]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041011</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041011"/>
        <updated>2023-10-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Szabolcs Zakany and Michel C. Milinkovitch
Researchers have predicted—and confirmed—a secondary pattern on the ocellated lizard’s scales that is too subtle for our eyes to see.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 041011] Published Fri Oct 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Szabolcs Zakany and Michel C. Milinkovitch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cost and routing of continuous-variable quantum networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042615</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042615"/>
        <updated>2023-10-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Federico Centrone, Frederic Grosshans, and Valentina Parigi
The authors give insight into the amount of entanglement that can be achieved from Gaussian graph states as well as the amount of squeezing required to prepare them. They find that these quantities are highly dependent on the structure of the quantum network.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 042615] Published Fri Oct 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Federico Centrone, Frederic Grosshans, and Valentina Parigi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Wire a $1000$-Qubit Trapped-Ion Quantum Computer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.040313</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.040313"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Malinowski, D.T.C. Allcock, and C.J. Ballance
A concrete proposal for a 1000-qubit trapped-ion quantum processor takes advantage of integrated switching electronics to reduce the wiring complexity without reducing operation fidelity.

[PRX Quantum 4, 040313] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Malinowski, D.T.C. Allcock, and C.J. Ballance</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dragon kings in self-organized criticality systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.L042013</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.L042013"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Guram Mikaberidze, Arthur Plaud, and Raissa M. D'Souza
Models of self-organized criticality can surprisingly produce dragon king failures—massive, self-amplifying cascading events. It is analytically demonstrated that dragon kings are created by the trade-off between driving impulse and dissipation rate.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, L042013] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guram Mikaberidze, Arthur Plaud, and Raissa M. D'Souza</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canted antiferromagnetism in polar ${\mathrm{MnSiN}}_{2}$ with high Néel temperature]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.104406</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.104406"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Linus Kautzsch, Alexandru B. Georgescu, Danilo Puggioni, Greggory Kent, Keith M. Taddei, Aiden Reilly, Ram Seshadri, James M. Rondinelli, and Stephen D. Wilson
Ternary nitrides are a burgeoning materials class hosting diverse structures, compositions, and properties that make them appealing for various applications. Magnetic nitrogen-rich compounds generally remain underexplored, despite the unique chemical bonding afforded by the N3− ion with open d-shell transition metals. Here, the authors explore the compound MnSiN2 where Mn2+ ions reside on a 3D diamond-like covalent network with strong magnetic superexchange pathways. The compound exhibits a high Néel ordering temperature of TN = 443 K and the precise canted ground state magnetic structure is resolved using a combination of DFT modeling and powder neutron diffraction.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 104406] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Linus Kautzsch, Alexandru B. Georgescu, Danilo Puggioni, Greggory Kent, Keith M. Taddei, Aiden Reilly, Ram Seshadri, James M. Rondinelli, and Stephen D. Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Gluon Showers inside a Quark-Gluon Plasma Strongly Coupled? A Theorist’s Test]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.162302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.162302"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Peter Arnold, Omar Elgedawy, and Shahin Iqbal
A theoretical study demonstrates that in-medium showers of high-energy gluons can be approximately treated as a sequence of individual splitting processes.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 162302] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Arnold, Omar Elgedawy, and Shahin Iqbal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal Lower Bound on Topological Entanglement Entropy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.166601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.166601"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Isaac H. Kim, Michael Levin, Ting-Chun Lin, Daniel Ranard, and Bowen Shi
A lower bound to the topological entanglement entropy partially restores its universality.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 166601] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaac H. Kim, Michael Levin, Ting-Chun Lin, Daniel Ranard, and Bowen Shi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Droplets sliding on single and multiple vertical fibers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.103601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.103601"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Leonard, J. Van Hulle, F. Weyer, D. Terwagne, and N. Vandewalle
Exploring droplet dynamics: This study sheds light on the behavior of droplets sliding down vertical fibers, a key issue in microfluidics and fog harvesting. Using real-time tracking, the research covers single and multi-fiber systems. A standout finding is that multiple vertical fibers increase droplet speed but also lead to greater liquid loss in grooves. This discovery is captured in a detailed theoretical model, offering valuable insights for optimizing droplet-based technologies.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 103601] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Leonard, J. Van Hulle, F. Weyer, D. Terwagne, and N. Vandewalle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Landau-Pomeranchuk-Migdal effect in sequential bremsstrahlung: Gluon shower development]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.074015</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.074015"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Peter Arnold, Omar Elgedawy, and Shahin Iqbal
A theoretical study demonstrates that in-medium showers of high-energy gluons can be approximately treated as a sequence of individual splitting processes.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 074015] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Arnold, Omar Elgedawy, and Shahin Iqbal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inclusive hadronic decay rate of the $τ$ lepton from lattice QCD]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.074513</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.074513"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Evangelista, R. Frezzotti, N. Tantalo, G. Gagliardi, F. Sanfilippo, S. Simula, and V. Lubicz (Extended Twisted Mass Collaboration)
The authors express the inclusive hadronic decay rate of the tau lepton as an integral over the spectral density of the two-point correlator of the weak V−A hadronic current which they compute fully nonperturbatively in lattice QCD. In a lattice QCD computation with all systematic errors except for isospin breaking effects under control, they then obtain the CKM matrix element Vud with subpercent errors showing that their nonperturbative method can become a viable alternative to superallowed nuclear beta decays for obtaining Vud.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 074513] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Evangelista, R. Frezzotti, N. Tantalo, G. Gagliardi, F. Sanfilippo, S. Simula, and V. Lubicz (Extended Twisted Mass Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Characterizing cosmic birefringence in the presence of Galactic foregrounds and instrumental systematic effects]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.082005</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.082005"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Baptiste Jost, Josquin Errard, and Radek Stompor
The authors propose a new analysis framework to account simultaneously for Galactic foregrounds and instrumental effects, in order to break the degeneracy between Cosmic Birefringence (CB) angle and Cosmic Microwave Background detector effects. They thus pave the way for Simons Observatory-like Small Aperture Telescopes to test claims for CB detection.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 082005] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Baptiste Jost, Josquin Errard, and Radek Stompor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly Heisenberg-limited noise-unbiased frequency estimation by tailored sensor design]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042419</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042419"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Francisco Riberi, Gerardo A. Paz-Silva, and Lorenza Viola
The authors consider frequency estimation in the presence of spatiotemporally correlated noise. They show that the usual approach involving unbiased estimators is ill-suited in such cases, and introduce new estimators which, at the cost of doubling the required resources, are insensitive to noise and retain the precision scaling of standard ones.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 042419] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Francisco Riberi, Gerardo A. Paz-Silva, and Lorenza Viola</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of Anisotropic Superfluid Density in an Artificial Crystal]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.163401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.163401"/>
        <updated>2023-10-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Tao, M. Zhao, and I. B. Spielman
Trapping a Bose-Einstein condensate (BEC) in an optical lattice, researchers confirm a 53-year-old theory that connects BECs to superfluids and supersolids.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 163401] Published Wed Oct 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Tao, M. Zhao, and I. B. Spielman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Controlled Excitation of Rotons in Superfluid Helium with an Optical Centrifuge]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.166001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.166001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexander A. Milner and Valery Milner
A laser pulse with rotating linear polarization creates roton pairs in superfluid helium.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 166001] Published Wed Oct 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexander A. Milner and Valery Milner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phase ordering dynamics of the random-field long-range Ising model in one dimension]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.044131</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.044131"/>
        <updated>2023-10-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ramgopal Agrawal, Federico Corberi, Eugenio Lippiello, and Sanjay Puri
There has been progress in understanding the phase-ordering dynamics of systems with long-range interactions, but less is known for such systems with disorder. This work addresses that topic by studying the influence of long-range interactions on the phase ordering dynamics of the one-dimensional random-field Ising model.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 044131] Published Wed Oct 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ramgopal Agrawal, Federico Corberi, Eugenio Lippiello, and Sanjay Puri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum spin liquids on the diamond lattice]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134424</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134424"/>
        <updated>2023-10-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aishwarya Chauhan, Atanu Maity, Chunxiao Liu, Jonas Sonnenschein, Francesco Ferrari, and Yasir Iqbal
The diamond lattice has been a promising playground for both classical and quantum spin liquids. Here, the authors conduct a comprehensive symmetry classification of S=½ quantum spin liquids with SU(2), U(1), and ℤ2 gauge fields, and present dynamical spin structure factors within a self-consistent simulation. The authors highlight three discoveries: spinon Ansätze with robust gapless nodal loops, topological bands realizing topological insulators, and that Gutzwiller projection of the 0- and π-flux SU(2) spin liquids generates long-range Néel order.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 134424] Published Wed Oct 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aishwarya Chauhan, Atanu Maity, Chunxiao Liu, Jonas Sonnenschein, Francesco Ferrari, and Yasir Iqbal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electrical detectability of magnon-mediated spin current shot noise]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144420</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144420"/>
        <updated>2023-10-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Luise Siegl, Michaela Lammel, Akashdeep Kamra, Hans Huebl, Wolfgang Belzig, and Sebastian T. B. Goennenwein
The spin of so-called squeezed magnons has been shown to deviate from the common value ħ, with corresponding changes in the spin-current shot noise. The authors calculate here the magnitude of the concomitant voltage noise in the charge channel for a typical electrically detected spin pumping signal and find that it is significantly smaller than the inevitable Johnson-Nyquist noise. Their analysis thus provides important guidance for the challenges in experimentally detecting squeezed magnons through electrical noise measurements.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 144420] Published Wed Oct 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luise Siegl, Michaela Lammel, Akashdeep Kamra, Hans Huebl, Wolfgang Belzig, and Sebastian T. B. Goennenwein</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rotor/spin-wave theory for quantum spin models with U(1) symmetry]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155130</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155130"/>
        <updated>2023-10-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tommaso Roscilde, Tommaso Comparin, and Fabio Mezzacapo
Elementary excitations of ordered quantum magnets are harmonic spin waves. Yet, when ordering breaks a continuous symmetry, excitations at zero momentum cannot really be treated as harmonic, because they correspond to the Goldstone mode that restores the symmetry in finite-size systems. Here, the authors show that zero-momentum excitations can be treated in a fully nonlinear way in terms of a macroscopic spin variable (the rotor): its spectrum reconstructs the so-called Anderson tower of states, a hallmark of continuous-symmetry breaking systems. The rotor variable can be considered as nearly separate from finite-momentum spin waves, leading to a quantitative reconstruction of the low-energy excitation spectrum of finite-size systems.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 155130] Published Wed Oct 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tommaso Roscilde, Tommaso Comparin, and Fabio Mezzacapo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transition from classical to quantum loss of light coherence]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042214</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042214"/>
        <updated>2023-10-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pierre Lassègues, Mateus Antônio Fernandes Biscassi, Martial Morisse, André Cidrim, Pablo Gabriel Santos Dias, Hodei Eneriz, Raul Celistrino Teixeira, Robin Kaiser, Romain Bachelard, and Mathilde Hugbart
The authors study the loss of light coherence when scattered by a macroscopic atomic cloud of cold neutral atoms through intensity-intensity correlation measurements. They demonstrate experimentally and theoretically the transition between classical and quantum mechanisms regimes for the coherence loss.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 042214] Published Wed Oct 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pierre Lassègues, Mateus Antônio Fernandes Biscassi, Martial Morisse, André Cidrim, Pablo Gabriel Santos Dias, Hodei Eneriz, Raul Celistrino Teixeira, Robin Kaiser, Romain Bachelard, and Mathilde Hugbart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of the Positive Muon Anomalous Magnetic Moment to 0.20 ppm]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.161802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.161802"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. P. Aguillard et al. (The Muon g−2 Collaboration)
The magnetic moment of the muon, a key probe of the standard model and its possible extensions, has been measured to a precision of 200 parts per billion, 2.3 times more precise than their first landmark result.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 161802] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. P. Aguillard &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (The Muon &lt;math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline"&gt;&lt;mi&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mo&gt;−&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;mn&gt;2&lt;/mn&gt;&lt;/math&gt; Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Femtosecond Reduction of Atomic Scattering Factors Triggered by Intense X-Ray Pulse]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.163201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.163201"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ichiro Inoue, Jumpei Yamada, Konrad J. Kapcia, Michal Stransky, Victor Tkachenko, Zoltan Jurek, Takato Inoue, Taito Osaka, Yuichi Inubushi, Atsuki Ito, Yuto Tanaka, Satoshi Matsuyama, Kazuto Yamauchi, Makina Yabashi, and Beata Ziaja
Measurements indicate that intense x-ray pulses can change the electronic structure of a material on femtosecond timescales, a finding that could improve imaging of light–matter interactions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 163201] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ichiro Inoue, Jumpei Yamada, Konrad J. Kapcia, Michal Stransky, Victor Tkachenko, Zoltan Jurek, Takato Inoue, Taito Osaka, Yuichi Inubushi, Atsuki Ito, Yuto Tanaka, Satoshi Matsuyama, Kazuto Yamauchi, Makina Yabashi, and Beata Ziaja</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Room-Temperature Magnetic Phase Transition in an Electrically Tuned van der Waals Ferromagnet]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.166703</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.166703"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Cheng Tan, Ji-Hai Liao, Guolin Zheng, Meri Algarni, Jia-Yi Lin, Xiang Ma, Edwin L. H. Mayes, Matthew R. Field, Sultan Albarakati, Majid Panahandeh-Fard, Saleh Alzahrani, Guopeng Wang, Yuanjun Yang, Dimitrie Culcer, James Partridge, Mingliang Tian, Bin Xiang, Yu-Jun Zhao, and Lan Wang
A ferromagnetism to antiferromagnetism phase transition in a van der Waals magnet at room temperature uses CrTe nanoflakes that may lead to improved spintronic devices.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 166703] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cheng Tan, Ji-Hai Liao, Guolin Zheng, Meri Algarni, Jia-Yi Lin, Xiang Ma, Edwin L. H. Mayes, Matthew R. Field, Sultan Albarakati, Majid Panahandeh-Fard, Saleh Alzahrani, Guopeng Wang, Yuanjun Yang, Dimitrie Culcer, James Partridge, Mingliang Tian, Bin Xiang, Yu-Jun Zhao, and Lan Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microscopic details of two-dimensional spectroscopy of one-dimensional quantum Ising magnets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134423</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134423"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): GiBaik Sim, Frank Pollmann, and Johannes Knolle
This work explores the effectiveness of two-dimensional coherent spectroscopy for understanding the microscopic properties of quantum magnets. Motivated by experiments on the Ising chain magnet CoNb2O6, it is shown that the 2D spectra are markedly different for the two proposed microscopic Hamiltonians - the transverse field Ising model and the twisted Kitaev spin chain - even though the linear response is similar. The findings showcase the power of 2D spectroscopy for quantifying microscopic descriptions and understanding the dynamics of fractionalized excitations of quantum magnets.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 134423] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GiBaik Sim, Frank Pollmann, and Johannes Knolle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic paramagnon-polarons in altermagnets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144418</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144418"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Charles R. W. Steward, Rafael M. Fernandes, and Jörg Schmalian
Altermagnetic states are qualitatively different from ferromagnetic and antiferromagnetic ones, as they are invariant under a combination of rotation and time reversal. The unique properties afforded by such symmetries have attracted significant attention by the community. Here, the authors unearth an unusual dynamic coupling that exists between the altermagnetic and lattice degrees of freedom, which resembles the Hall viscosity. This effect results in a hybridization between altermagnetic and phonon modes, enabling one to directly probe altermagnetic excitations in the phonon spectrum.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 144418] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charles R. W. Steward, Rafael M. Fernandes, and Jörg Schmalian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamical nuclear spin polarization in a quantum dot with an electron spin driven by electric dipole spin resonance]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155306</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155306"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Peter Stano, Takashi Nakajima, Akito Noiri, Seigo Tarucha, and Daniel Loss
When a quantum-dot electron spin is electrically driven to perform coherent Rabi oscillations, it can polarize nuclear spins through a resonance analogous to the Hartmann-Hahn effect known from NMR. Here, the authors theoretically analyze such a polarization rate in a generic setup including GaAs, Si, and Ge, and both electron and hole spin qubits. They present measurements in n-GaAs and estimate that the effect is also observable in Si. It might offer control over the Overhauser nuclear field in gated quantum dots.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 155306] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Stano, Takashi Nakajima, Akito Noiri, Seigo Tarucha, and Daniel Loss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Singular topology of scattering matrices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155418</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155418"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Cheng Guo, Jiazheng Li, Meng Xiao, and Shanhui Fan
The scattering matrix is a crucial characterization of a physical system. The authors present here a systematic topological theory of scattering matrices, focusing on their singular values and vectors. They identify topological characteristics such as winding number, Berry phase, and skew polarization. The theory uncovers the topological nature of coherent perfect absorption and introduces coherent perfect extinction, where a coherent wave is completely extinguished through interference. These findings advance the understanding of scattering and have implications for novel wave devices.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 155418] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cheng Guo, Jiazheng Li, Meng Xiao, and Shanhui Fan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disordered monitored free fermions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165126</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165126"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marcin Szyniszewski, Oliver Lunt, and Arijeet Pal
The authors investigate here the dynamics of free fermions in a random potential system under continuous monitoring. Repeated measurements are known to induce an entanglement phase transition from a logarithmically entangled critical state to area law, while disorder leads to Anderson localization. They show that their interplay results in a stable critical phase at finite disorder strength and dissipation, which drive a transition consistent with Berezinskii-Kosterlitz-Thouless universality. This work is important for testing such phase transitions in quantum dot arrays and nanowires.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 165126] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marcin Szyniszewski, Oliver Lunt, and Arijeet Pal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Possible ${s}_{±}$-wave superconductivity in ${\mathrm{La}}_{3}{\mathrm{Ni}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{7}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L140505</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L140505"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Qing-Geng Yang, Da Wang, and Qiang-Hua Wang
For the new high-temperature superconductor La3Ni2O7 under high pressure, the authors analyze its pairing mechanism and pairing symmetry in a bilayer two-orbital Hubbard model. By combining functional renormalization group in weak-to-moderate interaction regime and Gutzwiller approximation for its low-energy effective model projected to atomic one- and two-electron states in the strong-coupling regime, they find robust extended s-wave or s±-wave pairing as triggered by spin fluctuations.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L140505] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qing-Geng Yang, Da Wang, and Qiang-Hua Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Additive laser excitation of giant nonlinear surface acoustic wave pulses]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044044</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044044"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jude Deschamps, Yun Kai, Jet Lem, Ievgeniia Chaban, Alexey Lomonosov, Abdelmadjid Anane, Steven E. Kooi, Keith A. Nelson, and Thomas Pezeril
Pulsed lasers are routinely used to optically excite and detect ultrasounds in a broad frequency range, from megahertz to terahertz. Though well-established for decades, this technique of laser ultrasonics is constrained by the potential optical damage it may cause to the sample, resulting in the generation of relatively weak pressures, well below kilobars. This study introduces a methodology for the excitation of nondestructive shock waves, at a high repetition rate, limited only by the mechanical strength of the sample. This work establishes a way to repeatedly deliver high-amplitude strain pulses to samples of interest, facilitating the dynamical study of strain-induced phenomena.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 044044] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jude Deschamps, Yun Kai, Jet Lem, Ievgeniia Chaban, Alexey Lomonosov, Abdelmadjid Anane, Steven E. Kooi, Keith A. Nelson, and Thomas Pezeril</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lyapunov spectra of chaotic recurrent neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043044</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043044"/>
        <updated>2023-10-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rainer Engelken, Fred Wolf, and L. F. Abbott
The Lyapunov spectrum of recurrent neural networks is calculated and analytical approximations through random matrix theory are provided. The dependency of attractor dimensions and entropy rates on coupling strength and input fluctuations is identified and a point symmetry of the Lyapunov spectrum is revealed. A link is shown between Lyapunov exponents to error propagation and stability in trained recurrent networks for machine-learning applications.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 043044] Published Mon Oct 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rainer Engelken, Fred Wolf, and L. F. Abbott</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search for Light Dark Matter with NA64 at CERN]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.161801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.161801"/>
        <updated>2023-10-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yu. M. Andreev et al. (NA64 Collaboration)
An experiment at CERN performed by scattering 100 GeV electrons off a fixed target results in limits on thermal dark matter—that requires interactions mediated by hypothetical dark photons—in the MeV mass range.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 161801] Published Mon Oct 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yu. M. Andreev &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (NA64 Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doubly Charmed Tetraquark ${T}_{cc}^{+}$ from Lattice QCD near Physical Point]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.161901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.161901"/>
        <updated>2023-10-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yan Lyu, Sinya Aoki, Takumi Doi, Tetsuo Hatsuda, Yoichi Ikeda, and Jie Meng
A lattice QCD computation close to the physical point finds a near-threshold virtual state in the DD* scattering channel, that suggests the formation of a loosely bound state at the physical point consistent with the experimental observation of a doubly charmed tetraquark Tcc+.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 161901] Published Mon Oct 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yan Lyu, Sinya Aoki, Takumi Doi, Tetsuo Hatsuda, Yoichi Ikeda, and Jie Meng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlinear Topological Magnon Spin Hall Effect]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.166704</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.166704"/>
        <updated>2023-10-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zhejunyu Jin, Xianglong Yao, Zhenyu Wang, H. Y. Yuan, Zhaozhuo Zeng, Weiwei Wang, Yunshan Cao, and Peng Yan
Nonlinear scattering of magnons and skyrmions in antiferromagnets leads to a spin Hall effect that emerges from real-space topology.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 166704] Published Mon Oct 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhejunyu Jin, Xianglong Yao, Zhenyu Wang, H. Y. Yuan, Zhaozhuo Zeng, Weiwei Wang, Yunshan Cao, and Peng Yan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thermodynamic Bounds on Correlation Times]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.167101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.167101"/>
        <updated>2023-10-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Andreas Dechant, Jérôme Garnier-Brun, and Shin-ichi Sasa
An analysis of the correlation time of physical observables in steady-state diffusive systems reveals the existence of lower bounds both in and out of equilibrium.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 167101] Published Mon Oct 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andreas Dechant, Jérôme Garnier-Brun, and Shin-ichi Sasa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[${\mathrm{VO}}_{2}$ under hydrostatic pressure: Isostructural phase transition close to a critical endpoint]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144106</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144106"/>
        <updated>2023-10-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): P. Bouvier, L. Bussmann, D. Machon, I. Breslavetz, G. Garbarino, P. Strobel, and V. Dmitriev
The authors unveil here new findings in the realm of phase transitions in VO2 single crystals, all achieved under hydrostatic pressure conditions. They provide experimental results, exploiting the observation of soft phonons through Raman spectroscopy and high-quality structural refinements. These findings offer a fresh perspective on phase diagrams, including a precise description of the M1-M1′ isostructural transition occurring at a staggering 14 GPa. The study also reveals that isothermal compression at 298 K drives a thrilling journey close to the critical point. The authors present the first Raman signature of the elusive metallic X-phase, observed at pressures exceeding 32 GPa.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 144106] Published Mon Oct 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>P. Bouvier, L. Bussmann, D. Machon, I. Breslavetz, G. Garbarino, P. Strobel, and V. Dmitriev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skyrmions in nanorings: A versatile platform for skyrmionics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044039</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044039"/>
        <updated>2023-10-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dimitris Kechrakos, Vito Puliafito, Alejandro Riveros, Jiahao Liu, Wanjun Jiang, Mario Carpentieri, Riccardo Tomasello, and Giovanni Finocchio
After more than a decade of investigation, unconventional Skyrmionics stands as one of the most promising and interesting directions to explore. The authors show the potentials of the combination of skyrmions with nanoring geometry, by proposing three energy-efficient nanoscale devices: A skyrmion clock with a tunable frequency, a skyrmion alternator where the skyrmion motion is converted into an electrical signal (potentially at μV), and a skyrmion energy harvester to partially recover dissipated heat into electrical energy. This work will stimulate further development in this exciting research direction.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 044039] Published Mon Oct 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dimitris Kechrakos, Vito Puliafito, Alejandro Riveros, Jiahao Liu, Wanjun Jiang, Mario Carpentieri, Riccardo Tomasello, and Giovanni Finocchio</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scalable and programmable three-dimensional photonic processor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044041</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044041"/>
        <updated>2023-10-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xi Tan, Hang Song, Ye Ji, Hao Tang, Ying-Yu Fang, Xiao-Yun Xu, Yang-Yang Li, Xuan-Kun Li, Ka-Di Zhu, and Xian-Min Jin
Three-dimensional photonic chips are superior in handling NP-complete problems, but their large-scale application is hindered by the difficulty of programming them. The authors experimentally demonstrate a programmable three-dimensional photonic processor capable of solving the maximum clique problem by encoding injection conditions of photons. The prototype shows the potential of photonic computing, and is applied to solve molecular docking problems. The combination of non-von Neumann parallel computing architectures with fully programmable capabilities paves the way for wider practical applications and photonic computational advantages.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 044041] Published Mon Oct 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xi Tan, Hang Song, Ye Ji, Hao Tang, Ying-Yu Fang, Xiao-Yun Xu, Yang-Yang Li, Xuan-Kun Li, Ka-Di Zhu, and Xian-Min Jin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimentally realizable continuous-variable quantum neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042414</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042414"/>
        <updated>2023-10-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shikha Bangar, Leanto Sunny, Kübra Yeter-Aydeniz, and George Siopsis
The authors propose a continuous-variable quantum-classical neural network protocol that could be potentially realized in current photonic experiments. Their protocol only uses Gaussian operations, and a nonlinear operation is obtained through repeat-until-success measurements on ancillary qumodes. They applied their method to simulate quantum machine learning and computing problems.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 042414] Published Mon Oct 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shikha Bangar, Leanto Sunny, Kübra Yeter-Aydeniz, and George Siopsis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of an Excess of Dicharmonium Events in the Four-Muon Final State with the ATLAS Detector]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.151902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.151902"/>
        <updated>2023-10-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): G. Aad et al. (ATLAS Collaboration)
Statistically significant excesses are seen in the di-J/ψ and J/ψ+ψ(2S) channels using the ATLAS detector.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 151902] Published Fri Oct 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>G. Aad &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (ATLAS Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Active Spaghetti: Collective Organization in Cyanobacteria]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.158303</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.158303"/>
        <updated>2023-10-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mixon K. Faluweki, Jan Cammann, Marco G. Mazza, and Lucas Goehring
Lab experiments and theoretical models elucidate how chains of light-harvesting bacteria assemble into various density-dependent structures.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 158303] Published Fri Oct 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mixon K. Faluweki, Jan Cammann, Marco G. Mazza, and Lucas Goehring</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gapless spinons and a field-induced soliton gap in the hyperhoneycomb Cu oxalate framework compound [(${\mathrm{C}}_{2}{\mathrm{H}}_{5}{)}_{3}{\mathrm{NH}]}_{2}{\mathrm{Cu}}_{2}{({\mathrm{C}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{4})}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134418</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134418"/>
        <updated>2023-10-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. Dissanayake, A. C. Jacko, K. Kumarasinghe, R. Munir, H. Siddiquee, W. J. Newsome, F. J. Uribe-Romo, E. S. Choi, S. Yadav, X.-Z. Hu, Y. Takano, S. Pakhira, D. C. Johnston, Q.-P. Ding, Y. Furukawa, B. J. Powell, and Y. Nakajima
Frustrated magnets can be platforms for quantum spin-liquid states. A putative spin-liquid candidate, the hyperhoneycomb Cu oxalate framework compound [(C2H5)3NH]2Cu2(C2O4)3 exhibits the absence of long-range order and presence of charge-neutral excitations in the Mott insulating state at low temperatures. Here, the authors demonstrate experimental evidence for gapless spinons and a field-induced soliton gap in this material with the aid of theoretical calculations, and attribute them to weakly coupled antiferromagnetic Heisenberg chains, rather than a previously proposed spin-liquid state.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 134418] Published Fri Oct 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. Dissanayake, A. C. Jacko, K. Kumarasinghe, R. Munir, H. Siddiquee, W. J. Newsome, F. J. Uribe-Romo, E. S. Choi, S. Yadav, X.-Z. Hu, Y. Takano, S. Pakhira, D. C. Johnston, Q.-P. Ding, Y. Furukawa, B. J. Powell, and Y. Nakajima</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Floquet engineering multichannel Kondo physics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155120</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155120"/>
        <updated>2023-10-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Victor L. Quito and R. Flint
Floquet engineering has been used to engineer novel interactions in uncorrelated and magnetic insulating materials. Here, the authors apply this technique to simple heavy-fermion models, showing that driving these systems with periodic light introduces emergent Kondo screening channels with distinct symmetries, where the allowed channels are controlled by the light polarization. These systems can be driven through multichannel degeneracy points, dynamically realizing multichannel Kondo impurities and lattices that can be used to explore quantum critical phenomena and potentially enhance superconductivity.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 155120] Published Fri Oct 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Victor L. Quito and R. Flint</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Impact of the ground-state $4f$ symmetry for anisotropic $cf$ hybridization in the heavy-fermion superconductor ${\mathrm{CeNi}}_{2}{\mathrm{Ge}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165121</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165121"/>
        <updated>2023-10-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): H. Fujiwara, Y. Nakatani, H. Aratani, Y. Kanai-Nakata, K. Yamagami, S. Hamamoto, T. Kiss, A. Yamasaki, A. Higashiya, S. Imada, A. Tanaka, K. Tamasaku, M. Yabashi, T. Ishikawa, A. Yasui, H. Yamagami, J. Miyawaki, A. Miyake, T. Ebihara, Y. Saitoh, and A. Sekiyama
The Ce 4f-orbital symmetry in the ground states of the heavy-fermion superconductor CeNi2Ge2 is precisely determined here by utilizing linear dichroism in soft x-ray absorption and hard x-ray core-level photoemission spectroscopy. This yields the anisotropic 4f charge distribution, promoting the predominant hybridization with conducting electrons originating from the Ge site, which is verified by soft x-ray ARPES. These results suggest a possibility to drive the new exotic phases around the quantum critical points by controlling the Ge site.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 165121] Published Fri Oct 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>H. Fujiwara, Y. Nakatani, H. Aratani, Y. Kanai-Nakata, K. Yamagami, S. Hamamoto, T. Kiss, A. Yamasaki, A. Higashiya, S. Imada, A. Tanaka, K. Tamasaku, M. Yabashi, T. Ishikawa, A. Yasui, H. Yamagami, J. Miyawaki, A. Miyake, T. Ebihara, Y. Saitoh, and A. Sekiyama</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetic levitation by rotation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044036</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044036"/>
        <updated>2023-10-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Joachim Marco Hermansen, Frederik Laust Durhuus, Cathrine Frandsen, Marco Beleggia, Christian R.H. Bahl, and Rasmus Bjørk
A detailed experimental analysis explains the forces by which a spinning magnet can cause another magnet to levitate in midair.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 044036] Published Fri Oct 13, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joachim Marco Hermansen, Frederik Laust Durhuus, Cathrine Frandsen, Marco Beleggia, Christian R.H. Bahl, and Rasmus Bjørk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Respiratory aerosols and droplets in the transmission of infectious diseases]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/RevModPhys.95.045001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/RevModPhys.95.045001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mira L. Pöhlker, Christopher Pöhlker, Ovid O. Krüger, Jan-David Förster, Thomas Berkemeier, Wolfgang Elbert, Janine Fröhlich-Nowoisky, Ulrich Pöschl, Gholamhossein Bagheri, Eberhard Bodenschatz, J. Alex Huffman, Simone Scheithauer, and Eugene Mikhailov
The pandemic of coronavirus disease 2019 has led to a renewed focus on the physicochemical properties of the droplets and aerosol particles that are exhaled during breathing, speaking, singing, coughing, and sneezing. In this article, the properties of respiratory particles, including their number concentrations and size distributions, as well as their formation mechanisms at different sites in the respiratory system, are reviewed. The data in the literature are synthesized via a parametrization of the particle size distribution data using log-normal modes related to the different origin sites.

[Rev. Mod. Phys. 95, 045001] Published Thu Oct 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mira L. Pöhlker, Christopher Pöhlker, Ovid O. Krüger, Jan-David Förster, Thomas Berkemeier, Wolfgang Elbert, Janine Fröhlich-Nowoisky, Ulrich Pöschl, Gholamhossein Bagheri, Eberhard Bodenschatz, J. Alex Huffman, Simone Scheithauer, and Eugene Mikhailov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of the $γγ→ττ$ Process in $\mathrm{Pb}+\mathrm{Pb}$ Collisions and Constraints on the $τ$-Lepton Anomalous Magnetic Moment with the ATLAS Detector]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.151802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.151802"/>
        <updated>2023-10-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): G. Aad et al. (ATLAS Collaboration)
The ATLAS and CMS experiments have separately measured photon-induced τ-lepton pair production in Pb+Pb collisions, providing a novel probe of the τ anomalous magnetic moment.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 151802] Published Thu Oct 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>G. Aad &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (ATLAS Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of $τ$ Lepton Pair Production in Ultraperipheral Pb-Pb Collisions at $\sqrt{{s}_{NN}}=5.02\text{ }\text{ }\mathrm{TeV}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.151803</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.151803"/>
        <updated>2023-10-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Tumasyan et al. (CMS Collaboration)
The ATLAS and CMS experiments have separately measured photon-induced τ-lepton pair production in Pb+Pb collisions, providing a novel probe of the τ anomalous magnetic moment.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 151803] Published Thu Oct 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Tumasyan &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (CMS Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Controllable Single Cooper Pair Splitting in Hybrid Quantum Dot Systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.157001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.157001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Damaz de Jong, Christian G. Prosko, Lin Han, Filip K. Malinowski, Yu Liu, Leo P. Kouwenhoven, and Wolfgang Pfaff
A superconducting island with quantum dots on either side allows for coherent splitting of a single Cooper pair and detection of an emerging unpaired electron.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 157001] Published Thu Oct 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Damaz de Jong, Christian G. Prosko, Lin Han, Filip K. Malinowski, Yu Liu, Leo P. Kouwenhoven, and Wolfgang Pfaff</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coulomb-Higgs phase transition of three-dimensional lattice Abelian Higgs gauge models with noncompact gauge variables and gauge fixing]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.044125</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.044125"/>
        <updated>2023-10-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Claudio Bonati, Andrea Pelissetto, and Ettore Vicari
The authors study critical behavior of three-dimensional lattice gauge models. Results are consistent with predictions of the Abelian Higgs field theory and provide information of interest for statistical physics, condensed matter, and high-energy physics.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 044125] Published Thu Oct 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claudio Bonati, Andrea Pelissetto, and Ettore Vicari</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Causal connectability between quantum systems and the black hole interior in holographic duality]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.086019</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.086019"/>
        <updated>2023-10-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Samuel Leutheusser and Hong Liu
In a series of two papers, the authors explore the holographic duality between an eternal AdS black hole in the bulk and two copies of the boundary CFT in the thermal field double state. They provide an explicit construction in the boundary theory of an evolution operator for a bulk in-falling observer, thus making manifest the boundary emergence of the black hole horizons, the interiors, and the associated causal structure. They also elucidate that the emergence of the sharp bulk event horizon is related to the infinite N limit of the boundary theory.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 086019] Published Thu Oct 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Leutheusser and Hong Liu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emergent times in holographic duality]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.086020</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.086020"/>
        <updated>2023-10-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sam Leutheusser and Hong Liu
In a series of two papers, the authors explore the holographic duality between an eternal AdS black hole in the bulk and two copies of the boundary CFT in the thermal field double state. They provide an explicit construction in the boundary theory of an evolution operator for a bulk in-falling observer, thus making manifest the boundary emergence of the black hole horizons, the interiors, and the associated causal structure. They also elucidate that the emergence of the sharp bulk event horizon is related to the infinite N limit of the boundary theory.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 086020] Published Thu Oct 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Leutheusser and Hong Liu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scrambling and operator entanglement in local non-Hermitian quantum systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134305</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134305"/>
        <updated>2023-10-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Brian Barch, Namit Anand, Jeffrey Marshall, Eleanor Rieffel, and Paolo Zanardi
In weakly monitored quantum systems, traditional diagnostics of operator spreading such as out-of-time-ordered-correlators and Lieb-Robinson bounds can break down, as entanglement can spread at seemingly unbounded velocity. This has the adverse effect of making integrable and chaotic quantum dynamics appear identical. However, as the authors show here, the humble quantity of global operator entanglement remains a reliable metric of chaoticity in these systems. They elucidate this by studying entanglement phase transitions in a local, non-Hermitian transverse-field Ising model under the lens of operator and quenched entanglement dynamics.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 134305] Published Thu Oct 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Barch, Namit Anand, Jeffrey Marshall, Eleanor Rieffel, and Paolo Zanardi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlocal magnon transconductance in extended magnetic insulating films. I. Spin diode effect]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144410</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144410"/>
        <updated>2023-10-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Kohno, K. An, E. Clot, V. V. Naletov, N. Thiery, L. Vila, R. Schlitz, N. Beaulieu, J. Ben Youssef, A. Anane, V. Cros, H. Merbouche, T. Hauet, V. E. Demidov, S. O. Demokritov, G. de Loubens, and O. Klein
Combining the nonlinear properties of ferromagnets with the spin-transfer effect promises to realize a “perfect” diode with pure spin conductors. Practical implementations are nonlocal devices that emit and collect magnons between two parallel electrodes on a magnetic insulator. A diode-like current-voltage characteristic appears, which is attributed to nonlinear enhancement of the low-energy magnon population. However, its amplitude is rather small and can be explained by the strong enhancement of magnon-magnon scattering near the diode threshold. This suggests conductance by a magnon fluid instead of a frictionless condensate.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 144410] Published Thu Oct 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Kohno, K. An, E. Clot, V. V. Naletov, N. Thiery, L. Vila, R. Schlitz, N. Beaulieu, J. Ben Youssef, A. Anane, V. Cros, H. Merbouche, T. Hauet, V. E. Demidov, S. O. Demokritov, G. de Loubens, and O. Klein</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlocal magnon transconductance in extended magnetic insulating films. II. Two-fluid behavior]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144411</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144411"/>
        <updated>2023-10-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Kohno, K. An, E. Clot, V. V. Naletov, N. Thiery, L. Vila, R. Schlitz, N. Beaulieu, J. Ben Youssef, A. Anane, V. Cros, H. Merbouche, T. Hauet, V. E. Demidov, S. O. Demokritov, G. de Loubens, and O. Klein
Practical implementations of diode-like devices with pure spin conductors use magnon transport between two metallic electrodes deposited on a magnetic insulator. However, a diode-like response is only visible for a sufficiently large separation between the two electrodes. The authors attribute this behavior to the contribution of thermal magnons, which respond linearly to excitation and dominate the response for small separations. Their contribution decays rapidly with distance, revealing at large separations the nonlinear behavior that is associated with long-range propagating low-energy magnons.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 144411] Published Thu Oct 12, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Kohno, K. An, E. Clot, V. V. Naletov, N. Thiery, L. Vila, R. Schlitz, N. Beaulieu, J. Ben Youssef, A. Anane, V. Cros, H. Merbouche, T. Hauet, V. E. Demidov, S. O. Demokritov, G. de Loubens, and O. Klein</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimal Generators for Quantum Sensing]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.150802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.150802"/>
        <updated>2023-10-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jarrod T. Reilly, John Drew Wilson, Simon B. Jäger, Christopher Wilson, and Murray J. Holland
A new method identifies the most sensitive measurement that can be performed using a given quantum state, knowledge key for designing improved quantum sensors.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 150802] Published Wed Oct 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jarrod T. Reilly, John Drew Wilson, Simon B. Jäger, Christopher Wilson, and Murray J. Holland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magneto-Optical Detection of the Orbital Hall Effect in Chromium]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.156702</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.156702"/>
        <updated>2023-10-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Igor Lyalin, Sanaz Alikhah, Marco Berritta, Peter M. Oppeneer, and Roland K. Kawakami
Two different experiments on two different transition metals reveal that a current of electron orbital angular momentum flows in response to an electric field.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 156702] Published Wed Oct 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Igor Lyalin, Sanaz Alikhah, Marco Berritta, Peter M. Oppeneer, and Roland K. Kawakami</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orbital Hanle Magnetoresistance in a $3d$ Transition Metal]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.156703</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.156703"/>
        <updated>2023-10-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Giacomo Sala, Hanchen Wang, William Legrand, and Pietro Gambardella
Two different experiments on two different transition metals reveal that a current of electron orbital angular momentum flows in response to an electric field.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 156703] Published Wed Oct 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giacomo Sala, Hanchen Wang, William Legrand, and Pietro Gambardella</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum Optics Measurement Scheme for Quantum Geometry and Topological Invariants]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.156901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.156901"/>
        <updated>2023-10-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Markus Lysne, Michael Schüler, and Philipp Werner
A proposed optical setup combines a Fabry-Perot-type optical cavity with heterodyne photon detection for extracting the topological properties of two-dimensional semiconductor materials.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 156901] Published Wed Oct 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Markus Lysne, Michael Schüler, and Philipp Werner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Green's-function treatment of Rydberg molecules with spins]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042805</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042805"/>
        <updated>2023-10-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chris H. Greene and Matthew T. Eiles
The authors present a method based on the Coulomb Green’s function to derive the electronic structure of ultra-long-range Rydberg molecules including spins, providing a promising alternative to the standard method based on basis-set expansion, which was shown to have serious convergence problems. Use of this approach should enable more accurate studies of Rydberg-molecule spectra and the electron-atom scattering phase shifts upon which they depend.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 042805] Published Wed Oct 11, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris H. Greene and Matthew T. Eiles</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Testing the topological insulator behavior of half-Heusler PdYBi and PtYBi (111) epitaxial thin films]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.104203</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.104203"/>
        <updated>2023-10-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): V. Palin, A. Anadón, S. Andrieu, Y. Fagot-Revurat, C. de Melo, J. Ghanbaja, O. Kurnosikov, S. Petit-Watelot, F. Bertran, and J.-C. Rojas-Sánchez
Materials with high spin-to-charge interconversion efficiency are of high interest for advanced spintronic applications. Previous work has suggested that topological insulators may exhibit higher efficiency than traditionally-used heavy metals. Here, the authors explore the half-Heusler compounds PdYBi and PtYBi and their potential use for spin-to-charge interconversion. Epitaxial thin films of PdYBi and PtYBi are successfully prepared and demonstrated to exhibit nontrivial topology. Characterization of the magnetotransport in a model device shows that these half-Heusler films can outperform platinum in spin-to-charge interconversion.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 104203] Published Tue Oct 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>V. Palin, A. Anadón, S. Andrieu, Y. Fagot-Revurat, C. de Melo, J. Ghanbaja, O. Kurnosikov, S. Petit-Watelot, F. Bertran, and J.-C. Rojas-Sánchez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Realization of a $\mathbb{Z}$-Classified Chiral-Symmetric Higher-Order Topological Insulator in a Coupling-Inverted Acoustic Crystal]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.157201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.157201"/>
        <updated>2023-10-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dongyi Wang, Yuanchen Deng, Jun Ji, Mourad Oudich, Wladimir A. Benalcazar, Guancong Ma, and Yun Jing
An experiment shows the existence of Z-classified multiple chiral topological phase, which requires both chiral symmetry and a unique condition where the long-range hopping is stronger than the nearest-neighboring one.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 157201] Published Tue Oct 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dongyi Wang, Yuanchen Deng, Jun Ji, Mourad Oudich, Wladimir A. Benalcazar, Guancong Ma, and Yun Jing</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hydrodynamics-Induced Long-Range Attraction between Plates in Bacterial Suspensions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.158301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.158301"/>
        <updated>2023-10-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Luhui Ning, Xin Lou, Qili Ma, Yaochen Yang, Nan Luo, Ke Chen, Fanlong Meng, Xin Zhou, Mingcheng Yang, and Yi Peng
The flow field generated by swimming bacteria drives a long-range attractive force felt by passive objects much larger than the swimmers themselves.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 158301] Published Tue Oct 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luhui Ning, Xin Lou, Qili Ma, Yaochen Yang, Nan Luo, Ke Chen, Fanlong Meng, Xin Zhou, Mingcheng Yang, and Yi Peng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coexistence of extended and localized states in finite-sized mosaic Wannier-Stark lattices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L140202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L140202"/>
        <updated>2023-10-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jun Gao, Ivan M. Khaymovich, Adrian Iovan, Xiao-Wei Wang, Govind Krishna, Ze-Sheng Xu, Emrah Tortumlu, Alexander V. Balatsky, Val Zwiller, and Ali W. Elshaari
The transport of quantum particles and their possible localization are fundamental concepts in physics. Such particles are known to get stuck in strong electric fields due to the Wannier-Stark effect. But what will happen with this particle localization if the electric potential is present only on every second site? To answer this question, the authors mimic here the behavior of quantum particles with light in optical waveguides (shown in the image) and demonstrate that in finite systems there are both extended states, carrying the transport, and localized ones that are stuck. This first step opens the possibility to use this system as an encoder of quantum information in a compact way.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L140202] Published Tue Oct 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jun Gao, Ivan M. Khaymovich, Adrian Iovan, Xiao-Wei Wang, Govind Krishna, Ze-Sheng Xu, Emrah Tortumlu, Alexander V. Balatsky, Val Zwiller, and Ali W. Elshaari</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scattering-matrix approach for a quantitative evaluation of the topological protection in valley photonic crystals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.043505</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.043505"/>
        <updated>2023-10-10T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gaëtan Lévêque, Yan Pennec, Pascal Szriftgiser, Alberto Amo, and Alejandro Martínez
The authors explore limitations to topological protection in valley Hall waveguides by developing a phenomenological semi-analytical model for analyzing different sources of backscattering. The model can be used to predict the performance of larger-scale structures that are intractable using direct finite-element simulations.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 043505] Published Tue Oct 10, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gaëtan Lévêque, Yan Pennec, Pascal Szriftgiser, Alberto Amo, and Alejandro Martínez</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Particle acceleration by magnetic Rayleigh-Taylor instability: Mechanism for flares in black hole accretion flows]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043023</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043023"/>
        <updated>2023-10-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vladimir Zhdankin, Bart Ripperda, and Alexander A. Philippov
This article uses magnetic Rayleigh-Taylor instability in relativistic collisionless plasma as an example of an astrophysical process for nonthermal particle acceleration, and uncover the onset of large-scale plumes formed by accumulation of small ones via particle-in-cell simulations. This is posed as a potential mechanism for flares.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 043023] Published Mon Oct 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vladimir Zhdankin, Bart Ripperda, and Alexander A. Philippov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of Ultra-High-Energy Diffuse Gamma-Ray Emission of the Galactic Plane from 10 TeV to 1 PeV with LHAASO-KM2A]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.151001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.151001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zhen Cao et al. (LHAASO Collaboration)
Interstellar magnetic fields perturb the trajectories of cosmic rays, making it difficult to identify their sources. A new survey of gamma radiation produced when cosmic rays interact with the interstellar medium should help in this identification.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 151001] Published Mon Oct 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhen Cao &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHAASO Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mechanistic Insights into Water Autoionization through Metadynamics Simulation Enhanced by Machine Learning]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.158001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.158001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ling Liu, Yingqi Tian, Xuanye Yang, and Chungen Liu
Machine learning-assisted metadynamics is used to study water autoionization, one of the most important properties of water for all biological and chemical process including electrolysis (related to batteries).

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 158001] Published Mon Oct 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ling Liu, Yingqi Tian, Xuanye Yang, and Chungen Liu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental study of the penetrative convection in gases]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.103501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.103501"/>
        <updated>2023-10-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Valentin Dorel, Patrice Le Gal, and Michael Le Bars
Penetrative convection is the interaction between a lower turbulent convective layer of fluid and an upper stably-stratified one. It plays a key role in the atmosphere’s dynamics and in stellar interiors. In this study, we built an experiment of penetrative convection in gases which is closer to the geophysical applications. The internal gravity waves field is studied, as well as the growth of the convective layer. In our setup, the convective layer grows quadratically in time which is strikingly different from the 1/2 exponent obtained with classical models and salted water experiments.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 103501] Published Mon Oct 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Valentin Dorel, Patrice Le Gal, and Michael Le Bars</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statistical properties of shear and nonshear velocity components in isotropic turbulence and turbulent jets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.104602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.104602"/>
        <updated>2023-10-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ryo Enoki, Tomoaki Watanabe, and Koji Nagata
Velocity fields induced by small-scale shear layers and vortex tubes in turbulence are investigated with the triple decomposition of a velocity gradient tensor. The velocity fields are reconstructed with the Biot-Savart law applied to the vorticity vectors of shear and rigid-body rotation. The key image shows a mean flow pattern of small-scale shear layers in isotropic turbulence. The velocity associated with the shear layers dominates the turbulent kinetic energy budget, scalar transport, and energy cascade in isotropic turbulence and planar jets.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 104602] Published Mon Oct 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ryo Enoki, Tomoaki Watanabe, and Koji Nagata</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fractal nature of high-order time crystal phases]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L140102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L140102"/>
        <updated>2023-10-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Guido Giachetti, Andrea Solfanelli, Lorenzo Correale, and Nicolò Defenu
In Floquet time crystals, characterized by the spontaneous breaking of time-translational invariance, observables exhibit oscillations with a period multiple p>2 of the driving. Here, a new, experimentally accessible, order parameter is introduced, able to detect time-crystalline phases regardless of the value of p. This unveils a rich landscape with self-similar fractal boundaries in the phase diagram of the long-range kicked Ising model. These features are explained within the theoretical framework, along with the emergence of the Zp symmetry in Bloch eigenstates.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L140102] Published Mon Oct 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guido Giachetti, Andrea Solfanelli, Lorenzo Correale, and Nicolò Defenu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep macroscopic pure-optical potential for laser cooling and trapping of neutral atoms]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.043107</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.043107"/>
        <updated>2023-10-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): O. N. Prudnikov, R. Ya. Ilenkov, A. V. Taichenachev, V. I. Yudin, and S. N. Bagaev
It is possible to trap neutral atoms in optical lattices without using magnetic fields, but it is currently difficult to achieve deep trapping potentials in such systems. Here, the authors propose using bichromatic light to induce an optical rectification effect that results in a strong spatial force variance and therefore deep dissipative potentials, demonstrating that such lattices could replace magneto-optical traps in neutral atom cooling and trapping applications.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 043107] Published Mon Oct 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>O. N. Prudnikov, R. Ya. Ilenkov, A. V. Taichenachev, V. I. Yudin, and S. N. Bagaev</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topologically constrained fluctuations and thermodynamics regulate nonequilibrium response]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.044113</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.044113"/>
        <updated>2023-10-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gabriela Fernandes Martins and Jordan M. Horowitz
Near equilibrium, the fluctuation-dissipation theorem is an important tool in understanding how a system responds to external perturbations. Here the authors derive expressions that describe the response of physical observables outside of equilibrium, in terms of both the topology of the microscopic state space and the strength of thermodynamic driving.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 044113] Published Fri Oct 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gabriela Fernandes Martins and Jordan M. Horowitz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Near-infrared hybrid quantum photonic interface for ${}^{171}{\mathrm{Yb}}^{3+}$ solid-state qubits]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044018</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044018"/>
        <updated>2023-10-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chun-Ju Wu, Daniel Riedel, Andrei Ruskuc, Ding Zhong, Hyounghan Kwon, and Andrei Faraon
171Yb3+ ions in yttrium orthovanadate are promising candidates for building quantum networks, based on their excellent optical and spin properties and access to a secondary nuclear-spin quantum register. In this study the authors transfer GaAs photonic crystal nanobeam resonators to the surface of the host YVO4 to enhance the optical transitions of the Yb3+ ions and efficiently collect the emitted photons. This hybrid quantum photonic interface facilitates addressing of single Yb3+ ions and paves the way for the implementation of a scalable photonic architecture in the near infrared.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 044018] Published Fri Oct 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chun-Ju Wu, Daniel Riedel, Andrei Ruskuc, Ding Zhong, Hyounghan Kwon, and Andrei Faraon</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Connecting cooperative transport by ants with the physics of self-propelled particles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.1.023001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.1.023001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tabea Heckenthaler, Tobias Holder, Ariel Amir, Ofer Feinerman, and Ehud Fonio
Drawing from the physics of self-propelled particles, the authors introduce a macroscopic model to describe their experiments on ants’ cooperative transport. They connected this to previous coupled-carrier models, bridging the gap from micro to macro scales.

[PRX Life 1, 023001] Published Thu Oct 05, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tabea Heckenthaler, Tobias Holder, Ariel Amir, Ofer Feinerman, and Ehud Fonio</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>