<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2024-03-13T00:45:03.028Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2024-03-13T00:45:03.029Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RNA-induced Allosteric Coupling Drives Viral Capsid Assembly]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.2.013012</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.2.013012"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sean Hamilton, Tushar Modi, Petr Šulc, and S. Banu Ozkan
In this study, RNA-mediated allosteric protein regulation is proposed as a key mechanism driving viral capsid formation, revealing how single mutations can disrupt viral assembly and identifying new targets for antiviral treatments.

[PRX Life 2, 013012] Published Tue Mar 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Hamilton, Tushar Modi, Petr Šulc, and S. Banu Ozkan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monolithic Selenium/Silicon Tandem Solar Cells]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXEnergy.3.013013</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXEnergy.3.013013"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rasmus Nielsen, Andrea Crovetto, Alireza Assar, Ole Hansen, Ib Chorkendorff, and Peter C.K. Vesborg
Experiment and device simulation are combined to explore a monolithically integrated selenium/silicon tandem solar cell, offering insights toward positioning tandem solar cells as strong contenders for photovoltaic technologies.

[PRX Energy 3, 013013] Published Tue Mar 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rasmus Nielsen, Andrea Crovetto, Alireza Assar, Ole Hansen, Ib Chorkendorff, and Peter C.K. Vesborg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chemomechanics in alloy phase stability]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.033801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.033801"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sesha Sai Behara, John C. Thomas, Brian Puchala, and Anton Van der Ven
This work introduces a first-principles statistical mechanics method to calculate the free energies of crystalline alloys, including dependence on temperature, composition, and strain. The approach extends the alloy cluster expansion to include an explicit dependence on homogeneous strain in addition to site occupation variables that track chemical ordering. The method is applied to the Si-Ge binary alloy and is used to analyze phase stability under arbitrary epitaxial constraints. As a surrogate model, the new cluster expansion is a convenient compromise between the more restrictive configuration-only cluster expansions and machine-learned interatomic potentials, which require a substantially larger effort to train.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 033801] Published Tue Mar 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sesha Sai Behara, John C. Thomas, Brian Puchala, and Anton Van der Ven</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Selective observation of enantiomeric chiral phonons in $α$-quartz]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.104306</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.104306"/>
        <updated>2024-03-12T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Eiichi Oishi, Yasuhiro Fujii, and Akitoshi Koreeda
Phonons that have angular momentum and propagate in crystals are known as chiral phonons. The authors demonstrate the selective observation of chiral phonons in α-quartz, the most typical chiral crystal, by circularly polarized Raman spectroscopy. They clarify the Raman tensors of the chiral phonons verifying the angular momentum conservation law in the Raman process, involving photons and the chiral phonon. This study suggests the possibility of controlling the angular momentum and propagation direction of chiral phonons via the Raman process.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 104306] Published Tue Mar 12, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eiichi Oishi, Yasuhiro Fujii, and Akitoshi Koreeda</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Precision-Spectroscopic Determination of the Binding Energy of a Two-Body Quantum System: The Hydrogen Atom and the Proton-Size Puzzle]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.113001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.113001"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Simon Scheidegger and Frédéric Merkt
Researchers have measured the transition energy of several highly excited states, which could help resolve a discrepancy about the size of the proton.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 113001] Published Mon Mar 11, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Scheidegger and Frédéric Merkt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonequilibrium symmetry-protected topological order: Emergence of semilocal Gibbs ensembles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.115117</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.115117"/>
        <updated>2024-03-11T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maurizio Fagotti, Vanja Marić, and Lenart Zadnik
A generic nonequilibrium quantum system relaxes locally into a state resembling a thermal one even when isolated from the environment. In one-dimensional systems at finite temperature, ordered phases are generally excluded. Consequently, although symmetry-protected topological order may be present at zero temperature, its emergence at late times is not expected. This paper uncovers a mechanism that allows symmetry-protected topological order to emerge away from equilibrium for arbitrarily long times. It is based on the existence of hidden (semilocal) symmetries associated with operators that represent local observables only in a symmetry-restricted Hilbert space.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 115117] Published Mon Mar 11, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maurizio Fagotti, Vanja Marić, and Lenart Zadnik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evolutionary Conservation of Mechanical Strain Distributions in Functional Transitions of Protein Structures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011042</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011042"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pablo Sartori and Stanislas Leibler
The motions within the molecule provide a new way to compare the structures and functions of similar proteins.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011042] Published Fri Mar 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pablo Sartori and Stanislas Leibler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interaction between swarming active matter and flow: The impact on Lagrangian coherent structures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.033101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.033101"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xinyu Si and Lei Fang
We find that the impact of active matter on Lagrangian coherent structures (LCSs) was much more significant compared to localized random noise with similar energy. This is because the perturbation generated by active matter could couple with the background flow and further deform the LCSs. In addition, rotational elliptical regions of the flow were much more susceptible to active matter perturbation than the hyperbolic regions. Lastly, we revealed that the LCSs could be decently altered even at a small number density of active matter.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 033101] Published Fri Mar 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xinyu Si and Lei Fang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phonon thermal Hall effect in charge-compensated topological insulators]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.104304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.104304"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rohit Sharma, Mahasweta Bagchi, Yongjian Wang, Yoichi Ando, and Thomas Lorenz
The observation of surprisingly large thermal Hall ratios in a growing number of mainly oxide-based insulators is a major puzzle and raises the question about potential mechanisms that can induce a thermal Hall effect in materials with dominant charge-neutral heat carriers. Here, the authors report the finding of comparable thermal Hall ratios in a series of charge-compensated topological insulators and discuss this observation in the context of a recent proposal that a thermal Hall effect can result from skew scattering of phonons on charged defects.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 104304] Published Fri Mar 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rohit Sharma, Mahasweta Bagchi, Yongjian Wang, Yoichi Ando, and Thomas Lorenz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manipulating topological properties in ${\text{Bi}}_{2}{\text{Se}}_{3}/\text{BiSe}$/transition metal dichalcogenide heterostructures with interface charge transfer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.115112</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.115112"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xuance Jiang, Turgut Yilmaz, Elio Vescovo, and Deyu Lu
The 3D topological insulator Bi2Se3 transitions to a trivial insulator under the 2D limit. Through first-principles studies, the authors show here that significant charge transfer occurs at the Bi2Se3/BiSe/transition metal dichalcogenide heterostructure interfaces that stabilizes the BiSe layer as an electron donor and the resulting dipole field breaks the inversion symmetry of the Bi2Se3 layer. This results in giant Rashba band splitting and the reemergence of the Dirac states in thin Bi2Se3 layers.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 115112] Published Fri Mar 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xuance Jiang, Turgut Yilmaz, Elio Vescovo, and Deyu Lu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonlinear dynamics in neuromorphic photonic networks: Physical simulation in Verilog-A]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.034013</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.034013"/>
        <updated>2024-03-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hugh Morison, Jagmeet Singh, Nayem Al Kayed, A. Aadhi, Maryam Moridsadat, Marcus Tamura, Alexander N. Tait, and Bhavin J. Shastri
Recurrent neural networks based on silicon photonics can take on a wide range of dynamical features at high bandwidth, but experimental demonstrations are being held back by of the lack of a physical-level simulation platform that accounts for parasitic effects. This study uses photonic Verilog-A models to demonstrate characteristic neural dynamics. Simulation reveals that these dynamics exhibit a topological equivalence to the continuous-time recurrent-neural-network model.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 034013] Published Fri Mar 08, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hugh Morison, Jagmeet Singh, Nayem Al Kayed, A. Aadhi, Maryam Moridsadat, Marcus Tamura, Alexander N. Tait, and Bhavin J. Shastri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pressure-Induced Superconductivity In Polycrystalline ${\mathrm{La}}_{3}{\mathrm{Ni}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{7−δ}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011040</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011040"/>
        <updated>2024-03-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): G. Wang, N. N. Wang, X. L. Shen, J. Hou, L. Ma, L. F. Shi, Z. A. Ren, Y. D. Gu, H. M. Ma, P. T. Yang, Z. Y. Liu, H. Z. Guo, J. P. Sun, G. M. Zhang, S. Calder, J.-Q. Yan, B. S. Wang, Y. Uwatoko, and J.-G. Cheng
Researchers have measured a zero-resistance state for the nickelate La3Ni2O7, which measurements suggest may superconduct at temperatures above the boiling point of liquid nitrogen.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011040] Published Thu Mar 07, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>G. Wang, N. N. Wang, X. L. Shen, J. Hou, L. Ma, L. F. Shi, Z. A. Ren, Y. D. Gu, H. M. Ma, P. T. Yang, Z. Y. Liu, H. Z. Guo, J. P. Sun, G. M. Zhang, S. Calder, J.-Q. Yan, B. S. Wang, Y. Uwatoko, and J.-G. Cheng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Method to assess the trustworthiness of machine coding at scale]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.20.010113</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.20.010113"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rebeckah K. Fussell, Emily M. Stump, and N. G. Holmes
A four part method will help draw trustworthy claims from machine coding of qualitative data.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 20, 010113] Published Wed Mar 06, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rebeckah K. Fussell, Emily M. Stump, and N. G. Holmes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nanoscale electronic inhomogeneities in $1T{\text{-TaS}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.034002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.034002"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): B. Campbell, J. V. Riffle, A. de la Torre, Q. Wang, K. W. Plumb, and S. M. Hollen
In 1T-TaS2, native defects create electronic inhomogeneities spanning 5-10 nanometers that coexist with a well-formed commensurate charge density wave with a 1.3 nm period. Over these inhomogeneities, the band center shifts by up to 60meV and the gap varies by more than 100 meV. Surprisingly, the charge density wave order is unperturbed. These results reopen questions of how disorder affects charge density wave phases in correlated systems and emphasize the importance of real-space measurements in resolving the structural and electronic properties of quantum materials.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 034002] Published Wed Mar 06, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>B. Campbell, J. V. Riffle, A. de la Torre, Q. Wang, K. W. Plumb, and S. M. Hollen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orbital Magneto-Nonlinear Anomalous Hall Effect in Kagome Magnet ${\mathrm{Fe}}_{3}{\mathrm{Sn}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.106601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.106601"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lujunyu Wang, Jiaojiao Zhu, Haiyun Chen, Hui Wang, Jinjin Liu, Yue-Xin Huang, Bingyan Jiang, Jiaji Zhao, Hengjie Shi, Guang Tian, Haoyu Wang, Yugui Yao, Dapeng Yu, Zhiwei Wang, Cong Xiao, Shengyuan A. Yang, and Xiaosong Wu
Researchers have observed a new class of nonlinear Hall effect that can be understood through a geometric description of the electronic wave function.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 106601] Published Wed Mar 06, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lujunyu Wang, Jiaojiao Zhu, Haiyun Chen, Hui Wang, Jinjin Liu, Yue-Xin Huang, Bingyan Jiang, Jiaji Zhao, Hengjie Shi, Guang Tian, Haoyu Wang, Yugui Yao, Dapeng Yu, Zhiwei Wang, Cong Xiao, Shengyuan A. Yang, and Xiaosong Wu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Near- and mid-infrared excitation of ultrafast demagnetization in a cobalt multilayer system]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.094407</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.094407"/>
        <updated>2024-03-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Katherine Légaré, Guillaume Barrette, Laurent Giroux, Jean-Michel Parent, Elissa Haddad, Heide Ibrahim, Philippe Lassonde, Emmanuelle Jal, Boris Vodungbo, Jan Lüning, Fabio Boschini, Nicolas Jaouen, and François Légaré
Ultrafast demagnetization occurs when magnetic materials are excited by a sudden burst of energy, such as from an ultrashort laser pulse. After generating pulses from the ultraviolet to the mid-infrared spectral regions, the authors retrieve here the ultrafast magnetic dynamics of a multilayered cobalt ferromagnet excited by femtosecond pulses with wavelengths ranging from 0.8 to 8.7 µm. A weak relationship between the excitation wavelength and the magnetic dynamics is uncovered as well as a significant effect of the pulse’s shape and duration.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 094407] Published Wed Mar 06, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katherine Légaré, Guillaume Barrette, Laurent Giroux, Jean-Michel Parent, Elissa Haddad, Heide Ibrahim, Philippe Lassonde, Emmanuelle Jal, Boris Vodungbo, Jan Lüning, Fabio Boschini, Nicolas Jaouen, and François Légaré</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microbunch rotation in an x-ray free-electron laser using a first-order achromatic bend]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.27.030702</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.27.030702"/>
        <updated>2024-03-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rachel A. Margraf, James P. MacArthur, Gabriel Marcus, Heinz-Dieter Nuhn, Alberto Lutman, Aliaksei Halavanau, Zhen Zhang, and Zhirong Huang
Microbunch rotation through an achromatic bend enables hard x-ray multiplexing and could be used to out-couple microbunches from a cavity based XFEL.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 27, 030702] Published Tue Mar 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel A. Margraf, James P. MacArthur, Gabriel Marcus, Heinz-Dieter Nuhn, Alberto Lutman, Aliaksei Halavanau, Zhen Zhang, and Zhirong Huang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three-dimensional imaging of single atoms in an optical lattice via helical point-spread-function engineering]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.033304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.033304"/>
        <updated>2024-03-05T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tangi Legrand, Falk-Richard Winkelmann, Wolfgang Alt, Dieter Meschede, Andrea Alberti, and Carrie A. Weidner
The authors develop a method for determining the three-dimensional location of single atoms in a quantum gas microscopy system using point-spread-function engineering of the atoms’ fluorescence signal. The technique extends quantum simulation with microscopy systems into the regime of three dimensions.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 033304] Published Tue Mar 05, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tangi Legrand, Falk-Richard Winkelmann, Wolfgang Alt, Dieter Meschede, Andrea Alberti, and Carrie A. Weidner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shape effects in the fluctuations of random isochrones on a square lattice]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.034104</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.034104"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Iván Álvarez Domenech, Javier Rodríguez-Laguna, Rodolfo Cuerno, Pedro Córdoba-Torres, and Silvia N. Santalla
In first-passage percolation one is interested in the region that can be reached from an origin within a given time. The authors show that on a square lattice with disorder, the boundary of this region behaves as a fluctuating interface in the Kardar-Parisi-Zhang universality class.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 034104] Published Mon Mar 04, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Iván Álvarez Domenech, Javier Rodríguez-Laguna, Rodolfo Cuerno, Pedro Córdoba-Torres, and Silvia N. Santalla</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of ferrotoroidic domains in a metal]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L100401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L100401"/>
        <updated>2024-03-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Takeshi Hayashida, Ryusuke Misawa, Manfred Fiebig, and Tsuyoshi Kimura
Ferrotoroidic order refers to a spontaneous vortex arrangement of magnetic dipoles, which has recently been established as the fourth primary ferroic state of matter. Thus far, ferrotoroidic order has been studied extensively in insulators, but much less investigated in metallic materials. Here, the authors demonstrate the visualization of ferrotoroidic domains in metallic NdB4 by spatial distribution measurements of optical second harmonic generation (SHG). This study will stimulate research on unique functionalities of ferrotoroidic order in metals, such as an electric current induced domain switching.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, L100401] Published Mon Mar 04, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Takeshi Hayashida, Ryusuke Misawa, Manfred Fiebig, and Tsuyoshi Kimura</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Opposite Effects of the Rotational and Translational Energy on the Rates of Ion-Molecule Reactions near 0 K: The ${\mathrm{D}}_{2}^{+}+{\mathrm{NH}}_{3}$ and ${\mathrm{D}}_{2}^{+}+{\mathrm{ND}}_{3}$ Reactions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011034</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011034"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Raphaël Hahn, David Schlander, Valentina Zhelyazkova, and Frédéric Merkt
Experiments demonstrate some of the unusual features of molecular reactions that occur in the deep cold of interstellar space.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011034] Published Fri Mar 01, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Raphaël Hahn, David Schlander, Valentina Zhelyazkova, and Frédéric Merkt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ultrahigh Critical Current Density across Sliding Electrical Contacts in Structural Superlubric State]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.096201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.096201"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tielin Wu, Weipeng Chen, Lingyi Wangye, Yiran Wang, Zhanghui Wu, Ming Ma, and Quanshui Zheng
An experimental study of sliding electrical graphite contacts demonstrates simultaneous superlubricity and extremely high electrical conductivity.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 096201] Published Fri Mar 01, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tielin Wu, Weipeng Chen, Lingyi Wangye, Yiran Wang, Zhanghui Wu, Ming Ma, and Quanshui Zheng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exploration-Exploitation Paradigm for Networked Biological Systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.098402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.098402"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vito Dichio and Fabrizio De Vico Fallani
In the context of the brain wiring problem, development of the nematode, C. elegans, follows an exploration-exploitation paradigm.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 098402] Published Fri Mar 01, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vito Dichio and Fabrizio De Vico Fallani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of a giant band splitting in altermagnetic MnTe]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.115102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.115102"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Osumi, S. Souma, T. Aoyama, K. Yamauchi, A. Honma, K. Nakayama, T. Takahashi, K. Ohgushi, and T. Sato
This paper reports angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy and first-principles band calculations for MnTe, a candidate for an altermagnet that is now emerging as a new type of magnet, distinct from conventional ferromagnets and antiferromagnets. The authors provide direct experimental evidence for an exchange band splitting that reaches 0.8 eV. This band splitting was found to show strong anisotropy and multiple nodal lines in momentum space associated with the PT symmetry breaking characteristic of altermagnets.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 115102] Published Fri Mar 01, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Osumi, S. Souma, T. Aoyama, K. Yamauchi, A. Honma, K. Nakayama, T. Takahashi, K. Ohgushi, and T. Sato</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moiré fractals in twisted graphene layers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.125302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.125302"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Deepanshu Aggarwal, Rohit Narula, and Sankalpa Ghosh
Fractals are ubiquitous in nature. When two-dimensional crystals such as graphene or h-BN are multiply stacked and then twisted by a specific angle, the resulting super-moiré pattern exhibits electronic fractality. The authors call these novel structures “moiré fractals”. They derive a formula that relates their fractal dimension to the number of electronic bands in a given energy window. Such a number of bands fundamentally constrains charge and heat transport, thus providing a powerful tool for engineering designer quantum materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 125302] Published Fri Mar 01, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Deepanshu Aggarwal, Rohit Narula, and Sankalpa Ghosh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experimental demonstration of a two-dimensional hole gas in a GaN/AlGaN/GaN based heterostructure by optical spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.125401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.125401"/>
        <updated>2024-03-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Loïc Méchin, François Médard, Joël Leymarie, Sophie Bouchoule, Jean-Yves Duboz, Blandine Alloing, Jesús Zuñiga-Pérez, and Pierre Disseix
Optical spectroscopy techniques, including time-resolved and intensity-dependent photoluminescence, are employed here to optically demonstrate, for the first time, the presence of a buried two-dimensional hole gas (2DHG) in a nitride-based heterostructure. The characteristic spectral and temporal features of this recombination highlight the asymmetric electric field distribution on either side of the 2DHG. The effects of this electric field are discussed, particularly regarding their implications for optical recombination mechanisms within the heterostructure.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 125401] Published Fri Mar 01, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Loïc Méchin, François Médard, Joël Leymarie, Sophie Bouchoule, Jean-Yves Duboz, Blandine Alloing, Jesús Zuñiga-Pérez, and Pierre Disseix</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diverging nonlocal fields: Operationalizing critical disability physics identity with neurodivergent physicists outside academia]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.20.010111</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.20.010111"/>
        <updated>2024-02-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Liam G. McDermott, Nazeer A. Mosley, and Geraldine L. Cochran
Neurodivergent students experience unnecessary barriers to success in physics from assessment that is not constructed for how neurodivergent physicists perform physics-related tasks.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 20, 010111] Published Thu Feb 29, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liam G. McDermott, Nazeer A. Mosley, and Geraldine L. Cochran</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lateral solid phase epitaxy of yttrium iron garnet]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.L020402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.L020402"/>
        <updated>2024-02-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sebastian Sailler, Darius Pohl, Heike Schlörb, Bernd Rellinghaus, Andy Thomas, Sebastian T. B. Goennenwein, and Michaela Lammel
Yttrium iron garnet (YIG) is a prototypical material in the fields of spintronics and magnonics due to its exceptional magnetic properties. However, up to now, the focus has been on planar YIG thin films owing to the challenges associated with manufacturing non-planar structures. Here, the authors demonstrate the fabrication of single crystalline YIG via lateral solid phase epitaxy on top of an artificially defined SiOx mesa over micrometer length scales. The reported results lay the foundation for the development of non-planar, epitaxial YIG thin films as well as free standing YIG structures, while still maintaining complete control over the crystal orientation.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, L020402] Published Thu Feb 29, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sebastian Sailler, Darius Pohl, Heike Schlörb, Bernd Rellinghaus, Andy Thomas, Sebastian T. B. Goennenwein, and Michaela Lammel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Polar Self-Organization of Ferroelectric Nematic-Liquid-Crystal Molecules on Atomically Flat Au(111) Surface]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.098101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.098101"/>
        <updated>2024-02-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexandr A. Marchenko, Oleksiy L. Kapitanchuk, Yaroslava Yu. Lopatina, Kostiantyn G. Nazarenko, Anton I. Senenko, Nathalie Katsonis, Vassili G. Nazarenko, and Oleg D. Lavrentovich
Using a scanning tunneling microscope polar molecular ordering in a monolayer of ferroelectric nematic liquid crystal has been directly observed for the first time.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 098101] Published Thu Feb 29, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexandr A. Marchenko, Oleksiy L. Kapitanchuk, Yaroslava Yu. Lopatina, Kostiantyn G. Nazarenko, Anton I. Senenko, Nathalie Katsonis, Vassili G. Nazarenko, and Oleg D. Lavrentovich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-fidelity reconstruction of large-area damaged turbulent fields with a physically constrained generative adversarial network]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.024608</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.024608"/>
        <updated>2024-02-29T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Qinmin Zheng, Tianyi Li, Benteng Ma, Lin Fu, and Xiaomeng Li
In this work, we propose a novel framework for the high-fidelity reconstruction of large-area damaged turbulent fields with high resolution based on a physically constrained generative adversarial network. The network leverages complete/sparse fields of velocity components as physical constraints and adopts a PatchGAN discriminator network. The proposed reconstruction framework has been shown to achieve excellent reconstruction performance. The reconstructed flow fields are consistent with the raw flow fields in terms of magnitude, power spectrum, and two-point correlation function.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 024608] Published Thu Feb 29, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qinmin Zheng, Tianyi Li, Benteng Ma, Lin Fu, and Xiaomeng Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spatiotemporal Torquing of Light]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011031</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011031"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. W. Hancock, S. Zahedpour, A. Goffin, and H. M. Milchberg
Researchers have determined the amount of transverse orbital angular momentum that a type of optical vortex carries per photon, an important step for future applications.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011031] Published Wed Feb 28, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. W. Hancock, S. Zahedpour, A. Goffin, and H. M. Milchberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guiding diamond spin qubit growth with computational methods]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.026204</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.026204"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jonathan C. Marcks, Mykyta Onizhuk, Nazar Delegan, Yu-Xin Wang (王语馨), Masaya Fukami, Maya Watts, Aashish A. Clerk, F. Joseph Heremans, Giulia Galli, and David D. Awschalom
Spin defects in semiconductors play a major role in quantum technologies. Synthesizing high-quality spin qubits relies on controlling the incorporation of noise sources, such as other, unwanted spin defects, into the host crystal. In this work, the authors provide quantitative calculations of the coherence properties of spin qubits in diamond. They incorporate these results into an existing materials synthesis platform to develop predictive models and in situ feedback for more reliable creation of qubits tailored to applications.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 026204] Published Wed Feb 28, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan C. Marcks, Mykyta Onizhuk, Nazar Delegan, Yu-Xin Wang (王语馨), Masaya Fukami, Maya Watts, Aashish A. Clerk, F. Joseph Heremans, Giulia Galli, and David D. Awschalom</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conformal Invariance in Water-Wave Turbulence]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.094001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.094001"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Noseda and P. J. Cobelli
Experiments on gravity-capillary waves and analysis techniques drawn from stochastic partial differential equation theory establish a connection between zero-height isolines and the critical 2D Ising model’s domain walls, revealing a novel link between water-wave turbulence and critical systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 094001] Published Wed Feb 28, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Noseda and P. J. Cobelli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep-Learning Density Functional Perturbation Theory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.096401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.096401"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): He Li, Zechen Tang, Jingheng Fu, Wen-Han Dong, Nianlong Zou, Xiaoxun Gong, Wenhui Duan, and Yong Xu
A framework leveraging deep learning and automatic differentiation circumvents the computational bottleneck associated with density functional perturbation theory calculations.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 096401] Published Wed Feb 28, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>He Li, Zechen Tang, Jingheng Fu, Wen-Han Dong, Nianlong Zou, Xiaoxun Gong, Wenhui Duan, and Yong Xu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recycling of a quantum field and optimal states for single-qubit rotations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.022439</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.022439"/>
        <updated>2024-02-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shanon Vuglar and Julio Gea-Banacloche
The authors introduce a protocol to generate the electromagnetic field state that is optimal for controlling a given qubit rotation. The protocol, based on the interaction of the field with ancilla qubits, allows for field “recycling” and could potentially reduce error rates and improve energy efficiency in quantum computing schemes.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 022439] Published Wed Feb 28, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shanon Vuglar and Julio Gea-Banacloche</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement-Free Fault-Tolerant Quantum Error Correction in Near-Term Devices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.5.010333</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.5.010333"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sascha Heußen, David F. Locher, and Markus Müller
A fault-tolerant quantum error-correction scheme is presented that does not require measuring individual qubits and could thus revolutionize platforms that do not support midcircuit measurements.

[PRX Quantum 5, 010333] Published Tue Feb 27, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sascha Heußen, David F. Locher, and Markus Müller</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Large-scale characterization of ${\mathrm{Cu}}_{2}\mathrm{O}$ monocrystals via Rydberg excitons]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.026202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.026202"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kerwan Morin, Delphine Lagarde, Angélique Gillet, Xavier Marie, and Thomas Boulier
This research introduces a novel experimental technique to characterize Rydberg excitons in copper oxide (Cu2O) crystals with sub-micron resolution. By employing spatially resolved resonant absorption spectroscopy and photoluminescence imaging, the study unveils the influence of optically-active charged oxygen vacancies on Rydberg excitons. This approach yields comprehensive spatial maps of exciton properties, including energy, linewidth, and peak absorption without any mobile part, providing valuable insights into crystal quality. The findings highlight the predominant role of charged oxygen vacancies in influencing Rydberg excitons in Cu2O and offer a reliable method for assessing crystal quality in view of solid-state Rydberg physics.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 026202] Published Tue Feb 27, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kerwan Morin, Delphine Lagarde, Angélique Gillet, Xavier Marie, and Thomas Boulier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Viscoplastic rimming flow inside a rotating cylinder]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.023304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.023304"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Thomasina V. Ball and Neil J. Balmforth
When a small fraction of viscoplastic fluid is placed into a rotating cylinder, steady states can be reached with pool at the bottom of the cylinder and a residual coating elsewhere. Lubrication theory used to model the film thickness builds on previous models by bridging between two asymptotic limits, incorporating both the gravitational force along the cylinder and the hydrostatic pressure gradients. The model predicts steady states are reached after a small number of rotations and allows exploration of drainage when the cylinder comes to a halt. Experiments using a Carbopol suspension provide a suitable comparison to test the thin film theory.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 023304] Published Tue Feb 27, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomasina V. Ball and Neil J. Balmforth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spectral and Krylov complexity in billiard systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.046017</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.046017"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hugo A. Camargo, Viktor Jahnke, Hyun-Sik Jeong, Keun-Young Kim, and Mitsuhiro Nishida
The authors study spectral and Krylov complexity in quantum billiard systems at finite temperature. They show that spectral complexity may be used to probe the transition between the chaotic and integrable configurations for the billiard systems. For Krylov complexity, they study the associated Lanczos coefficients showing that their growth rate satisfies the conjectured generalized chaos bound, and that they produce an exponential growth of the Krylov complexity at early times.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 046017] Published Tue Feb 27, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hugo A. Camargo, Viktor Jahnke, Hyun-Sik Jeong, Keun-Young Kim, and Mitsuhiro Nishida</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Producing circular field harmonics inside elliptic magnet apertures with superconducting canted-cosine-theta coils]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.27.022402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.27.022402"/>
        <updated>2024-02-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): L. Brouwer
An analytic solution to the electromagnetic design of elliptic-bore superconducting accelerator magnets, and its application to canted-cosine-theta magnets.

[Phys. Rev. Accel. Beams 27, 022402] Published Tue Feb 27, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L. Brouwer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonreciprocal Frustration: Time Crystalline Order-by-Disorder Phenomenon and a Spin-Glass-like State]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011029</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011029"/>
        <updated>2024-02-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ryo Hanai
New theoretical work establishes an analogy between systems that are dynamically frustrated, such as glasses, and thermodynamic systems whose members have conflicting goals, such as predator–prey ecosystems.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011029] Published Mon Feb 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ryo Hanai</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of van der Waals phonons in the single-layer cuprate ${(\mathrm{Bi},\mathrm{Pb})}_{2}{(\mathrm{Sr},\mathrm{La})}_{2}{\mathrm{CuO}}_{6+δ}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024804</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024804"/>
        <updated>2024-02-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Y. Y. Peng, I. Boukahil, K. Krongchon, Q. Xiao, A. A. Husain, Sangjun Lee, Q. Z. Li, A. Alatas, A. H. Said, H. T. Yan, Y. Ding, L. Zhao, X. J. Zhou, T. P. Devereaux, L. K. Wagner, C. D. Pemmaraju, and P. Abbamonte
Interlayer van der Waals (vdW) coupling is ubiquitous in two-dimensional materials. The authors explore these interactions in the cuprate (Bi, Pb)2(Sr,La)2CuO6+δ, revealing ultra-low energy phonon modes similar to graphene and transition metal dichalcogenides. Using high-resolution inelastic hard x-ray scattering and first-principles simulations, they reveal vdW phonons from the shear motion of adjacent Bi-O layers. These findings deepen our understanding of the vibrational properties of cuprates and suggest opportunities for the design of novel heterostructures. These results highlight the generic nature of vdW modes in layered materials, including doped copper oxides, and provide insights for future materials design and research.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 024804] Published Mon Feb 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Y. Y. Peng, I. Boukahil, K. Krongchon, Q. Xiao, A. A. Husain, Sangjun Lee, Q. Z. Li, A. Alatas, A. H. Said, H. T. Yan, Y. Ding, L. Zhao, X. J. Zhou, T. P. Devereaux, L. K. Wagner, C. D. Pemmaraju, and P. Abbamonte</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum dots as optimized chiral emitters for photonic integrated circuits]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085431</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085431"/>
        <updated>2024-02-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jakub Rosiński, Michał Gawełczyk, Karol Tarnowski, Paweł Karwat, Daniel Wigger, and Paweł Machnikowski
A quantum emitter coupled to a photonic waveguide may emit photons in one particular direction. It is, however, challenging to create a system that matches the requirements of the directional coupling over a broad area of the waveguide. The authors show here that a properly designed quantum dot can be fine tuned in situ with a magnetic field to yield the desired directionality. This finding overcomes the obstacles on the path to efficient chiral coupling in QD-based photonic integrated circuits.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 085431] Published Mon Feb 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jakub Rosiński, Michał Gawełczyk, Karol Tarnowski, Paweł Karwat, Daniel Wigger, and Paweł Machnikowski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum criticality and entanglement for the two-dimensional long-range Heisenberg bilayer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L081114</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L081114"/>
        <updated>2024-02-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Menghan Song, Jiarui Zhao, Yang Qi, Junchen Rong, and Zi Yang Meng
The authors conduct here a pioneering and unbiased investigation into the entanglement properties of (2+1)-dimensional O(3) quantum critical points and two-dimensional Néel states in systems with long-range interactions. This study uncovers exotic properties, such as the vanishing of logarithmic corrections to entanglement entropies at QCPs and an enhancement in Néel states as long-range interactions amplify. Moreover, they determine precise critical exponents of QCPs influenced by long-range interactions, characterized by three distinct renormalization group fixed points.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, L081114] Published Mon Feb 26, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Menghan Song, Jiarui Zhao, Yang Qi, Junchen Rong, and Zi Yang Meng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of the Electromagnetic Field Effect via Charge-Dependent Directed Flow in Heavy-Ion Collisions at the Relativistic Heavy Ion Collider]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011028</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011028"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. I. Abdulhamid et al. (STAR Collaboration)
Collisions of heavy ions briefly produced a magnetic field 1018 times stronger than Earth’s, and it left observable effects.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011028] Published Fri Feb 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. I. Abdulhamid &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (STAR Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Performance of ChatGPT on the test of understanding graphs in kinematics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.20.010109</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.20.010109"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Giulia Polverini and Bor Gregorcic
ChatGPT does well at proposing productive strategies for solving problems on the test of understanding graphs in kinematics, but does poorly at getting correct answers due to limited ability to visually interpret graphs.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 20, 010109] Published Fri Feb 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giulia Polverini and Bor Gregorcic</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tuning of spin-orbit coupling in chiral molecule-incorporated two-dimensional organic-inorganic hybrid perovskite copper halides with ferromagnetic exchange interactions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024409</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024409"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kouji Taniguchi, Po-Jung Huang, Hajime Sagayama, Ryoji Kiyanagi, Kazuki Ohishi, Shunsuke Kitou, Yuiga Nakamura, and Hitoshi Miyasaka
Simultaneous control of noncentrosymmetry and spin-orbit-coupling strength has been demonstrated in a series of chiral molecule-incorporated two-dimensional organic-inorganic hybrid perovskite copper halides (2D-OIHPs) with ferromagnetic exchange interaction. By substituting the halogen from Cl to Br, a systematic change of the magnetic phase diagram from the simple ferromagnetic phase to complicated multiple phases has been observed. This change is due to competition between the ferromagnetic exchange interaction and the Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya interaction. Materials design focusing on the structural flexibility of 2D-OIHP could pave the way to developing new types of nontrivial topological spin systems.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 024409] Published Fri Feb 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kouji Taniguchi, Po-Jung Huang, Hajime Sagayama, Ryoji Kiyanagi, Kazuki Ohishi, Shunsuke Kitou, Yuiga Nakamura, and Hitoshi Miyasaka</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mass, Spectroscopy, and Two-Neutron Decay of $^{16}\mathrm{Be}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.082501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.082501"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): B. Monteagudo et al.
Identification of both the ground and first excited states of 16Be allows for a precise determination of its mass.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 082501] Published Fri Feb 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>B. Monteagudo &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Avalanches and Extreme Value Statistics of a Mesoscale Moving Contact Line]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.084003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.084003"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Caishan Yan, Dongshi Guan, Yin Wang, Pik-Yin Lai, Hsuan-Yi Chen, and Penger Tong
The pinning-depinning dynamics of a circular moving contact line are studied at the single-slip resolution using a mesoscale experimental framework.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 084003] Published Fri Feb 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Caishan Yan, Dongshi Guan, Yin Wang, Pik-Yin Lai, Hsuan-Yi Chen, and Penger Tong</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exact Solution of the Bose-Hubbard Model with Unidirectional Hopping]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.086502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.086502"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mingchen Zheng, Yi Qiao, Yupeng Wang, Junpeng Cao, and Shu Chen
Using a quantum inverse scattering framework, it is shown that the non-Hermitian one-dimensional Bose-Hubbard model is integrable.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 086502] Published Fri Feb 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mingchen Zheng, Yi Qiao, Yupeng Wang, Junpeng Cao, and Shu Chen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Non-Gaussian Displacements in Active Transport on a Carpet of Motile Cells]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.088301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.088301"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Robert Großmann, Lara S. Bort, Ted Moldenhawer, Maike Stange, Setareh Sharifi Panah, Ralf Metzler, and Carsten Beta
A carpet of active cells functions as an active bath for passive tracer particles, inducing non-Gaussian displacement and a crossover from superdiffusive to normal diffusive behavior.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 088301] Published Fri Feb 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Großmann, Lara S. Bort, Ted Moldenhawer, Maike Stange, Setareh Sharifi Panah, Ralf Metzler, and Carsten Beta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plume-surface interaction during lunar landing using a two-way coupled DSMC-DEM approach]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.024306</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.024306"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Bajpai, A. Bhateja, and R. Kumar
In this investigation, a novel two-way coupled gas-granular solver is developed, incorporating direct simulation Monte Carlo (DSMC) for gas particle collisions and discrete element method (DEM) for granular particle interactions. Gas-grain interaction model consists of momentum and energy exchange between the two phases. Using this framework, we have performed a comprehensive study of dust dispersion due to plume impingement on a lunar surface. We have predicted not only the velocity field of gas and grain phases, but also their temperature field, which can be meaningful information for spacecraft designers.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 024306] Published Fri Feb 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Bajpai, A. Bhateja, and R. Kumar</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Current fluctuations in a partially asymmetric simple exclusion process with a defect particle]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.024127</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.024127"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ivan Lobaskin, Martin R. Evans, and Kirone Mallick
An exclusion process on a ring is studied in this paper, where the presence of a defect particle immersed in a bath of normal particles leads to phase transitions between localized and shock phases. The authors use the functional Bethe ansatz to analytically compute the mean current and, for the first time, the diffusion constant, and report good agreement with Monte Carlo simulations.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 024127] Published Fri Feb 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ivan Lobaskin, Martin R. Evans, and Kirone Mallick</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bell inequality is violated in ${B}^{0}→J/ψ{K}^{*}(892{)}^{0}$ decays]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.L031104</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.L031104"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Fabbrichesi, R. Floreanini, E. Gabrielli, and L. Marzola
The authors use data from the LHCb collaboration for the helicity amplitudes in the B0 –> J/ψK*(892)0 decays to compute the entanglement among the polarizations of the final vector mesons. They show explicitly that the Bell inequality is violated, in accord with the general principles of quantum mechanics.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, L031104] Published Fri Feb 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Fabbrichesi, R. Floreanini, E. Gabrielli, and L. Marzola</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three-dimensional checkerboard spin structure on a breathing pyrochlore lattice]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.064421</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.064421"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Margarita G. Dronova, Václav Petříček, Zachary Morgan, Feng Ye, Daniel M. Silevitch, and Yejun Feng
The magnetism in the spinel compound ZnFe2O4 is one of the examples in P.W. Anderson’s original discussion of magnetic order and disorder on the pyrochlore lattice in the 1950’s. It has been studied for over seven decades, but the details of the ordering have remained unresolved. Here, a combination of high-quality single crystal growth, continuous-wave neutron diffraction, and a representation analysis based magnetic refinement reveal a noncollinear spin structure of alternatively stacked ferromagnetic and antiferromagnetic tetrahedra in a three-dimensional checkerboard array. This rare magnetic structure is stabilized by the existing breathing pyrochlore lattice and provides a precise insight into the magnetic structure factor, which challenges the claim for a classical spin liquid in several chromate spinel oxides.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 064421] Published Fri Feb 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Margarita G. Dronova, Václav Petříček, Zachary Morgan, Feng Ye, Daniel M. Silevitch, and Yejun Feng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intercalation-induced states at the Fermi level and the coupling of intercalated magnetic ions to conducting layers in ${\mathrm{Ni}}_{1/3}{\mathrm{NbS}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085135</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085135"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuki Utsumi Boucher, Izabela Biało, Mateusz A. Gala, Wojciech Tabiś, Marcin Rosmus, Natalia Olszowska, Jacek J. Kolodziej, Bruno Gudac, Mario Novak, Naveen Kumar Chogondahalli Muniraju, Ivo Batistić, Neven Barišić, Petar Popčević, and Eduard Tutiš
The intercalation with magnetic ions (Ni, Co) provides strong spin-selective hybridization between NbS2 layers. The symmetries of dominant bridging orbitals as displayed in the accompanying figure (a, b) and the type of magnetic order strongly affect the electronic structure and the conduction bands (c), as seen in ARPES spectra and understood through DFT+U calculations. In addition, the magnetic fluctuations at bridging sites are prone to produce strong electron correlation effects at the Fermi level (d), inaccessible by DFT+U calculations.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 085135] Published Fri Feb 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuki Utsumi Boucher, Izabela Biało, Mateusz A. Gala, Wojciech Tabiś, Marcin Rosmus, Natalia Olszowska, Jacek J. Kolodziej, Bruno Gudac, Mario Novak, Naveen Kumar Chogondahalli Muniraju, Ivo Batistić, Neven Barišić, Petar Popčević, and Eduard Tutiš</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reorientation of magnetic stripe domains by mid-infrared pulses]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L060408</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.L060408"/>
        <updated>2024-02-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maxime Gidding, Carl S. Davies, and Andrei Kirilyuk
Infrared pulses can be used to generate ultrafast strains in magnetic dielectrics, leading to magnetisation switching. Here, the authors find that in multidomain samples, such strains can drive domain reorientation, with the domains becoming aligned along the magnetocrystalline anisotropy axes. Moreover, the application of subsequent pulses leads to the pushing of the reoriented domains far beyond the radius of the infrared pulse.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, L060408] Published Fri Feb 23, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maxime Gidding, Carl S. Davies, and Andrei Kirilyuk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Positronium Laser Cooling via the ${1}^{3}S\text{−}{2}^{3}P$ Transition with a Broadband Laser Pulse]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.083402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.083402"/>
        <updated>2024-02-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): L. T. Glöggler et al. (AEḡIS Collaboration)
Researchers have managed to cool an atom-like system made of an electron and a positron using a technique commonly used in cold-atom experiments.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 083402] Published Thu Feb 22, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L. T. Glöggler &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (AEḡIS Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random Matrix Statistics in Propagating Correlation Fronts of Fermions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.087101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.087101"/>
        <updated>2024-02-22T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kazuya Fujimoto and Tomohiro Sasamoto
The dynamic higher-order fluctuations around the correlation front in one-dimensional noninteracting fermions can exhibit the universal behavior of the random matrix theory’s Gaussian orthogonal and symplectic ensembles.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 087101] Published Thu Feb 22, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kazuya Fujimoto and Tomohiro Sasamoto</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Giant interfacial in-plane magnetic anisotropy in Co/Pt bilayers grown on MgO(110) substrates]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024408</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024408"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Chao Zhou, Jia Xu, and Yizheng Wu
A material with strong in-plane magnetic anisotropy is crucial for determining the magnetization configuration of magnetic materials and their applications in high-density and high-frequency devices. Here, the authors successfully reported a giant interfacial uniaxial in-plane anisotropy in Co/Pt(110) bilayers, which is five times larger than that in Co/Pt(111), the most popular magnetic thin film with perpendicular magnetic anisotropy. Furthermore, such large interfacial magnetic anisotropy can be enhanced by forming a Pt/Co/Pt sandwich structure. These results enabled the integration of in-plane magnetic anisotropy systems into spintronic devices with increased speed and density.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 024408] Published Wed Feb 21, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chao Zhou, Jia Xu, and Yizheng Wu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scanning SQUID study of ferromagnetism and superconductivity in infinite-layer nickelates]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024802"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ruby A. Shi, Bai Yang Wang, Yusuke Iguchi, Motoki Osada, Kyuho Lee, Berit H. Goodge, Lena F. Kourkoutis, Harold Y. Hwang, and Kathryn A. Moler
This work studied superconductivity and magnetism in infinite-layer nickelate films with scanning SQUID and cross-sectional STEM. The authors found a landscape of superparamagnetism from NiOx nanoparticles that are extrinsic to the superconductivity. They imaged superconducting vortices and determined the penetration depth. They measured the local diamagnetism, finding a consistent value of the penetration depth. The superfluid density exhibits nearly T-linear dependence, suggesting possible d-wave superconductivity. Using scanning SQUID to image the various sources of magnetism in superconducting nickelates paves the way for further studies of vortex dynamics and flux quantization in these recently discovered superconductors.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 024802] Published Wed Feb 21, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ruby A. Shi, Bai Yang Wang, Yusuke Iguchi, Motoki Osada, Kyuho Lee, Berit H. Goodge, Lena F. Kourkoutis, Harold Y. Hwang, and Kathryn A. Moler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Equation of State and Thermometry of the 2D $\mathrm{SU}(N)$ Fermi-Hubbard Model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.083401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.083401"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): G. Pasqualetti, O. Bettermann, N. Darkwah Oppong, E. Ibarra-García-Padilla, S. Dasgupta, R. T. Scalettar, K. R. A. Hazzard, I. Bloch, and S. Fölling
Ultracold Yb gas in an optical lattice realizes the equation of state of the Fermi-Hubbard model across the Mott crossover temperature.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 083401] Published Wed Feb 21, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>G. Pasqualetti, O. Bettermann, N. Darkwah Oppong, E. Ibarra-García-Padilla, S. Dasgupta, R. T. Scalettar, K. R. A. Hazzard, I. Bloch, and S. Fölling</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Statistical state dynamics-based study of the stability of the mean statistical state of wall-bounded turbulence]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.024605</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.024605"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Brian F. Farrell and Petros J. Ioannou
In wall turbulence, the time-mean flow is returned to after almost any disturbance, which indicates that it is a stable statistical feature underlying the disorder of turbulence. However, the stability of this statistical feature can not be determined directly from the stability of the time-mean flow itself. What is required is a statistical stability analysis method. We determine the statistical stability of the time-mean state by averaging the dynamics of the return to the time-mean state over the turbulent attractor using the linear inverse model method.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 024605] Published Wed Feb 21, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian F. Farrell and Petros J. Ioannou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discord in the voter model for complex networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.024312</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.024312"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Antoine Vendeville, Shi Zhou, and Benjamin Guedj
The formation and evolution of opinion in social networks is a topic receiving increasing attention. By employing the multistate voter model on a network, the authors derive a general method to compute the probability of disagreement between a pair of agents in the model, which is applicable to any directed, weighted network.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 024312] Published Wed Feb 21, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Antoine Vendeville, Shi Zhou, and Benjamin Guedj</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological quantum computation on a chiral Kondo chain]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.075145</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.075145"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tianhao Ren, Elio J. König, and Alexei M. Tsvelik
This work describes a chiral Kondo chain model with symplectic symmetry. The authors demonstrate that it has a quantum critical ground state populated by non-Abelian anyons. Such a model is more robust than previously proposed models, and it can be experimentally implemented using hybrid quantum devices featuring superconducting islands coupled to chiral edges of topological insulators. Proposals for measurement-only anyonic quantum computations and error mitigations based on such a setup are provided.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 075145] Published Wed Feb 21, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tianhao Ren, Elio J. König, and Alexei M. Tsvelik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantitative measurement of figure of merit for transverse thermoelectric conversion in $\mathrm{Fe}/\mathrm{Pt}$ metallic multilayers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.024039</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.024039"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Takumi Yamazaki, Takamasa Hirai, Takashi Yagi, Yuichiro Yamashita, Ken-ichi Uchida, Takeshi Seki, and Koki Takanashi
Metallic multilayers play a pivotal role in spintronics and also have recently attracted attention as spin-caloritronic materials for energy conversion, but their thermoelectric performance has not been quantified. This study of Fe/Pt multilayers presents a method to evaluate the figure of merit for transverse thermoelectric conversion in thin-film stacks. A multilayered structure reduces thermal conductivity and notably enhances the figure of merit. Interestingly, epitaxial multilayers exhibit better thermoelectric performance than their polycrystalline counterparts, due to their higher transverse thermoelectric coefficient and electron-transport anisotropy.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 024039] Published Wed Feb 21, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Takumi Yamazaki, Takamasa Hirai, Takashi Yagi, Yuichiro Yamashita, Ken-ichi Uchida, Takeshi Seki, and Koki Takanashi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast and reliable entanglement distribution with quantum repeaters: Principles for improving protocols using reinforcement learning]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.024041</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.024041"/>
        <updated>2024-02-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Stav Haldar, Pratik J. Barge, Sumeet Khatri, and Hwang Lee
Tomorrow’s quantum technologies for communication, sensing, and distributed computing will rely on networks with entanglement shared between spatially separated nodes. The authors provide improved protocols and policies for entanglement distribution along a chain of nodes, accounting for practical limitations such as photon losses, nonideal measurements, and quantum memories with short coherence times. These policies feature dynamic, state-dependent memory cutoffs and collaboration between nodes, all of which are quantified. Nesting policies for small repeater chains yields policies for large chains that improve upon a swap-as-soon-as-possible approach, and thus pave the way to scaling up.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 024041] Published Wed Feb 21, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stav Haldar, Pratik J. Barge, Sumeet Khatri, and Hwang Lee</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enhanced Production of ${\mathrm{Λ}}_{b}^{0}$ Baryons in High-Multiplicity $pp$ Collisions at $\sqrt{s}=13\text{ }\text{ }\mathrm{TeV}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.081901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.081901"/>
        <updated>2024-02-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Aaij et al. (LHCb Collaboration)
Bottom quarks are increasingly more likely to exist in three-quark states rather than two-quark ones as the density of their environment increases.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 081901] Published Tue Feb 20, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Aaij &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHCb Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing Hydrodynamic Fluctuation-Induced Forces with an Oscillating Robot]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.084001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.084001"/>
        <updated>2024-02-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Steven W. Tarr, Joseph S. Brunner, Daniel Soto, and Daniel I. Goldman
A free-floating robot that oscillates symmetrically can use confined hydrodynamic surface wave fields to move without the need for a traditional propulsion mechanism.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 084001] Published Tue Feb 20, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven W. Tarr, Joseph S. Brunner, Daniel Soto, and Daniel I. Goldman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flexophotovoltaic Effect and Above-Band-Gap Photovoltage Induced by Strain Gradients in Halide Perovskites]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.086902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.086902"/>
        <updated>2024-02-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zhiguo Wang, Shengwen Shu, Xiaoyong Wei, Renhong Liang, Shanming Ke, Longlong Shu, and Gustau Catalan
The engineering of structural deformations in light-sensitive semiconductors can boost the efficiency of solar cells.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 086902] Published Tue Feb 20, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zhiguo Wang, Shengwen Shu, Xiaoyong Wei, Renhong Liang, Shanming Ke, Longlong Shu, and Gustau Catalan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bloch-wave interferometry of driven quasiparticles in bulk GaAs]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.054308</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.054308"/>
        <updated>2024-02-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Seamus D. O'Hara, Joseph B. Costello, Qile Wu, Ken West, Loren Pfeiffer, and Mark S. Sherwin
Interferometers that manipulate and detect electromagnetic waves are indispensable to science. Quasiparticles in crystalline solids can be described as Bloch waves, but rapid dephasing of accelerating charged quasiparticles has so far prevented the development of interferometers sensitive to their inertial properties. Here, the authors show that polarizations of near-infrared sidebands emitted by GaAs in strong terahertz fields can be viewed as interferograms from a Michelson-like interferometer for Bloch waves. A simple analytical model connects these inteferograms to quasiparticle masses and dephasing.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 054308] Published Tue Feb 20, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Seamus D. O'Hara, Joseph B. Costello, Qile Wu, Ken West, Loren Pfeiffer, and Mark S. Sherwin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic structure of nitrogen-doped lutetium hydrides]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.L021801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.L021801"/>
        <updated>2024-02-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Adam Denchfield, Hyowon Park, and Russell J. Hemley
Hydrides at high pressures constitute the only materials to be superconducting above 200 K, and are typically marked by an appreciable hydrogen density of states and van Hove singularities at the Fermi energy. Given the recent interest in nitrogen-doped lutetium hydride, the authors focused on finding the structures which would have electronic properties that could plausibly support high-temperature superconductivity within a narrow pressure range. They have identified a narrow range of stoichiometries Lu8H23−xN with hydrogen-dominant conduction states, and found one structure which exhibits a very large hydrogen density of states with an extremely sharp van Hove singularity, whose properties may therefore change dramatically under pressure.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, L021801] Published Fri Feb 16, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Denchfield, Hyowon Park, and Russell J. Hemley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voltage-Controlled Magnon Transistor via Tuning Interfacial Exchange Coupling]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076701"/>
        <updated>2024-02-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Y. Z. Wang, T. Y. Zhang, J. Dong, P. Chen, G. Q. Yu, C. H. Wan, and X. F. Han
Researchers have demonstrated that magnetic spin waves called magnons can be controlled by voltage and thus could operate more efficiently as information carriers in future devices.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 076701] Published Fri Feb 16, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Y. Z. Wang, T. Y. Zhang, J. Dong, P. Chen, G. Q. Yu, C. H. Wan, and X. F. Han</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Field-Induced Hybridization of Moiré Excitons in ${\mathrm{MoSe}}_{2}/{\mathrm{WS}}_{2}$ Heterobilayers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076902"/>
        <updated>2024-02-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Borislav Polovnikov, Johannes Scherzer, Subhradeep Misra, Xin Huang, Christian Mohl, Zhijie Li, Jonas Göser, Jonathan Förste, Ismail Bilgin, Kenji Watanabe, Takashi Taniguchi, Alexander Högele, and Anvar S. Baimuratov
Laser modulation spectroscopy on a MoSe2/WS2 heterostructure shows an intricate interplay of both intra- and interlayer moiré excitons and allows to determine unambiguously the nature of the observed optical resonances.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 076902] Published Fri Feb 16, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Borislav Polovnikov, Johannes Scherzer, Subhradeep Misra, Xin Huang, Christian Mohl, Zhijie Li, Jonas Göser, Jonathan Förste, Ismail Bilgin, Kenji Watanabe, Takashi Taniguchi, Alexander Högele, and Anvar S. Baimuratov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Excited-state geometry relaxation of point defects in monolayer hexagonal boron nitride]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085127</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085127"/>
        <updated>2024-02-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexander Kirchhoff, Thorsten Deilmann, and Michael Rohlfing
Optical excitation and deexcitation processes are governed by the dependence of the involved energy levels on the atom positions. This geometry dependence is calculated here for several defects in h-BN, e.g., CBVN, within constrained density functional theory and many-body perturbation theory. The investigated Stokes shifts show distinct differences compared to experiments. For the Tamm-Dancoff approximation, an approximation frequently employed in the calculation of exciton energies in crystalline solids, the authors find small but significant influence for defect systems.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 085127] Published Fri Feb 16, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexander Kirchhoff, Thorsten Deilmann, and Michael Rohlfing</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of New Isotopes in the Fragmentation of $^{198}\mathrm{Pt}$ at FRIB]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.072501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.072501"/>
        <updated>2024-02-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): O. B. Tarasov, A. Gade, K. Fukushima, M. Hausmann, E. Kwan, M. Portillo, M. Smith, D. S. Ahn, D. Bazin, R. Chyzh, S. Giraud, K. Haak, T. Kubo, D. J. Morrissey, P. N. Ostroumov, I. Richardson, B. M. Sherrill, A. Stolz, S. Watters, D. Weisshaar, and T. Zhang
Less than a year after its opening, the Facility for Rare Isotope Beams produced five never-before-seen isotopes for observation, a success that researchers say highlights the discovery potential of the facility.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 072501] Published Thu Feb 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>O. B. Tarasov, A. Gade, K. Fukushima, M. Hausmann, E. Kwan, M. Portillo, M. Smith, D. S. Ahn, D. Bazin, R. Chyzh, S. Giraud, K. Haak, T. Kubo, D. J. Morrissey, P. N. Ostroumov, I. Richardson, B. M. Sherrill, A. Stolz, S. Watters, D. Weisshaar, and T. Zhang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discovery of New Isotopes $^{160}\mathrm{Os}$ and $^{156}\mathrm{W}$: Revealing Enhanced Stability of the $N=82$ Shell Closure on the Neutron-Deficient Side]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.072502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.072502"/>
        <updated>2024-02-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): H. B. Yang (杨华彬) et al.
Adding what seems like too many protons to a nucleus can increase one measure of its stability.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 072502] Published Thu Feb 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>H. B. Yang (杨华彬) &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Shot Noise Does Not Generally Detect Pairing in Mesoscopic Superconducting Tunnel Junctions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076001"/>
        <updated>2024-02-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jiasen Niu, Koen M. Bastiaans, Jian-Feng Ge, Ruchi Tomar, John Jesudasan, Pratap Raychaudhuri, Max Karrer, Reinhold Kleiner, Dieter Koelle, Arnaud Barbier, Eduard F. C. Driessen, Yaroslav M. Blanter, and Milan P. Allan
Shot noise measurements in Nb-based superconducting tunnel junctions indicate that transparency channels obscure pairing in noise measurements, a common roadblock in measurements in such junctions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 076001] Published Thu Feb 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jiasen Niu, Koen M. Bastiaans, Jian-Feng Ge, Ruchi Tomar, John Jesudasan, Pratap Raychaudhuri, Max Karrer, Reinhold Kleiner, Dieter Koelle, Arnaud Barbier, Eduard F. C. Driessen, Yaroslav M. Blanter, and Milan P. Allan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of double-kink states in multivalley acoustic crystals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.054109</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.054109"/>
        <updated>2024-02-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xiao-Hui Gou, Hua-Shan Lai, Xiao-Chen Sun, Si-Yuan Yu, Y. B. Chen, Cheng He, and Yan-Feng Chen
Graphene structures usually accommodate one pair of Dirac cones, naturally forming a single kink valley state after symmetry breaking. The authors report here that acoustic S-graphene, i.e., a carbon allotrope of graphene, can harbor two pairs of Dirac cones, further shaping double-kink valley states. By selectively exciting different symmetric or antisymmetric branches, robust yet tunable superdirectional sound radiation is experimentally demonstrated. This study could double the degrees of freedom for valleytronics and help in the design of unique functional devices.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 054109] Published Thu Feb 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xiao-Hui Gou, Hua-Shan Lai, Xiao-Chen Sun, Si-Yuan Yu, Y. B. Chen, Cheng He, and Yan-Feng Chen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonreciprocal spin-wave transport in an asymmetric three-dimensional magnonic coupler]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.024031</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.024031"/>
        <updated>2024-02-15T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A.A. Grachev, S.A. Odintsov, E.N. Beginin, and A.V. Sadovnikov
The use of elementary quanta of magnetic excitation—magnons, or spin waves—as carriers of information attracts more and more interest, as transferring the magnetic moment (spin) of an electron without transferring its electric charge avoids the heat generation inherent in CMOS technology. This study aims to exploit directed spin-wave propagation in a structure composed of parallel stripes of thin-film yttrium iron garnet, forming an asymmetric three-dimensional coupler geometry. This approach has the potential to enhance the density of functional elements in three-dimensional magnonic networks.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 024031] Published Thu Feb 15, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A.A. Grachev, S.A. Odintsov, E.N. Beginin, and A.V. Sadovnikov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantifying the Properties of Nonproductive Attempts at Thermally Activated Energy-Barrier Crossing through Direct Observation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011017</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011017"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aaron Lyons, Anita Devi, Noel Q. Hoffer, and Michael T. Woodside
Researchers have measured short-timescale fluctuations in metastable systems, uncovering information about failed attempts to cross the barriers that define the metastable state.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011017] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aaron Lyons, Anita Devi, Noel Q. Hoffer, and Michael T. Woodside</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum oscillations in kagome metals ${\mathrm{CsTi}}_{3}{\mathrm{Bi}}_{5}$ and ${\mathrm{RbTi}}_{3}{\mathrm{Bi}}_{5}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024003"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zackary Rehfuss, Christopher Broyles, David Graf, Yongkang Li, Hengxin Tan, Zhen Zhao, Jiali Liu, Yuhang Zhang, Xiaoli Dong, Haitao Yang, Hongjun Gao, Binghai Yan, and Sheng Ran
We explore quantum oscillations in the kagome metals CsTi3Bi5 and RbTi3Bi5, using high magnetic fields and low temperatures. We reveal new quantum oscillation frequencies in CsTi3Bi5, showing a complex Fermi surface that matches density functional theory predictions. Interestingly, the Rb compound exhibits notably different results from the Cs compound, despite theoretical expectations of similarity. This work deepens our understanding of the electronic intricacies within kagome lattice systems and spotlights their role as a playground for unearthing novel quantum states. Our findings pave the way for future investigations in the quantum behaviors of kagome metals, offering insights for advanced material development.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 024003] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zackary Rehfuss, Christopher Broyles, David Graf, Yongkang Li, Hengxin Tan, Zhen Zhao, Jiali Liu, Yuhang Zhang, Xiaoli Dong, Haitao Yang, Hongjun Gao, Binghai Yan, and Sheng Ran</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological diffusive metal in amorphous transition metal monosilicides]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.L021201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.L021201"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Selma Franca and Adolfo G. Grushin
Transition metal monosilicides RhSi and CoSi have intriguing physical properties such as long Fermi arc surface states and unusual optical responses. These features originate from multifold fermions - higher spin generalizations of Weyl quasiparticles that are protected by crystalline symmetries. Since these materials are prone to intrinsic disorder, the authors theoretically study topological properties of amorphous RhSi and CoSi. Using the spectral localizer, they find that multifold fermions survive disorder strengths that convert the semimetal into a diffusive metal phase. These conclusions are supported by photoemission simulations showing the presence of Fermi arcs in the corresponding disorder range.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, L021201] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Selma Franca and Adolfo G. Grushin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal Features of Entanglement Entropy in the Honeycomb Hubbard Model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076502</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.076502"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jonathan D’Emidio, Román Orús, Nicolas Laflorencie, and Fernando de Juan
The entanglement entropy of two-dimensional interacting fermions can be simulated with quantum Monte Carlo techniques.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 076502] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jonathan D’Emidio, Román Orús, Nicolas Laflorencie, and Fernando de Juan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arresting of interfacial phase separation with an imposed flow]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.024003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.9.024003"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ryuta X. Suzuki, Shoji Seya, Takahiko Ban, Manoranjan Mishra, and Yuichiro Nagatsu
We experimentally investigate displacement of a more viscous liquid by a less viscous one in a Hele-Shaw cell using an aqueous two phase system, where phase separation occurs in the growing liquid-liquid interfacial region, by varying the injection flow rate and the phase separation rate. We show that the degree of the interfacial phase separation scales as a unique function of the ratio of the flow and phase separation rates and it decreases with the ratio. These results demonstrate that the interfacial phase separation is arrested by the imposed flow and determined by competition between the flow and phase separation rates. The arresting effect and the mechanism are numerically verified.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 9, 024003] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ryuta X. Suzuki, Shoji Seya, Takahiko Ban, Manoranjan Mishra, and Yuichiro Nagatsu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mean-field method for generic conductance-based integrate-and-fire neurons with finite timescales]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.024406</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.109.024406"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marcelo P. Becker and Marco A. P. Idiart
This article presents a mean-field method to determine the transfer function that describes the behavior of spiking neurons in a network. The authors extend a Fokker-Planck approach to the case of conductance-based integrate-and-fire neurons with various sources of noise, and find good agreement with data from simulations.

[Phys. Rev. E 109, 024406] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marcelo P. Becker and Marco A. P. Idiart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Toward accurate modeling of line-intensity mapping one-point statistics: Including extended profiles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.043517</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.109.043517"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): José Luis Bernal
The authors construct an analytic model of the line-intensity mapping (LIM) probability density field to include sources extended in angle and frequency, thus contributing to more than one observational resolution element. Preliminary simulation-based testing shows promise, encouraging further LIM development.

[Phys. Rev. D 109, 043517] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>José Luis Bernal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantitative feasibility study of sequential neutron captures using intense lasers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.025802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.025802"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Vojtěch Horný, Sophia N. Chen, Xavier Davoine, Laurent Gremillet, and Julien Fuchs
Laser-generated nucleosynthesis remains out of reach of present-day technology—but more powerful lasers could eventually make it possible.

[Phys. Rev. C 109, 025802] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vojtěch Horný, Sophia N. Chen, Xavier Davoine, Laurent Gremillet, and Julien Fuchs</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic heterogeneity at the experimental glass transition predicted by transferable machine learning]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.064205</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.064205"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gerhard Jung, Giulio Biroli, and Ludovic Berthier
Dynamic heterogeneities represent a critical aspect of glassy dynamics, and their analysis constitutes a fundamental step in understanding the essence of the glass transition. The authors employ physics-inspired machine learning to predict the microscopic structural relaxation from amorphous configurations of deeply supercooled liquids. Leveraging the transferability in temperature of the trained networks enables the prediction of dynamic heterogeneities at the experimental glass transition temperature, thereby circumventing the prohibitively large computational cost associated with conventional simulation methods at such low temperatures.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 064205] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gerhard Jung, Giulio Biroli, and Ludovic Berthier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ground-state phase diagram and superconductivity of the doped Hubbard model on six-leg square cylinders]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085121</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085121"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yi-Fan Jiang, Thomas P. Devereaux, and Hong-Chen Jiang
The authors employ the density-matrix renormalization group to investigate the doped Hubbard model on six-leg square cylinders. It uncovers a rich quantum phase diagram, intricately sensitive to next-nearest-neighbor electron hopping (t′). The positive-t′ region shows a robust d-wave superconducting phase with intertwined superconducting and charge-density-wave orders. In contrast, the negative-t′ side remains insulating, where doped holes form either long-range charge stripe order at small t′ or a holon Wigner crystal with one doped hole per emergent unit cell and short-range spin correlations at larger t’.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 085121] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yi-Fan Jiang, Thomas P. Devereaux, and Hong-Chen Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coherence of group-IV color centers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085414</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.109.085414"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Isaac B. W. Harris and Dirk Englund
Group-IV color centers in diamond are a promising platform for quantum entanglement distribution experiments. However, they suffer from a phonon-mediated decoherence mechanism that limits the maximum temperature at which they can operate. This theoretical work develops a model that accurately predicts coherence time, and further predicts regimes in which the coherence can be extended, potentially leading to higher-temperature operation.

[Phys. Rev. B 109, 085414] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaac B. W. Harris and Dirk Englund</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum light-field microscopy for volumetric imaging with extreme depth of field]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.024029</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.21.024029"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yingwen Zhang, Duncan England, Antony Orth, Ebrahim Karimi, and Benjamin Sussman
Light-field microscopy (LFM) extracts volumetric data from a specimen by simultaneously capturing the positional and angular information of light rays emanating from the sample. While conventional LFM requires a compromise between depth of field (DOF) and resolution, this work introduces a quantum approach to eliminate this compromise by harnessing position-momentum entanglement of photon pairs. Compared to conventional LFM at the same resolution, the quantum approach can yield up to tenfold improvement in DOF. This work illustrates the power of utilizing multidimensional entanglement in microscopy and hopefully will inspire further innovations in the field.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 21, 024029] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yingwen Zhang, Duncan England, Antony Orth, Ebrahim Karimi, and Benjamin Sussman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Loss features in ultracold $^{162}\mathrm{Dy}$ gases: Two- versus three-body processes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.023319</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.109.023319"/>
        <updated>2024-02-14T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maxime Lecomte, Alexandre Journeaux, Loan Renaud, Jean Dalibard, and Raphael Lopes
The authors study the low-field loss features in ultracold thermal samples of 162Dy by examining the density and temperature dependence of various loss features. They demonstrate that a majority of loss features are accurately described by a two-body loss rate instead of the commonly assumed three-body rate.

[Phys. Rev. A 109, 023319] Published Wed Feb 14, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maxime Lecomte, Alexandre Journeaux, Loan Renaud, Jean Dalibard, and Raphael Lopes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ternary Oxides of $s$- and $p$-Block Metals for Photocatalytic Solar-to-Hydrogen Conversion]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXEnergy.3.013007</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXEnergy.3.013007"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Simon Gelin, Nicole E. Kirchner-Hall, Rowan R. Katzbaer, Monica J. Theibault, Yihuang Xiong, Wayne Zhao, Mohammed M. Khan, Eric Andrewlavage, Paul Orbe, Steven M. Baksa, Matteo Cococcioni, Iurii Timrov, Quinn Campbell, Héctor Abruña, Raymond E. Schaak, and Ismaila Dabo
Computational materials design is combined with synthesis and electrochemical characterization to propose nine oxide semiconductors as water-splitting photocatalysts.

[PRX Energy 3, 013007] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Gelin, Nicole E. Kirchner-Hall, Rowan R. Katzbaer, Monica J. Theibault, Yihuang Xiong, Wayne Zhao, Mohammed M. Khan, Eric Andrewlavage, Paul Orbe, Steven M. Baksa, Matteo Cococcioni, Iurii Timrov, Quinn Campbell, Héctor Abruña, Raymond E. Schaak, and Ismaila Dabo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic Allometry of Nuclei in Early Embryos of <i>Caenorhabditis elegans</i>]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011016</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.14.011016"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rolf Fickentscher, Tomoko Ozawa, Akatsuki Kimura, and Matthias Weiss
By monitoring a tiny worm’s embryonic cells, researchers have deduced that the availability of material for the membrane of a cell’s nucleus constrains the volume of the nucleus.

[Phys. Rev. X 14, 011016] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rolf Fickentscher, Tomoko Ozawa, Akatsuki Kimura, and Matthias Weiss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plasmonic vortices host magnetoelectric interactions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.6.013163</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.6.013163"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Atreyie Ghosh, Sena Yang, Yanan Dai, W. Vincent Liu, and Hrvoje Petek
Plasmonic vortices are found to host pseudoscalar 𝙀∙𝘽 fields that are odd under parity 𝒫 and time 𝒯 inversion, but even under the joint 𝒫𝒯 symmetry, enabling them to drive the magnetoelectric response and act as a source of the axion field.

[Phys. Rev. Research 6, 013163] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Atreyie Ghosh, Sena Yang, Yanan Dai, W. Vincent Liu, and Hrvoje Petek</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nanoscale dynamics of hydrogen in ${\mathrm{VO}}_{2}$ studied by $μ\mathrm{SR}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.8.024602"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): H. Okabe, M. Hiraishi, A. Koda, Y. Matsushita, T. Ohsawa, N. Ohashi, and R. Kadono
Vanadium dioxide (VO2) is a promising next-generation electronic material for artificial neural networks. Here, the authors use muon spin spectroscopy to provide a microscopic basis for understanding nanoscale hydrogen diffusion in VO2, using muons as a microscopic simulator of dilute hydrogen. This innovation allows the authors to investigate the dynamics of trace hydrogen in nanoscale regions such as thin films, which is very difficult to achieve with conventional methods. This study is expected not only to make a significant contribution to the development of VO2 devices but also to provide a unique method for observing the dynamics of hydrogen at the nanoscale.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 8, 024602] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>H. Okabe, M. Hiraishi, A. Koda, Y. Matsushita, T. Ohsawa, N. Ohashi, and R. Kadono</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exponential Capacity of Dense Associative Memories]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.077301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.132.077301"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Carlo Lucibello and Marc Mézard
A statistical mechanics analysis allows for the computation of asymptotic thresholds for pattern retrieval in the context of dense associative memories.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 132, 077301] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carlo Lucibello and Marc Mézard</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eigenvector continuation for the pairing Hamiltonian]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.024311</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.024311"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Companys Franzke, A. Tichai, K. Hebeler, and A. Schwenk
This work reports on an emulator for the evaluation of many-body observables based on an eigenvector continuation (EC) framework as an example of a reduced-basis method for a detailed study of the exactly solvable pairing Hamiltonian that serves as a model for nuclear superfluidity. EC is established as a robust resummation tool for many-body perturbation theory even though the bare perturbative expansion breaks down. The authors obtain a reliable, computation-saving, description of the exact solution with a small number of training points, provided these are taken from both sides of the pairing phase transition.

[Phys. Rev. C 109, 024311] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Companys Franzke, A. Tichai, K. Hebeler, and A. Schwenk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ternary quasifission in collisions of actinide nuclei]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.024316</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.109.024316"/>
        <updated>2024-02-13T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. D. Zhang, B. Li, D. Vretenar, T. Nikšić, Z. X. Ren, P. W. Zhao, and J. Meng
Far away from the heaviest known nuclei, an island of relatively stable nuclei should exist in the nuclear chart. Reaching that island of stability requires a nuclear reaction that will transfer a large number of nucleons from one nucleus to another, such as in the collision of two actinide nuclei, which are heavy and already neutron-rich. In one particular collision scenario, ternary quasifission, the composite system formed by the two colliding nuclei is not in equilibrium, splitting into three fragments, instead of the more commonly observed binary fission process. The authors report a systematic study of ternary quasifission in 238U + 238U collisions in a microscopic framework that has been successfully applied to various nuclear phenomena. They find that including octupole deformation has a pronounced effect on the formation of the middle fragment. For tail-to-tail and tail-to-side collisions, the model calculations predict the formation of very heavy neutron-rich systems in certain energy intervals, a result that is potentially interesting for the synthesis of superheavy elements.

[Phys. Rev. C 109, 024316] Published Tue Feb 13, 2024]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. D. Zhang, B. Li, D. Vretenar, T. Nikšić, Z. X. Ren, P. W. Zhao, and J. Meng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>