<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-11-13T00:47:09.359Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-11-13T00:47:09.359Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Incorporating intrinsic compressibility effects in velocity transformations for wall-bounded turbulent flows]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L112601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L112601"/>
        <updated>2023-11-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Asif Manzoor Hasan, Johan Larsson, Sergio Pirozzoli, and Rene Pecnik
The law of the wall states that, after appropriate scaling, the mean velocity of incompressible turbulent flows near flat solid walls is a universal function of the wall-normal distance. An analogous law does not exist for compressible flows due to complexities arising from mean property variations and intrinsic compressibility effects, which occur when pressure directly changes the density of fluid elements. By accounting for both these effects, we propose a new velocity scaling that transforms the mean velocity of compressible flows to the incompressible law of the wall. This transformation is more accurate than the state-of-the-art, and is applicable to a wider range of flows.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, L112601] Published Thu Nov 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Asif Manzoor Hasan, Johan Larsson, Sergio Pirozzoli, and Rene Pecnik</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Contribution of negative-energy states to the $E2\text{−}M1$ polarizability of optical clocks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.L051101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.L051101"/>
        <updated>2023-11-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fang-Fei Wu, Ting-Yun Shi, Wei-Tou Ni, and Li-Yan Tang
The authors theoretically investigate the impact of Dirac negative-energy states on the E2 and M1 polarizabilities in optical clocks. They demonstrate the importance of negative-energy states for the M1 polarizability and resolve the sign inconsistency between the theoretical calculations and experimental measurements in the E2-M1 polarizability difference of the Sr clock.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, L051101] Published Thu Nov 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fang-Fei Wu, Ting-Yun Shi, Wei-Tou Ni, and Li-Yan Tang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Contribution of negative-energy states to multipolar polarizabilities of the Sr optical lattice clock]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.L051102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.L051102"/>
        <updated>2023-11-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. G. Porsev, M. G. Kozlov, and M. S. Safronova
An accurate formula for the magnetic-dipole polarizability that takes into account both the positive- and negative-energy-state contributions is presented. The major discrepancy between the theory and experiment is explained.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, L051102] Published Thu Nov 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. G. Porsev, M. G. Kozlov, and M. S. Safronova</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantitative statistical analysis of order-splitting behavior of individual trading accounts in the Japanese stock market over nine years]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043131</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043131"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuki Sato and Kiyoshi Kanazawa
An analysis of data from the Tokyo Stock Exchange provides the first quantitative evidence for the Lillo-Mike-Farmer model—a long-standing theory in economics.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 043131] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuki Sato and Kiyoshi Kanazawa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oscillations and Cavity Modes in the Circular Hydraulic Jump]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.194001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.194001"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aurélien Goerlinger, Michael Baudoin, Farzam Zoueshtiagh, and Alexis Duchesne
A fluid phenomenon seen daily in kitchens has been found to exhibit unexpected behavior.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 194001] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aurélien Goerlinger, Michael Baudoin, Farzam Zoueshtiagh, and Alexis Duchesne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Acoustically Driven Magnon-Phonon Coupling in a Layered Antiferromagnet]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.196701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.196701"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Thomas P. Lyons, Jorge Puebla, Kei Yamamoto, Russell S. Deacon, Yunyoung Hwang, Koji Ishibashi, Sadamichi Maekawa, and Yoshichika Otani
The low oscillation frequency of spin waves in chromium trichloride enables researchers to explore this antiferromagnet’s rich properties with standard laboratory equipment.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 196701] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas P. Lyons, Jorge Puebla, Kei Yamamoto, Russell S. Deacon, Yunyoung Hwang, Koji Ishibashi, Sadamichi Maekawa, and Yoshichika Otani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inferring Microscopic Financial Information from the Long Memory in Market-Order Flow: A Quantitative Test of the Lillo-Mike-Farmer Model]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.197401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.197401"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuki Sato and Kiyoshi Kanazawa
An analysis of data from the Tokyo Stock Exchange provides the first quantitative evidence for the Lillo-Mike-Farmer model—a long-standing theory in economics.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 197401] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuki Sato and Kiyoshi Kanazawa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crystal and magnetic structure of cesium superoxide]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.174412</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.174412"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. A. Ewings, M. Reehuis, F. Orlandi, P. Manuel, D. D. Khalyavin, A. S. Gibbs, A. D. Fortes, A. Hoser, A. J. Princep, and M. Jansen
Cesium superoxide is magnetic, due to the half-occupied π orbitals on its O2− molecules. Neutron diffraction experiments done here find that the crystal structure undergoes a sequence of transitions from tetragonal to incommensurate to orthorhombic, with the latter two exhibiting staggered displacements of the cesium ions. The symmetry of this structure permits antisymmetric exchange, which is consistent with a canted antiferromagnetic structure also observed, and a nice example of a structure-property relationship.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 174412] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. A. Ewings, M. Reehuis, F. Orlandi, P. Manuel, D. D. Khalyavin, A. S. Gibbs, A. D. Fortes, A. Hoser, A. J. Princep, and M. Jansen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kondo interaction of quantum spin Hall edge channels with charge puddles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.205302"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christopher Fuchs, Saquib Shamim, Pragya Shekhar, Lena Fürst, Johannes Kleinlein, Jukka I. Väyrynen, Hartmut Buhmann, and Laurens W. Molenkamp
Since the first observation of the quantum spin Hall effect, it is known that the helical edge channel conductance exhibits fluctuations around the quantized value, in contrast to the (integer) quantum Hall effect. Here, the authors show, in a mechanistic study, that these fluctuations originate from spin-flip scattering mediated by charge puddles via a Kondo-type interaction, an effect which is expected to occur in any narrow-gap quantum spin Hall insulator.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 205302] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher Fuchs, Saquib Shamim, Pragya Shekhar, Lena Fürst, Johannes Kleinlein, Jukka I. Väyrynen, Hartmut Buhmann, and Laurens W. Molenkamp</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physically motivated analytical expression for the temperature dependence of the zero-field splitting of the nitrogen-vacancy center in diamond]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L180102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L180102"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. C. Cambria, G. Thiering, A. Norambuena, H. T. Dinani, A. Gardill, I. Kemeny, V. Lordi, Á. Gali, J. R. Maze, and S. Kolkowitz
The zero-field splitting (ZFS) of the nitrogen vacancy (NV) center in diamond’s ground-state electronic spin is temperature dependent, enabling nanoscale thermometry with NV centers. Here, the authors propose a simple, analytical expression that captures the measured ZFS over a wide range of temperatures. The authors explain the physical motivations for this expression and suggest that similar expressions may apply to other properties of the NV center, as well as to other solid-state spin systems.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L180102] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. C. Cambria, G. Thiering, A. Norambuena, H. T. Dinani, A. Gardill, I. Kemeny, V. Lordi, Á. Gali, J. R. Maze, and S. Kolkowitz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Structure and dynamics of a pinned vortex liquid in a superconducting $a\text{−}{\mathrm{Re}}_{6}\mathrm{Zr}$ thin film]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L180503</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L180503"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rishabh Duhan, Subhamita Sengupta, Ruchi Tomar, Somak Basistha, Vivas Bagwe, Chandan Dasgupta, and Pratap Raychaudhuri
Real space imaging using a scanning tunnelling microscope reveals the formation of an inhomogeneous vortex liquid state in few nanometer thick superconducting films that does not freeze into a crystal or a glass down to 0.41 K. Vortices in this two-dimensional liquid form a network of percolating paths, due to the combined effect of pinning and intervortex interaction. While some vortices remain static, others move on this network, with their relative fractions changing with magnetic field, temperature, and applied current.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L180503] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rishabh Duhan, Subhamita Sengupta, Ruchi Tomar, Somak Basistha, Vivas Bagwe, Chandan Dasgupta, and Pratap Raychaudhuri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optimal qubit circuits for quantum-enhanced telescopes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.052408</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.052408"/>
        <updated>2023-11-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Robert Czupryniak, John Steinmetz, Paul G. Kwiat, and Andrew N. Jordan
The authors propose two optimal phase-estimation schemes that can be used for quantum-enhanced long-baseline interferometry where distributed entanglement eliminates the loss of stellar photons during transmission over the baselines. The schemes can lead to a reduction of both the number of ancilla qubits and the number of gate operations by a factor of two.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 052408] Published Wed Nov 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Robert Czupryniak, John Steinmetz, Paul G. Kwiat, and Andrew N. Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phase-Driving Hole Spin Qubits]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.197001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.197001"/>
        <updated>2023-11-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Stefano Bosco, Simon Geyer, Leon C. Camenzind, Rafael S. Eggli, Andreas Fuhrer, Richard J. Warburton, Dominik M. Zumbühl, J. Carlos Egues, Andreas V. Kuhlmann, and Daniel Loss
A microwave pulse modulates the phase of a spin qubit, providing an alternative driving mechanism in quantum information processing.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 197001] Published Tue Nov 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stefano Bosco, Simon Geyer, Leon C. Camenzind, Rafael S. Eggli, Andreas Fuhrer, Richard J. Warburton, Dominik M. Zumbühl, J. Carlos Egues, Andreas V. Kuhlmann, and Daniel Loss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theoretical modeling of capillary surfer interactions on a vibrating fluid bath]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.114001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.114001"/>
        <updated>2023-11-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anand U. Oza, Giuseppe Pucci, Ian Ho, and Daniel M. Harris
“Capillary surfers” are small objects that self-propel while floating at the interface of a vibrating fluid bath. In this paper, we construct and analyze a theoretical model for the waves generated by such surfers and thus the hydrodynamic forces exerted by one surfer on another. Our model recovers the dynamical modes of surfer pairs found in experiments, and predicts that surfer collectives may lock into a variety of quantized bound states. Generally, our work shows that capillary surfers are a promising platform for studying wave-coupled active matter.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 114001] Published Tue Nov 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anand U. Oza, Giuseppe Pucci, Ian Ho, and Daniel M. Harris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capillary surfers: Wave-driven particles at a vibrating fluid interface]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L112001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.L112001"/>
        <updated>2023-11-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ian Ho, Giuseppe Pucci, Anand U. Oza, and Daniel M. Harris
A small solid particle resting atop a vibrating fluid interface generates a field of outwardly propagating capillary waves due to its relative vertical motion. In this paper, we show that if the particle’s symmetry is broken, the resultant unbalanced wave stresses enable steady self-propulsion along the interface. Such “capillary surfers” interact with each other hydrodynamically at long range via their mutual wavefield and form a number of dynamic bound states. This new active system bridges the gap between dissipation- and inertia-dominated regimes and promises a number of novel collective behaviors.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, L112001] Published Tue Nov 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ian Ho, Giuseppe Pucci, Anand U. Oza, and Daniel M. Harris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flavored jets with exact anti-${k}_{t}$ kinematics and tests of infrared and collinear safety]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.094010</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.094010"/>
        <updated>2023-11-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fabrizio Caola, Radosław Grabarczyk, Maxwell L. Hutt, Gavin P. Salam, Ludovic Scyboz, and Jesse Thaler
A longstanding goal in collider analysis has been to assign flavor consistently to jets of final state particles which can then be associated with the initial partons coming from hard scattering processes. This paper presents “Interleaved Flavor Neutralization” to define jets with infrared- and collinear-safe (IRC safe) flavor and clustering properties similar to successful kinematic jet definitions. The authors carry out detailed checks to show the algorithm is IRC safe to at least sixth order in the strong coupling constant.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 094010] Published Mon Nov 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fabrizio Caola, Radosław Grabarczyk, Maxwell L. Hutt, Gavin P. Salam, Ludovic Scyboz, and Jesse Thaler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multipartite entanglement in the measurement-induced phase transition of the quantum Ising chain]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.184302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.184302"/>
        <updated>2023-11-06T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alessio Paviglianiti and Alessandro Silva
Quantum systems subject to external monitoring manifest a rich phenomenology in their entanglement properties. Here, the authors use quantum Fisher information to uncover a multipartite entanglement phase transition in the monitored quantum Ising chain. By changing the measurement rate, they observe a shift from bounded to long-range multipartiteness of quantum correlations. They show that the quantum Fisher information displays distinct behavior from the entanglement entropy, and the two outline different phase boundaries.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 184302] Published Mon Nov 06, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alessio Paviglianiti and Alessandro Silva</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Loss Compensation and Superresolution in Metamaterials with Excitations at Complex Frequencies]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041024</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041024"/>
        <updated>2023-11-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Seunghwi Kim, Yu-Gui Peng, Simon Yves, and Andrea Alù
Illuminating a high-resolution lens with waves whose intensity diminishes over time can improve the image quality.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 041024] Published Fri Nov 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Seunghwi Kim, Yu-Gui Peng, Simon Yves, and Andrea Alù</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of Capillary Forces Using Two Fibers Dynamically Withdrawn from a Liquid: Evidence for an Enhanced Cheerios Effect]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.184003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.184003"/>
        <updated>2023-11-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hadrien Bense, Emmanuel Siéfert, and Fabian Brau
The attractive force that causes floating Cheerios to clump together increases in strength when objects are withdrawn from a liquid.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 184003] Published Fri Nov 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hadrien Bense, Emmanuel Siéfert, and Fabian Brau</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anisotropic Nonlocal Damping in $\mathrm{Ferromagnet}/α\text{−}\mathrm{GeTe}$ Bilayers Enabled by Splitting Energy Bands]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.186703</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.186703"/>
        <updated>2023-11-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xu Yang, Liang Qiu, Yan Li, Hao-Pu Xue, Jia-Nan Liu, Rui Sun, Qing-Lin Yang, Xue-Song Gai, Yan-Sheng Wei, Andrew H. Comstock, Dali Sun, Xiang-Qun Zhang, Wei He, Yusheng Hou, and Zhao-Hua Cheng
Anisotropic nonlocal Gilbert damping, an effect induced by the anisotropic splitting of energy bands, has been observed experimentally for the first time in GeTe.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 186703] Published Fri Nov 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xu Yang, Liang Qiu, Yan Li, Hao-Pu Xue, Jia-Nan Liu, Rui Sun, Qing-Lin Yang, Xue-Song Gai, Yan-Sheng Wei, Andrew H. Comstock, Dali Sun, Xiang-Qun Zhang, Wei He, Yusheng Hou, and Zhao-Hua Cheng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement-induced state transitions in a superconducting qubit: Within the rotating-wave approximation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.054008</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.054008"/>
        <updated>2023-11-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mostafa Khezri, Alex Opremcak, Zijun Chen, Kevin C. Miao, Matt McEwen, Andreas Bengtsson, Theodore White, Ofer Naaman, Daniel Sank, Alexander N. Korotkov, Yu Chen, and Vadim Smelyanskiy
Fast nondemolition measurement of superconducting qubits is important for the operation of quantum computers, but readout is constrained by measurement-induced state transitions that shift the qubit population outside of its computational subspace. This work experimentally characterizes the phenomenon and provides an intuitive model to explain its physical process. Surprisingly, the offset charge of the transmon qubit, which is usually ignored, is important in explaining the experiments. These results inform engineering and physics-based solutions to this problem by providing performance limits for the dispersive readout of superconducting qubits.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 054008] Published Fri Nov 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mostafa Khezri, Alex Opremcak, Zijun Chen, Kevin C. Miao, Matt McEwen, Andreas Bengtsson, Theodore White, Ofer Naaman, Daniel Sank, Alexander N. Korotkov, Yu Chen, and Vadim Smelyanskiy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Data-driven discovery and extrapolation of parameterized pattern-forming dynamics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.L042017</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.L042017"/>
        <updated>2023-11-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zachary G. Nicolaou, Guanyu Huo, Yihui Chen, Steven L. Brunton, and J. Nathan Kutz
A new machine-learning framework enables the discovery of governing equations in pattern-forming systems parameterized by external driving conditions. The resulting data-driven models reveal effective nonlinear corrections to classical perturbation theory, enabling extrapolation including the prediction of bifurcations far from the conditions used in training.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, L042017] Published Thu Nov 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zachary G. Nicolaou, Guanyu Huo, Yihui Chen, Steven L. Brunton, and J. Nathan Kutz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal to nonuniversal transition of the statistics of rare events during the spread of random walks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.L052102</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.L052102"/>
        <updated>2023-11-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. K. Singh and Stanislav Burov
In a large class of systems governed by rare event statistics, the probability density function for particle position shows a universal exponential decay. Using the continuous-time random walk method, this paper shows that there is a critical transition between this universal behavior and a more specific, slower decay.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, L052102] Published Thu Nov 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. K. Singh and Stanislav Burov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cryogenic spin Peltier effect detected by a ${\mathrm{Ru}\mathrm{O}}_{2}\text{−}{\mathrm{Al}\mathrm{O}}_{x}$ on-chip microthermometer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.054006</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.054006"/>
        <updated>2023-11-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Takashi Kikkawa, Haruka Kiguchi, Alexey A. Kaverzin, Ryo Takahashi, and Eiji Saitoh
Exploring low-temperature thermometry, particularly at the micro- to nanoscale, is essential not only for advancing thermoelectric science, but also for the development of quantum technology. The authors present a methodology and an experimental platform based on an on-chip microthermometer, enabling the detection of extremely small temperature changes in thin films, down to tens of nanokelvins. Using this approach, the authors observe the spin Peltier effect (temperature modulation induced by spin current) at 2 K. Their methods have the potential to uncover other low-temperature thermoelectric effects in microdevices, including those made of two-dimensional van der Waals materials.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 054006] Published Thu Nov 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Takashi Kikkawa, Haruka Kiguchi, Alexey A. Kaverzin, Ryo Takahashi, and Eiji Saitoh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comparative study of the superconductivity in the Holstein and optical Su-Schrieffer-Heeger models]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.184501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.184501"/>
        <updated>2023-11-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Andy Tanjaroon Ly, Benjamin Cohen-Stead, Sohan Malkaruge Costa, and Steven Johnston
Su-Schrieffer-Heeger (SSH) electron-phonon (e−ph) interactions have been theorized to play critical roles in several novel states of matter, ranging from nontrivial topological states to high-temperature bipolaronic superconductivity. This work compares the superconducting and competing charge and bond correlations of the two-dimensional Holstein and optical (SSH) models. The authors find that near half-filling, light SSH (bi)polarons support superconductivity to larger values of e−ph coupling compared to the Holstein polaron. These results are essential for identifying and engineering bipolaronic superconductivity in quantum materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 184501] Published Wed Nov 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Andy Tanjaroon Ly, Benjamin Cohen-Stead, Sohan Malkaruge Costa, and Steven Johnston</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Piezo-orbital backaction force in a rare-earth-doped crystal]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.054004</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.054004"/>
        <updated>2023-11-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Louchet-Chauvet, P. Verlot, J.-P. Poizat, and T. Chanelière
Hybrid optomechanics can bridge the quantum and classical domains, to generally extend quantum principles to macroscopic scale. A milestone here would be observing the fundamental backaction force that occurs when a hybrid mechanical system is optically probed, which can be dominated by classical thermal effects. Using a large ensemble of rare-earth ions in a crystal plus time-resolved tomography, researchers see this backaction as a tiny distortion of the crystal’s surface around a laser beam’s spot, and unambiguously distinguish the photothermal contribution from that of the backaction. Thus rare-earth ions in crystals are confirmed as a promising platform for hybrid optomechanics.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 054004] Published Wed Nov 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Louchet-Chauvet, P. Verlot, J.-P. Poizat, and T. Chanelière</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Imaging electron angular distributions to assess a full-power petawatt-class laser focus]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.053101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.053101"/>
        <updated>2023-11-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Smrithan Ravichandran, Marine Huault, Roberto Lera, Calvin Z. He, Andrew Longman, Robert Fedosejevs, Luis Roso, and Wendell T. Hill, III
Electrons can help infer laser intensities that are too high to measure using conventional methods.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 053101] Published Wed Nov 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Smrithan Ravichandran, Marine Huault, Roberto Lera, Calvin Z. He, Andrew Longman, Robert Fedosejevs, Luis Roso, and Wendell T. Hill, III</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chiral currents in Bose-Einstein condensates subject to current-density interactions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.053302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.053302"/>
        <updated>2023-11-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Maria Arazo, Montserrat Guilleumas, Ricardo Mayol, Vicente Delgado, and Antonio Muñoz Mateo
The authors study a quasi-one-dimensional Bose-Einstein condensate in a rotating ring geometry subject to a current nonlinearity. The stability of stationary states is examined both by linear excitation analysis and time evolution of the Gross-Pitaevskii equation with current-density interactions.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 053302] Published Wed Nov 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maria Arazo, Montserrat Guilleumas, Ricardo Mayol, Vicente Delgado, and Antonio Muñoz Mateo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Engineering Field-Insensitive Molecular Clock Transitions for Symmetry Violation Searches]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.183003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.183003"/>
        <updated>2023-10-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuiki Takahashi, Chi Zhang, Arian Jadbabaie, and Nicholas R. Hutzler
Researchers have engineered ultracold molecular transitions ideally suited for probing beyond-standard-model effects of symmetry violations.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 183003] Published Tue Oct 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuiki Takahashi, Chi Zhang, Arian Jadbabaie, and Nicholas R. Hutzler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-Purity Generation and Switching of Twisted Single Photons]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.183801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.183801"/>
        <updated>2023-10-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Haoqi Zhao, Yichen Ma, Zihe Gao, Na Liu, Tianwei Wu, Shuang Wu, Xilin Feng, James Hone, Stefan Strauf, and Liang Feng
An experiment combines the two-dimensional semiconductor WSe2 with a spin-orbit-coupled microring resonator to demonstrate the high-purity generation of twisted single photons and its convenient switching between different orbital angular momentum states.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 183801] Published Tue Oct 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Haoqi Zhao, Yichen Ma, Zihe Gao, Na Liu, Tianwei Wu, Shuang Wu, Xilin Feng, James Hone, Stefan Strauf, and Liang Feng</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Probing a Defect-Site-Specific Electronic Orbital in Graphene with Single-Atom Sensitivity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.186202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.186202"/>
        <updated>2023-10-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mingquan Xu, Aowen Li, Stephen J. Pennycook, Shang-Peng Gao, and Wu Zhou
Energy-loss spectroscopy mapping of a silicon point defect in graphene demonstrates real-space mapping of specific electronic excitations at the single-atom scale.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 186202] Published Tue Oct 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mingquan Xu, Aowen Li, Stephen J. Pennycook, Shang-Peng Gao, and Wu Zhou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Characteristic rupture height of the mediating air film beneath an impacting drop on atomically smooth mica]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.103602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.103602"/>
        <updated>2023-10-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ramin Kaviani and John M. Kolinski
Before a droplet can contact a solid surface, it must drain the air beneath it. In our daily experience, the air doesn’t alter the global outcome of contact formation in the blink of an eye. In this work, we find that the lubricating air film formed beneath an impacting droplet can resist rupture for droplets impacting at a velocity exceeding 1/2 a meter per second; however, beyond a critical impact velocity, contact always occurs from the liquid’s closest approach to the solid surface through the air, at a distance of 20 - 30 nanometers. Below the critical velocity, contact is suppressed for impact upon atomically smooth, cleaved mica, shedding light on the critical phase of liquid-solid contact.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 103602] Published Tue Oct 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ramin Kaviani and John M. Kolinski</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Constraints on anisotropic primordial non-Gaussianity from intrinsic alignments of SDSS-III BOSS galaxies]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.083533</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.083533"/>
        <updated>2023-10-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Toshiki Kurita and Masahiro Takada
The authors employ a novel power-spectrum estimator to measure galaxy intrinsic alignments from Sloan Digital Sky Survey data. They showcase the method’s usefulness, constraining the level of non-gaussianities in primordial cosmological structure perturbations.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 083533] Published Tue Oct 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Toshiki Kurita and Masahiro Takada</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-pressure behavior of the magnetic van der Waals molecular framework Ni(NCS)${}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144439</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144439"/>
        <updated>2023-10-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Madeleine Geers, David M. Jarvis, Cheng Liu, Siddharth S. Saxena, Jem Pitcairn, Emily Myatt, Sebastian A. Hallweger, Silva M. Kronawitter, Gregor Kieslich, Sanliang Ling, Andrew B. Cairns, Dominik Daisenberger, Oscar Fabelo, Laura Cañadillas-Delgado, and Matthew J. Cliffe
The ease of applying external stimuli, such as pressure, is an attractive feature for devices based on van der Waals materials. The authors report here the effect of pressure up to 8 kbar on Ni(NCS)2, a two-dimensional van der Waals magnet, using bulk magnetic susceptibility and neutron and x-ray diffraction. Ni(NCS)2 is found to be more compressible than metal halide analogues, with anisotropic compressibility both within the layers and between them. In addition to the large mechanical response, the magnetic ordering temperature is significantly enhanced: ΔTN /TN = 19%.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 144439] Published Tue Oct 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Madeleine Geers, David M. Jarvis, Cheng Liu, Siddharth S. Saxena, Jem Pitcairn, Emily Myatt, Sebastian A. Hallweger, Silva M. Kronawitter, Gregor Kieslich, Sanliang Ling, Andrew B. Cairns, Dominik Daisenberger, Oscar Fabelo, Laura Cañadillas-Delgado, and Matthew J. Cliffe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Broadband Quantum Enhancement of the LIGO Detectors with Frequency-Dependent Squeezing]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041021</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041021"/>
        <updated>2023-10-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. Ganapathy et al. (LIGO O4 Detector Collaboration)
The LIGO experiment has demonstrated a noise-squeezing technique for its entire frequency-detection range—a feat that could boost the detection rate of black hole mergers by up to 65%.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 041021] Published Mon Oct 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. Ganapathy &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LIGO O4 Detector Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of Single-Top-Quark Production in Association with a Photon Using the ATLAS Detector]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.181901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.181901"/>
        <updated>2023-10-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): G. Aad et al. (ATLAS Collaboration)
The Large Hadron Collider’s ATLAS Collaboration observes, for the first time, the coincident production of a photon and a top quark.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 181901] Published Mon Oct 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>G. Aad &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (ATLAS Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Controlling the Spatial Profile and Energy Landscape of Organic Polariton Condensates in Double-Dye Cavities]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.186902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.186902"/>
        <updated>2023-10-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anton D. Putintsev, Kirsty E. McGhee, Denis Sannikov, Anton V. Zasedatelev, Julian D. Töpfer, Till Jessewitsch, Ullrich Scherf, David G. Lidzey, and Pavlos G. Lagoudakis
Ultrafast and reversible manipulation of the spatial profile and energy landscape of organic polariton condensates is experimentally demonstrated in double-dye cavities by shaping both the local potential and the dissipation in real space at room temperature.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 186902] Published Mon Oct 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anton D. Putintsev, Kirsty E. McGhee, Denis Sannikov, Anton V. Zasedatelev, Julian D. Töpfer, Till Jessewitsch, Ullrich Scherf, David G. Lidzey, and Pavlos G. Lagoudakis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skyrmion motion in magnetic anisotropy gradients: Acceleration caused by deformation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144438</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144438"/>
        <updated>2023-10-30T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ismael Ribeiro de Assis, Ingrid Mertig, and Börge Göbel
Skyrmions in weak parameter gradients behave similarly to current-driven skyrmions, moving uniformly along a fixed skyrmion Hall angle relative to the current direction. This study reveals a distinct type of motion that becomes relevant for large parameter gradients: skyrmions undergo significant profile changes, resulting in a nonuniform motion. They accelerate and follow curved trajectories. Leveraging this insight, the authors introduce novel strategies for suppressing the skyrmion Hall effect, both parallel and perpendicular to the gradient direction.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 144438] Published Mon Oct 30, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ismael Ribeiro de Assis, Ingrid Mertig, and Börge Göbel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strong Evidence for $^{9}\mathrm{N}$ and the Limits of Existence of Atomic Nuclei]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.172501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.172501"/>
        <updated>2023-10-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. J. Charity, J. Wylie, S. M. Wang, T. B. Webb, K. W. Brown, G. Cerizza, Z. Chajecki, J. M. Elson, J. Estee, D. E. M. Hoff, S. A. Kuvin, W. G. Lynch, J. Manfredi, N. Michel, D. G. McNeel, P. Morfouace, W. Nazarewicz, C. D. Pruitt, C. Santamaria, S. Sweany, J. Smith, L. G. Sobotka, M. B. Tsang, and A. H. Wuosmaa
A highly unstable nucleus that decays by emitting five protons has been observed, offering an extreme case for testing nuclear models.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 172501] Published Fri Oct 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. J. Charity, J. Wylie, S. M. Wang, T. B. Webb, K. W. Brown, G. Cerizza, Z. Chajecki, J. M. Elson, J. Estee, D. E. M. Hoff, S. A. Kuvin, W. G. Lynch, J. Manfredi, N. Michel, D. G. McNeel, P. Morfouace, W. Nazarewicz, C. D. Pruitt, C. Santamaria, S. Sweany, J. Smith, L. G. Sobotka, M. B. Tsang, and A. H. Wuosmaa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Invariant-mass spectroscopy in projectile fragmentation reactions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.044318</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.044318"/>
        <updated>2023-10-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. J. Charity and L. G. Sobotka
A highly unstable nucleus that decays by emitting five protons has been observed, offering an extreme case for testing nuclear models.

[Phys. Rev. C 108, 044318] Published Fri Oct 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. J. Charity and L. G. Sobotka</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unveiling the impact of temperature on magnon diffuse scattering detection in the transmission electron microscope]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134435</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134435"/>
        <updated>2023-10-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): José Ángel Castellanos-Reyes, Paul Zeiger, Anders Bergman, Demie Kepaptsoglou, Quentin M. Ramasse, Juan Carlos Idrobo, and Ján Rusz
This study delves deeply into the complexities of magnon diffuse scattering (MDS) in bcc Fe, unraveling the interplay between atomic vibrations and magnon signals in scanning transmission electron microscopy (STEM). The work details the role of temperature to explore feasible paths for MDS detection that could bring new understanding of magnetic solid-state phenomena at the nanometer scale.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 134435] Published Fri Oct 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>José Ángel Castellanos-Reyes, Paul Zeiger, Anders Bergman, Demie Kepaptsoglou, Quentin M. Ramasse, Juan Carlos Idrobo, and Ján Rusz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamical vortex transitions in a gate-tunable two-dimensional Josephson junction array]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134517</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134517"/>
        <updated>2023-10-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. G. L. Bøttcher, F. Nichele, J. Shabani, C. J. Palmstrøm, and C. M. Marcus
The sudden depinning of vortices with increasing current through a super-semihybrid Josephson junction array results in a burst of differential resistance at integer and half-integer peaks of critical current. A striking feature is the split feature at f=0, indicating the absence of vortices at precisely zero field. The flat-topped portion at f=1/2 and the slanted top part at f=1 also reveal features of how the dynamical transition occurs.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 134517] Published Fri Oct 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. G. L. Bøttcher, F. Nichele, J. Shabani, C. J. Palmstrøm, and C. M. Marcus</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strong coupling of monolayer $\mathrm{W}{\mathrm{S}}_{2}$ excitons and surface plasmon polaritons in a planar $\mathrm{Ag}/\mathrm{W}{\mathrm{S}}_{2}$ hybrid structure]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165426</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165426"/>
        <updated>2023-10-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Nicolas Zorn Morales, Daniel Steffen Rühl, Sergey Sadofev, Giovanni Ligorio, Emil List-Kratochvil, Günter Kewes, and Sylke Blumstengel
This paper shows that the strong coupling regime between excitons in a WS2 monolayer and surface plasmon polaritons of a thin Ag film can be reached in a planar geometry of utmost simplicity. Total internal reflection ellipsometry provides a salient feature of strong coupling. The finding opens up the opportunity to engineer the light-matter interaction strength and even to tune the exciton-plasmon system between the weak and strong coupling regime via application of external stimuli.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 165426] Published Fri Oct 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nicolas Zorn Morales, Daniel Steffen Rühl, Sergey Sadofev, Giovanni Ligorio, Emil List-Kratochvil, Günter Kewes, and Sylke Blumstengel</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emergence of a Spin Microemulsion in Spin-Orbit Coupled Bose-Einstein Condensates]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.173403</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.173403"/>
        <updated>2023-10-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ethan C. McGarrigle, Kris T. Delaney, Leon Balents, and Glenn H. Fredrickson
A phase that shares some properties with mayonnaise can form in a Bose-Einstein condensate.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 173403] Published Thu Oct 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ethan C. McGarrigle, Kris T. Delaney, Leon Balents, and Glenn H. Fredrickson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Internal clock of many-body delocalization]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134204</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134204"/>
        <updated>2023-10-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ferdinand Evers, Ishita Modak, and Soumya Bera
For over two decades, researchers have investigated the effect of many-body interactions on Anderson localization. Early studies proposed many-body localization, i.e., strict particle confinement under strong disorder. Here, the authors challenge this notion by highlighting the prevalence of many-body delocalization in a fruit-fly model: the disordered Heisenberg chain. Its relaxation dynamics synchronize over various variables and parameters while adopting the entanglement entropy as an “internal clock”. These results suggest entanglement evolution as a novel temporal measure for a nuanced understanding of relaxation dynamics.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 134204] Published Thu Oct 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ferdinand Evers, Ishita Modak, and Soumya Bera</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Educational data augmentation in physics education research using ChatGPT]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.020150</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.020150"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fabian Kieser, Peter Wulff, Jochen Kuhn, and Stefan Küchemann
ChatGPT can be used to answer concept inventories and subsequently generate humanlike answers.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 19, 020150] Published Wed Oct 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fabian Kieser, Peter Wulff, Jochen Kuhn, and Stefan Küchemann</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Second Data Release from the European Pulsar Timing Array: Challenging the Ultralight Dark Matter Paradigm]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.171001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.171001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Clemente Smarra et al. (European Pulsar Timing Array)
If ultralight dark matter particles exist, they can contribute no more than 70% of the dark matter between Earth and a set of monitored pulsars.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 171001] Published Wed Oct 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Clemente Smarra &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (European Pulsar Timing Array)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fluid-Glass-Jamming Rheology of Soft Active Brownian Particles]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178302"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Roland Wiese, Klaus Kroy, and Demian Levis
With activity taking the place of temperature, a fluid-glass-jamming phase diagram is constructed for active Brownian particles under shear.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 178302] Published Wed Oct 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Roland Wiese, Klaus Kroy, and Demian Levis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lorentz Reciprocal Theorem in Fluids with Odd Viscosity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178303</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178303"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuto Hosaka, Ramin Golestanian, and Andrej Vilfan
The Lorentz reciprocal theorem, crucial for understanding microswimmer propulsion, is generalizable to fluids with odd viscosity.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 178303] Published Wed Oct 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuto Hosaka, Ramin Golestanian, and Andrej Vilfan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spontaneous Demixing of Binary Colloidal Flocks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178304</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178304"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Samadarshi Maity and Alexandre Morin
A homogenous mixture of two self-propelling species first forms a polar vortex and then spontaneously demixes, thanks to a difference in speeds and other competing effects.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 178304] Published Wed Oct 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samadarshi Maity and Alexandre Morin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of inertia-gravity wave attractors in an axisymmetric enclosed basin]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.104802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.104802"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Corentin Pacary, Thierry Dauxois, Evgeny Ermanyuk, Pascal Metz, Marc Moulin, and Sylvain Joubaud
The peculiar reflection of internal waves in rotating stratified fluids enables the concentration of energy on a limit cycle, called an attractor. In this work, the existence of internal gravity wave attractors for rotating stratified fluids is predicted in three-dimensional axisymmetric geometry. This information is used to design experiments using a truncated conical shaped tank in order to form an inertia-gravity waves attractor. We highlight an important difference in the nonlinear regime between the stratification-only and the rotation-only cases.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 104802] Published Wed Oct 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Corentin Pacary, Thierry Dauxois, Evgeny Ermanyuk, Pascal Metz, Marc Moulin, and Sylvain Joubaud</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Negative tripartite mutual information after quantum quenches in integrable systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134434</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134434"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Fabio Caceffo and Vincenzo Alba
The tripartite information (TMI) has emerged as a tool to sieve quantum correlations in quantum many-body systems. A negative TMI is interpreted as evidence for quantum information delocalization in chaotic systems. Here, the authors show that a negative TMI can appear in out-of-equilibrium free-fermion models, and it is linked to the presence of entangled multiplets of excitations. Negative TMI signals a weakening of the relationship between entanglement and thermodynamics, which can be understood in a generalized quasiparticle picture framework.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 134434] Published Wed Oct 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Fabio Caceffo and Vincenzo Alba</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perpendicular electronic transport and moiré-induced resonance in twisted interfaces of three-dimensional graphite]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165422</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165422"/>
        <updated>2023-10-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tenta Tani, Takuto Kawakami, and Mikito Koshino
In moiré materials, the interference patterns give rise to flat bands and introduce novel physical properties. While previous work has mainly focused on two-dimensional systems, the authors theoretically investigate here emergent phenomena in twisted three-dimensional graphite composed of a misoriented pair of graphite pieces. Despite the twisted interface comprising only a small fraction of the entire structure, it is revealed that the moiré pattern produces interface localized bands, leading to a pronounced Fano resonance in electric conduction.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 165422] Published Wed Oct 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tenta Tani, Takuto Kawakami, and Mikito Koshino</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making context explicit in equation construction and interpretation: Symbolic blending]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.020149</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevPhysEducRes.19.020149"/>
        <updated>2023-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Benjamin P. Schermerhorn and John R. Thompson
The symbolic blending model can be used to analyze students’ mathematical sense-making when constructing equations in upper-division physics.

[Phys. Rev. Phys. Educ. Res. 19, 020149] Published Tue Oct 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Benjamin P. Schermerhorn and John R. Thompson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generation of High-Density High-Polarization Positrons via Single-Shot Strong Laser-Foil Interaction]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.175101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.175101"/>
        <updated>2023-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kun Xue, Ting Sun, Ke-Jia Wei, Zhong-Peng Li, Qian Zhao, Feng Wan, Chong Lv, Yong-Tao Zhao, Zhong-Feng Xu, and Jian-Xing Li
Numerical simulations show that highly-polarized dense positron beams can be generated during single-shot interaction of a strong laser with a tilted solid foil by carefully controlling the angle of incidence of the laser on the target.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 175101] Published Tue Oct 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kun Xue, Ting Sun, Ke-Jia Wei, Zhong-Peng Li, Qian Zhao, Feng Wan, Chong Lv, Yong-Tao Zhao, Zhong-Feng Xu, and Jian-Xing Li</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Traveling Perversion as Constant Torque Actuator]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.177201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.177201"/>
        <updated>2023-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Émilien Dilly, Sébastien Neukirch, Julien Derr, and Dražen Zanchi
Helical bacteria and corkscrew rods can both undergo handedness reversals that could be useful in future robotic systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 177201] Published Tue Oct 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Émilien Dilly, Sébastien Neukirch, Julien Derr, and Dražen Zanchi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bend or Twist? What Plectonemes Reveal about the Mysterious Motility of <i>Spiroplasma</i>]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178401"/>
        <updated>2023-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Paul M. Ryan, Joshua W. Shaevitz, and Charles W. Wolgemuth
Helical bacteria and corkscrew rods can both undergo handedness reversals that could be useful in future robotic systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 178401] Published Tue Oct 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul M. Ryan, Joshua W. Shaevitz, and Charles W. Wolgemuth</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to train your demon to do fast information erasure without heat production]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.044138</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.044138"/>
        <updated>2023-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Stephen Whitelam
Time-dependent protocols that perform irreversible logical operations, such as memory erasure, cost work and produce heat, placing bounds on the efficiency of computers. Using a model of a physical memory, the author shows that a neural-network demon can learn feedback-control protocols to do fast memory erasure without input of work or production of heat.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 044138] Published Tue Oct 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen Whitelam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Resonant x-ray diffraction study using circularly polarized x rays on antiferromagnetic ${\mathrm{TbB}}_{4}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134433</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134433"/>
        <updated>2023-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Misawa, K. Arakawa, T. Yoshioka, H. Ueda, F. Iga, K. Tamasaku, Y. Tanaka, and T. Kimura
The interference effect between the magnetic scattering and the charge scattering in resonant x-ray diffraction (RXD) leads to circular dichroism. The authors utilize this effect here to distinguish the antiferromagnetic (AFM) domain state in the noncollinear antiferromagnet TbB4, breaking both the space-inversion (P) and time-reversal (T) symmetries but preserving the combined PT symmetry. This result shows that circularly polarized RXD using the interference effect enables us to detect AFM order parameters and spatially resolve the domain state in PT-symmetric AFM materials.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 134433] Published Tue Oct 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Misawa, K. Arakawa, T. Yoshioka, H. Ueda, F. Iga, K. Tamasaku, Y. Tanaka, and T. Kimura</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gate-voltage switching of nonreciprocal transport in oxide-based Rashba interfaces]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044060</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044060"/>
        <updated>2023-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Julien Bréhin, Luis M. Vicente Arche, Sara Varotto, Srijani Mallik, Jean-Philippe Attané, Laurent Vila, Agnès Barthélémy, Nicolas Bergeal, and Manuel Bibes
Rashba interfaces enable spin-charge interconversion via the direct and inverse Edelstein effects, and so may be used to replace ferromagnets as efficient sources and detectors of spin. However, the direction of spins generated by a ferromagnet can be easily switched, while that of spins generated by a Rashba system is usually fixed, being set by its electronic structure. This study shows that in SrTiO3-based Rashba interfaces, where multiple electronic bands contribute differently to charge-spin conversion, the application of gate voltage enables a sign change of the charge-spin conversion effect. This offers possibilities for innovative spin-based logic devices.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 044060] Published Tue Oct 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julien Bréhin, Luis M. Vicente Arche, Sara Varotto, Srijani Mallik, Jean-Philippe Attané, Laurent Vila, Agnès Barthélémy, Nicolas Bergeal, and Manuel Bibes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multimode Brownian dynamics of a nanomechanical resonator in a viscous fluid]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044061</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044061"/>
        <updated>2023-10-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): H. Gress, J. Barbish, C. Yanik, I.I. Kaya, R.T. Erdogan, M.S. Hanay, M. González, O. Svitelskiy, M.R. Paul, and K.L. Ekinci
The ultimate precision attainable in a mechanical measurement can be determined from the random Brownian motion of the mechanical structure, if the nature of the fluctuations is well understood. To this end, the authors study the Brownian fluctuations of a nanomechanical beam in a viscous fluid. Their predictions based on elasticity theory, fluid dynamics, and statistical mechanics agree well with their experiments, indicating that the observed fluctuations come with “viscous memory”, but no spatial correlations. The insights from this work are expected to impact the design of nanoelectromechanical systems, cantilevers for atomic force microscopy, and other mechanical sensors.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 044061] Published Tue Oct 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>H. Gress, J. Barbish, C. Yanik, I.I. Kaya, R.T. Erdogan, M.S. Hanay, M. González, O. Svitelskiy, M.R. Paul, and K.L. Ekinci</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fabry-Pérot Interferometry at the $ν=2/5$ Fractional Quantum Hall State]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041012</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041012"/>
        <updated>2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Nakamura, S. Liang, G. C. Gardner, and M. J. Manfra
Fabry-Perot interferometry can observe anyon behavior at complex fractional states—a key requirement for analyzing non-abelian states that are sought after for intrinsically fault-tolerant qubits.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 041012] Published Mon Oct 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Nakamura, S. Liang, G. C. Gardner, and M. J. Manfra</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tuning the Curie temperature of a two-dimensional magnet/topological insulator heterostructure to above room temperature by epitaxial growth]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.104004</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.104004"/>
        <updated>2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Wenyi Zhou, Alexander J. Bishop, Xiyue S. Zhang, Katherine Robinson, Igor Lyalin, Ziling Li, Ryan Bailey-Crandell, Thow Min Jerald Cham, Shuyu Cheng, Yunqiu Kelly Luo, Daniel C. Ralph, David A. Muller, and Roland K. Kawakami
The heterostructures of 2D magnets and topological insulators are attractive candidates for quantum anomalous hall effect and highly-efficient spin-orbit torque switching. To better study these phenomena, it will be crucial to synthesize epitaxial heterostructures for scalability while maintaining high-quality interfaces to preserve the topological surface states and having the Curie temperature (TC) above room temperature. Here, the authors utilize molecular beam epitaxy to tune the TC in heterostructures of van der Waals (vdW) magnet Fe3GeTe2 and topological insulator Bi2Te3 to above room temperature by varying growth conditions. Electron microscopy reveals the existence of thicker vdW compounds in the FemGenTe2 family, as well as some intercalants in between vdW gaps, which are possible origins for the enhanced TC.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 104004] Published Mon Oct 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Wenyi Zhou, Alexander J. Bishop, Xiyue S. Zhang, Katherine Robinson, Igor Lyalin, Ziling Li, Ryan Bailey-Crandell, Thow Min Jerald Cham, Shuyu Cheng, Yunqiu Kelly Luo, Daniel C. Ralph, David A. Muller, and Roland K. Kawakami</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Construction of Coarse-Grained Molecular Dynamics with Many-Body Non-Markovian Memory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.177301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.177301"/>
        <updated>2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Liyao Lyu and Huan Lei
A machine-learning-based coarse-grained molecular dynamics (CGMD) model faithfully retains the many-body nature of the intermolecular dissipative interactions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 177301] Published Mon Oct 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liyao Lyu and Huan Lei</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electric Fields in Liquid Water Irradiated with Protons at Ultrahigh Dose Rates]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.178001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): F. Gobet, P. Barberet, M.-H. Delville, G. Devès, T. Guérin, R. Liénard, H. N. Tran, C. Vecco-Garda, A. Würger, S. Zein, and H. Seznec
Ultrahigh dose rates of proton irradiation induce electrokinetic effects in water that can perturb the dynamics of charged particles, such as macromolecules, in biological tissues and other aqueous systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 178001] Published Mon Oct 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>F. Gobet, P. Barberet, M.-H. Delville, G. Devès, T. Guérin, R. Liénard, H. N. Tran, C. Vecco-Garda, A. Würger, S. Zein, and H. Seznec</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple parameter estimation using observable features of gravitational-wave signals]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.082006</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.082006"/>
        <updated>2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Stephen Fairhurst, Charlie Hoy, Rhys Green, Cameron Mills, and Samantha A. Usman
Rapid extraction of parameters to characterize sources of gravitational wave signals is vitally important to gravitational wave astronomy. This paper provides an intuitive method for extracting parameters more efficiently than existing full parameter estimation methods. Among other applications, these new methods appear to be promising ways of addressing real-time needs such as generating gravitational wave event alerts.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 082006] Published Mon Oct 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen Fairhurst, Charlie Hoy, Rhys Green, Cameron Mills, and Samantha A. Usman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Homotopic classification of band structures: Stable, fragile, delicate, and stable representation-protected topology]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155137</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155137"/>
        <updated>2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Piet W. Brouwer and Vatsal Dwivedi
Fragile and delicate topological phases of noninteracting fermions can be trivialized under addition of trivial bands, in contrast to strong topological phases. Here, the authors describe a classification procedure based on homotopy theory for topological insulators with a fixed number of bands. They thereby classify band structures symmetric under discrete rotations and time-reversal at the highest possible level of granularity and identify instances of “representation-protected stable topology”, which is robust to addition of trivial bands with a fixed orbital type.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 155137] Published Mon Oct 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Piet W. Brouwer and Vatsal Dwivedi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Range-separated hybrid functional pseudopotentials]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165142</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165142"/>
        <updated>2023-10-23T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yang Yang, Georgia Prokopiou, Tian Qiu, Aaron M. Schankler, Andrew M. Rappe, Leeor Kronik, and Robert A. DiStasio, Jr.
This work presents a general scheme for constructing pseudopotentials for advanced density functional theory (DFT) calculations employing range-separated hybrid (RSH) functionals. The authors demonstrate pseudopotential construction for several atoms and RSH functionals, and find that pseudopotential consistency errors tend to be systematic when computing solid-state properties and can exceed 0.1 eV for band gaps. This work removes the need to incur such unnecessary errors when performing state-of-the-art electronic structure calculations at the computationally demanding RSH-DFT level.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 165142] Published Mon Oct 23, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yang Yang, Georgia Prokopiou, Tian Qiu, Aaron M. Schankler, Andrew M. Rappe, Leeor Kronik, and Robert A. DiStasio, Jr.</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum Thermometry with Single Molecules in Nanoprobes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.040314</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.040314"/>
        <updated>2023-10-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): V. Esteso, R. Duquennoy, R.C. Ng, M. Colautti, P. Lombardi, G. Arregui, E. Chavez-Angel, C.M. Sotomayor-Torres, P.D. Garcia, M. Hilke, and C. Toninelli
A single-molecule thermometer provides two-dimensional mapping with high spatial and temperature resolution under cryogenic conditions.

[PRX Quantum 4, 040314] Published Fri Oct 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>V. Esteso, R. Duquennoy, R.C. Ng, M. Colautti, P. Lombardi, G. Arregui, E. Chavez-Angel, C.M. Sotomayor-Torres, P.D. Garcia, M. Hilke, and C. Toninelli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple Reaction-Diffusion Modeling Predicts Inconspicuous Neighborhood-Dependent Color Subclustering of Lizard Scales]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041011</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevX.13.041011"/>
        <updated>2023-10-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Szabolcs Zakany and Michel C. Milinkovitch
Researchers have predicted—and confirmed—a secondary pattern on the ocellated lizard’s scales that is too subtle for our eyes to see.

[Phys. Rev. X 13, 041011] Published Fri Oct 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Szabolcs Zakany and Michel C. Milinkovitch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cost and routing of continuous-variable quantum networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042615</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042615"/>
        <updated>2023-10-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Federico Centrone, Frederic Grosshans, and Valentina Parigi
The authors give insight into the amount of entanglement that can be achieved from Gaussian graph states as well as the amount of squeezing required to prepare them. They find that these quantities are highly dependent on the structure of the quantum network.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 042615] Published Fri Oct 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Federico Centrone, Frederic Grosshans, and Valentina Parigi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Wire a $1000$-Qubit Trapped-Ion Quantum Computer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.040313</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.040313"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Malinowski, D.T.C. Allcock, and C.J. Ballance
A concrete proposal for a 1000-qubit trapped-ion quantum processor takes advantage of integrated switching electronics to reduce the wiring complexity without reducing operation fidelity.

[PRX Quantum 4, 040313] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Malinowski, D.T.C. Allcock, and C.J. Ballance</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dragon kings in self-organized criticality systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.L042013</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.L042013"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Guram Mikaberidze, Arthur Plaud, and Raissa M. D'Souza
Models of self-organized criticality can surprisingly produce dragon king failures—massive, self-amplifying cascading events. It is analytically demonstrated that dragon kings are created by the trade-off between driving impulse and dissipation rate.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, L042013] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guram Mikaberidze, Arthur Plaud, and Raissa M. D'Souza</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Canted antiferromagnetism in polar ${\mathrm{MnSiN}}_{2}$ with high Néel temperature]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.104406</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.104406"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Linus Kautzsch, Alexandru B. Georgescu, Danilo Puggioni, Greggory Kent, Keith M. Taddei, Aiden Reilly, Ram Seshadri, James M. Rondinelli, and Stephen D. Wilson
Ternary nitrides are a burgeoning materials class hosting diverse structures, compositions, and properties that make them appealing for various applications. Magnetic nitrogen-rich compounds generally remain underexplored, despite the unique chemical bonding afforded by the N3− ion with open d-shell transition metals. Here, the authors explore the compound MnSiN2 where Mn2+ ions reside on a 3D diamond-like covalent network with strong magnetic superexchange pathways. The compound exhibits a high Néel ordering temperature of TN = 443 K and the precise canted ground state magnetic structure is resolved using a combination of DFT modeling and powder neutron diffraction.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 104406] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Linus Kautzsch, Alexandru B. Georgescu, Danilo Puggioni, Greggory Kent, Keith M. Taddei, Aiden Reilly, Ram Seshadri, James M. Rondinelli, and Stephen D. Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Gluon Showers inside a Quark-Gluon Plasma Strongly Coupled? A Theorist’s Test]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.162302</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.162302"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Peter Arnold, Omar Elgedawy, and Shahin Iqbal
A theoretical study demonstrates that in-medium showers of high-energy gluons can be approximately treated as a sequence of individual splitting processes.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 162302] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Arnold, Omar Elgedawy, and Shahin Iqbal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Universal Lower Bound on Topological Entanglement Entropy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.166601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.166601"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Isaac H. Kim, Michael Levin, Ting-Chun Lin, Daniel Ranard, and Bowen Shi
A lower bound to the topological entanglement entropy partially restores its universality.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 166601] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Isaac H. Kim, Michael Levin, Ting-Chun Lin, Daniel Ranard, and Bowen Shi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Droplets sliding on single and multiple vertical fibers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.103601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.103601"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Leonard, J. Van Hulle, F. Weyer, D. Terwagne, and N. Vandewalle
Exploring droplet dynamics: This study sheds light on the behavior of droplets sliding down vertical fibers, a key issue in microfluidics and fog harvesting. Using real-time tracking, the research covers single and multi-fiber systems. A standout finding is that multiple vertical fibers increase droplet speed but also lead to greater liquid loss in grooves. This discovery is captured in a detailed theoretical model, offering valuable insights for optimizing droplet-based technologies.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 103601] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Leonard, J. Van Hulle, F. Weyer, D. Terwagne, and N. Vandewalle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Landau-Pomeranchuk-Migdal effect in sequential bremsstrahlung: Gluon shower development]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.074015</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.074015"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Peter Arnold, Omar Elgedawy, and Shahin Iqbal
A theoretical study demonstrates that in-medium showers of high-energy gluons can be approximately treated as a sequence of individual splitting processes.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 074015] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Arnold, Omar Elgedawy, and Shahin Iqbal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Inclusive hadronic decay rate of the $τ$ lepton from lattice QCD]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.074513</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.074513"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Evangelista, R. Frezzotti, N. Tantalo, G. Gagliardi, F. Sanfilippo, S. Simula, and V. Lubicz (Extended Twisted Mass Collaboration)
The authors express the inclusive hadronic decay rate of the tau lepton as an integral over the spectral density of the two-point correlator of the weak V−A hadronic current which they compute fully nonperturbatively in lattice QCD. In a lattice QCD computation with all systematic errors except for isospin breaking effects under control, they then obtain the CKM matrix element Vud with subpercent errors showing that their nonperturbative method can become a viable alternative to superallowed nuclear beta decays for obtaining Vud.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 074513] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Evangelista, R. Frezzotti, N. Tantalo, G. Gagliardi, F. Sanfilippo, S. Simula, and V. Lubicz (Extended Twisted Mass Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Characterizing cosmic birefringence in the presence of Galactic foregrounds and instrumental systematic effects]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.082005</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.082005"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Baptiste Jost, Josquin Errard, and Radek Stompor
The authors propose a new analysis framework to account simultaneously for Galactic foregrounds and instrumental effects, in order to break the degeneracy between Cosmic Birefringence (CB) angle and Cosmic Microwave Background detector effects. They thus pave the way for Simons Observatory-like Small Aperture Telescopes to test claims for CB detection.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 082005] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Baptiste Jost, Josquin Errard, and Radek Stompor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly Heisenberg-limited noise-unbiased frequency estimation by tailored sensor design]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042419</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042419"/>
        <updated>2023-10-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Francisco Riberi, Gerardo A. Paz-Silva, and Lorenza Viola
The authors consider frequency estimation in the presence of spatiotemporally correlated noise. They show that the usual approach involving unbiased estimators is ill-suited in such cases, and introduce new estimators which, at the cost of doubling the required resources, are insensitive to noise and retain the precision scaling of standard ones.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 042419] Published Thu Oct 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Francisco Riberi, Gerardo A. Paz-Silva, and Lorenza Viola</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of Anisotropic Superfluid Density in an Artificial Crystal]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.163401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.163401"/>
        <updated>2023-10-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Tao, M. Zhao, and I. B. Spielman
Trapping a Bose-Einstein condensate (BEC) in an optical lattice, researchers confirm a 53-year-old theory that connects BECs to superfluids and supersolids.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 163401] Published Wed Oct 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Tao, M. Zhao, and I. B. Spielman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Controlled Excitation of Rotons in Superfluid Helium with an Optical Centrifuge]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.166001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.166001"/>
        <updated>2023-10-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alexander A. Milner and Valery Milner
A laser pulse with rotating linear polarization creates roton pairs in superfluid helium.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 166001] Published Wed Oct 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexander A. Milner and Valery Milner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phase ordering dynamics of the random-field long-range Ising model in one dimension]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.044131</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.044131"/>
        <updated>2023-10-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ramgopal Agrawal, Federico Corberi, Eugenio Lippiello, and Sanjay Puri
There has been progress in understanding the phase-ordering dynamics of systems with long-range interactions, but less is known for such systems with disorder. This work addresses that topic by studying the influence of long-range interactions on the phase ordering dynamics of the one-dimensional random-field Ising model.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 044131] Published Wed Oct 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ramgopal Agrawal, Federico Corberi, Eugenio Lippiello, and Sanjay Puri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum spin liquids on the diamond lattice]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134424</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134424"/>
        <updated>2023-10-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Aishwarya Chauhan, Atanu Maity, Chunxiao Liu, Jonas Sonnenschein, Francesco Ferrari, and Yasir Iqbal
The diamond lattice has been a promising playground for both classical and quantum spin liquids. Here, the authors conduct a comprehensive symmetry classification of S=½ quantum spin liquids with SU(2), U(1), and ℤ2 gauge fields, and present dynamical spin structure factors within a self-consistent simulation. The authors highlight three discoveries: spinon Ansätze with robust gapless nodal loops, topological bands realizing topological insulators, and that Gutzwiller projection of the 0- and π-flux SU(2) spin liquids generates long-range Néel order.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 134424] Published Wed Oct 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aishwarya Chauhan, Atanu Maity, Chunxiao Liu, Jonas Sonnenschein, Francesco Ferrari, and Yasir Iqbal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electrical detectability of magnon-mediated spin current shot noise]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144420</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144420"/>
        <updated>2023-10-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Luise Siegl, Michaela Lammel, Akashdeep Kamra, Hans Huebl, Wolfgang Belzig, and Sebastian T. B. Goennenwein
The spin of so-called squeezed magnons has been shown to deviate from the common value ħ, with corresponding changes in the spin-current shot noise. The authors calculate here the magnitude of the concomitant voltage noise in the charge channel for a typical electrically detected spin pumping signal and find that it is significantly smaller than the inevitable Johnson-Nyquist noise. Their analysis thus provides important guidance for the challenges in experimentally detecting squeezed magnons through electrical noise measurements.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 144420] Published Wed Oct 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luise Siegl, Michaela Lammel, Akashdeep Kamra, Hans Huebl, Wolfgang Belzig, and Sebastian T. B. Goennenwein</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rotor/spin-wave theory for quantum spin models with U(1) symmetry]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155130</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155130"/>
        <updated>2023-10-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tommaso Roscilde, Tommaso Comparin, and Fabio Mezzacapo
Elementary excitations of ordered quantum magnets are harmonic spin waves. Yet, when ordering breaks a continuous symmetry, excitations at zero momentum cannot really be treated as harmonic, because they correspond to the Goldstone mode that restores the symmetry in finite-size systems. Here, the authors show that zero-momentum excitations can be treated in a fully nonlinear way in terms of a macroscopic spin variable (the rotor): its spectrum reconstructs the so-called Anderson tower of states, a hallmark of continuous-symmetry breaking systems. The rotor variable can be considered as nearly separate from finite-momentum spin waves, leading to a quantitative reconstruction of the low-energy excitation spectrum of finite-size systems.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 155130] Published Wed Oct 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tommaso Roscilde, Tommaso Comparin, and Fabio Mezzacapo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transition from classical to quantum loss of light coherence]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042214</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.042214"/>
        <updated>2023-10-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pierre Lassègues, Mateus Antônio Fernandes Biscassi, Martial Morisse, André Cidrim, Pablo Gabriel Santos Dias, Hodei Eneriz, Raul Celistrino Teixeira, Robin Kaiser, Romain Bachelard, and Mathilde Hugbart
The authors study the loss of light coherence when scattered by a macroscopic atomic cloud of cold neutral atoms through intensity-intensity correlation measurements. They demonstrate experimentally and theoretically the transition between classical and quantum mechanisms regimes for the coherence loss.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 042214] Published Wed Oct 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pierre Lassègues, Mateus Antônio Fernandes Biscassi, Martial Morisse, André Cidrim, Pablo Gabriel Santos Dias, Hodei Eneriz, Raul Celistrino Teixeira, Robin Kaiser, Romain Bachelard, and Mathilde Hugbart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of the Positive Muon Anomalous Magnetic Moment to 0.20 ppm]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.161802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.161802"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): D. P. Aguillard et al. (The Muon g−2 Collaboration)
The magnetic moment of the muon, a key probe of the standard model and its possible extensions, has been measured to a precision of 200 parts per billion, 2.3 times more precise than their first landmark result.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 161802] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>D. P. Aguillard &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (The Muon &lt;math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline"&gt;&lt;mi&gt;g&lt;/mi&gt;&lt;mo&gt;−&lt;/mo&gt;&lt;mn&gt;2&lt;/mn&gt;&lt;/math&gt; Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Femtosecond Reduction of Atomic Scattering Factors Triggered by Intense X-Ray Pulse]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.163201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.163201"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ichiro Inoue, Jumpei Yamada, Konrad J. Kapcia, Michal Stransky, Victor Tkachenko, Zoltan Jurek, Takato Inoue, Taito Osaka, Yuichi Inubushi, Atsuki Ito, Yuto Tanaka, Satoshi Matsuyama, Kazuto Yamauchi, Makina Yabashi, and Beata Ziaja
Measurements indicate that intense x-ray pulses can change the electronic structure of a material on femtosecond timescales, a finding that could improve imaging of light–matter interactions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 163201] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ichiro Inoue, Jumpei Yamada, Konrad J. Kapcia, Michal Stransky, Victor Tkachenko, Zoltan Jurek, Takato Inoue, Taito Osaka, Yuichi Inubushi, Atsuki Ito, Yuto Tanaka, Satoshi Matsuyama, Kazuto Yamauchi, Makina Yabashi, and Beata Ziaja</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Room-Temperature Magnetic Phase Transition in an Electrically Tuned van der Waals Ferromagnet]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.166703</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.166703"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Cheng Tan, Ji-Hai Liao, Guolin Zheng, Meri Algarni, Jia-Yi Lin, Xiang Ma, Edwin L. H. Mayes, Matthew R. Field, Sultan Albarakati, Majid Panahandeh-Fard, Saleh Alzahrani, Guopeng Wang, Yuanjun Yang, Dimitrie Culcer, James Partridge, Mingliang Tian, Bin Xiang, Yu-Jun Zhao, and Lan Wang
A ferromagnetism to antiferromagnetism phase transition in a van der Waals magnet at room temperature uses CrTe nanoflakes that may lead to improved spintronic devices.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 166703] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cheng Tan, Ji-Hai Liao, Guolin Zheng, Meri Algarni, Jia-Yi Lin, Xiang Ma, Edwin L. H. Mayes, Matthew R. Field, Sultan Albarakati, Majid Panahandeh-Fard, Saleh Alzahrani, Guopeng Wang, Yuanjun Yang, Dimitrie Culcer, James Partridge, Mingliang Tian, Bin Xiang, Yu-Jun Zhao, and Lan Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microscopic details of two-dimensional spectroscopy of one-dimensional quantum Ising magnets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134423</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.134423"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): GiBaik Sim, Frank Pollmann, and Johannes Knolle
This work explores the effectiveness of two-dimensional coherent spectroscopy for understanding the microscopic properties of quantum magnets. Motivated by experiments on the Ising chain magnet CoNb2O6, it is shown that the 2D spectra are markedly different for the two proposed microscopic Hamiltonians - the transverse field Ising model and the twisted Kitaev spin chain - even though the linear response is similar. The findings showcase the power of 2D spectroscopy for quantifying microscopic descriptions and understanding the dynamics of fractionalized excitations of quantum magnets.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 134423] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GiBaik Sim, Frank Pollmann, and Johannes Knolle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic paramagnon-polarons in altermagnets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144418</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.144418"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Charles R. W. Steward, Rafael M. Fernandes, and Jörg Schmalian
Altermagnetic states are qualitatively different from ferromagnetic and antiferromagnetic ones, as they are invariant under a combination of rotation and time reversal. The unique properties afforded by such symmetries have attracted significant attention by the community. Here, the authors unearth an unusual dynamic coupling that exists between the altermagnetic and lattice degrees of freedom, which resembles the Hall viscosity. This effect results in a hybridization between altermagnetic and phonon modes, enabling one to directly probe altermagnetic excitations in the phonon spectrum.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 144418] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charles R. W. Steward, Rafael M. Fernandes, and Jörg Schmalian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamical nuclear spin polarization in a quantum dot with an electron spin driven by electric dipole spin resonance]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155306</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155306"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Peter Stano, Takashi Nakajima, Akito Noiri, Seigo Tarucha, and Daniel Loss
When a quantum-dot electron spin is electrically driven to perform coherent Rabi oscillations, it can polarize nuclear spins through a resonance analogous to the Hartmann-Hahn effect known from NMR. Here, the authors theoretically analyze such a polarization rate in a generic setup including GaAs, Si, and Ge, and both electron and hole spin qubits. They present measurements in n-GaAs and estimate that the effect is also observable in Si. It might offer control over the Overhauser nuclear field in gated quantum dots.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 155306] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Stano, Takashi Nakajima, Akito Noiri, Seigo Tarucha, and Daniel Loss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Singular topology of scattering matrices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155418</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.155418"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Cheng Guo, Jiazheng Li, Meng Xiao, and Shanhui Fan
The scattering matrix is a crucial characterization of a physical system. The authors present here a systematic topological theory of scattering matrices, focusing on their singular values and vectors. They identify topological characteristics such as winding number, Berry phase, and skew polarization. The theory uncovers the topological nature of coherent perfect absorption and introduces coherent perfect extinction, where a coherent wave is completely extinguished through interference. These findings advance the understanding of scattering and have implications for novel wave devices.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 155418] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Cheng Guo, Jiazheng Li, Meng Xiao, and Shanhui Fan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disordered monitored free fermions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165126</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.165126"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marcin Szyniszewski, Oliver Lunt, and Arijeet Pal
The authors investigate here the dynamics of free fermions in a random potential system under continuous monitoring. Repeated measurements are known to induce an entanglement phase transition from a logarithmically entangled critical state to area law, while disorder leads to Anderson localization. They show that their interplay results in a stable critical phase at finite disorder strength and dissipation, which drive a transition consistent with Berezinskii-Kosterlitz-Thouless universality. This work is important for testing such phase transitions in quantum dot arrays and nanowires.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 165126] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marcin Szyniszewski, Oliver Lunt, and Arijeet Pal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Possible ${s}_{±}$-wave superconductivity in ${\mathrm{La}}_{3}{\mathrm{Ni}}_{2}{\mathrm{O}}_{7}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L140505</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L140505"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Qing-Geng Yang, Da Wang, and Qiang-Hua Wang
For the new high-temperature superconductor La3Ni2O7 under high pressure, the authors analyze its pairing mechanism and pairing symmetry in a bilayer two-orbital Hubbard model. By combining functional renormalization group in weak-to-moderate interaction regime and Gutzwiller approximation for its low-energy effective model projected to atomic one- and two-electron states in the strong-coupling regime, they find robust extended s-wave or s±-wave pairing as triggered by spin fluctuations.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L140505] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Qing-Geng Yang, Da Wang, and Qiang-Hua Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Additive laser excitation of giant nonlinear surface acoustic wave pulses]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044044</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.044044"/>
        <updated>2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jude Deschamps, Yun Kai, Jet Lem, Ievgeniia Chaban, Alexey Lomonosov, Abdelmadjid Anane, Steven E. Kooi, Keith A. Nelson, and Thomas Pezeril
Pulsed lasers are routinely used to optically excite and detect ultrasounds in a broad frequency range, from megahertz to terahertz. Though well-established for decades, this technique of laser ultrasonics is constrained by the potential optical damage it may cause to the sample, resulting in the generation of relatively weak pressures, well below kilobars. This study introduces a methodology for the excitation of nondestructive shock waves, at a high repetition rate, limited only by the mechanical strength of the sample. This work establishes a way to repeatedly deliver high-amplitude strain pulses to samples of interest, facilitating the dynamical study of strain-induced phenomena.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 044044] Published Tue Oct 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jude Deschamps, Yun Kai, Jet Lem, Ievgeniia Chaban, Alexey Lomonosov, Abdelmadjid Anane, Steven E. Kooi, Keith A. Nelson, and Thomas Pezeril</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lyapunov spectra of chaotic recurrent neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043044</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.043044"/>
        <updated>2023-10-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rainer Engelken, Fred Wolf, and L. F. Abbott
The Lyapunov spectrum of recurrent neural networks is calculated and analytical approximations through random matrix theory are provided. The dependency of attractor dimensions and entropy rates on coupling strength and input fluctuations is identified and a point symmetry of the Lyapunov spectrum is revealed. A link is shown between Lyapunov exponents to error propagation and stability in trained recurrent networks for machine-learning applications.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 043044] Published Mon Oct 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rainer Engelken, Fred Wolf, and L. F. Abbott</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search for Light Dark Matter with NA64 at CERN]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.161801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.161801"/>
        <updated>2023-10-16T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yu. M. Andreev et al. (NA64 Collaboration)
An experiment at CERN performed by scattering 100 GeV electrons off a fixed target results in limits on thermal dark matter—that requires interactions mediated by hypothetical dark photons—in the MeV mass range.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 161801] Published Mon Oct 16, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yu. M. Andreev &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (NA64 Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>