<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2023-08-10T00:53:38.568Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2023-08-10T00:53:38.568Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.15.1</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Cross an Energy Barrier at Zero Kelvin without Tunneling Effect]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.066701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.066701"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Seiji Miyashita and Bernard Barbara
Irradiating a uniaxial magnetic system with a specific sequence of microwave pulses can induce in the system quantum oscillations that cause the material’s spins to flip back and forth.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 066701] Published Wed Aug 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Seiji Miyashita and Bernard Barbara</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Instability of Magnetic Skyrmion Strings Induced by Longitudinal Spin Currents]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.066702</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.066702"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Shun Okumura, Volodymyr P. Kravchuk, and Markus Garst
A simple mechanism to topologically unwind magnetic textures uses currents flowing perpendicular to the skyrmion plane to trigger a Goldstone spin-wave instability that eventually destroys skyrmions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 066702] Published Wed Aug 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Shun Okumura, Volodymyr P. Kravchuk, and Markus Garst</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Von Kármán vortex street past a permeable circular cylinder: Two-dimensional flow and dynamic-mode-decomposition-based secondary stability analysis]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.083901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.083901"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): F. Caruso Lombardi, A. Bongarzone, G. A. Zampogna, F. Gallaire, S. Camarri, and P. G. Ledda
We explore the role of permeability in modifying the vortex shedding past a permeable circular cylinder. The two-dimensional (2D) von Kármán vortex street sets at progressively larger distances from the body and is eventually suppressed, as permeability increases. Using Dynamic Mode Decomposition we perform a linear stability analysis with respect to three-dimensional perturbations of the 2D periodic vortex shedding. We identify a range of permeability in which the shedding remains 2D, at least for the values of Reynolds number considered here; for larger values of permeability, the wake remains steady and 2D.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 083901] Published Wed Aug 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>F. Caruso Lombardi, A. Bongarzone, G. A. Zampogna, F. Gallaire, S. Camarri, and P. G. Ledda</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Refined spin-wave model and multimagnon bound states in ${\mathrm{Li}}_{2}{\mathrm{CuO}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.064408</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.064408"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Eli Zoghlin, Matthew B. Stone, and Stephen D. Wilson
Quasi-one-dimensional materials serve as both testbeds for tractable magnetic models and as a perennial source of intriguing physics. An excellent example is the emergence of multimagnon bound states in ferromagnetic (FM) spin chains, which provide a platform for probing a few-body quantum phenomenon. Despite being studied for many years, the exchange anisotropy-driven bound state of a FM chain has yet to be observed by inelastic neutron scattering (INS). As INS provides a unique window into the nature of magnon-magnon interactions, this represents a substantive gap in the literature. Here, the authors rectify this gap by presenting detailed INS data on the S=½ spin chain Li2CuO2. Their data allows for determination of a refined spin Hamiltonian which fully describes the one-magnon dispersion. With these details in hand, they demonstrate the existence of two-magnon and, potentially, three-magnon bound states in Li2CuO2, with the potential three-magnon bound state showing anomalous behavior.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 064408] Published Wed Aug 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eli Zoghlin, Matthew B. Stone, and Stephen D. Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hybrid higher-order skin-topological effect in hyperbolic lattices]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.075122</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.075122"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Junsong Sun, Chang-An Li, Shiping Feng, and Huaiming Guo
The hyperbolic lattice, existing in a space of constant negative curvature, displays unique physical properties compared to its Euclidean counterpart, and has garnered significant attention recently. Here, the authors have proposed the existence of a higher-order skin-topological effect in hyperbolic lattices. This result first introduces a non-Hermitian effect into hyperbolic lattices, which extends the regime of topological phases with hyperbolic geometry.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 075122] Published Wed Aug 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Junsong Sun, Chang-An Li, Shiping Feng, and Huaiming Guo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Low-dissipation data bus via coherent quantum dynamics]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.075405</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.075405"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Dylan Lewis, João P. Moutinho, Antonio T. Costa, Yasser Omar, and Sougato Bose
The transport of information is an essential component of both classical and quantum computers. Coherent quantum dynamics offers the potential for the transfer of information through a linear array of quantum dots almost without dissipation. Here, the authors describe a protocol and calculate the energetic cost of transferring quantum states as a quantum or classical data bus, showing its advantage over the shuttling of electrons and classical data buses.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 075405] Published Wed Aug 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dylan Lewis, João P. Moutinho, Antonio T. Costa, Yasser Omar, and Sougato Bose</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electronic nematic order in the normal state of strontium ruthenate]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L081105</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L081105"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ryan S. Russell, Hari P. Nair, Kyle M. Shen, Darrell G. Schlom, and John W. Harter
The nature of unconventional superconductivity in Sr2RuO4 remains stubbornly unresolved, and it is clear that a fundamental piece of the puzzle is still missing. Here, the authors use static and ultrafast optical dichroism measurements to uncover signatures of electronic nematic order in high quality epitaxially strained thin films of Sr2RuO4. Through the development of a simple Ising model of the nematic order, the authors show that optical pumping induces a coherent oscillation of its amplitude mode. Whether and how this nematic order ultimately influences the superconductivity in Sr2RuO4 remains a key open question.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L081105] Published Wed Aug 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ryan S. Russell, Hari P. Nair, Kyle M. Shen, Darrell G. Schlom, and John W. Harter</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reducing Rydberg-state dc polarizability by microwave dressing]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.022805</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevA.108.022805"/>
        <updated>2023-08-09T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. C. Bohorquez, R. Chinnarasu, J. Isaacs, D. Booth, M. Beck, R. McDermott, and M. Saffman
The authors demonstrate a reduction of the dc polarizability of cesium atom Rydberg states in a 77-K environment utilizing microwave field dressing. The results could be useful for stabilizing Rydberg resonances against varying dc fields present near surfaces and potentially enabling the development of hybrid Rydberg-atom–superconducting-resonator quantum gates.

[Phys. Rev. A 108, 022805] Published Wed Aug 09, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. C. Bohorquez, R. Chinnarasu, J. Isaacs, D. Booth, M. Beck, R. McDermott, and M. Saffman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Photon emission statistics of a driven microwave cavity]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033091</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033091"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pedro Portugal, Fredrik Brange, Kalle S. U. Kansanen, Peter Samuelsson, and Christian Flindt
A theory that can predict the photon-emission statistics from driven microwave cavities is developed. Specifically, it’s shown how the photon-emission statistics is fully determined by a Riccati equation.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 033091] Published Tue Aug 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pedro Portugal, Fredrik Brange, Kalle S. U. Kansanen, Peter Samuelsson, and Christian Flindt</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[All-Order Coulomb Corrections to Delbrück Scattering above the Pair-Production Threshold]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.061601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.061601"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Sommerfeldt, V. A. Yerokhin, Th. Stöhlker, and A. Surzhykov
Improved calculations of a quantum phenomenon called Delbrück scattering resolve a long-standing discrepancy between theory and experiment.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 061601] Published Tue Aug 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Sommerfeldt, V. A. Yerokhin, Th. Stöhlker, and A. Surzhykov</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[High-accuracy variational Monte Carlo for frustrated magnets with deep neural networks]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.054410</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.054410"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christopher Roth, Attila Szabó, and Allan H. MacDonald
Establishing quantum spin liquid physics in microscopic models is a daunting task due to a variety of competing low-energy states, requiring sophisticated computational approaches to find the true ground state. Here, the authors present such a technique, based on neural networks with space-group symmetry, to obtain significantly improved ground-state wave functions of frustrated Heisenberg models. The authors also use this approach to find excited states and provide a blueprint for testing analytical predictions from spin-liquid theories.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 054410] Published Tue Aug 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher Roth, Attila Szabó, and Allan H. MacDonald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phase transitions and bunching of correlated particles in a non-Hermitian quasicrystal]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.075121</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.075121"/>
        <updated>2023-08-08T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Stefano Longhi
Strongly correlated systems in non-Hermitian models are an emergent area of research. Here, the author considers the correlated hopping dynamics of two fermions in a quasicrystal with a complex phase, unraveling non-Hermitian-induced mobility edges and the tendency of the fermions to stick together, forming a doublon state in the long time limit of evolution, a phenomenon that can be dubbed non-Hermitian particle bunching.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 075121] Published Tue Aug 08, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stefano Longhi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast Neutrino Flavor Conversions Can Help and Hinder Neutrino-Driven Explosions]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.061401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.061401"/>
        <updated>2023-08-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jakob Ehring, Sajad Abbar, Hans-Thomas Janka, Georg Raffelt, and Irene Tamborra
We present the first simulations of core-collapse supernovae in axial symmetry with feedback from fast neutrino flavor conversion (FFC). Our schematic treatment of FFCs assumes instantaneous flavor equilibration under the constraint of lepton-number conservation individually for each flavor. Systema…
[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 061401] Published Mon Aug 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jakob Ehring, Sajad Abbar, Hans-Thomas Janka, Georg Raffelt, and Irene Tamborra</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Search for Higgs Boson Decay to a Charm Quark-Antiquark Pair in Proton-Proton Collisions at $\sqrt{s}=13\text{ }\text{ }\mathrm{TeV}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.061801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.061801"/>
        <updated>2023-08-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Tumasyan et al. (CMS Collaboration)
Decays of Z bosons to charm quark-antiquark pairs have been observed for the first time at a hadron collider, as part of a search for decays of Higgs bosons to charm quark-antiquark pairs, which are bounded at 14 times the standard model value.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 061801] Published Mon Aug 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Tumasyan &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (CMS Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anti-Parity-Time Symmetry in a Su-Schrieffer-Heeger Sonic Lattice]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.066601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.066601"/>
        <updated>2023-08-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bolun Hu, Zhiwang Zhang, Zichong Yue, Danwei Liao, Yimin Liu, Haixiao Zhang, Ying Cheng, Xiaojun Liu, and Johan Christensen
A novel acoustic Su-Schrieffer-Heeger chain with non-Hermitian components displays a non-Hermitian phase transition and reveals new acoustic topological interface states with tunable robust confinement.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 066601] Published Mon Aug 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bolun Hu, Zhiwang Zhang, Zichong Yue, Danwei Liao, Yimin Liu, Haixiao Zhang, Ying Cheng, Xiaojun Liu, and Johan Christensen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Physical Constraints in Intracellular Signaling: The Cost of Sending a Bit]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.068401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.068401"/>
        <updated>2023-08-07T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Samuel J. Bryant and Benjamin B. Machta
Calculations of the minimum energy a cell requires to transmit a signal between two internal components could help scientists understand how energy and information combine to produce living systems.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 068401] Published Mon Aug 07, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel J. Bryant and Benjamin B. Machta</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bichromatic Imaging of Single Molecules in an Optical Tweezer Array]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.053202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.053202"/>
        <updated>2023-08-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Connor M. Holland, Yukai Lu, and Lawrence W. Cheuk
The proposed bichromatic imaging scheme could lead to high-fidelity detection of single CaF molecules trapped in an optical tweezer array.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 053202] Published Fri Aug 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Connor M. Holland, Yukai Lu, and Lawrence W. Cheuk</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonaffine Mechanics of Entangled Networks Inspired by Intermediate Filaments]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.058101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.058101"/>
        <updated>2023-08-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Marco Pensalfini, Tom Golde, Xavier Trepat, and Marino Arroyo
Simulations show that the topology of biopolymer “tangles” controls how biological cells resist deformation.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 058101] Published Fri Aug 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Marco Pensalfini, Tom Golde, Xavier Trepat, and Marino Arroyo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[On-Demand Breaking of Action-Reaction Reciprocity between Magnetic Microdisks Using Global Stimuli]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.058301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.058301"/>
        <updated>2023-08-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Gaurav Gardi and Metin Sitti
A model system of floating disks can be tuned to execute a variety of behaviors by controlling the interactions between the disks.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 058301] Published Fri Aug 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gaurav Gardi and Metin Sitti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ferroelectric tuning of superconductivity and band topology in a two-dimensional heterobilayer]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L060501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L060501"/>
        <updated>2023-08-04T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jianyong Chen, Wei Qin, Ping Cui, and Zhenyu Zhang
Ferroelectricity, superconductivity, and topology are three cornerstone concepts of condensed matter physics, and integration of any two may further fertilize exotic emergent phenomena. To date, harmonic coexistence of all three remains to be materialized. Here, the authors predict simultaneous tuning of superconducting transition temperature and band topology by ferroelectricity, with a heterobilayer of superconducting IrTe2 and ferroelectric In2Se3 as a physically realistic example. Such reversible and nonvolatile tunabilities may find important applications in novel superconducting devices and topological quantum computation.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L060501] Published Fri Aug 04, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jianyong Chen, Wei Qin, Ping Cui, and Zhenyu Zhang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple extension of the plane-wave final state in photoemission: Bringing understanding to the photon-energy dependence of two-dimensional materials]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033075</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033075"/>
        <updated>2023-08-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christian S. Kern, Anja Haags, Larissa Egger, Xiaosheng Yang, Hans Kirschner, Susanne Wolff, Thomas Seyller, Alexander Gottwald, Mathias Richter, Umberto De Giovannini, Angel Rubio, Michael G. Ramsey, François C. Bocquet, Serguei Soubatch, F. Stefan Tautz, Peter Puschnig, and Simon Moser
The photoemission cross section of graphene is measured for two light polarizations and a wide range of photon energies at a flux-calibrated synchrotron light source. Modeling scattering effects by a simplistic model and sophisticated time-dependent density-functional-theory calculations, the complex phase shifts in the photoemission final state are extracted from the experiment to obtain complete information about the photoemission process.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 033075] Published Thu Aug 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christian S. Kern, Anja Haags, Larissa Egger, Xiaosheng Yang, Hans Kirschner, Susanne Wolff, Thomas Seyller, Alexander Gottwald, Mathias Richter, Umberto De Giovannini, Angel Rubio, Michael G. Ramsey, François C. Bocquet, Serguei Soubatch, F. Stefan Tautz, Peter Puschnig, and Simon Moser</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discovery of Gamma Rays from the Quiescent Sun with HAWC]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.051201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.051201"/>
        <updated>2023-08-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. Albert et al. (HAWC Collaboration)
Measurements of the highest-energy radiation from the Sun ever seen highlight the need for better solar models.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 051201] Published Thu Aug 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. Albert &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (HAWC Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Composition Dependent Instabilities in Mixtures with Many Components]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.058401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.058401"/>
        <updated>2023-08-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Filipe C. Thewes, Matthias Krüger, and Peter Sollich
A new form of demixing instability may explain the strong dependence of phase separation in biological mixtures on their composition.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 058401] Published Thu Aug 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Filipe C. Thewes, Matthias Krüger, and Peter Sollich</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of the $J$/$ψ$ photoproduction cross section over the full near-threshold kinematic region]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.025201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.025201"/>
        <updated>2023-08-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Adhikari et al. (GlueX Collaboration)
New results from the GlueX experiment provide improved cross sections for the photoproduction from the proton of J/ψ mesons via the γ+p→J/ψ+p reaction. Such mesons have charm/anti-charm heavy-quark content. Measurements of this reaction near the kinematic threshold can help constrain aspects of the density distribution of gluons in the proton and how they contribute to the proton mass, under the assumption that J/ψ production proceeds primarily through the exchange of gluons with the proton. However, these new measurements suggest contributions in addition to gluon exchange, pointing to the need for further theoretical work and more precise experimental measurements.

[Phys. Rev. C 108, 025201] Published Thu Aug 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Adhikari &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;span class="sc"&gt;GlueX&lt;/span&gt; Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetic inhomogeneities in the quadruple perovskite manganite $[{\mathrm{Y}}_{2−x}{\mathrm{Mn}}_{x}]{\mathrm{Mn}}_{6}{\mathrm{O}}_{12}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.054403</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.054403"/>
        <updated>2023-08-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): A. M. Vibhakar, D. D. Khalyavin, P. Manuel, N. J. Steinke, L. Zhang, K. Yamaura, A. A. Belik, and R. D. Johnson
The authors show here that the introduction of substitutional disorder in the presence of competing exchange interactions causes the [Y2−xMnx]Mn6O12 quadruple perovskite manganites to develop short-range antiferromagnetic clusters contained in a paramagnetic matrix, before transitioning to a phase characterized by well correlated long-range ferrimagnetic order that coexists with the short-range antiferromagnetic clusters. It is spin doping through the substitution of magnetic Mn ions for nonmagnetic Y ions that gives rise to a spin texture that is inhomogeneous on the nanoscale.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 054403] Published Thu Aug 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A. M. Vibhakar, D. D. Khalyavin, P. Manuel, N. J. Steinke, L. Zhang, K. Yamaura, A. A. Belik, and R. D. Johnson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum oscillations in a doped Mott insulator beyond Onsager's relation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.085106</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.085106"/>
        <updated>2023-08-03T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Valentin Leeb and Johannes Knolle
The Fermi surface — the manifold of gapless excitations forming due to Pauli’s famous exclusion principle— determines all electronic properties of metals. In 1952 Lars Onsager discovered how to measure a Fermi surface by studying the response of a metallic material as a function of an applied magnetic field. In fact, observables like electrical resistivity or the magnetization oscillate as a function of inverse field. Onsager’s relation forms the basis for our understanding of electronic properties of metals and is used in many experimental labs around the world. Here, the authors find that, in the presence of strong interactions between electrons, Onsager’s relation can be violated and they provide the first rigorous calculations of this effect. In general, solving for the emergent Landau levels of a strongly interacting material in a magnetic field is a hard problem. The methodological progress made here is enabled by concentrating on an exactly soluble model with infinite-range interactions. This research establishes the importance of inter Landau level interactions for understanding correlated materials in magnetic fields.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 085106] Published Thu Aug 03, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Valentin Leeb and Johannes Knolle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Test of Lepton Universality in $b→s{ℓ}^{+}{ℓ}^{−}$ Decays]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.051803</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.051803"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Aaij et al. (LHCb Collaboration)
New data from observations of B-meson decay again vindicate the standard model of particle physics.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 051803] Published Wed Aug 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Aaij &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHCb Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Test of Light-Lepton Universality in the Rates of Inclusive Semileptonic $B$-Meson Decays at Belle II]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.051804</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.051804"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): L. Aggarwal et al. (Belle II Collaboration)
New data from observations of B-meson decay again vindicate the standard model of particle physics.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 051804] Published Wed Aug 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L. Aggarwal &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (Belle II Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Super Interferometric Range Resolution]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.053803</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.053803"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): John C. Howell, Andrew N. Jordan, Barbara Šoda, and Achim Kempf
A low-frequency radar method with improved resolution could aid in the detection of landmines and archeological objects.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 053803] Published Wed Aug 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John C. Howell, Andrew N. Jordan, Barbara Šoda, and Achim Kempf</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dispersion induced by unsteady diffusion-driven flow in a parallel-plate channel]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.084501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.084501"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lingyun Ding and Richard M. McLaughlin
We study the unsteady diffusion-induced flow in an inclined channel domain, and mixing of a diffusing passive scalar advected by such flows. Diffusion-driven flow is a boundary layer flow due to the combination of gravity and diffusion, existing in density-stratified fluids when gravity is not parallel to the solid boundary. We find that the flow can be either highly oscillatory in space and time, or monotonic depending on the physical parameters. On transient timescales there are situations in which the effective mixing is reduced below the bare molecular diffusivity. Such flows are relevant for applications including solute evolution in rock fissures and also in microfluidics.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 084501] Published Wed Aug 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lingyun Ding and Richard M. McLaughlin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamic hysteresis at a noisy saddle node shows power-law scaling but nonuniversal exponent]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.024101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.024101"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Satyaki Kundu, Ranjan Kumar Patel, Srimanta Middey, and Bhavtosh Bansal
Dynamic hysteresis is a delay in the response of a bistable system because it cannot keep up with the rate of change of a driving field. The authors study this phenomenon experimentally for a metal-insulator transition in a thin film, and show theoretically that the system exhibits power-law scaling with a nonuniversal exponent.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 024101] Published Wed Aug 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Satyaki Kundu, Ranjan Kumar Patel, Srimanta Middey, and Bhavtosh Bansal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measurement of lepton universality parameters in ${B}^{+}→{K}^{+}{ℓ}^{+}{ℓ}^{−}$ and ${B}^{0}→{K}^{*0}{ℓ}^{+}{ℓ}^{−}$ decays]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.032002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.032002"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Aaij et al. (LHCb Collaboration)
New data from observations of B-meson decay again vindicate the standard model of particle physics.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 032002] Published Wed Aug 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Aaij &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHCb Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Braiding fractional quantum Hall quasiholes on a superconducting quantum processor]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.064303</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.064303"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ammar Kirmani, Derek S. Wang, Pouyan Ghaemi, and Armin Rahmani
Using a noisy quantum computer, the authors emulate direct braiding in a fractional quantum Hall system via a simplified model for a thin cylinder. The quantum algorithm prepares a ground state with two quasiholes, performs a unitary operation controlled by an ancilla to move one quasihole around the other, and measures the ancilla with error mitigation to extract the wave function’s acquired phase. This approach offers a method for studying braiding statistics in fractional Hall states in digitized devices.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 064303] Published Wed Aug 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ammar Kirmani, Derek S. Wang, Pouyan Ghaemi, and Armin Rahmani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Competing role of the $p$ and $d$ orbitals in the orbital angular momentum induced spin splitting of surface states on Au(110)]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.085401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.085401"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): H. Ishida
There is currently large interest in the orbital Rashba effect at crystal surfaces. Here, the author investigates the orbital angular momentum induced spin splitting of surface states on Au(110) by first-principles calculations. It is revealed that although the p component of the orbital angular momentum is much smaller than the d component, the former gives rise to a large anisotropy in the orientation dependence of spin-splitting energies. This is because the spin-orbit coupling parameter for the p orbital of Au is several times larger than that for the d orbital.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 085401] Published Wed Aug 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>H. Ishida</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tuning heat transport in graphene by tension]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L081401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L081401"/>
        <updated>2023-08-02T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): H. Liu, M. Lee, M. Šiškins, H. S. J. van der Zant, P. G. Steeneken, and G. J. Verbiest
The speed of sound and flexural phonons in two-dimensional materials depends strongly on the tension in these ultraflexible membranes. Here, the authors experimentally demonstrate that freestanding graphene membranes cool down 33% faster when increasing tension by electrostatic gating. They attribute this effect mainly to improved acoustic impedance match of flexural phonons at the boundaries of the membrane and thus provide a route towards electronic devices and circuits for high-speed control of nanoscale heat transport.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L081401] Published Wed Aug 02, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>H. Liu, M. Lee, M. Šiškins, H. S. J. van der Zant, P. G. Steeneken, and G. J. Verbiest</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interrelated Thermalization and Quantum Criticality in a Lattice Gauge Simulator]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.050401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.050401"/>
        <updated>2023-08-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Han-Yi Wang, Wei-Yong Zhang, Zhiyuan Yao, Ying Liu, Zi-Hang Zhu, Yong-Guang Zheng, Xuan-Kai Wang, Hui Zhai, Zhen-Sheng Yuan, and Jian-Wei Pan
Atoms trapped in a one-dimensional optical lattice can mimic how—in a basic quantum field theory—massive particles reach, or fail to reach, thermal equilibrium.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 050401] Published Tue Aug 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Han-Yi Wang, Wei-Yong Zhang, Zhiyuan Yao, Ying Liu, Zi-Hang Zhu, Yong-Guang Zheng, Xuan-Kai Wang, Hui Zhai, Zhen-Sheng Yuan, and Jian-Wei Pan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Topological Superconductivity in Doped Magnetic Moiré Semiconductors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.056001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.056001"/>
        <updated>2023-08-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Valentin Crépel, Daniele Guerci, Jennifer Cano, J. H. Pixley, and Andrew Millis
Robust attraction and low-energy symmetry properties in transition metal dichalcogenide twisted bilayers may produce topologically protected superconductivity.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 056001] Published Tue Aug 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Valentin Crépel, Daniele Guerci, Jennifer Cano, J. H. Pixley, and Andrew Millis</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robust Fermi-Liquid Instabilities in Sign Problem-Free Models]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.056501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.056501"/>
        <updated>2023-08-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ori Grossman and Erez Berg
For all known symmetry-classes that generate a sign-problem free model within the determinant quantum Monte Carlo method, the Fermi liquid is unstable at zero temperature.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 056501] Published Tue Aug 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ori Grossman and Erez Berg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Surprises in the deep Hilbert space of all-to-all systems: From superexponential scrambling to slow entanglement growth]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.054301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.054301"/>
        <updated>2023-08-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Zihao Qi, Thomas Scaffidi, and Xiangyu Cao
Quantum dynamics of spin systems with uniform infinite-range interaction are often considered “simple” because they become semiclassical in the thermodynamic limit. However, the standard semiclassical theory only applies to a shallow surface of the vast many-body Hilbert space. What happens away from this? Here, the authors dive into the “deep Hilbert space” and unveil a number of exotic phenomena in this rarely charted territory.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 054301] Published Tue Aug 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Zihao Qi, Thomas Scaffidi, and Xiangyu Cao</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Energy transfer in random-matrix ensembles of Floquet Hamiltonians]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.064301</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.064301"/>
        <updated>2023-08-01T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christina Psaroudaki and Gil Refael
Quantum machines have been a fascination for years. This paper examines a specific quantum machine - a spin driven by two harmonically related light beams. When the spin adopts a specific Floquet state, it receives energy from one beam and transfers it to the other, acting as an energy frequency converter. The authors study the power distribution of this 2-beam and spin system, uncovering an intriguing transition in distribution width, tuned by the drive amplitude.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 064301] Published Tue Aug 01, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christina Psaroudaki and Gil Refael</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rare $^{40}\mathrm{K}$ Decay with Implications for Fundamental Physics and Geochronology]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.052503</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.052503"/>
        <updated>2023-07-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Stukel et al. (KDK Collaboration)
Researchers revisit a neglected decay mode with implications for fundamental physics and for dating some of the oldest rocks on Earth and in the Solar System.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 052503] Published Mon Jul 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Stukel &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (KDK Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Generation of Near-Equipartition Magnetic Fields in Turbulent Collisionless Plasmas]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.055201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.055201"/>
        <updated>2023-07-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Lorenzo Sironi, Luca Comisso, and Ryan Golant
Weibel-generated magnetic fields can be dynamo amplified and reach near equipartition under the continuous action of turbulent gravitational forces generated by the large-scale structure in the universe.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 055201] Published Mon Jul 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lorenzo Sironi, Luca Comisso, and Ryan Golant</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evidence for ground-state electron capture of $^{40}\mathrm{K}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.014327</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.014327"/>
        <updated>2023-07-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): L. Hariasz et al. (KDK Collaboration)
Potassium-40 (40K) is a long-lived, naturally occurring radioisotope whose decay properties impact geochronology as well as rare-event searches. The KDK Collaboration reports first experimental evidence for the existence of the very rare electron-capture branch from 40K to the ground state of 40Ar, suppressed by two orders of magnitude as compared to the decay to the excited state of 40Ar. This measurement quantifies a previously ill-known background in rare-event searches, resolves a longstanding uncertainty in potassium-based geological age estimates, and benchmarks the theoretical modeling of highly forbidden weak decays including a neutrinoless double-β decay.

[Phys. Rev. C 108, 014327] Published Mon Jul 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>L. Hariasz &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (KDK Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Structure, stability, and superconductivity of N-doped lutetium hydrides at kbar pressures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014511</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014511"/>
        <updated>2023-07-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Katerina P. Hilleke, Xiaoyu Wang, Dongbao Luo, Nisha Geng, Busheng Wang, Francesco Belli, and Eva Zurek
The recent results describing a room-temperature superconductor in the lutetium nitrogen hydrogen system have prompted an avalanche of work. In this computational study, a range of techniques from crystal structure prediction to prototype modification, produce an array of low-pressure dynamically stable Lu-N-H phases. None were thermodynamically stable. The best fit to the experimental EOS came from fluorite-type LuH2, while the highest estimated Tc (a meager 17 K) arose from an extremely thermodynamically unstable phase based on 50% N substitution (LuNH)

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 014511] Published Mon Jul 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katerina P. Hilleke, Xiaoyu Wang, Dongbao Luo, Nisha Geng, Busheng Wang, Francesco Belli, and Eva Zurek</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Suppression of spin-wave nonreciprocity due to interfacial Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya interaction by lateral confinement in magnetic nanostructures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.024430</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.024430"/>
        <updated>2023-07-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): S. Tacchi, R. Silvani, M. Kuepferling, A. Fernández Scarioni, S. Sievers, H. W. Schumacher, E. Darwin, M.-A. Syskaki, G. Jakob, M. Kläui, and G. Carlotti
Brillouin light scattering (BLS) experiments assisted by micromagnetic simulations show that the difference in frequency between counterpropagating spin waves in extended films and multilayers, induced by interfacial Dzyaloshinskii–Moriya interaction (i-DMI), is strongly reduced when lateral confinement is introduced. This poses a limit to the exploitation of BLS to quantify the i-DMI strength in the case of magnetic elements, such as dots and wires, with lateral dimensions below about 400 nm.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 024430] Published Mon Jul 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>S. Tacchi, R. Silvani, M. Kuepferling, A. Fernández Scarioni, S. Sievers, H. W. Schumacher, E. Darwin, M.-A. Syskaki, G. Jakob, M. Kläui, and G. Carlotti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ultrahigh-Sensitivity Bragg Atom Gravimeter and its Application in Testing Lorentz Violation]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014067</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014067"/>
        <updated>2023-07-31T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Tao Zhang, Le-Le Chen, Yu-Biao Shu, Wen-Jie Xu, Yuan Cheng, Qin Luo, Zhong-Kun Hu, and Min-Kang Zhou
This study reports a significant result in atom interferometry, specifically for gravity measurements: an achieved sensitivity of 2.2×10−8 m/s2 per shot, which advances the state of the art by about a factor of two. Integrating for 2000 s, the resolution here is 8×10−10 m/s2, which is equivalent to the effect produced by a 60-kg person 2 m away. Based on such extremely sensitive and stable gravity measurements, a test of local Lorentz invariance in the gravity sector is performed, where the accuracy of the upper bound on the space-space component is improved by a factor of four—a milestone result in testing fundamental physics with such metrology.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 014067] Published Mon Jul 31, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tao Zhang, Le-Le Chen, Yu-Biao Shu, Wen-Jie Xu, Yuan Cheng, Qin Luo, Zhong-Kun Hu, and Min-Kang Zhou</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Dark Matter Search Results from the LUX-ZEPLIN (LZ) Experiment]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.041002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.041002"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. Aalbers et al. (LUX-ZEPLIN Collaboration)
Two mammoth underground detectors have delivered more stringent upper limits on how strongly a putative dark matter candidate interacts with normal matter.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 041002] Published Fri Jul 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. Aalbers &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LUX-ZEPLIN Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Dark Matter Search with Nuclear Recoils from the XENONnT Experiment]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.041003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.041003"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): E. Aprile et al. (XENON Collaboration)
Two mammoth underground detectors have delivered more stringent upper limits on how strongly a putative dark matter candidate interacts with normal matter.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 041003] Published Fri Jul 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>E. Aprile &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (XENON Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phonon Laser in the Quantum Regime]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.043605</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.043605"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Behrle, T. L. Nguyen, F. Reiter, D. Baur, B. de Neeve, M. Stadler, M. Marinelli, F. Lancellotti, S. F. Yelin, and J. P. Home
A laser for vibrational energy, rather than for light, operating in the quantum regime could teach researchers about the interplay between spin, vibration, and dissipation in quantum mechanics.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 043605] Published Fri Jul 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Behrle, T. L. Nguyen, F. Reiter, D. Baur, B. de Neeve, M. Stadler, M. Marinelli, F. Lancellotti, S. F. Yelin, and J. P. Home</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis of Metallic Space-Time Gratings Using Lorentz Transformations]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014063</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014063"/>
        <updated>2023-07-28T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Antonio Alex-Amor, Carlos Molero, and Mário G. Silveirinha
Research on space-time-modulated systems has recently attracted interest due to their fascinating properties, such as nonreciprocity and frequency mixing. However, the scarcity of commercial full-wave solutions limits their study at present. Here mathematical tools are presented to shed light on the physics of moving and space-time metallic gratings, for direct application in engineering.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 014063] Published Fri Jul 28, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Antonio Alex-Amor, Carlos Molero, and Mário G. Silveirinha</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Observation of a Doubly Charged Tetraquark and Its Neutral Partner]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.041902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.041902"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Aaij et al. (LHCb Collaboration)
CERN’s Large Hadron Collider has detected the signals of two new four-quark states that are unusual because of their charges and their quark compositions.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 041902] Published Thu Jul 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Aaij &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHCb Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetic Susceptibility of Andreev Bound States in Superfluid $^{3}\mathrm{He}\text{−}\mathrm{B}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.046001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.046001"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. W. Scott, M. D. Nguyen, D. Park, and W. P. Halperin
The magnetic susceptibility of superfluid Helium-3 in an anisotropic stretched aerogel exhibits behavior indicative of surface Andreev bound states within the planar aerogel structure.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 046001] Published Thu Jul 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. W. Scott, M. D. Nguyen, D. Park, and W. P. Halperin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nonmonotonous Translocation Time of Polymers across Pores]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.048101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.048101"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Emanuele Locatelli, Valentino Bianco, Chantal Valeriani, and Paolo Malgaretti
The translocation time of linear polymers across a varying-section channel shows a nonmonotonous dependence on the polymer size, that may be a useful tool to design channels for polymer sorting.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 048101] Published Thu Jul 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emanuele Locatelli, Valentino Bianco, Chantal Valeriani, and Paolo Malgaretti</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bag-mediated film atomization in a cough machine]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.074802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.074802"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pallav Kant, Cesar Pairetti, Youssef Saade, Stéphane Popinet, Stéphane Zaleski, and Detlef Lohse
Studying the fluid dynamics of exhalations, from droplet formation to turbulent cloud transport, is vital for understanding respiratory disease transmission. Our research combines experiments and numerical modeling to uncover the interfacial phenomena involved in bioaerosol generation during forceful breathing actions like coughing or sneezing. By investigating these fluid-mechanical processes, we aim to establish a foundation for optimizing mitigation strategies and promoting public health and well-being.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 074802] Published Thu Jul 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pallav Kant, Cesar Pairetti, Youssef Saade, Stéphane Popinet, Stéphane Zaleski, and Detlef Lohse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amplitude analysis of ${B}^{0}→{\overline{D}}^{0}{D}_{s}^{+}{π}^{−}$ and ${B}^{+}→{D}^{−}{D}_{s}^{+}{π}^{+}$ decays]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.012017</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.012017"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Aaij et al. (LHCb Collaboration)
CERN’s Large Hadron Collider has detected the signals of two new four-quark states that are unusual because of their charges and their quark compositions.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 012017] Published Thu Jul 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Aaij &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHCb Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Control of Four-Magnon Scattering by Pure Spin Current in a Magnonic Waveguide]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014062</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014062"/>
        <updated>2023-07-27T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Hache, L. Körber, T. Hula, K. Lenz, A. Kákay, O. Hellwig, J. Lindner, J. Fassbender, and H. Schultheiss
Spintronic devices have attracted strong interest in neuromorphic computing, because of their inherent nonlinear behavior and synchronization capabilities. To build magnon-based networks between spintronic oscillators acting as neurons, control mechanisms are the key to adjusting their interactions. This study uses spin-orbit torque to reduce damping and enable magnon scattering in ultrathin waveguides. Microwave power and frequency, as well as spin-current magnitude, can be used as control parameters for nonlinear generation of additional magnon modes at distinct frequencies. Field-dependent time- and space-resolved measurements expose the underlying physical process.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 014062] Published Thu Jul 27, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Hache, L. Körber, T. Hula, K. Lenz, A. Kákay, O. Hellwig, J. Lindner, J. Fassbender, and H. Schultheiss</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Control over epitaxy and the role of the InAs/Al interface in hybrid two-dimensional electron gas systems]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.073403</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.073403"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Erik Cheah, Daniel Z. Haxell, Rüdiger Schott, Peng Zeng, Ekaterina Paysen, Sofieke C. ten Kate, Marco Coraiola, Max Landstetter, Ali B. Zadeh, Achim Trampert, Marilyne Sousa, Heike Riel, Fabrizio Nichele, Werner Wegscheider, and Filip Krizek
The interface quality in semiconductor/superconductor (SE/SC) platforms plays a crucial role for the superconducting coupling strength. In this work, a novel growth approach to grow grain-boundary-free Al on a lattice-mismatched InAs quantum well is introduced. More specifically, a monocrystalline Al phase is achieved by intentional roughening of the semiconductor surface. This approach can in general be applied to other mismatched material systems where a high degree of crystallinity is essential. Furthermore, the authors investigate the altered interfaces in transport measurements, hoping to shed more light upon the pressing question: “What is the role of the detailed crystallography of the SC for the performance of SE/SC hybrid devices?”

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 073403] Published Wed Jul 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erik Cheah, Daniel Z. Haxell, Rüdiger Schott, Peng Zeng, Ekaterina Paysen, Sofieke C. ten Kate, Marco Coraiola, Max Landstetter, Ali B. Zadeh, Achim Trampert, Marilyne Sousa, Heike Riel, Fabrizio Nichele, Werner Wegscheider, and Filip Krizek</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Symmetry-enforced Fermi degeneracy in topological semimetal $\mathrm{Rh}{\mathrm{Sb}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.074205</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.074205"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): K. Wang, L. Wang, I-L. Liu, F. Boschini, M. Zonno, M. Michiardi, E. Rotenberg, A. Bostwick, D. Graf, B. J. Ramshaw, A. Damascelli, and J. Paglione
Following the discovery of topological insulators, new classes of topological materials such as Dirac, Weyl, and “nodal” semimetals have attracted considerable interest. This work reports an experimental exploration of RhSb3, a symmorphic cubic unfilled skutterudite compound that was predicted to host a quasi-linear electronic band dispersion long before the topological revolution. Angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy, magnetotransport, and quantum oscillation measurements are used to confirm this material family to host a symmetry-enforced Fermi degeneracy, complete with nonzero Berry phase and location of the Fermi energy in the linear regime of the system’s valence band.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 074205] Published Wed Jul 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>K. Wang, L. Wang, I-L. Liu, F. Boschini, M. Zonno, M. Michiardi, E. Rotenberg, A. Bostwick, D. Graf, B. J. Ramshaw, A. Damascelli, and J. Paglione</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anisotropic magnetism of the Shastry-Sutherland lattice material $\mathrm{Ba}{\mathrm{Nd}}_{2}\mathrm{Pt}{\mathrm{O}}_{5}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.074407</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.074407"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Christopher M. Pasco, Binod K. Rai, Matthias Frontzek, Gabriele Sala, Matthew B. Stone, Bryan C. Chakoumakos, V. Ovidiu Garlea, Andrew D. Christianson, and Andrew F. May
The Shastry-Sutherland (SS) model is one of the few solvable models for emergent properties of frustrated spin systems. However, relatively few materials realize an interacting spin network that is topologically equivalent to the SS model. In this work, researchers have expanded the material space with a foundational study of single crystalline BaNd2PtO5, which contains an effective SS lattice of Nd moments. A complex three-dimensional magnetic structure was observed via neutron single crystal diffraction. This spin structure is associated with a large magnetic anisotropy and a particularly strong sensitivity of the magnetization to the crystal orientation. These results offer an interesting new candidate for studying the physics associated with the SS model and establish a high sensitivity to crystal orientation as a guide when studying related materials.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 074407] Published Wed Jul 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Christopher M. Pasco, Binod K. Rai, Matthias Frontzek, Gabriele Sala, Matthew B. Stone, Bryan C. Chakoumakos, V. Ovidiu Garlea, Andrew D. Christianson, and Andrew F. May</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hindered segmental dynamics in associative protein hydrogels studied by neutron spin-echo spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.075602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.075602"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Ameya Rao, Brian R. Carrick, Helen Yao, and Bradley D. Olsen
In this study, associative polymer hydrogels formed by well-defined artificial proteins are found to exhibit unexpected submolecular dynamics, including a suppression of segmental diffusion with junction density and self-similar diffusive behavior in gels of different strand lengths and numbers of stickers per chain. These properties are in contrast to conventional polymer gels, demonstrating the rich physics of transient bonds in physically associating systems on molecular-scale dynamics.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 075602] Published Wed Jul 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ameya Rao, Brian R. Carrick, Helen Yao, and Bradley D. Olsen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stability and magnetic behavior of exfoliable nanowire one-dimensional materials]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.076002</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.7.076002"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Joshua T. Paul, Janet Lu, Sohum Shah, Stephen R. Xie, and Richard G. Hennig
Researchers have demonstrated a way to sift a database of crystalline compounds for structures that can be separated into useful one-dimensional materials.

[Phys. Rev. Materials 7, 076002] Published Wed Jul 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joshua T. Paul, Janet Lu, Sohum Shah, Stephen R. Xie, and Richard G. Hennig</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Electroassociation of Ultracold Dipolar Molecules into Tetramer Field-Linked States]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.043402</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.043402"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Goulven Quéméner, John L. Bohn, and James F. E. Croft
A proposed method uses electric fields to form tetramers from two ultracold dipolar molecules, analogous to the magnetic field association between two atoms to form molecules.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 043402] Published Wed Jul 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Goulven Quéméner, John L. Bohn, and James F. E. Croft</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information-field-based global Bayesian inference of the jet transport coefficient]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.L011901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.108.L011901"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Man Xie, Weiyao Ke, Hanzhong Zhang, and Xin-Nian Wang
All recent analyses of heavy-ion data that extract information about the transport properties of excited strongly interacting matter use Bayesian techniques to fit parameters of functional forms motivated by physical insight. These explicit parameterizations may introduce undesired long-range correlations between different regions of parameter space. This paper develops an information field approach to avoid an explicit functional parameterization and obtain a global Bayesian inference of the jet transport coefficient q̂ as a function of the temperature.

[Phys. Rev. C 108, L011901] Published Wed Jul 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Man Xie, Weiyao Ke, Hanzhong Zhang, and Xin-Nian Wang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revealing temperature evolution of the Dirac band in ${\mathrm{ZrTe}}_{5}$ via magnetoinfrared spectroscopy]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L041202</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L041202"/>
        <updated>2023-07-26T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Yuxuan Jiang, Tianhao Zhao, Luojia Zhang, Qiang Chen, Haidong Zhou, Mykhaylo Ozerov, Dmitry Smirnov, and Zhigang Jiang
The topological phases and their dependence on the lattice constant in zirconium pentatelluride ZrTe5 have been under heated debate. Here, the authors study the temperature evolution of the Dirac band in ZrTe5 and find no indication of band-gap closure as temperature changes. They show that a weak topological insulator phase across the temperature range may not be the only explanation. A topological phase transition is still possible if the band mixing and inversion are considered.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L041202] Published Wed Jul 26, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Yuxuan Jiang, Tianhao Zhao, Luojia Zhang, Qiang Chen, Haidong Zhou, Mykhaylo Ozerov, Dmitry Smirnov, and Zhigang Jiang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tissue Flows Are Tuned by Actomyosin-Dependent Mechanics in Developing Embryos]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.1.013004</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.1.013004"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Marisol Herrera-Perez, Christian Cupo, Cole Allan, Alicia B. Dagle, and Karen E. Kasza
In this study, the authors utilize optogenetic tools to achieve precise in vivo manipulation of actomyosin, allowing them to investigate the effects of its activation and deactivation on tissue behavior during early development in Drosophila.

[PRX Life 1, 013004] Published Tue Jul 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Marisol Herrera-Perez, Christian Cupo, Cole Allan, Alicia B. Dagle, and Karen E. Kasza</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flat $\mathrm{Γ}$ Moiré Bands in Twisted Bilayer ${\mathrm{WSe}}_{2}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.046401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.046401"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): G. Gatti, J. Issing, L. Rademaker, F. Margot, T. A. de Jong, S. J. van der Molen, J. Teyssier, T. K. Kim, M. D. Watson, C. Cacho, P. Dudin, J. Avila, K. Cordero Edwards, P. Paruch, N. Ubrig, I. Gutiérrez-Lezama, A. F. Morpurgo, A. Tamai, and F. Baumberger
Combined real- and momentum-space mapping of moire superlattices reveals intriguing flat-band physics of certain van der Waals materials.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 046401] Published Tue Jul 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>G. Gatti, J. Issing, L. Rademaker, F. Margot, T. A. de Jong, S. J. van der Molen, J. Teyssier, T. K. Kim, M. D. Watson, C. Cacho, P. Dudin, J. Avila, K. Cordero Edwards, P. Paruch, N. Ubrig, I. Gutiérrez-Lezama, A. F. Morpurgo, A. Tamai, and F. Baumberger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two-Dimensional Crystals far from Equilibrium]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.047101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.047101"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Leonardo Galliano, Michael E. Cates, and Ludovic Berthier
Crystals cannot form in two-dimensional particle systems at equilibrium. A new study has found a regime where a crystal can form if the system is driven out of equilibrium.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 047101] Published Tue Jul 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Leonardo Galliano, Michael E. Cates, and Ludovic Berthier</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robust wall modes and their interplay with bulk turbulence in confined rotating Rayleigh-Bénard convection]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.073501</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.073501"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Xander M. de Wit, Wouter J. M. Boot, Matteo Madonia, Andrés J. Aguirre Guzmán, and Rudie P. J. Kunnen
Rotating Rayleigh-Benard convection is the fundamental flow system to understand many geophysical and astrophysical flows. Typically studied in a confined cylindrical geometry, it was found in recent years that in such confined set-ups, a strong flow structure can develop near the side wall, obscuring observations of the bulk dynamics that we are interested in. Here we study different properties of this wall bounded flow, focussing on the interaction between the bulk and side wall region, to advance our understanding of how to disentangle the two.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 073501] Published Tue Jul 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Xander M. de Wit, Wouter J. M. Boot, Matteo Madonia, Andrés J. Aguirre Guzmán, and Rudie P. J. Kunnen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Substrate-mediated leg interactions play a key role in insect stability on granular slopes]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.014903</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.014903"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Miguel Piñeirua, Anna Verbe, and Jérôme Casas
Experiments show that an optimal distance between points of contact helps insects and other multilegged creatures avoid slipping down a steep granular slope.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 014903] Published Tue Jul 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miguel Piñeirua, Anna Verbe, and Jérôme Casas</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anharmonicity of the antiferrodistortive soft mode in barium zirconate ${\mathrm{BaZrO}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014309</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014309"/>
        <updated>2023-07-25T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Petter Rosander, Erik Fransson, Cosme Milesi-Brault, Constance Toulouse, Frédéric Bourdarot, Andrea Piovano, Alexei Bossak, Mael Guennou, and Göran Wahnström
BaZrO3 is one of the very few perovskites that is claimed to remain cubic down to 0 K, but its tendency towards an antiferrodistortive (AFD) instability has fueled a lot of debates. Here, the AFD phonon mode is studied using inelastic neutron scattering (INS) and inelastic x-ray scattering (IXS), combined with a computational approach including anharmonicity. Both classical molecular dynamics (MD) and a self-consistent phonon approach are used, the latter including quantum fluctuations of the atomic motion. This robust description of the AFD mode clarifies that BaZrO3 stays cubic down to 0 K.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 014309] Published Tue Jul 25, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Petter Rosander, Erik Fransson, Cosme Milesi-Brault, Constance Toulouse, Frédéric Bourdarot, Andrea Piovano, Alexei Bossak, Mael Guennou, and Göran Wahnström</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Single Flux Quantum-Based Digital Control of Superconducting Qubits in a Multichip Module]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.030310</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXQuantum.4.030310"/>
        <updated>2023-07-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C.H. Liu, A. Ballard, D. Olaya, D.R. Schmidt, J. Biesecker, T. Lucas, J. Ullom, S. Patel, O. Rafferty, A. Opremcak, K. Dodge, V. Iaia, T. McBroom, J.L. DuBois, P.F. Hopkins, S.P. Benz, B.L.T. Plourde, and R. McDermott
Integration of quantum bits and single flux quantum control elements in a multichip module provides a path to scaling, and an understanding of error mechanisms will guide future improvements in control fidelity.

[PRX Quantum 4, 030310] Published Mon Jul 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C.H. Liu, A. Ballard, D. Olaya, D.R. Schmidt, J. Biesecker, T. Lucas, J. Ullom, S. Patel, O. Rafferty, A. Opremcak, K. Dodge, V. Iaia, T. McBroom, J.L. DuBois, P.F. Hopkins, S.P. Benz, B.L.T. Plourde, and R. McDermott</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Femtosecond Polarization Shaping of Free-Electron Laser Pulses]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.045001</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.045001"/>
        <updated>2023-07-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Giovanni Perosa et al.
A new method can generate intense, extreme-ultraviolet (XUV) pulses with time-dependent polarization using a free-electron laser, which may lead to new coherent control schemes for probing and manipulating core electrons in matter.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 045001] Published Mon Jul 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Giovanni Perosa &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coupling of Ferromagnetic and Antiferromagnetic Spin Dynamics in ${\mathrm{Mn}}_{2}\mathrm{Au}/\mathrm{NiFe}$ Thin Film Bilayers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.046701</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.046701"/>
        <updated>2023-07-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Hassan Al-Hamdo, Tobias Wagner, Yaryna Lytvynenko, Gutenberg Kendzo, Sonka Reimers, Moritz Ruhwedel, Misbah Yaqoob, Vitaliy I. Vasyuchka, Philipp Pirro, Jairo Sinova, Mathias Kläui, Martin Jourdan, Olena Gomonay, and Mathias Weiler
By coupling antiferromagnetic and ferromagnetic modes in a ferromagnet-antiferromagnet bilayer, the antiferromagnetic dynamics can be made visible in the GHz range

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 046701] Published Mon Jul 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hassan Al-Hamdo, Tobias Wagner, Yaryna Lytvynenko, Gutenberg Kendzo, Sonka Reimers, Moritz Ruhwedel, Misbah Yaqoob, Vitaliy I. Vasyuchka, Philipp Pirro, Jairo Sinova, Mathias Kläui, Martin Jourdan, Olena Gomonay, and Mathias Weiler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drag resistance mediated by quantum spin liquids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014425</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014425"/>
        <updated>2023-07-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Raffaele Mazzilli, Alex Levchenko, and Elio J. König
Probing quantum spin liquid behavior in atomically thin materials is a challenging task. The authors propose here an experimental setup consisting of two metallic layers separated by a thin quantum spin liquid. The voltage induced in one of the metals by injecting a current in the other metal probes the nontrivial dynamics of gapless excitations in the quantum spin liquid. This analysis captures U(1) and ℤ2 quantum spin liquids and may find realizations in materials such as α-RuCl3, 1T-TaSe2, and 1T-TaS2.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 014425] Published Mon Jul 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Raffaele Mazzilli, Alex Levchenko, and Elio J. König</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Magnetocaloric-Effect-Enhanced Near-Field Magneto-optical Thermal Switch]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014053</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014053"/>
        <updated>2023-07-24T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Simo Pajovic and Svetlana V. Boriskina
Magnetism has played an increasingly important role in thermal technologies over the past century, including solid-state magnetic refrigerators and magneto-optical thermal switches. In this study, modeling shows that a two-pronged approach enables a thermal switch with two tuning “knobs”: a magnetocaloric knob to tune the temperature gradient, and a magneto-optical knob to fine-tune the effective thermal resistance. This enables additional modes of operation, such as reversing the flow of heat. This work highlights the utility of combining various “-caloric” effects with complementary modes of heat transfer for fresh ways of controlling thermal energy.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 014053] Published Mon Jul 24, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simo Pajovic and Svetlana V. Boriskina</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prediction of a roton-type feature in warm dense hydrogen]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033039</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.5.033039"/>
        <updated>2023-07-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Paul Hamann, Linda Kordts, Alexey Filinov, Michael Bonitz, Tobias Dornheim, and Jan Vorberger
This paper provides confirmation that a roton-type correlation effect manifest itself in warm dense hydrogen.

[Phys. Rev. Research 5, 033039] Published Fri Jul 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Paul Hamann, Linda Kordts, Alexey Filinov, Michael Bonitz, Tobias Dornheim, and Jan Vorberger</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Operator Product Expansion Coefficients of the 3D Ising Criticality via Quantum Fuzzy Spheres]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.031601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.031601"/>
        <updated>2023-07-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Liangdong Hu, Yin-Chen He, and W. Zhu
A new numerical technique leads to the precise determination of conformal data in the 3D Ising model, including some previously unknown expansion coefficients.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 031601] Published Fri Jul 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Liangdong Hu, Yin-Chen He, and W. Zhu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vortex dynamics and fin-fin interactions resulting in performance enhancement in fish-like propulsion]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.073101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.073101"/>
        <updated>2023-07-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Jiacheng Guo (郭佳诚), Pan Han (韩攀), Wei Zhang (张伟), Junshi Wang (王君实), George V. Lauder, Valentina Di Santo, and Haibo Dong (董海波)
The generation of leading-edge vortices (LEV) by the caudal fin (CF) has long been recognized as playing a key role in efficient propulsion in fish-like swimming. This study focuses on LEV enhancement due to vortex shedding of the median anal fin (AF), utilizing trout’s unique morphology and fin configurations. The shed anal-fin vortex (AFV) is found to stabilize and strengthen the LEV of the CF through its shearing with the CF leading edge, creating stronger leading-edge suction, resulting in stronger thrust production and increased propulsive efficiency in trout-like swimming.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 073101] Published Fri Jul 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jiacheng Guo (郭佳诚), Pan Han (韩攀), Wei Zhang (张伟), Junshi Wang (王君实), George V. Lauder, Valentina Di Santo, and Haibo Dong (董海波)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mass Partitioning in Fragmenting Tin Sheets]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014048</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevApplied.20.014048"/>
        <updated>2023-07-21T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Bo Liu, Randy A. Meijer, Wei Li, Javier Hernandez-Rueda, Hanneke Gelderblom, and Oscar O. Versolato
This article reports experiments on the mass partitioning of a fragmenting liquid sheet, formed after the impact of a nanosecond laser pulse on a tin microdroplet, to help in optimizing mass utilization of the liquid tin that is key to extreme-ultraviolet nanolithography. The authors apply machine learning to analyze subresolution fragments in the temporal evolution of the sheet and its bounding rim, ligaments protruding from the rim, and droplets shed by the ligaments. A full accounting includes the further contributions unique to laser-droplet impact: the mass ablated by the laser, and a surprising, centrally located mass remnant.

[Phys. Rev. Applied 20, 014048] Published Fri Jul 21, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bo Liu, Randy A. Meijer, Wei Li, Javier Hernandez-Rueda, Hanneke Gelderblom, and Oscar O. Versolato</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thermodynamic Limits of Sperm Swimming Precision]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.1.013003</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PRXLife.1.013003"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): C. Maggi, F. Saglimbeni, V. Carmona Sosa, R. Di Leonardo, B. Nath, and A. Puglisi
This study employs the thermodynamic uncertainty relation to explore the connection between energy dissipation and mesoscopic fluctuations in sperm beating, elucidating the role of the coupling among molecular motors that actuate the flagellar movement.

[PRX Life 1, 013003] Published Thu Jul 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>C. Maggi, F. Saglimbeni, V. Carmona Sosa, R. Di Leonardo, B. Nath, and A. Puglisi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exciton superfluidity in two-dimensional heterostructures from first principles: Importance of material-specific screening]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014506</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014506"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Rune Højlund, Emil Grovn, Sahar Pakdel, Kristian S. Thygesen, and Fredrik Nilsson
van der Waal heterostructures can host long-lived excitons that can condense and exhibit superfluidity at low temperatures. In this paper, Højlund, Grovn and coworkers derive a first-principles framework, based on existing open-source codes, that can be used to model these systems. This framework is then used to evaluate the exciton binding energies and superfluid properties of hundreds of different heterostructures. Based on these calculations, the authors propose optimized materials with superior properties compared to the standard platforms.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 014506] Published Thu Jul 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rune Højlund, Emil Grovn, Sahar Pakdel, Kristian S. Thygesen, and Fredrik Nilsson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dynamics of orbital degrees of freedom probed via isotope $^{121,123}\mathrm{Sb}$ nuclear quadrupole moments in Sb-substituted iron pnictide superconductors]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014507</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.014507"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): T. Kouchi, K. Yoshinaga, T. Asano, S. Nishioka, M. Yashima, H. Mukuda, A. Iyo, T. Kawashima, and S. Miyasaka
Since the discovery of the iron-based high-temperature superconductors, the superconductivity mechanism related to spin fluctuations and nematic (orbital) fluctuations has been much discussed, but it is remains unclear. Here, the authors reveal that the isotope 121,123Sb nuclei with large quadrupole moments are a sensitive local probe to observe the dynamics of orbital degrees of freedom. This provides us with a new approach to investigate systematically the correlation between the superconductivity and both the nematic and spin fluctuations, even in polycrystalline samples.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 014507] Published Thu Jul 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>T. Kouchi, K. Yoshinaga, T. Asano, S. Nishioka, M. Yashima, H. Mukuda, A. Iyo, T. Kawashima, and S. Miyasaka</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Optical magnetoelectric effects resonantly enhanced via electromagnons in cycloidal helimagnets ${\mathrm{Eu}}_{1−x}{\mathrm{Y}}_{x}{\mathrm{MnO}}_{3}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.024418</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.024418"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Ogino, Y. Kaneko, Y. Tokura, and Y. Takahashi
Dynamical magnetoelectric coupling gives rise to nonreciprocal phenomena for light such as the optical diode effect and the nonreciprocity of light polarization. Here, the authors comprehensively study these nonreciprocal optical effects resonantly enhanced by electromagnons for multiferroic spin spiral states of perovskite manganites. The giant nonreciprocity observed near the phase boundary demonstrates an important role of anharmonicity of spin excitations for these nonreciprocal effects. Furthermore, they find one of the largest values for the dynamical magnetoelectric coupling on the resonance of electromagnons.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 024418] Published Thu Jul 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Ogino, Y. Kaneko, Y. Tokura, and Y. Takahashi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Obstructions to gapped phases from noninvertible symmetries]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.045134</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.045134"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Anuj Apte, Clay Córdova, and Ho Tat Lam
Our understanding of quantum symmetry of systems has considerably broadened over the last decade. The idea of symmetry has become intrinsically linked with topology described and algebraically characterized by higher categories. Studying three-dimensional systems with noninvertible symmetries, the authors show here that these symmetries are in general incompatible with a unique gapped ground state. Their results extend the ideas behind the Lieb-Shultz-Mattis theorem to the arena of higher-dimensional field theories invariant under a novel class of symmetries.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 045134] Published Thu Jul 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Anuj Apte, Clay Córdova, and Ho Tat Lam</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strain control of exciton and trion spin-valley dynamics in monolayer transition metal dichalcogenides]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L041404</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L041404"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Z. An, P. Soubelet, Y. Zhumagulov, M. Zopf, A. Delhomme, C. Qian, P. E. Faria Junior, J. Fabian, X. Cao, J. Yang, A. V. Stier, F. Ding, and J. J. Finley
The spin-valley physics of monolayer transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) remains one of the main interests in the class of van der Waals materials. At low temperature, it is mainly driven by the electron-hole exchange interaction (EHEI) that describes the annihilation of an exciton in one valley and the creation of an exciton in the time-reversal equivalent valley. Here, the authors show that the EHEI in monolayer TMDs is biaxial strain dependent and, surprisingly, it is an order of magnitude more strain dependent than expected from these first principles calculations. This points to a valley scattering channel that has not been considered in the literature so far.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L041404] Published Thu Jul 20, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Z. An, P. Soubelet, Y. Zhumagulov, M. Zopf, A. Delhomme, C. Qian, P. E. Faria Junior, J. Fabian, X. Cao, J. Yang, A. V. Stier, F. Ding, and J. J. Finley</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Direct Observation of Collider Neutrinos with FASER at the LHC]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.031801</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.031801"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Henso Abreu et al. (FASER Collaboration)
The first observation of neutrinos produced at a particle collider opens a new field of study and offers ways to test the limits of the standard model.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 031801] Published Wed Jul 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Henso Abreu &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (FASER Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of Collider Muon Neutrinos with the SND@LHC Experiment]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.031802</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.031802"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Albanese et al. (SND@LHC Collaboration)
The first observation of neutrinos produced at a particle collider opens a new field of study and offers ways to test the limits of the standard model.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 031802] Published Wed Jul 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Albanese &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (SND@LHC Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Large-Momentum-Transfer Atom Interferometers with $\mathrm{μ}\mathrm{rad}$-Accuracy Using Bragg Diffraction]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.033602</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.033602"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J.-N. Kirsten-Siemß, F. Fitzek, C. Schubert, E. M. Rasel, N. Gaaloul, and K. Hammerer
A new method using atoms on optical gratings significantly improves the precision of the Bragg atom interferometers by reducing some of the detrimental systematic effects.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 033602] Published Wed Jul 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J.-N. Kirsten-Siemß, F. Fitzek, C. Schubert, E. M. Rasel, N. Gaaloul, and K. Hammerer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Extended Spatial Coherence of Interlayer Excitons in ${\mathrm{MoSe}}_{2}/{\mathrm{WSe}}_{2}$ Heterobilayers]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.036902</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.036902"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Mirco Troue, Johannes Figueiredo, Lukas Sigl, Christos Paspalides, Manuel Katzer, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Malte Selig, Andreas Knorr, Ursula Wurstbauer, and Alexander W. Holleitner
Evidence of coherent light emission from excitons in a 2D-material structure could inspire new quantum-technology applications.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 036902] Published Wed Jul 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mirco Troue, Johannes Figueiredo, Lukas Sigl, Christos Paspalides, Manuel Katzer, Takashi Taniguchi, Kenji Watanabe, Malte Selig, Andreas Knorr, Ursula Wurstbauer, and Alexander W. Holleitner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Compensation of seeding bias for particle tracking velocimetry in turbulent flows]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.074603</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevFluids.8.074603"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Thomas Barois, Bianca Viggiano, Thomas Basset, Raúl Bayoán Cal, Romain Volk, Mathieu Gibert, and Mickaël Bourgoin
For small particles locally injected in a turbulent flow and used as fluid tracers, the reconstruction of the mean flow is biased by the particle dispersion caused by turbulence. For example, in a turbulent jet with nozzle injection, the entrained flow is inaccurately measured because all the tracked particles come from the jet source. In this work, we present a compensation method that provides the accurate mean velocity for turbulent flows in non-homogeneous seeding conditions.

[Phys. Rev. Fluids 8, 074603] Published Wed Jul 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Thomas Barois, Bianca Viggiano, Thomas Basset, Raúl Bayoán Cal, Romain Volk, Mathieu Gibert, and Mickaël Bourgoin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stability of the modulator in a plasma-modulated plasma accelerator]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.015204</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevE.108.015204"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): J. J. van de Wetering, S. M. Hooker, and R. Walczak
Laser-plasma accelerators can provide a compact method for acceleration of particles. The authors of this paper derive a three-dimensional analytic theory for a laser-plasma accelerator that some of the authors introduced earlier. Using theory and simulations, they evaluate the influence of various parameters on the stability of the accelerator and conclude that higher energies can be achieved than those demonstrated in the original proposal.

[Phys. Rev. E 108, 015204] Published Wed Jul 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>J. J. van de Wetering, S. M. Hooker, and R. Walczak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interplay between magnetism and band topology in the kagome magnets $R{\mathrm{Mn}}_{6}{\mathrm{Sn}}_{6}$]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.045132</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.045132"/>
        <updated>2023-07-19T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Y. Lee, R. Skomski, X. Wang, P. P. Orth, Y. Ren, Byungkyun Kang, A. K. Pathak, A. Kutepov, B. N. Harmon, R. J. McQueeney, I. I. Mazin, and Liqin Ke
The kagome magnets RMn6Sn6 have recently emerged as a new topological materials platform. By elucidating the topological nature of the band structure, the authors conclude that the observed anomalous Hall conductivity is unrelated to the previously speculated quasi-two-dimensional Dirac points. The microscopic origin of magnetocrystalline anisotropy is explored at various levels: phenomenological, analytical, and ab initio. The authors discovered how the special Mn coordination of the rare-earth atoms results in significant high-order anisotropy.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 045132] Published Wed Jul 19, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Y. Lee, R. Skomski, X. Wang, P. P. Orth, Y. Ren, Byungkyun Kang, A. K. Pathak, A. Kutepov, B. N. Harmon, R. J. McQueeney, I. I. Mazin, and Liqin Ke</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Single-Photon Synchronization with a Room-Temperature Atomic Quantum Memory]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.033601</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.033601"/>
        <updated>2023-07-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Omri Davidson, Ohad Yogev, Eilon Poem, and Ofer Firstenberg
Researchers use two clouds of rubidium vapor to generate, store, and simultaneously release two photons.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 033601] Published Tue Jul 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Omri Davidson, Ohad Yogev, Eilon Poem, and Ofer Firstenberg</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Voltage X-Ray Reflectometry: A Method to Study Electric-Field-Induced Changes in Interfacial Electronic Structures]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.036201</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.036201"/>
        <updated>2023-07-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Sven Erik Ilse, Gisela Schütz, and Eberhard Goering
A new method enables element-specific measurements of electric-field-induced changes to electronic structures at buried interfaces.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 036201] Published Tue Jul 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sven Erik Ilse, Gisela Schütz, and Eberhard Goering</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Comprehensive <i>Ab Initio</i> Investigation of the Phase Diagram of Quasi-One-Dimensional Molecular Solids]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.036401</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.036401"/>
        <updated>2023-07-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Kazuyoshi Yoshimi, Takahiro Misawa, Takao Tsumuraya, and Hitoshi Seo
By deriving the \textit{ab initio} effective low-energy Hamiltonians of complex materials and analyzing them with a highly accurate numerical solver, a crucial parameter which determines physical properties has been identified, providing guidelines for designing functional organic materials.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 036401] Published Tue Jul 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kazuyoshi Yoshimi, Takahiro Misawa, Takao Tsumuraya, and Hitoshi Seo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kinematic Sunyaev-Zel’dovich effect with ACT, DES, and BOSS: A novel hybrid estimator]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.023516</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevD.108.023516"/>
        <updated>2023-07-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): M. Mallaby-Kay et al.
This paper introduces a novel, “hybrid” (optical+spectroscopic) estimator for kinematic Sunyaev-Zel’dovich (kSZ) studies. It is expected to be most useful for increasing the SZ signal when results from upcoming data surveys become available.

[Phys. Rev. D 108, 023516] Published Tue Jul 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>M. Mallaby-Kay &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt;</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Partial fillings of the bosonic ${E}_{8}$ quantum Hall state]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.035136</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.035136"/>
        <updated>2023-07-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Pak Kau Lim, Michael Mulligan, and Jeffrey C. Y. Teo
Interactions are crucial in driving topological phenomena in bosonic systems. Here, the authors construct exactly solvable models of topological phases of interacting bosons that preserve electric charge. They focus on the E8 bosonic integer quantum Hall state and show how its intrinsic E8 symmetry allows for the emergence of fractional topological phases of bosons. They detail the charge and statistics of the quasiparticle excitations of the resulting fractional quantum Hall states.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, 035136] Published Tue Jul 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pak Kau Lim, Michael Mulligan, and Jeffrey C. Y. Teo</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin-statistics relation for quantum Hall states]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L041105</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevB.108.L041105"/>
        <updated>2023-07-18T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Alberto Nardin, Eddy Ardonne, and Leonardo Mazza
Forty years ago, Laughlin explained the newly discovered fractional quantum Hall effect by proposing his famous wave function. He predicted the existence of anyons, particles with fractional charge, obeying fractional statistics. The fractional charge was confirmed almost thirty years ago, while the fractional statistics was observed only a few years back. In this paper, the authors focus on yet another fundamental property of the anyons, namely their spin. They derive a “spin-statistics relation” for anyons in fractional quantum Hall states, directly from the microscopic theory. This relation is a generalization of the fundamental “spin-statistics relation” that all ordinary particles obey.

[Phys. Rev. B 108, L041105] Published Tue Jul 18, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alberto Nardin, Eddy Ardonne, and Leonardo Mazza</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Observation of a $J/ψ\mathrm{Λ}$ Resonance Consistent with a Strange Pentaquark Candidate in ${B}^{−}→J/ψ\mathrm{Λ}\overline{p}$ Decays]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.031901</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.031901"/>
        <updated>2023-07-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): R. Aaij et al. (LHCb Collaboration)
A pentaquark candidate that has strange quark content, seen as a resonant structure in B−→JψΛp¯ decay, is observed for the first time.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 031901] Published Mon Jul 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>R. Aaij &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; (LHCb Collaboration)</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Synthesis of Single Crystals of $ε$-Iron and Direct Measurements of Its Elastic Constants]]></title>
        <id>http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.034101</id>
        <link href="http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevLett.131.034101"/>
        <updated>2023-07-17T10:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author(s): Agnès Dewaele, Bernard Amadon, Alexei Bosak, Volodymyr Svitlyk, and Florent Occelli
Laboratory experiments elucidate the directions and speeds at which acoustic waves propagate in the type of iron that likely makes up Earth’s core.

[Phys. Rev. Lett. 131, 034101] Published Mon Jul 17, 2023]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Agnès Dewaele, Bernard Amadon, Alexei Bosak, Volodymyr Svitlyk, and Florent Occelli</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>